<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0"
>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 19:13:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/newsletter/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <copyright><![CDATA[2023 Sunghyun Cho]]></copyright>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-12-04]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/12/04&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-12-04</h1>
<h2><a href="https://walzr.com/IMG_0001/">IMG_0001</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Between 2009 and 2012, iPhones featured a &quot;Send to YouTube&quot; button in the Photos app, resulting in numerous uploads with default IMG_XXXX filenames.- A bot was developed, inspired by Ben Wallace, to locate 5 million of these videos, showcasing raw and unedited moments.- The collection of videos is available for viewing, presented in a random order, offering a glimpse into unfiltered content from that era.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42314547">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion revolves around a minimalist user interface (UI) feature that displays view counts on videos, evoking nostalgia for the early internet&#39;s more personal and authentic content.- Users express mixed emotions, with some viewing personal videos as an invasion of privacy, despite their public availability, highlighting ongoing privacy concerns in internet culture.- The conversation reflects on the evolution of internet culture, contrasting the raw authenticity of past online experiences with the more sanitized and potentially privacy-invasive nature of today&#39;s web.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.armaansahni.com/game/">My son (9 yrs old) used plain JavaScript to make a game, and wants your feedback</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A 9-year-old has been learning coding, mastering HTML and CSS, and recently used Google Gemini to enhance his skills.- He created a game by coding HTML, CSS, and JavaScript in VSCode and used Piskel for animated graphics, with guidance from his parents and Google Gemini.- The child documented his experience in a blog post, discussing the process and receiving feedback from his programmer parents to refine his writing.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42312121">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A 9-year-old created a game using JavaScript, showcasing skills in HTML, CSS, and game design with tools like VSCode and Piskel.- The young developer received guidance from his programmer parents and used Google Gemini to enhance his coding skills.- Community feedback has been positive, with suggestions for improvements, indicating a supportive environment for his coding journey.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://egoless.engineering">Egoless Engineering</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The talk emphasizes the importance of fostering better work environments by breaking down unnecessary role divisions and encouraging collaboration across roles.- It highlights inefficiencies caused by excessive role splitting and the misconception of &quot;devops&quot; practices that create barriers rather than promoting collaboration.- The speaker advocates for valuing cooperation, curiosity, and shared responsibility, suggesting that misery should not be equated with productivity.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42311069">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Egoless Engineering focuses on collaboration, ownership, and minimizing unnecessary processes to enhance team efficiency.</li>
<li>It highlights the importance of creating high-trust environments to boost productivity and warns against the inefficiencies caused by politics in modern team structures.</li>
<li>Balancing autonomy with necessary oversight is crucial, especially in large projects, to foster a culture of trust and collaboration while managing human traits like ego.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.phoenixframework.org/blog/phoenix-liveview-1.0-released?release=1.0">Phoenix LiveView 1.0.0 is here</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Phoenix LiveView 1.0.0 has been released, offering a major update that simplifies dynamic server-rendered applications by reducing the need for JavaScript and enhancing real-time capabilities.- Key features of this release include a diffing engine for efficient updates, HEEx components for improved HTML composability, and interactive uploads, all leveraging Elixir and the Erlang VM for superior latency and scalability.- The update also introduces new features like streams and async operations, with future plans to integrate JavaScript hooks and Web Components, encouraging developers to explore its easy setup.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42312301">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Phoenix LiveView 1.0.0 has been released, featuring a new installer for easier setup and enhanced functionalities.</li>
<li>The release is considered a major milestone for the Elixir and Phoenix projects, with users praising its productivity and ease of use compared to other frameworks.</li>
<li>Despite some challenges like managing unreliable connections, the community is actively seeking solutions, and the creator, Chris McCord, is open to feedback.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/genie-2-a-large-scale-foundation-world-model/">Genie 2: A large-scale foundation world model</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Research Genie 2, released on December 4, 2024, is a large-scale foundation world model designed to generate diverse 3D environments for AI agent training.- Developed by Jack Parker-Holder&#39;s team, Genie 2 can create action-controllable, playable worlds from a single image prompt, supporting rapid prototyping and interactive experiences.- Genie 2 advances AI research by modeling object interactions, character animations, and environmental physics, addressing the challenge of creating rich training environments for embodied agents.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42317903">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Genie 2, developed by DeepMind, is a new world model that demonstrates potential in navigating environments using photos and text but lacks technical details, code, and open access.</li>
<li>It is considered more of a prototype for research and development rather than a finished product, leading to criticism about its inaccessibility and limited practical application.</li>
<li>The discussion around Genie 2 underscores the challenges of AI-generated content, the potential for future applications, and the competitive nature of AI development, with its real-world utility and impact still uncertain.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.openttd.org/">OpenTTD is an open source simulation game based upon Transport Tycoon Deluxe</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>OpenTTD 14.1 was released on May 3, 2024, focusing on bug fixes since the initial release.- Key updates include resolving a multiplayer desynchronization bug and enhancements to the ship pathfinder and unbunching feature.- Players have shown significant engagement, logging 34,700 hours in 17,219 games in the past week.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42314700">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>OpenTTD is an open-source simulation game inspired by Transport Tycoon Deluxe, notable for being playable without needing additional assets, unlike many other open-source remakes.- Released in 2004, OpenTTD replaced the original game graphics by 2009, enabling its distribution on platforms like Steam while maintaining the original style without asset copying.- The game supports multiplayer and has educational applications, such as in AI development, and continues to be popular for its nostalgic appeal and engaging gameplay.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/keyvank/30cc">My C compiler compiled itself</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42311031">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A user detailed their journey in developing a self-compiling C compiler, highlighting the challenges and rewards of the process.</li>
<li>Feedback focused on adhering to DRY (Don&#39;t Repeat Yourself) principles and avoiding unnecessary type casting with malloc(), a memory allocation function in C.</li>
<li>The discussion expanded to include topics like compiler compatibility, coding style, bootstrapping, and the pros and cons of using Makefiles versus Python scripts for project builds.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://tej.as/blog/how-to-grow-professional-relationships-tjs-model">How to grow professional relationships</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The TJS (The Journey to Synergy) Collaboration Model outlines seven states of professional relationships, ranging from competitive to shared identity, to enhance collaboration.</li>
<li>The model emphasizes moving from a zero-sum mindset to high-quality synergy, encouraging an abundance mindset and alignment with personal goals and values.</li>
<li>Key stages include Competition, Coexist, Communicate, Cooperate, Coordinate, Collaborate, and &quot;We are the same,&quot; with the ultimate goal of achieving more collectively than individually.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42315946">Reactions</a></h3>
<h2><a href="https://ppc.web.cern.ch/">A particle physics course for high-school students</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>CERN&#39;s Physics Education Research team has developed a pilot particle physics course for high-school students, consisting of 16 chapters with videos and quizzes.- The course, lasting approximately 4 hours, covers fundamental topics such as &quot;What is a particle?&quot; and &quot;What is a particle accelerator?&quot; and includes DIY experiments.- Participants can complete chapters in any order and earn a digital certificate upon completing all quizzes, with feedback encouraged to enhance future iterations.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42314340">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A particle physics course for high-school students in the UK involved 54 teenagers from 36 schools, conducted online over eight weeks.- Despite challenges such as limited interaction and self-esteem issues, over 80% of students passed a test with questions from an Oxford postgraduate quantum physics exam, with half achieving distinctions.- The course&#39;s success without complex math led to discussions on enforcing camera use in online classes, engaging students, and language accessibility for non-English speakers.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.infected.systems/posts/2024-12-01-no-nat-november/">No NAT November: My month without IPv4</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The &quot;No NAT November&quot; challenge involved disabling IPv4 and using only IPv6, highlighting the potential and challenges of transitioning to IPv6-only networks.- The author suggests an &quot;IPv6-mostly&quot; approach, which prioritizes IPv6 while maintaining dual-stack networks, reducing maintenance and preparing for an IPv4-free future.- Transitional technologies like NAT64 and DNS64 helped address compatibility issues, with Apple devices adapting well, while Windows and Linux showed mixed results.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42313507">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion highlights challenges in transitioning from IPv4 to IPv6, including ISP support issues, hardware limitations, and business and technical hurdles.</li>
<li>Users note benefits of IPv6, such as improved latency and simplified network management by avoiding NAT (Network Address Translation) complexities.</li>
<li>The conversation includes skepticism about IPv6 adoption and explores technical solutions, configurations, and its impact on security and network management.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/formaldehyde-epa-trump-public-health-danger">Formaldehyde Causes More Cancer Than Any Other Toxic Air Pollutant</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Formaldehyde, a prevalent air pollutant from sources like car exhaust and factories, poses significant cancer risks, particularly linked to myeloid leukemia.- Efforts to regulate formaldehyde have been obstructed by industry influence and political changes, with notable setbacks during the Trump administration.- ProPublica&#39;s investigation underscores the underestimated risks of formaldehyde exposure and the ongoing challenges in implementing effective regulations, despite some progress under the Biden administration.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42313910">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Formaldehyde is recognized as a major carcinogenic air pollutant, with ongoing debates about its regulation and associated health risks, particularly myeloid leukemia.</li>
<li>The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) faces criticism from some scientists regarding its assessment of formaldehyde&#39;s risks, highlighting the tension between public safety and economic interests.</li>
<li>Formaldehyde is commonly found in products like building materials and hair treatments, raising exposure concerns, while broader discussions include pollution from vehicle tires and reducing car dependency.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://emacsconf.org/2024/">EmacsConf 2024</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>EmacsConf 2024 is scheduled to be held online on December 7-8, featuring talks, volunteer opportunities, and discussions centered around GNU Emacs and Emacs Lisp.</li>
<li>The event will utilize free software for streaming and includes a satellite event in Lucerne, Switzerland, offering a hybrid experience.</li>
<li>Participants can engage in discussions via the emacsconf-discuss mailing list, organize through emacsconf-org, and connect on IRC at #emacsconf on irc.libera.chat, with content licensed under CC BY-SA 4.0 and GPLv3+.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42314024">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>EmacsConf 2024 emphasizes the lasting dedication of the Emacs community, showcasing its unique features despite not being as popular as editors like VS Code.- Key discussions focus on Emacs&#39; niche appeal, the relationship between popularity and software sustainability, and innovative presentations at the conference.- Notable topics include Emacs&#39; integration with AI and unique modes such as gptel, highlighting its adaptability and continued relevance.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/12/04/us/brian-thompson-united-healthcare-death/index.html">UnitedHealthcare CEO fatally shot in midtown Manhattan</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42317968">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The UnitedHealthcare CEO was tragically shot in Manhattan, leading to widespread speculation about the motive behind the incident.</li>
<li>Some suggest the motive may be linked to UnitedHealthcare&#39;s controversial practices, including denying claims for terminal illnesses.</li>
<li>The event has ignited conversations about the safety of high-profile individuals and the impact of corporate actions on public sentiment.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/12/03/arts/stephen-king-maine-radio-stations.html">Stephen King to shut down his 3 radio stations in Maine</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Stephen King is closing his three radio stations in Bangor, Maine, after over 40 years of ownership, due to financial losses and his age.</li>
<li>The stations, which reflect King&#39;s passion for rock music and local media, will cease operations on New Year&#39;s Eve.</li>
<li>This decision marks a significant change in King&#39;s business affairs, as he reorganizes his ventures.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42310683">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Stephen King is shutting down his three radio stations in Maine due to the challenges posed by the rise of corporate broadcasting, which makes it hard for small stations to compete.</li>
<li>The radio industry is facing difficulties as digital platforms like podcasts and YouTube become more popular, drawing audiences away from traditional radio.</li>
<li>The closure of King&#39;s stations underscores the broader struggles of independent radio businesses in adapting to a rapidly evolving media environment.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://insideevs.com/news/742893/porsche-macan-electric-ev-recall-headlights/">The Porsche Macan EV is being recalled because its headlights are too bright</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Porsche is recalling 2,941 Macan Electric models in the U.S. due to headlights that are too bright, requiring a service center visit for a software update.</li>
<li>The issue cannot be resolved through an over-the-air update, necessitating a physical visit to a service center for the free fix.</li>
<li>The recall affects vehicles manufactured between March 15 and November 4, 2024, with dealers and owners being notified in December 2024 and January 2025, respectively.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42311912">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Porsche Macan EV is being recalled due to headlights that are excessively bright, causing discomfort and safety concerns for drivers.</li>
<li>The recall underscores the differences in headlight regulations between the US and Europe, with the US having stricter brightness limits but less enforcement on proper adjustment.</li>
<li>The issue highlights a broader frustration among drivers regarding the increasing brightness of modern car headlights, particularly on larger vehicles like SUVs and trucks.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="IMG_0001" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=IMG_0001&subheading=Wednesday%2C%20December%204%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/12/04</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-04T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-12-03]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/12/03&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-12-03</h1>
<h2><a href="https://www.map.cv/blog/redbook">Facebook&#39;s Little Red Book</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>In 2012, Facebook created a &quot;Little Red Book&quot; to maintain its identity and focus as it expanded to a billion users, emphasizing principles like breaking things, thinking big, and moving fast.</li>
<li>The book, designed by Ben Barry, served as a manifesto to preserve Facebook&#39;s ethos during rapid growth, showcasing the importance of storytelling in scaling company culture.</li>
<li>A high-quality digital version of this rare book has been created to illustrate how successful companies maintain their identity and culture.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42299863">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Facebook&#39;s &quot;Little Red Book&quot; was an employee guide from 2012, designed to inspire a sense of mission and tech optimism.</li>
<li>The guide has faced criticism for its naivety and lack of self-awareness, especially in light of Facebook&#39;s later controversies involving data privacy and misinformation.</li>
<li>The book is viewed as a relic from a more hopeful era in tech, contrasting with the current complex realities of social media.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://apnews.com/article/south-korea-yoon-martial-law-997c22ac93f6a9bece68454597e577c1">South Korean president declares emergency martial law</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42306020">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol declared emergency martial law, but the National Assembly voted to demand its lifting, rendering the declaration void.</li>
<li>The military insists martial law will continue until the president officially ends it, leading to debates about constitutional obligations and potential impeachment.</li>
<li>The declaration is compared to a coup attempt, raising concerns about the military&#39;s role and the president&#39;s motives, including avoiding scandal investigations.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.henrikkarlsson.xyz/p/art-gallery">Lessons I learned working at an art gallery</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42302784">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The text emphasizes the subjective nature of art evaluation and the significance of networking in an artist&#39;s career success.- It discusses the challenges in predicting successful art exhibitions and the role of early professional connections.- The conversation extends to the complexities of defining &quot;great art,&quot; the influence of commercial success, and the importance of communication in professional settings.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://commoncog.com/c/cases/y-combinator-power/">Y Combinator and Power in Silicon Valley</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>In 2010, AdGrok, a small startup, faced a lawsuit from their former employer, Adchemy, which threatened their financial stability.- Y Combinator, a startup accelerator backing AdGrok, played a pivotal role in resolving the lawsuit by leveraging its influence with Adchemy&#39;s investors and potential business partners.- Despite winning the lawsuit, the ordeal led to AdGrok&#39;s sale to Twitter in 2011, while Adchemy was later sold to Walmart Labs in a fire-sale acquisition.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42303798">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Y Combinator (YC) is a major player in Silicon Valley, influencing which startups gain traction post-accelerator.- Critics suggest YC has adopted a &quot;spray and pray&quot; strategy, prioritizing the number of startups over selectivity and quality.- The debate centers on whether YC should scale its operations or concentrate on fewer, high-quality startups, reflecting broader complexities in startup culture and investment strategies.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://chshersh.com/blog/2023-12-16-8-months-of-ocaml-after-8-years-of-haskell.html">8 months of OCaml after 8 years of Haskell in production (2023)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author compares Haskell and OCaml based on their experience, highlighting that Haskell has more features and packages, but OCaml&#39;s simplicity enhances productivity.- Haskell&#39;s tooling is powerful yet inconsistent, while OCaml&#39;s tooling is straightforward and reliable, with succinct compiler messages.- Both languages are suitable for industrial use, but the author prefers OCaml for its focus on development rather than overthinking, despite Haskell&#39;s more comprehensive documentation.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42302426">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The author compares their experiences with Haskell and OCaml, highlighting Haskell&#39;s elegant but complex syntax and inconsistent tooling, particularly with specific GHC (Glasgow Haskell Compiler) versions.- OCaml is praised for its straightforwardness, simpler module system, faster compiler, and practicality in production, with fewer language extensions and a more manageable learning curve.- The author emphasizes the significance of a robust standard library for the success of a programming language.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://apnews.com/article/hiv-infections-aids-prevention-shot-02606f7d7892f0baf55bd0a0ff2ba3de">Twice-Yearly HIV Shot Shows 100% Effectiveness in Women</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42302963">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A new twice-yearly HIV shot has demonstrated 100% effectiveness in women, providing a promising alternative to daily pills or monthly shots.</li>
<li>This development is crucial for individuals who find it challenging to adhere to daily medication regimens, potentially simplifying HIV prevention efforts.</li>
<li>Despite its promise, the cost of the injectable form is a concern, though Gilead plans to offer more affordable, generic versions in 120 lower-income countries, potentially impacting public health in high HIV prevalence regions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/12/blizzards-pulling-of-warcraft-i-ii-tests-gogs-new-preservation-program/">Blizzard&#39;s pulling of Warcraft I and II tests GOG&#39;s new Preservation Program</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Blizzard has requested GOG to remove the DRM-free bundle of Warcraft I &amp; II from its store due to the release of remastered versions.</li>
<li>GOG is offering the bundle at a discount before removal, ensuring that buyers will still have access and receive updates for compatibility with modern systems.</li>
<li>This situation underscores the ongoing tension between remastered and original game versions, with GOG striving to preserve classic games despite publisher decisions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42303274">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Blizzard&#39;s removal of Warcraft I and II from GOG has drawn criticism, particularly in light of the negative feedback on the Warcraft 3 remaster.</li>
<li>Fans express concern that Blizzard, post-Activision merger, is focusing more on short-term profits than on maintaining game quality.</li>
<li>This situation underscores the difficulties in preserving gaming history, as highlighted by GOG&#39;s Preservation Program, and reflects the industry&#39;s trend towards profit-driven models.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2024/raspberry-pi-boosts-pi-5-performance-sdram-tuning">Raspberry Pi boosts Pi 5 performance with SDRAM tuning</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Raspberry Pi engineers have optimized SDRAM (Synchronous Dynamic Random-Access Memory) timings, resulting in a 10-20% performance boost for Pi 5 and Pi 4 at 2.4 GHz.</li>
<li>Overclocking, which involves increasing the clock speed beyond the manufacturer&#39;s specifications, can achieve up to a 32% speedup, with most Pi 5s reaching 2.6-3.0 GHz.</li>
<li>These performance enhancements, including NUMA (Non-Uniform Memory Access) emulation for better multi-core workload handling, may soon be available through firmware updates, potentially becoming standard features.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42303111">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Raspberry Pi 5 has improved performance due to SDRAM tuning, leading to discussions about using Intel N100s as an alternative.- Rising prices of Raspberry Pis make Intel N100s more attractive for those prioritizing performance per dollar, despite the Pi&#39;s advantages in GPIO (General Purpose Input/Output) and compact size.- The debate centers on the best use cases, with some favoring Raspberry Pis for simplicity and others choosing N100s for their superior power and versatility.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2024/12/03/no-need-to-email-me-about-cisco-anyconnect/">No need to email me about Cisco AnyConnect</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author&#39;s name and email are included in Cisco&#39;s AnyConnect VPN client due to the use of the curl library, leading to confusion among users seeking support.- The author clarifies they are the lead developer of curl, a component used in the app, but not affiliated with Cisco or AnyConnect.- Users needing support for AnyConnect should contact Cisco directly at <a href="mailto:ac-mobile-feedback@cisco.com">ac-mobile-feedback@cisco.com</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42303903">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Daniel Stenberg, the creator of curl, frequently receives misdirected support requests for Cisco AnyConnect, illustrating issues with companies obscuring their support channels.- Users often bypass their IT departments, possibly due to previous negative interactions, leading them to seek help from unrelated parties.- The conversation also highlights the difficulties of directly contacting individuals online, primarily due to concerns about spam.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.perl.com/article/duckduckgo-donates-25-000-to-the-perl-and-raku-foundation/">DuckDuckGo Donates $25k to the Perl and Raku Foundation</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>DuckDuckGo has donated $25,000 to The Perl and Raku Foundation (TPRF) on &quot;Giving Tuesday,&quot; contributing to their mission of advancing Perl and Raku programming languages.</li>
<li>Since 2011, DuckDuckGo has donated over $6 million to organizations that support online trust, highlighting its commitment to fostering secure and trustworthy online environments.</li>
<li>The donation will aid in funding core Perl development and community projects, with TPRF expressing gratitude for DuckDuckGo&#39;s support and confidence in their mission.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42307223">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>DuckDuckGo&#39;s $25k donation to the Perl and Raku Foundation has ignited discussions on the sustainability of open-source projects.</li>
<li>The decline in Perl usage and the lack of contributions from companies that rely on it highlight concerns about its future funding and tech debt issues.</li>
<li>The debate on the open-source model&#39;s reliance on donations and volunteer work suggests exploring alternative funding methods.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2024/12/company-claims-1000-percent-price-hike-drove-it-from-vmware-to-open-source-rival/">Company claims 1k% price hike drove it from VMware to open source rival</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Beeks Group, a UK cloud operator, transitioned 20,000 virtual machines (VMs) from VMware to OpenNebula following a 1,000% price increase after Broadcom acquired VMware.</li>
<li>This migration enhanced VM efficiency by 200% and allowed Beeks to allocate more resources to client workloads.</li>
<li>Broadcom&#39;s acquisition of VMware has led to increased costs and reduced support, prompting many companies, including AT&amp;T, to seek alternatives due to customer dissatisfaction.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42304955">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A significant price increase has prompted a company to transition from VMware to an open-source alternative, reflecting a broader trend in the industry.</li>
<li>The acquisition of VMware by Broadcom and subsequent pricing changes are driving businesses to explore other options, with Red Hat gaining new customers as a result.</li>
<li>The industry&#39;s shift towards containerization and Kubernetes is reducing the appeal of traditional virtual machines, emphasizing the need to consider vendor lock-in and explore alternatives like Proxmox or OpenNebula.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Facebook's Little Red Book" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Facebook's%20Little%20Red%20Book&subheading=Tuesday%2C%20December%203%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/12/03</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-03T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-12-02]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/12/02&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-12-02</h1>
<h2><a href="https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/newsroom/news/intel-ceo-news-dec-2024.html">Intel announces retirement of Pat Gelsinger</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Intel&#39;s CEO Pat Gelsinger announced his retirement after over 40 years, effective December 1, 2024, with David Zinsner and Michelle Johnston Holthaus serving as interim co-CEOs.</li>
<li>The board is committed to maintaining product leadership and efficiency, with Frank Yeary as interim executive chair during the search for a new CEO.</li>
<li>Intel remains a leader in semiconductor technology, inspired by Moore’s Law, with a focus on innovation and leadership continuity.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42296067">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Intel CEO Pat Gelsinger&#39;s retirement has prompted speculation about the company&#39;s future, with opinions divided on whether his aggressive strategy was beneficial or indicative of underlying issues.</li>
<li>Discussions have emerged about potential mergers, including a controversial suggestion of merging with AMD, which raises concerns about creating a monopoly.</li>
<li>The announcement has elicited mixed reactions, with some viewing it as a mistake and others considering it a necessary change for Intel&#39;s progress.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://publicdomainreview.org/features/entering-the-public-domain/2025/">What Will Enter the Public Domain in 2025?</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>On January 1, 2025, new works will enter the public domain, including those by creators who died in 1954 and 1974, and U.S. films/books from 1929.</li>
<li>The Public Domain Review, a UK Community Interest Company, uses profits for community benefit and relies on reader donations.</li>
<li>Readers are encouraged to explore resources like John Mark Ockerbloom’s “Public Domain Day Countdown” and Communia’s Manifesto for more information on the public domain.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42290448">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>In 2025, the expiration of the last patents on the h.264 (AVC) video codec will make it freely available, potentially increasing accessibility and reducing costs for users.</li>
<li>The HEVC codec remains entangled in patent complexities, highlighting ongoing challenges in video codec accessibility.</li>
<li>Discussions on copyright reform are ongoing, with proposals for shorter terms and more compulsory licenses to balance creators&#39; rights with public access, addressing concerns that current long terms primarily benefit corporations.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.math.uh.edu/~dblecher/pf2.html">How to Study Mathematics (2017)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The essay by Lawrence Neff Stout provides strategies for studying college-level mathematics, emphasizing the need for a deeper understanding of theory, definitions, and proofs compared to high school math.- Key strategies include understanding precise definitions, memorizing and comprehending theorems and proofs, and using techniques like working backwards to see how concepts interconnect.- The essay highlights the importance of practicing problems to develop techniques and judgment, and stresses that understanding is more crucial than memorization in college mathematics.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42290996">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Enjoyment in studying mathematics can enhance understanding and lead to success, as many students struggle with the subject due to unengaging teaching methods.- Having a mentor to reveal the enjoyable aspects of math and building confidence early can prevent students from giving up prematurely.- Effective strategies include engaging deeply with material, solving problems, and understanding definitions and proofs, balancing intuition with rigorous study for mastery.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.science.org/content/article/gene-behind-orange-fur-cats-found-last">Gene behind orange fur in cats</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42291386">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Recent studies indicate that the Arhgap36 gene, which influences GTP levels and MC1R receptor activity, may be responsible for orange fur in cats, rather than the Mc1r gene linked to red hair in humans.</li>
<li>This discovery underscores the complexity of genetics, where a single gene can impact multiple traits, and is part of broader research efforts to understand genetic mechanisms.</li>
<li>Understanding these genetic factors has potential implications for breeding and health, contributing to the popularity of orange cats, often noted for their playful behavior.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://corp.oup.com/news/brain-rot-named-oxford-word-of-the-year-2024/">’Brain rot‘ named Oxford Word of the Year 2024</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Oxford Word of the Year for 2024 is &quot;brain rot,&quot; selected through a public vote with over 37,000 participants, highlighting its growing relevance.- &quot;Brain rot&quot; describes the mental decline from consuming trivial online content, with a 230% increase in usage from 2023 to 2024, reflecting concerns about digital consumption&#39;s impact on mental health.- Originally coined by Henry David Thoreau in 1854, the term has gained popularity on platforms like TikTok, sparking discussions about the effects of excessive online content, particularly among Gen Z and Gen Alpha.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42292294">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>&quot;Brain rot&quot; has been selected as Oxford Word of the Year 2024, referring to the decline in mental state from excessive consumption of trivial online content.- The term underscores worries about shrinking attention spans and the addictive qualities of digital media, such as social media, TV, and video games.- Conversations around &quot;brain rot&quot; emphasize the need for moderation to balance relaxation and avoid overstimulation.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://retrogamecoders.com/c64-visual-studio-code/">Programming the C64 with Visual Studio Code</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The VS64 extension allows programming the Commodore 64 using Visual Studio Code on Mac, Windows, and Linux, providing a modern, cross-platform alternative to the Windows-only CBM PRG Studio.</li>
<li>VS64 supports BASIC, Assembly, and C programming with syntax highlighting, tools, and features like auto-numbering and label usage, enhancing the development experience.</li>
<li>It integrates with ACME and Kick assemblers, CC65 and LLVM-MOS C/C++ compilers, and the VICE C64 emulator for debugging, making it a comprehensive tool for C64 development.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42290861">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion emphasizes the nostalgia and continued interest in retro computing, particularly programming the Commodore 64 (C64) using Visual Studio Code.</li>
<li>Participants share experiences with vintage systems, crediting them for inspiring their software development careers, and discuss tools like &quot;retro debugger&quot; and YouTube tutorials for learning about old games and demos.</li>
<li>The conversation highlights the challenges and joys of programming in assembly language and BASIC, and mentions modern tools and extensions that enhance the retro coding experience.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Intel announces retirement of Pat Gelsinger" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Intel%20announces%20retirement%20of%20Pat%20Gelsinger&subheading=Monday%2C%20December%202%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/12/02</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-02T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-12-01]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/12/01&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-12-01</h1>
<h2><a href="https://adventofcode.com/2024/about">Advent of Code 2024</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Advent of Code, created by Eric Wastl, is an Advent calendar featuring programming puzzles suitable for all skill levels, which can be solved in any programming language.</li>
<li>The puzzles are designed to run efficiently on older hardware and are intended for practice, interviews, or entertainment, without requiring a computer science background.</li>
<li>Participants are encouraged to share their experiences, test solutions with examples, and seek help if needed, while adhering to guidelines such as not using AI for solving puzzles and respecting trademark rules.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42287231">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Advent of Code 2024 has begun, with participants engaging in creative problem-solving and sharing their experiences.- Some participants are experimenting with unique approaches, such as using C without standard libraries or exploring new programming languages like Swift or Ada.- While there are concerns about AI&#39;s impact on the leaderboard, the event primarily fosters personal enjoyment, learning, and community interaction.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://follow.agwa.name/notice/AoZSMI38xcA3TrN1sm">A Brazilian CA trusted only by Microsoft has issued a certificate for google.com</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42284202">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A Brazilian Certificate Authority (CA), trusted solely by Microsoft, issued a certificate for google.com, breaching Google&#39;s Certificate Authority Authorization (CAA) rules.</li>
<li>This incident raises concerns about the CA&#39;s reliability and Microsoft&#39;s decision to trust it, as other major browsers do not.</li>
<li>The certificate could facilitate man-in-the-middle attacks, allowing attackers to impersonate Google and distribute malware, underscoring the need for stricter oversight and transparency in CA trust decisions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/privastead/privastead">Open-source private home security camera system (end-to-end encryption)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author developed a home security camera system called Privastead, focusing on privacy by using end-to-end encryption with OpenMLS and implementing it mostly in Rust.- Privastead is open-sourced for those with privacy concerns, requiring a compatible IP camera, a local machine, a server, and an Android smartphone for setup.- Currently, the system supports only one IP camera and Android, but the author seeks community feedback and contributions to enhance its capabilities.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42284412">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Privastead is an open-source home security camera system developed to address privacy concerns with existing solutions, utilizing end-to-end encryption via OpenMLS.- The system is primarily implemented in Rust and requires a supported IP camera, a local machine, a server, and an Android smartphone for operation.- The project is available on GitHub, inviting feedback and contributions from the community to enhance its functionality.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/maharmstone/ntfs2btrfs">Ntfs2btrfs does in-place conversion of NTFS filesystem to the open-source Btrfs</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Ntfs2btrfs is a tool designed to convert NTFS file systems to Btrfs in-place, preserving the original image as a reflink copy for potential space recovery.</li>
<li>The tool is available for both Windows and Linux, with specific installation instructions and dependencies for each platform, and it includes features like compression support and rollback to NTFS.</li>
<li>Limitations include the lack of support for older extended attributes, large alternate data streams (ADS), and encrypted files, with specific conditions required for booting Windows from a Btrfs file system.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42283950">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Ntfs2btrfs is a tool that enables in-place conversion from NTFS (New Technology File System) to Btrfs (B-tree File System), sparking discussions on its utility and timing for large data transfers.</li>
<li>Users share mixed experiences with Btrfs, appreciating features like snapshots but recalling past stability issues, while also discussing other filesystems like ZFS and bcachefs.</li>
<li>The conversation underscores the complexities and risks of filesystem management, with some users advocating for backups and fresh formats over conversion tools.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://chipsandcheese.com/p/amd-disables-zen-4s-loop-buffer">AMD Disables Zen 4&#39;s Loop Buffer</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>AMD has disabled the loop buffer in its Zen 4 CPUs, a feature intended for power optimization rather than performance enhancement.- Performance tests indicate negligible differences with the loop buffer disabled, as the op cache compensates with sufficient bandwidth.- The decision to disable the loop buffer, possibly due to a hardware bug, is unlikely to significantly impact performance or power consumption, and the feature was not widely documented by AMD.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42283933">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>AMD has disabled the loop buffer in its Zen 4 CPUs, likely due to undisclosed hardware vulnerabilities, resulting in a minor performance decrease in certain situations.- The loop buffer was designed to enhance power efficiency and performance, but its removal indicates it may not have offered substantial advantages.- The quiet decision to disable the loop buffer has led to concerns regarding transparency and the management of hardware vulnerabilities.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://sfconservancy.org/news/2024/nov/29/openwrt-one-wireless-router-now-ships-black-friday/">OpenWRT One Released: First Router Designed Specifically for OpenWrt</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Software Freedom Conservancy (SFC) and OpenWrt have released the OpenWrt One, a wireless router designed to promote software freedom and the right to repair, priced at $89 with a case or $68.42 for the board.</li>
<li>The router is unbrickable, fully copyleft-compliant, and features a MediaTek MT7981B SoC, MT7976C wifi, 1 GiB DDR4 RAM, supporting Power over Ethernet (PoE) and USB-C power, with a USB serial interface for advanced users.</li>
<li>The device is FCC compliant, demonstrating that software right to repair can align with regulatory requirements, and each purchase includes a $10 donation to OpenWrt at the Software Freedom Conservancy.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42285689">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>OpenWRT One, the first router specifically designed for the OpenWrt open-source firmware, has been released, priced at $89.- It aims to balance copyleft compliance with FCC regulations, though it still includes some proprietary binary blobs for Wi-Fi functionality.- The release has sparked discussions on the benefits of separating router and Wi-Fi functions for greater flexibility in networking hardware.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://twitter.com/JeffDean/status/1858540085794451906">Jeff Dean Responds to EDA Industry about AlphaChip</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42285128">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Jeff Dean addressed criticisms regarding Google&#39;s AlphaChip, noting that critics did not adhere to essential replication steps, like pre-training.- The debate questions whether AlphaChip&#39;s performance is on par with existing tools, with some suggesting Google&#39;s claims may be exaggerated.- This discussion underscores tensions between Google and the Electronic Design Automation (EDA) industry, involving accusations of bias and concerns about the replicability of Google&#39;s research.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Advent of Code 2024" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Advent%20of%20Code%202024&subheading=Sunday%2C%20December%201%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/12/01</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-01T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-11-30]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/11/30&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-11-30</h1>
<h2><a href="https://blog.koenvh.nl/what-does-this-button-do-cm42u2oi7000a09l42f54g2pr">What does this button do? – My new car has a mysterious and undocumented switch</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A 2020 Opel Corsa owner discovered a mysterious switch linked to a fleet tracking system, likely installed by the previous owner, a large company.</li>
<li>The system functions as a GPS tracker and possibly an immobilizer, tracking the driver&#39;s movements and sending data to a fleet manager.</li>
<li>The owner plans to remove the system due to privacy concerns, highlighting the issue of unknowingly driving with tracking devices.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42276620">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A new car model features a switch linked to GPS and eSIM technology, raising privacy concerns as these features cannot be disabled, potentially enabling data collection and government surveillance.</li>
<li>Some consumers prefer older cars to avoid privacy issues, as modern vehicles are often compared to &quot;smartphones on wheels&quot; due to their connectivity features.</li>
<li>Privacy studies highlight significant concerns with new cars, though some brands offer options to opt out of data sharing, sparking ongoing debates about balancing technological advancements and privacy rights.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.nullpt.rs/breaking-the-4chan-captcha">Breaking the 4Chan CAPTCHA</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The project aimed to develop a machine learning model using TensorFlow to solve 4Chan CAPTCHAs with over 80% accuracy, ultimately achieving over 90% accuracy.</li>
<li>The model utilized an LSTM CNN architecture with CTC encoding, trained on 500 hand-solved and 50,000 synthetic images, and was converted for browser use with TensorFlow.js.</li>
<li>The project provided valuable insights into machine learning and computer vision, overcoming challenges like data collection, synthetic data generation, and compatibility issues.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42276865">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>4Chan&#39;s CAPTCHA system has been compromised, showcasing the limitations of text-based CAPTCHAs as computers now surpass human capabilities in solving them.</li>
<li>Despite their vulnerabilities, CAPTCHAs still play a role in increasing the cost of spamming, thus deterring some potential spammers.</li>
<li>The ethical implications of CAPTCHA-breaking are debated, as it facilitates more spam and AI-generated content, affecting website owners and users, highlighting the need for more effective anti-spam solutions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.theparisreview.org/blog/2017/02/15/rhythmical-lines/">Geometric line-art of Wacław Szpakowski (2017)</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42277850">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Geometric line-art by Wacław Szpakowski is gaining recognition for its complex designs, drawing comparisons to Op Art and artists like Bridget Riley and Bernard Cohen.- The art, which resembles mathematical patterns, is inspiring digital and generative art creators, highlighting its potential in modern digital platforms.- Discussions emphasize the historical significance of Szpakowski&#39;s work and its blend of math and art, with links to related art and exhibitions being shared.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://minjunes.ai/posts/sleep/index.html">Engineering Sleep</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Familial Natural Short Sleep (FNSS) is a condition where individuals can sleep less without adverse effects due to a genetic mutation, notably in the DEC2 gene affecting orexin levels.- Orexin plays a key role in sleep regulation, with imbalances leading to sleepiness or insomnia, and research is exploring FNSS replication through orexin agonists or gene therapy.- Despite its potential, FNSS remains under-researched, indicating a need for further studies to develop improved sleep engineering methods.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42279454">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Familial Natural Short Sleep (FNSS) is a genetic mutation enabling individuals to sleep less without adverse effects, sparking interest in its potential benefits and risks.</li>
<li>Concerns are raised about the long-term health impacts of reduced sleep, including a possible increased risk of dementia, despite some personal anecdotes of successful sleep optimization.</li>
<li>The discussion also considers the evolutionary role of sleep, the potential for sleep biohacking, and societal implications, questioning whether reduced sleep needs are ultimately beneficial or harmful.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.baldurbjarnason.com/2024/the-deterioration-of-google/">The Deterioration of Google</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The closure of Giant Freakin Robot underscores the challenges faced by independent publishers, as many sites are shutting down due to decreased traffic from major platforms like Google and Facebook.- Google&#39;s machine learning system, designed to enhance search results, has unintentionally delisted numerous small sites, leading to financial difficulties for content creators.- The algorithm&#39;s complexity and Google&#39;s dominant market position contribute to the ongoing issue, leaving creators with limited alternatives and solutions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42277673">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The decline of Google is linked to its focus on advertising revenue over search quality, resulting in reduced innovation and vision.</li>
<li>Users report a decline in the quality of services such as Google Maps and Google Docs, with no significant achievements from Google in recent years.</li>
<li>The rise of Search Engine Optimization (SEO) and AI-generated content has complicated search results, prompting users to explore alternatives like Kagi and DuckDuckGo for better search experiences.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://solarboi.com/2024/11/17/sol-ark-oem-disables-all-deye-inverters-in-the-us/">Sol-Ark manufacturer reportedly disables all Deye inverters in the US</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Sol-Ark disabled all Deye inverters in the US, disrupting homeowners by intentionally bricking them with a message about regional restrictions.</li>
<li>Sol-Ark, holding exclusive US sales rights, offered a discounted replacement program to affected customers, raising concerns about control and security of internet-connected solar inverters.</li>
<li>The incident emphasizes the importance of selecting inverters with reliable support and secure networking to avoid similar disruptions, particularly with Chinese-manufactured products.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42279010">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Sol-Ark allegedly disabled all Deye inverters in the US, sparking frustration over the dependency on internet-connected devices and cloud services.- Users express concerns about the reliance on cloud services for local devices, fearing potential future disruptions and advocating for local control.- The incident underscores the risks associated with cloud-dependent technology, prompting calls for improved consumer protection and alternative solutions.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="What does this button do? – My new car has a mysterious and undocumented switch" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=What%20does%20this%20button%20do%3F%20%E2%80%93%20My%20new%20car%20has%20a%20mysterious%20and%20undocumented%20switch&subheading=Saturday%2C%20November%2030%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/11/30</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-11-30T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-11-29]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/11/29&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-11-29</h1>
<h2><a href="https://ContinueAndPersist.org">Send someone you appreciate an official &#39;Continue and Persist&#39; Letter</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42268580">Reactions</a></h3>
<h2><a href="https://news.alvaroduran.com/p/engineers-do-not-get-to-make-startup">Engineers do not get to make startup mistakes when they build ledgers</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Payments Engineer Playbook underscores the critical role of accurate ledgers in fintech startups, highlighting the pitfalls of neglecting double-entry accounting systems.</li>
<li>Alvaro Duran shares a cautionary tale from his startup experience, where the absence of a double-entry system led to financial discrepancies and customer dissatisfaction.</li>
<li>Duran is contemplating authoring a book on creating scalable and future-proof ledgers, seeking feedback on its potential interest.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42269227">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Engineers in financial systems must avoid errors, as seen in Synapse&#39;s case, where their ledger inaccurately showed more customer balances than actual funds, resulting in missing millions.- Fintech companies often promise FDIC insurance, but it only applies if the bank fails, not if the fintech mismanages funds, highlighting the importance of accurate financial tracking.- Double-entry bookkeeping is vital for accuracy, ensuring every transaction is balanced and traceable, which helps prevent errors and potential fraud in financial systems.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://dontfuckwithscroll.com">Don&#39;t Fuck with Scroll</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Momentum scrolling plugins are criticized for disrupting the natural web browsing experience by degrading usability, accessibility, and performance.- Key issues include violating user expectations, causing motion sickness, reducing accessibility, and inconsistent performance, particularly on older devices.- These plugins also increase page load times, break native browser features, and add maintenance overhead, leading to user frustration and complexity.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42273505">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion emphasizes frustrations with Single Page Applications (SPAs) affecting web navigation, particularly concerning URLs, browser navigation, and the back button.- Critics argue that improperly implemented SPAs compromise web fundamentals like bookmarkability and navigation, prioritizing performance over user experience.- The conversation also addresses issues such as hijacking standard browser functions and the importance of respecting user autonomy in web design, advocating for maintaining traditional web functionalities.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://adriano.fyi/posts/hetzner-raises-prices-while-significantly-lowering-bandwidth-in-us/">Hetzner raises prices while significantly lowering bandwidth (US)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Hetzner is increasing prices in the US by up to 27.52% for CPX21 servers while reducing bandwidth by an average of 88.19%.- The changes, announced on Thanksgiving, are intended to align costs with resource usage, as lighter users were subsidizing heavier users.- New pricing and bandwidth limits will take effect from December 2024 for new servers and February 2025 for existing ones, with Hetzner maintaining it offers the best price-performance ratio.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42268475">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Hetzner, a web hosting company, has increased its prices and reduced bandwidth offerings in the United States.</li>
<li>The topic has generated significant discussion, leading to multiple duplicate posts on Hacker News, a popular tech news platform.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://phys.org/news/2024-11-car-quarter-microplastics-environment-urgent.html">Car tires shed a quarter of all microplastics in the environment</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42269925">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Car tires are a major source of microplastic pollution, contributing to a quarter of all microplastics in the environment.- There is a debate on whether to tax tires based on their compounds to address pollution, as opposed to taxing vehicles by weight.- The discussion includes privacy and practicality concerns regarding taxing based on weight and distance driven, with examples from the UK and the Netherlands considering different methods for implementation.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://neugierig.org/software/blog/2020/05/ninja.html">The success and failure of Ninja (2020)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Ninja, a build system created as a side project, has gained significant popularity and is now used by major projects like Chrome, Android, and Meson.</li>
<li>The system is designed for speed and efficiency, utilizing a bipartite graph for better build structure and focusing on fast incremental builds.</li>
<li>The creator reflects on the challenges of being an open-source maintainer, noting the high demands and limited gratitude despite Ninja&#39;s success.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42268310">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion focuses on the Ninja build system&#39;s role in Android&#39;s AOSP (Android Open Source Project) and the transition complexities from makefiles to Ninja.</li>
<li>Users debate Ninja&#39;s advantages over Makefiles, considering architecture, social issues, and the impact of iteration time on programmer satisfaction.</li>
<li>The conversation also mentions other build systems like Samurai and the challenges of maintaining handcrafted build systems, highlighting the role of social dynamics in tech environments.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://hez2010.github.io/async-runtimes-benchmarks-2024/">How much memory do you need in 2024 to run 1M concurrent tasks?</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A 2024 benchmark tested memory consumption for running 1 million concurrent tasks using coroutines across various programming languages, including Rust, C#, Go, and Java.- C# with NativeAOT demonstrated the best memory efficiency, outperforming other languages, while Go consumed more memory than anticipated, even more than Java with GraalVM.- The study underscores that some languages, like .NET with NativeAOT and Java&#39;s GraalVM, have improved scalability, whereas Go&#39;s goroutines were less efficient, and Rust&#39;s memory usage was optimized by adjusting task handling.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42270378">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>In 2024, the memory required to run 1 million concurrent tasks varies by programming language and concurrency model, with Rust and C# using around 0.12 KiB per task, while Go uses about 2.64 KiB per task.</li>
<li>Node.js, despite appearing efficient with promises, does not execute tasks in parallel, highlighting differences in concurrency handling among languages.</li>
<li>The benchmark underscores that real-world applications involve more complex operations than simple tasks, impacting memory usage and performance.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/rust/comments/1h15md8/goodbye_rust_i_wish_you_success_but_im_back_to_c/">Goodbye, Rust. I wish you success but I&#39;m back to C++ (sorry, it is a rant)</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42268819">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A Reddit user criticized Rust for its complexity and limited job opportunities, comparing it to Betamax and Esperanto, which are technically superior but not widely adopted.</li>
<li>While some users appreciate Rust&#39;s strictness and safety features, others note its slower adoption rate compared to languages like Go.</li>
<li>Despite these challenges, Rust is gaining traction in major companies like AWS and Microsoft, with some viewing it as a potential future replacement for C++.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://lwn.net/SubscriberLink/998793/6c8d00bd1b2a7948/">GIMP 3.0 is on the way</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>GIMP 3.0 is anticipated to release soon, marking the first major update since 2018, featuring a modernized GTK 3 interface and improved performance.- Key updates include non-destructive editing, enhanced color management, improved layer workflows, and a new extension system for easier plugin management.- Although the exact release date is unknown, development builds are available, indicating a significant advancement for the open-source image editor with more frequent future updates expected.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42272927">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>GIMP 3.0 is under development, adding support for color palettes beyond sRGB, such as CMYK and CIELAB, which are important for print and publishing.</li>
<li>The update seeks to enhance color accuracy by converting to other color spaces only when necessary, minimizing data loss.</li>
<li>Despite advancements like non-destructive editing, some users are concerned about GIMP&#39;s user interface and functionality compared to Photoshop, citing slow development due to a small volunteer team.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/vinceanalytics/vince">Vince – A self hosted alternative to Google Analytics</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Vince is a Golang-based port of the Plausible Analytics dashboard, designed as a single binary, single-user system for multiple websites without runtime dependencies.- It includes features like automatic TLS (Transport Layer Security), outbound link tracking, file download tracking, 404 page tracking, and custom event tracking, making it nearly equivalent to the Plausible dashboard.- Vince aims to make the Plausible dashboard accessible for self-hosting, serving as a drop-in replacement for personal websites, with a demo available on a $6 Vultr instance.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42270389">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Vince is a self-hosted alternative to Google Analytics, developed as a Golang port of the Plausible Analytics dashboard, focusing on dashboard-related features.</li>
<li>It offers features such as automatic TLS (Transport Layer Security), outbound link tracking, and custom event tracking, with no runtime dependencies, making it suitable for personal websites.</li>
<li>Vince is GDPR (General Data Protection Regulation) compliant, uses Pebble for data storage, and is available as an open-source project on GitHub, providing an accessible self-hosting option without Plausible&#39;s setup complexity.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://apnews.com/article/australia-social-media-children-ban-safeguarding-harm-accounts-d0cde2603bdbc7167801da1d00ecd056">Australian Parliament bans social media for under-16s</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42270966">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Australia has implemented a ban on social media usage for individuals under 16, igniting discussions about child protection versus parental rights.- The law mandates age verification, which has raised privacy concerns and fears of increased surveillance.- The legislation was expedited with minimal public input, leaving its effectiveness and enforceability in question.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/tonghohin/screen-sharing">Screen Sharing in the Browser</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Bolt.new is a tool that allows users to rapidly create web applications, demonstrated by building a screen-sharing app in just 30 minutes.- The app functions by generating a unique code for a room, which others can use to join and view the screen being shared.- The project was further developed using Cursor and is available for viewing on GitHub, with a live demo hosted on Vercel.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42269897">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A browser-based screen-sharing app was developed using Bolt.new in just 30 minutes, allowing users to create and join rooms with unique codes for screen sharing.- The app is available on GitHub, with a demo provided, and has received feedback regarding screen sharing stoppage issues and mobile compatibility.- The app does not utilize a TURN server, which is typically used to relay media in WebRTC applications when direct peer-to-peer connections fail.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://prometheus.io/blog/2024/11/14/prometheus-3-0/">Prometheus 3.0</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Prometheus 3.0, the first major release in 7 years, introduces a modernized UI, Remote Write 2.0, UTF-8 support, OTLP support, and native histograms.- Key features include improved protocol efficiency with Remote Write 2.0, enhanced interoperability with OpenTelemetry through OTLP ingestion, and more efficient metrics with native histograms.- Users should be aware of some breaking changes and consult the migration guide, but the release maintains backward compatibility and encourages user feedback.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42274660">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Prometheus 3.0 has been released, introducing features like reduced memory usage and support for OTLP (OpenTelemetry Protocol) ingestion.- The release has prompted discussions on its scalability compared to alternatives like Mimir, Victoria, and Cortex, with some users opting for these solutions for enhanced performance.- There are concerns about the clarity of the release notes, indicating a need for improved communication from the developers.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Send someone you appreciate an official 'Continue and Persist' Letter" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Send%20someone%20you%20appreciate%20an%20official%20'Continue%20and%20Persist'%20Letter&subheading=Friday%2C%20November%2029%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/11/29</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-11-29T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-11-28]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/11/28&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-11-28</h1>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/xairy/lights-out">Malware can turn off webcam LED and record video, demonstrated on ThinkPad X230</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The repository offers tools to manipulate the webcam LED on a ThinkPad X230, illustrating how malware could potentially record video without LED notification.- The process involves reflashing the webcam firmware via USB, a technique that could be applied to various laptops, using scripts for firmware manipulation and LED control.- The webcam uses a Ricoh R5U8710 controller, and caution is advised as reflashing could damage the webcam; further insights are available in the &quot;Lights Out&quot; talk at POC 2024.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42259278">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Malware has the capability to disable webcam LEDs and record video without user knowledge, as demonstrated on a ThinkPad X230.- Unlike MacBooks, which have hardwired LEDs to signal camera use, many other laptops lack this feature, raising privacy concerns.- To enhance security, experts recommend using physical covers or switches for webcams and microphones to prevent unauthorized access and protect sensitive information.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42264427">Hetzner cuts traffic on US VPSs</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The tariff structure for Cloud servers (CCX and CPX lines) and Load balancers in Ashburn and Hillsboro, US, is being updated.- New prices and traffic amounts will apply to newly-created and rescaled servers starting December 1, 2024, with existing servers seeing changes from February 1, 2025.- The update aims to provide fairer pricing based on local conditions, while traffic overage prices remain unchanged.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42264427">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Hetzner is revising its pricing model for Cloud servers and Load balancers in the US, reducing included traffic from 20TB to as low as 1TB and raising prices.</li>
<li>The changes will take effect in December 2024 for new servers and February 2025 for existing ones, aiming to balance costs between low and high-resource users.</li>
<li>The decision has led to debates about fairness and business strategies, with some users unhappy about the drastic reduction in included traffic.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.abc.net.au/news/2024-11-28/social-media-age-ban-passes-parliament/104647138">Australia: Kids under 16 to be banned from social media after Senate passes laws</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Australia has passed new legislation banning children under 16 from using social media, with the aim of protecting mental health.</li>
<li>Social media companies have a year to comply, facing fines up to $50 million for non-compliance, while users and parents face no penalties.</li>
<li>The law does not apply to messaging apps, online gaming, or educational services, and has received mixed reactions from mental health experts, politicians, and tech companies.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42264733">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Australia is set to ban children under 16 from using social media, necessitating ID verification to confirm age, which has sparked privacy concerns.</li>
<li>Critics worry this could grant the government access to social media data and diminish user anonymity, with some suggesting legacy media backs the law to limit social media competition.</li>
<li>The law&#39;s effectiveness and enforcement are uncertain, with potential loopholes and challenges in its implementation.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://qwenlm.github.io/blog/qwq-32b-preview/">QwQ: Alibaba&#39;s O1 Like Reasoning LLM</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>QwQ (Qwen with Questions) is an AI model designed to explore problems with curiosity and philosophical inquiry, constantly questioning its assumptions.</li>
<li>Despite limitations such as language mixing and recursive reasoning loops, QwQ excels in technical domains, achieving high scores on benchmarks like GPQA, AIME, MATH-500, and LiveCodeBench.</li>
<li>The model demonstrates strong problem-solving abilities in mathematics and programming, contributing to the ongoing journey of understanding AI reasoning and machine intelligence.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42259184">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Alibaba&#39;s QwQ, a reasoning large language model (LLM), is gaining attention for its impressive performance on diverse hardware, including MacBooks, and its ability to solve complex tasks with detailed explanations.</li>
<li>Discussions around QwQ include its hardware requirements, potential censorship issues on sensitive topics, and its openness and reasoning capabilities, despite some noted limitations.</li>
<li>The conversation highlights the broader implications of open-source LLMs and the competitive dynamics in the field of artificial intelligence development.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://lithub.com/in-praise-of-print-why-reading-remains-essential-in-an-era-of-epistemological-collapse/">In Praise of Print: Reading Is Essential in an Era of Epistemological Collapse</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Ed Simon emphasizes the lasting significance of print reading, referencing Sven Birkerts&#39; &quot;The Gutenberg Elegies&quot; to highlight concerns about digital media&#39;s impact on deep reading and misinformation.</li>
<li>Simon argues that print books provide a unique, immersive experience that digital media cannot replicate, fostering introspection and privacy away from the internet&#39;s constant noise.</li>
<li>He concludes that preserving literacy and deep reading is essential for maintaining individual thought and resisting the pervasive influence of digital technology.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42263834">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The debate between print and digital reading centers on concerns about digital media&#39;s impact on deep engagement with content.- Proponents of digital reading cite convenience and accessibility, while critics worry about its effects on critical thinking and attention spans.- This discussion reflects broader issues of technology&#39;s influence on information consumption and the balance between technological progress and traditional knowledge acquisition.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/abus-aikorea/voice-pro">Voice-Pro – AI Voice Cloning Magic: Transform Any Voice in 15 Seconds</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Voice-Pro is an open-source Gradio WebUI designed for advanced audio manipulation, including zero-shot voice cloning and a voice changer with over 50 celebrity voices.</li>
<li>It offers features like YouTube audio downloading, vocal isolation, multi-language text-to-speech, and translation, utilizing Whisper engines.</li>
<li>Voice-Pro is particularly beneficial for content creators, developers, and audio enthusiasts, with resources available on GitHub and video tutorials on YouTube.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42261909">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Voice-Pro is an open-source AI tool that enables voice cloning in 15 seconds, featuring zero-shot voice cloning and a voice changer with over 50 celebrity voices.- It includes functionalities like YouTube audio downloading, vocal isolation, and multi-language text-to-speech and translation, powered by Whisper engines, and is available on GitHub.- Despite its creative potential, there are concerns about misuse for identity theft and scams, and it currently lacks support for Linux or MacOS, with questions about installation and hidden costs.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/cje050wz22qo">London&#39;s 850-year-old food markets to close</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>London&#39;s historic Smithfield and Billingsgate markets, significant for their 850-year history, will close by 2028 as the City of London Corporation withdraws support.- The markets, known as the UK&#39;s largest wholesale meat and inland fish markets, will be replaced by new developments, with traders receiving compensation and relocation assistance.- Plans to move the markets to Dagenham were abandoned due to high costs, raising concerns about the future supply of fish in London and marking a loss of tradition.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42260027">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>London&#39;s historic food markets, such as Smithfield and Billingsgate, are planned to close, with the City of London Corporation promoting it as a &quot;positive new chapter&quot; for traders.- Critics suggest the closures are intended to facilitate real estate development, turning the area into a commercial hub, raising concerns about cultural heritage loss.- The decision awaits parliamentary approval, with worries about the potential negative impact on local businesses.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://store.steampowered.com/app/2800590/picoCAD/">picoCAD – a tiny modeler for tiny models</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>picoCAD, a 3D modeling tool for creating retro-style models, was released on November 27, 2024, by Apskeppet, catering to both beginners and experts.- The tool is available for Windows and macOS, with an introductory price of $5.09 until December 4, 2024.- Users are encouraged to join the community and explore tutorials to enhance their creativity with picoCAD.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42262734">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>picoCAD is a straightforward 3D modeling tool favored for its simplicity and ease of use, especially for creating low-poly models, compared to more complex software like Blender.- Developed by Johan Peitz, picoCAD allows export to obj/mtl formats, though it lacks native binary export on Picotron.- Users appreciate its unique aesthetic and simplicity, often comparing it to other tools like Crocotile and Kenney Shape.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2411.16544">Float Self-Tagging</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The paper introduces &quot;self-tagging,&quot; a method for encoding type information within 64-bit objects, optimizing memory layout for dynamic languages without sacrificing data space.</li>
<li>Self-tagging improves execution time in float-heavy benchmarks by 2.3x in Scheme and 2.7x in JavaScript, offering a more efficient alternative to existing methods like tagged pointers and NaN-tagging.</li>
<li>This approach allows for efficient encoding of both data and type, enhancing performance without affecting other operations, making it a promising solution for handling 64-bit IEEE754 double-precision floats in dynamic languages.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42260030">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The paper introduces &quot;Float Self-Tagging,&quot; a technique aimed at optimizing float storage in dynamic programming languages by using high bits for tagging, allowing most floats to remain unboxed and improving performance.</li>
<li>Critics of the paper argue that its comparisons are flawed and recommend testing against established methods such as NaN-tagging, which is a technique for encoding additional information in the NaN (Not-a-Number) values of floating-point numbers.</li>
<li>The technique is noted for its simplicity and potential, with similar methods already implemented in languages like Koka and CRuby, and related optimizations seen in systems like Apple&#39;s Objective-C and the Java Virtual Machine (JVM).</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.ftm.nl/artikelen/ruzie-tussen-ziekenhuis-en-farma-industrie-over-goedkeuring-kankermedicijn">Developing a cancer drug without Big Pharma: this hospital shows it can be done</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Rising healthcare costs in the Netherlands are attributed to bureaucracy, waste, and unnecessary care, highlighting systemic inefficiencies.</li>
<li>A Dutch hospital developed a cancer drug independently of major pharmaceutical companies, offering a treatment five times cheaper than a comparable American therapy, demonstrating the potential for non-profit hospitals to reduce healthcare costs.</li>
<li>Despite the innovation, the expensive and complex European Medicines Agency (EMA) registration process deters hospitals; however, the AVL hospital has funded a phase 3 study through donations, aiming for EMA approval to maintain their affordable therapy against costly pharmaceutical competition.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42260017">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A hospital has successfully developed a cancer drug independently, demonstrating that drug development can occur without the involvement of major pharmaceutical companies.- The traditional drug development process is criticized for being costly and influenced by non-scientific factors, such as ego and politics.- The discussion emphasizes the complexities in drug development, including regulatory challenges and the high failure rate of drugs during clinical trials.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.sheldonbrown.com/AluminumBikeProject.html">MIT Aluminum Bicycle Project 1974 (2016)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>In 1974, M.I.T. hosted a course where participants, including Marc Rosenbaum and Harriet Fell, constructed aluminum bicycle frames, with Rosenbaum&#39;s design being the lightest track bicycle at the time.- Rosenbaum&#39;s bike, made from 6061-T6 aluminum and titanium, featured larger diameter tubes and precision bearings, weighing 12 lbs. 5 oz., and is now displayed at the M.I.T. Museum.- Harriet Fell&#39;s frame was involved in a patent dispute between Cannondale and Klein, with Cannondale using it to argue against Klein&#39;s patent by claiming prior art.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42261053">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>In 1974, MIT considered aluminum for bicycle frames, rejecting magnesium due to its brittleness and corrosion issues, though modern magnesium alloys like LPSO show potential.- Historical attempts with magnesium frames, such as Kirk&#39;s, often failed due to material weaknesses, while carbon fiber and titanium are favored for their strength and flexibility.- Despite advancements in materials, weight remains a focus in bicycle design, with increasing emphasis on aerodynamics and rider comfort.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://infosec.exchange/@0xabad1dea/113543212666056329">Dell is posting unsigned updates to their website which fail to install</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42261707">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Dell has been releasing unsigned updates on their website, leading to installation failures and raising security concerns about potential exploitation by hackers.</li>
<li>Users have reported mismatches between update catalogs and signatures, with some issues resolved following complaints, but criticism remains regarding Dell&#39;s update management.</li>
<li>The situation underscores the critical need for verifying software updates to ensure security and reliability across various platforms, including Apple and Linux.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/semiconductor-fabrication">The Forgotten Story of How IBM Invented the Automated Fab</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>In 1970, IBM&#39;s Bill Harding initiated Project SWIFT, aiming to automate wafer-fabrication to produce integrated circuits (ICs) in under a day, a significant reduction from the typical month-long process.- SWIFT achieved a 5-hour turnaround per layer, a feat still unmatched, and introduced innovations like automated processing and real-time control, foundational to modern semiconductor manufacturing.- Despite its brief existence, Project SWIFT&#39;s advancements and Harding&#39;s visionary leadership significantly influenced the evolution of semiconductor production techniques.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42260364">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>IBM once led the charge in automated fabrication, aiming for complete vertical integration from raw materials to software, making custom chips more viable than standard options.- Due to the high costs of advancing technology, many companies, including IBM, have outsourced production or spun off their fabrication facilities.- Current efforts, such as Jim Keller&#39;s Atomic Semi, focus on making small fabrication runs economical, exploring innovations like structured ASICs (Application-Specific Integrated Circuits) and maskless lithography to reduce costs and improve accessibility to custom silicon.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.gamesradar.com/games/publishers-are-absolutely-terrified-preserved-video-games-would-be-used-for-recreational-purposes-so-the-us-copyright-office-has-struck-down-a-major-effort-for-game-preservation/">The US copyright office has struck down a major effort for game preservation</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The US Copyright Office has rejected a DMCA exemption request that aimed to allow libraries to remotely share digital access to preserved video games, concluding a three-year campaign by the Video Game History Foundation (VGHF) and the Software Preservation Network.</li>
<li>The proposed exemption would have facilitated a digital library for historians and researchers to access out-of-print games, but was denied due to concerns about potential recreational use and market harm, as argued by industry groups.</li>
<li>The VGHF expressed disappointment, criticizing the decision as being heavily influenced by industry lobbying, which prioritized industry interests over public access to historical games.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42259133">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The US Copyright Office has declined a proposal aimed at preserving video games, due to concerns that these games might be used for recreational purposes rather than preservation.</li>
<li>This decision has ignited discussions among retro game enthusiasts, who argue that older games provide more enjoyment and nostalgia compared to modern games.</li>
<li>Critics of the decision believe that current copyright laws are overly restrictive, impeding the preservation of cultural and historical media, and suggest shortening copyright terms to promote innovation and allow older works to enter the public domain sooner.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/s41593-023-01514-1">Inferring neural activity before plasticity for learning beyond backpropagation</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article introduces &quot;prospective configuration,&quot; a novel credit assignment principle in learning, as an alternative to the traditional backpropagation method.</li>
<li>Prospective configuration involves neural networks predicting desired neural activity patterns before adjusting synaptic weights, enhancing efficiency and effectiveness in learning.</li>
<li>This method aligns more closely with observed neural activity in human and animal studies and may offer advantages in both biological and artificial learning systems over backpropagation.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42259185">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A new theory, &quot;prospective configuration,&quot; is proposed to explain how the brain addresses the credit assignment problem, differing from the backpropagation method used in artificial neural networks (ANNs).</li>
<li>The theory suggests that neural activity changes precede synaptic weight modifications, contrasting with backpropagation where weight changes lead to altered neural activity.</li>
<li>This approach may better align with biological processes and could provide insights into developing more efficient learning algorithms, contributing to debates on AI and human brain learning similarities and differences.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Malware can turn off webcam LED and record video, demonstrated on ThinkPad X230" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Malware%20can%20turn%20off%20webcam%20LED%20and%20record%20video%2C%20demonstrated%20on%20ThinkPad%20X230&subheading=Thursday%2C%20November%2028%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/11/28</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-11-28T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-11-27]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/11/27&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-11-27</h1>
<h2><a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.actureunlock&hl=en_US">App that asks ‘why?’ every time you unlock your phone</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Intenty is an app that encourages users to develop healthier phone habits through awareness prompts when unlocking their devices.- The app emphasizes privacy by operating entirely locally without ads or tracking, and it uses Android permissions solely for functionality without data collection.- With a minimalist design and smart customization, Intenty has a 4.4-star rating and over 10,000 downloads, appealing to users aiming to reduce mindless phone usage.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42254156">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>An app that prompts users with &quot;why?&quot; upon unlocking their phone is gaining attention on Hacker News for its potential to reduce distractions.</li>
<li>Users find the app helpful but sometimes inconvenient for quick tasks, leading to suggestions for improvements like randomizing prompts or allowing app-specific bypasses.</li>
<li>The developer is considering user feedback for updates, including a one-time purchase option instead of a subscription model.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.downtowndougbrown.com/2024/11/the-capacitor-that-apple-soldered-incorrectly-at-the-factory/">The capacitor that Apple soldered incorrectly at the factory</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Doug Brown highlights a manufacturing error in Apple&#39;s Macintosh LC III, where a capacitor was installed backwards, potentially causing issues.</li>
<li>The Macintosh LC III, produced between 1993 and 1994 for the education market, did not undergo a major recall despite this error.</li>
<li>Brown advises caution when replacing capacitors, especially with modern tantalum capacitors, and recommends installing them correctly, contrary to the PCB&#39;s silkscreen instructions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42253119">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Apple mistakenly installed a capacitor in reverse on a 34-year-old computer, highlighting the importance of correct capacitor orientation, especially for electrolytic capacitors, which have polarity and can fail if installed incorrectly.</li>
<li>This incident has sparked discussions about product longevity and planned obsolescence, with some suggesting that modern electronics are intentionally designed to have shorter lifespans to boost sales.</li>
<li>The situation is reminiscent of past manufacturing errors by other companies, such as Commodore, indicating a recurring issue in the tech industry.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://benhouston3d.com/blog/why-i-left-kubernetes-for-google-cloud-run">I Didn&#39;t Need Kubernetes, and You Probably Don&#39;t Either</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author transitioned from Kubernetes to Google Cloud Run, citing Kubernetes&#39;s complexity, cost, and slow autoscaling as drawbacks.- Google Cloud Run is highlighted as a simpler, cost-effective alternative, charging only for actual CPU and memory usage, and offering quick scaling without Kubernetes&#39;s management overhead.- The author uses GitHub Actions for continuous integration/continuous deployment (CI/CD), managed databases, and pub-sub messaging, emphasizing Cloud Run&#39;s suitability for projects needing simplicity and efficiency over Kubernetes&#39;s extensive features.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42252336">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article critiques Kubernetes for being overly complex and often unnecessary for smaller projects, suggesting simpler solutions like a single virtual machine (VM) or server might be more efficient.</li>
<li>It highlights the challenges of managing Kubernetes, including the added complexity from various add-ons and the tendency for some engineers to complicate systems.</li>
<li>The consensus is that while Kubernetes is valuable, it is not always the best choice for smaller-scale operations, where simplicity can be more beneficial.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2024/11/hacker-in-snowflake-extortions-may-be-a-u-s-soldier/">Hacker in Snowflake extortions may be a U.S. soldier</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Two individuals were arrested for data theft from companies using Snowflake, while a third suspect, known as &quot;Kiberphant0m,&quot; is still at large and believed to be a U.S. Army soldier in South Korea.</li>
<li>The group has been involved in selling stolen data and extorting companies, with AT&amp;T reportedly paying $370,000 to have stolen records deleted.</li>
<li>Canadian authorities have arrested Alexander Moucka, and John Erin Binns is jailed in Turkey, both linked to the breaches, while Kiberphant0m remains active in cybercrime forums.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42251799">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A hacker involved in extorting Snowflake, identified as Kiberphant0m, is under investigation, with speculation about possible ties to the U.S. military.</li>
<li>Kiberphant0m denies any military connection, suggesting it was a deceptive tactic, though analysts doubt this would be effective in misleading investigators.</li>
<li>The hacker&#39;s careless actions, such as posting a photo in army fatigues, underscore the difficulties in maintaining operational security and avoiding digital traces.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://zetaoffice.net/">ZetaOffice: LibreOffice in the Browser</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>ZetaOffice Web introduces LibreOffice to web browsers, enabling access from any device with options for self-hosting or using a Content Delivery Network (CDN) for data control.- The suite includes Writer, Calc, and Impress for word processing, spreadsheets, and presentations, and is available for both web and desktop on Linux and Windows, ensuring document compatibility.- ZetaOffice offers open-source software with paid options for CDN use and support, and integrates with existing systems via the LibreOffice UNO API, functioning efficiently in modern browsers.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42249746">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>ZetaOffice, a browser-based version of LibreOffice, faces criticism for performance and usability issues, including broken input and text rendering.</li>
<li>There is an ongoing debate about whether using a canvas or targeting the DOM (Document Object Model) is better for rendering document layouts in web-based office suites.</li>
<li>Despite challenges, ZetaOffice aims to provide a consistent cross-platform experience and is also available as a native desktop application.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.techradar.com/pro/security/d-link-says-it-wont-patch-60-000-older-modems-as-theyre-not-worth-saving">D-Link says it won&#39;t patch 60k older modems</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>D-Link has announced it will not provide security patches for 60,000 older modems that have reached end-of-life status, urging users to upgrade to newer models instead.</li>
<li>The unpatched security vulnerabilities could potentially allow hackers to take control of these devices, posing a significant risk.</li>
<li>Most of the affected modems are located in Taiwan, and for users unable to upgrade, D-Link recommends restricting remote access and using secure passwords as precautionary measures.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42249790">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>D-Link has decided not to patch vulnerabilities in 60,000 older modems, exposing them to security risks, which raises concerns about device security and manufacturer responsibility.</li>
<li>The announcement has sparked discussions on the importance of long-term support and the potential benefits of open-source solutions like OpenWRT for maintaining device security.</li>
<li>There are suggestions for legal mandates requiring manufacturers to provide security updates or release firmware to the public when devices reach end-of-life, highlighting a broader industry issue.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.technicianonline.com/news/popular-nc-state-professor-marshall-brain-dies-alleges-retaliation-for-ethics-complaints/article_152e5c80-ac2e-11ef-8b3f-036ac3c8d9bf.html">Marshall Brain died hours after alleging retaliation at NC State</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>NC State professor Marshall Brain, founder of HowStuffWorks.com, was found deceased in his office on November 20, after alleging retaliation from university officials.</li>
<li>Brain claimed he was forced into retirement following ethics complaints, but the university has not commented on these allegations or his death.</li>
<li>Former students and colleagues have expressed disappointment over the university&#39;s silence, highlighting the ongoing nature of this developing story.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42251656">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Marshall Brain, a former professor at NC State, passed away after claiming retaliation from university administrators due to his ethical complaints.</li>
<li>His case underscores the tension between idealism and reality, illustrating the potential dangers of holding those in power accountable.</li>
<li>The incident prompts discussions on the effectiveness of internal reporting systems and the broader power dynamics within academic institutions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://ianthehenry.com/posts/janet-for-mortals/">Janet for Mortals (2023)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author has released a free online book titled &quot;Janet for Mortals,&quot; focusing on the Janet programming language, which took 20 weeks to write.- The book includes 44,000 words and is accompanied by a website featuring a REPL (Read-Eval-Print Loop) for interactive learning.- The book and related projects, such as C++ library bindings and a testing framework, have gained positive attention on platforms like Hacker News.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42253241">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>&quot;Janet for Mortals&quot; is a book that offers an interactive REPL (Read-Eval-Print Loop) accessible via the escape key, enabling users to experiment with the Janet programming language directly in their browser without installation.</li>
<li>Janet is recognized for its ease of embedding and creating Domain-Specific Languages (DSLs), though some users note that its documentation could be improved.</li>
<li>The book&#39;s engaging style and the language&#39;s unique features have generated interest and positive feedback, despite some debate over the book&#39;s title.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2024/raspberry-pi-cm5-2-3x-faster-drop-upgrade-mostly">Raspberry Pi CM5 is a faster, drop-in upgrade</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Raspberry Pi Compute Module 5 (CM5) is a significant upgrade from the CM4, offering 2-3 times faster performance, USB 3, and PCIe Gen 3 compatibility while maintaining the same form factor.</li>
<li>The CM5 is priced similarly to the CM4, with the 8GB model starting at $75, and includes a faster CPU, RAM, and improved graphics, though it uses more power at full capacity.</li>
<li>An updated IO board is also released for $20, featuring USB-C power and other enhancements, highlighting the CM5&#39;s support and modularity despite competition from other single-board computers (SBCs).</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42254379">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Raspberry Pi CM5 offers a significant performance boost over the CM4, with 2-3 times the speed, and includes a USB 3 upgrade.</li>
<li>While the 8GB version retains its price, other versions are more costly, and some users note that other boards might have better specifications.</li>
<li>Despite hardware improvements, the CM5 lacks hardware encode support but can decode H.265, and the Raspberry Pi&#39;s strong community and support remain key advantages.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/11/isps-say-their-excellent-customer-service-is-why-users-dont-switch-providers/">ISPs say their &quot;excellent customer service&quot; is why users don&#39;t switch providers</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>ISP lobby groups argue that competition ensures high customer service standards, making additional regulations unnecessary, as poor service would drive customers to switch providers.</li>
<li>Regulators in California and Oregon report widespread customer dissatisfaction, highlighting issues such as long hold times and billing problems, contradicting ISP claims.</li>
<li>The FCC is reviewing customer service practices, but with Brendan Carr&#39;s leadership, appointed by President-elect Trump, new regulations are unlikely, as the focus shifts towards reducing regulatory burdens.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42251564">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>ISPs attribute customer retention to their &quot;excellent customer service,&quot; but many believe it&#39;s due to a lack of competition in certain areas.</li>
<li>In regions with limited ISP options, users often remain with their current provider despite dissatisfaction with service quality.</li>
<li>Efforts in countries like Australia and Canada to regulate the market and boost competition face ongoing challenges, with users calling for genuine competition and improved regulation.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42256093">Recommendation for a SWE looking to get up to speed with latest on AI</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The user is actively seeking reliable sources for the latest updates in Artificial Intelligence (AI), particularly through tech blogs similar to Hacker News (HN).</li>
<li>They have experience using ChatGPT and the OpenAI API, specifically version 3.5, indicating a practical interest in AI tools.</li>
<li>The user found Simon Willison&#39;s blog but feels it lacks cohesion, suggesting a need for more structured and comprehensive AI information sources.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42256093">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Software engineers can enhance their AI skills by participating in Kaggle competitions, which offer practical, hands-on learning experiences.</li>
<li>Staying informed through tech blogs, newsletters, and YouTube channels like Simon Willison&#39;s, AI Supremacy, and 3Blue1Brown can provide foundational and current AI knowledge.</li>
<li>Engaging with AI communities on platforms like Reddit and Twitter, as well as exploring educational resources such as books and online courses from MIT xPRO, can deepen understanding and keep engineers updated on the latest AI trends.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.washingtonpost.com/technology/2024/11/26/openai-sora-ai-video-model-artists-protest/">OpenAI hits pause on video model Sora after artists leak access in protest</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42252806">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>OpenAI paused its video model Sora after artists leaked access in protest over unpaid participation, despite no promise of compensation.- The protest raises concerns about AI potentially replacing artists and highlights ethical issues related to unpaid labor in AI development.- Some view the protest as a strategic effort to bring attention to these broader issues within the industry.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/26/us/usps-new-mail-trucks.html">Yes, it ‘looks like a duck,’ but carriers like the new USPS mail truck</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The U.S. Postal Service is introducing new electric mail trucks as part of a $9.6 billion modernization plan, offering features like air-conditioning, increased cargo space, and enhanced safety.</li>
<li>Originally intended to be mostly gas-powered, 75% of the fleet will now be electric due to legal challenges, marking a significant shift towards sustainability.</li>
<li>Despite their unconventional design, the trucks have been positively received for their comfort and efficiency, incorporating input from postal carriers and including features like nonslip surfaces, airbags, and a collision-avoidance system.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42249545">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The new USPS mail truck design emphasizes visibility and safety, featuring a low hood and large bumpers to enhance pedestrian safety and driver comfort, particularly in urban settings.</li>
<li>While its unconventional appearance has sparked debate, the truck is engineered for durability, akin to the long-serving Grumman LLV.</li>
<li>The design also focuses on improving postal workers&#39; conditions and includes options for electric vehicles to meet modern delivery demands.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://volfpeter.github.io/htmy/">Htmy – Async, pure-Python rendering engine</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>&quot;htmy&quot; is a pure-Python rendering engine that supports asynchronous and synchronous function components, React-like context management, and built-in HTML tags, making it versatile for various web development needs.- It offers features like Markdown support, JSON-based internationalization, and easy integration with any backend or frontend frameworks, enhancing its adaptability and customization.- The library is open-sourced under the MIT license, encouraging community contributions, and can be installed via PyPI using <code>pip install htmy</code>.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42251919">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Htmy is an asynchronous, pure-Python HTML rendering engine, sparking debate over its verbosity compared to Jinja and the necessity of async in HTML rendering.</li>
<li>The discussion highlights the potential benefits of async for dynamic data fetching in component-based designs, though opinions vary on whether it complicates code.</li>
<li>Htmy aims to provide a flexible rendering solution, but its advantages over established tools like Jinja are still under discussion.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="App that asks ‘why?’ every time you unlock your phone" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=App%20that%20asks%20%E2%80%98why%3F%E2%80%99%20every%20time%20you%20unlock%20your%20phone&subheading=Wednesday%2C%20November%2027%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/11/27</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-11-27T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-11-26]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/11/26&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-11-26</h1>
<h2><a href="https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2024/11/amazon-s3-functionality-conditional-writes/">Amazon S3 Adds Put-If-Match (Compare-and-Swap)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Amazon S3 introduces conditional writes, enabling updates only if an object remains unmodified, preventing concurrent overwrites by verifying the object&#39;s ETag.- This feature, akin to the HTTP if-none-match header, allows clients to use the if-match header to ensure ETag consistency before writing, enhancing efficiency for distributed applications.- Available at no extra cost across all AWS Regions, implementation can be done using the AWS SDK, API, or CLI, with further details in the S3 User Guide.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42240678">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Amazon S3 has launched a new feature called Put-If-Match, which acts like a compare-and-swap operation, allowing conditional object writing based on version matching.- This feature improves synchronization and concurrency control, enabling developers to perform more complex operations, such as building databases on S3 without extra infrastructure.- The update brings Amazon S3 in line with similar features offered by other cloud storage services like Google Cloud Storage and Azure Blob Storage.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://fasterthanli.me/articles/lies-we-tell-ourselves-to-keep-using-golang">Lies we tell ourselves to keep using Golang (2022)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article critiques Golang, noting that while it has appealing features like an asynchronous runtime and garbage collector, it also has significant drawbacks, such as the absence of sum types and inadequate error handling.- It argues that Go&#39;s perceived simplicity can be deceptive, leading to hidden complexities and challenges in production environments, and stresses the importance of recognizing these issues rather than adopting Go solely for its ease of use.- The article contrasts Go with Rust, suggesting that despite Rust&#39;s challenges, it provides more robust solutions for managing complexity and ensuring code correctness.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42243500">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article critiques Go&#39;s error handling, contrasting it with Rust&#39;s more sophisticated approach, which some find more elegant.</li>
<li>There is a divide in opinion: some appreciate Go&#39;s simplicity and explicit error handling, while others find it tedious and error-prone.</li>
<li>Despite criticisms, Go remains popular due to its simplicity and widespread adoption by large companies.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.wired.com/story/cybertrucks-many-recalls-make-it-worse-than-91-percent-of-all-2024-vehicles/">Cybertruck&#39;s Many Recalls</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Tesla Cybertruck has experienced multiple recalls since its launch, with the latest involving faulty drive inverters affecting over 2,400 units, raising concerns about its reliability.</li>
<li>Despite quality issues, the Cybertruck&#39;s unique design continues to attract buyers, although its inability to meet European safety standards limits its market reach.</li>
<li>The recalls, while demonstrating regulatory effectiveness, may harm Tesla&#39;s brand reputation, especially given Elon Musk&#39;s significant influence on US regulations.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42242971">Reactions</a></h3>
<h2><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/11/22/y-combinator-often-backs-startups-that-duplicate-other-yc-companies-data-shows-its-not-just-ai-code-editors/">Y Combinator often backs startups that duplicate other YC companies, data shows</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Y Combinator (YC), a prominent startup accelerator, is known for launching successful companies like Airbnb and Stripe, but many of its startups build similar or identical products to previous YC companies.</li>
<li>The PearAI controversy highlighted this trend, where PearAI was accused of cloning another YC product, yet YC CEO Garry Tan defended the practice, citing the importance of choice and innovation.</li>
<li>Deckmatch&#39;s analysis of YC trends shows popular startup categories include AI code editors, restaurant PoS systems, and business finance tools, with some areas like crypto trading seeing decreased interest.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42243746">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Y Combinator frequently invests in startups that replicate other YC-backed companies, prioritizing the founders&#39; potential over unique ideas.- This strategy is seen as a way to hedge bets on similar concepts, as success often depends on execution and timing rather than the originality of the idea.- While some view this as a potential conflict of interest, it is a common venture capital practice to fund multiple companies in the same sector to validate markets and enhance the likelihood of success.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://status.flyio.net">Fly.io outage – resolved</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42241851">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Fly.io experienced a temporary outage, which was resolved, but it raised user concerns about the platform&#39;s reliability due to past incidents.- Users compared Fly.io to alternatives like Railway and Cloudflare, highlighting differences in reliability, features, and user experiences.- Despite the challenges, some users value Fly.io for its ease of use and competitive pricing, while discussions emphasized the importance of high availability and monitoring dependencies.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.viksnewsletter.com/p/short-intro-to-automotive-lidar">A Short Introduction to Automotive Lidar Technology</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Vik&#39;s Newsletter delves into automotive lidar technology, which is vital for self-driving cars due to its ability to produce high-resolution images using infrared lasers.- The newsletter discusses lidar&#39;s operating principles, including wavelength choices, photodetectors, and ranging techniques like Time-of-Flight and Frequency Modulated Continuous Wave.- It also examines various lidar systems, such as mechanical and solid-state options, with the aim of reducing costs and enhancing technology for wider adoption in autonomous vehicles.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42239721">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Automotive lidar technology is evolving, with rotating scanners like Velodyne&#39;s being used despite their high cost, while alternatives like flash lidar and MEMS mirrors face market and technical challenges.</li>
<li>Waymo&#39;s continued use of rotating lidars, even in vulnerable vehicle corners, underscores the need for more affordable and integrated solutions, as pulsed lidar offers reduced interference compared to continuous systems.</li>
<li>Lidar provides high-resolution imaging and performs well in low-light conditions, but faces competition from camera-based systems, which some companies, like Tesla, prefer for cost reasons, fueling ongoing debates on the best approach for autonomous driving.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://papersplease.org/wp/2024/11/25/do-you-need-id-to-read-the-real-id-rules/">Do you need ID to read the REAL-ID rules?</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>An attempt to access the TSA&#39;s new digital-ID rules revealed issues with the REAL-ID Act, as the rules are not publicly accessible and require ID for access, raising concerns about secret laws and due process.</li>
<li>The TSA&#39;s digital-ID standards, derived from private documents, involve complex interactions between apps, devices, and government agencies, with privacy concerns over logged ID usage.</li>
<li>The author argues that the TSA&#39;s practices violate public access rights and has reported the issue to the Office of the Federal Register, seeking the withdrawal of the rule.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42239952">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion revolves around the necessity of having an ID to access REAL-ID rules, with some users questioning the effectiveness of TSA&#39;s security measures.- Concerns are raised about the implications of mobile driver&#39;s licenses (mDLs) and the privacy issues they may present.- Users express skepticism about the effectiveness of TSA and the concept of security theater, while also questioning the long-term implications of digital IDs like REAL-ID and mDLs.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://medium.com/@drspoulsen/a-solution-to-the-onion-problem-of-j-kenji-l%C3%B3pez-alt-c3c4ab22e67c">A solution to The Onion problem of J. Kenji Lopez-Alt (2021)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The post addresses the &quot;Onion Problem,&quot; which involves cutting onions to achieve minimal variance in slice volumes for uniformity.- A mathematical exploration using calculus determined the optimal cutting point is 55.73066% below the onion&#39;s center, termed the &quot;true onion constant.&quot;- This finding refines a previous suggestion of cutting towards a point 60% below the center, providing a more precise method for even onion slices.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42244814">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion explores a mathematical model for cutting onions evenly, inspired by J. Kenji Lopez-Alt, using a half-disk representation to simplify the geometry and minimize slice size variance.- Users debate the model&#39;s practicality and accuracy, considering the onion&#39;s 3D structure and non-uniform layers, and suggest alternative cutting methods or tools.- The conversation also considers the balance between uniformity and culinary preferences, referencing food personalities like Adam Ragusea.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://twitter.com/TomHacohen/status/1861137484249252093">Redis is trying to take over the all of the OSS Redis libraries</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Redis is reportedly taking control of all open-source software (OSS) Redis libraries, which include popular ones like Jedis, Lettuce, and redis-py.</li>
<li>These libraries are currently down, and another library, redis-rs, is also facing potential control or shutdown.</li>
<li>This situation is significant as it affects developers who rely on these libraries for Redis integration in their applications.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42239607">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Redis Inc. is taking control of open-source Redis libraries, sparking controversy and leading some developers to remove Redis dependencies due to trademark enforcement issues.</li>
<li>Libraries such as redis-py, Lettuce, and Jedis have been moved under Redis Inc.&#39;s official organization, seen as a defensive strategy against competitors like Valkey.</li>
<li>The community is worried about trademark claims and potential vendor lock-in, prompting discussions on alternatives like Valkey and Kvrocks, and highlighting the challenges of trademark enforcement in open-source projects.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="http://jpkoning.blogspot.com/2024/11/setelinleikkaus-when-finns-snipped.html">Setelinleikkaus: When Finns snipped their cash in half to curb inflation</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>In 1945, Finland implemented &quot;setelinleikkaus,&quot; a policy requiring citizens to cut large banknotes in half to combat post-WWII inflation, with one half retaining value and the other becoming a government bond.- The policy was ineffective as it only targeted physical cash, a minor part of the money supply, unlike more successful reforms in other European countries like Belgium.- The article speculates that future inflation control might involve digital account freezes, a more precise but potentially controversial method.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42243755">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>In 1945, Finland uniquely addressed inflation by physically cutting banknotes in half, contrasting with modern methods like adjusting interest rates.</li>
<li>This historical approach has sparked discussions on current monetary policy, where central banks manage inflation through interest rates and open market operations.</li>
<li>The potential future control of digital money, possibly via central bank digital currencies, raises concerns about increased government oversight of personal finances.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.metmuseum.org/perspectives/peter-hristoff-islamic-prayer-rugs">Prayer, Placement, and Absolution: Peter Hristoff on Islamic Prayer Rugs (2015)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Peter Hristoff&#39;s artwork delves into the intersection of art and spirituality, particularly through the medium of prayer rugs, starting from 1997.- His creations, including drawings and serigraph prints, evolve into larger &quot;rug&quot; pieces on rice paper, inspired by Turkish rugs and kilims, which he views as personal diaries with symbolic meanings.- Hristoff&#39;s work embodies &quot;bright sadness,&quot; a blend of joy and sorrow, influenced by Patriarch Bartholomew&#39;s writings, and continues to explore the spiritual and physical aspects of human nature.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42239487">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Peter Hristoff&#39;s article explores the significance of Islamic prayer rugs, emphasizing their intricate designs, such as tessellations, which symbolize God&#39;s infiniteness.- The article discusses the Islamic prohibition of representational art, leading to the use of calligraphy and geometric patterns in Islamic artifacts.- It highlights the historical and cultural context of prayer rugs, noting their use across various religious traditions, including Christianity, and their practical and spiritual roles.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://deno.com/blog/deno-v-oracle">Deno vs. Oracle: Canceling the JavaScript Trademark</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Deno has filed a petition with the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) to cancel Oracle&#39;s trademark on &quot;JavaScript,&quot; aiming to make it a public good and remove legal barriers to its use.</li>
<li>The petition argues that &quot;JavaScript&quot; is a generic term, Oracle committed fraud in renewing the trademark, and Oracle has abandoned the trademark through nonuse.</li>
<li>Over 14,000 developers support Deno&#39;s move, and Oracle has until January 4, 2025, to respond, with Deno ready to share all proceedings with the community.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42239263">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Deno has filed a petition with the United States Patent and Trademark Office (USPTO) to cancel Oracle&#39;s trademark on JavaScript, sparking a debate on trademark ethics and community benefits.</li>
<li>The discussion involves Deno&#39;s compatibility with Node Package Manager (NPM) and its impact on the broader JavaScript ecosystem, reflecting differing opinions on the future of JavaScript and runtime environments.</li>
<li>Opinions are divided, with some viewing Oracle&#39;s trademark use as unethical, while others question Deno&#39;s intentions, suggesting it might be a public relations strategy.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/captn3m0/jekyll-sqlite">SQLite Plugin for Jekyll</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author has developed a Jekyll SQLite plugin to enhance data manipulation capabilities within Jekyll, a popular static site generator.</li>
<li>This plugin allows users to perform SQL queries for data-wrangling, addressing limitations of Liquid, Jekyll&#39;s templating language, in handling complex data operations.</li>
<li>The plugin has been successfully used in production for a year, demonstrated with the Northwind dataset, and the author invites feedback and suggestions for improvement.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42244987">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A Jekyll SQLite plugin enables the use of SQLite as a data source in Jekyll, enhancing data manipulation capabilities with SQL.- It integrates Jekyll&#39;s Datafiles and Data Pages generator features, allowing for complex data handling beyond traditional CSV/JSON/YAML formats.- The plugin has been in production for a year, receiving positive feedback for making static site generation more dynamic and flexible.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://pmc.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/articles/PMC6290285/">Premature Graying of Hair: Review with Updates</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Premature graying of hair (PGH) is defined as graying before age 20 in Caucasians and before 30 in African Americans, impacting self-esteem.- The causes of PGH are not fully understood but are associated with aging disorders, autoimmune diseases, and oxidative stress, with factors like smoking and nutritional deficiencies contributing.- Common treatments for PGH include hair dyes and nutritional supplements, with studies indicating links between PGH and emotional factors, genetic predispositions, and environmental influences.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42241702">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Premature graying of hair is associated with vitamin B12 deficiency, particularly in individuals with pernicious anemia, a condition where the body cannot absorb B12 properly.- Diagnosing B12 deficiency can be challenging as supplementation may artificially increase B12 levels, and some individuals cannot convert certain forms of B12 to active forms, leading to &quot;paradoxical B12 deficiency.&quot;- Factors such as stress, genetics, and health conditions like autoimmune thyroidism also contribute to graying, and while some supplements may help, there is no proven method to reverse gray hair.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.thalium.re/posts/llvm-powered-devirtualization/">LLVM-powered devirtualization</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The internship at Thalium focused on deobfuscating virtualized binaries using LLVM, a compiler framework, to make code more understandable, especially in the context of malware.- Virtualization, a strong obfuscation technique used by tools like Tigress and VMProtect, encodes programs into virtual instructions, making reverse engineering complex.- The project successfully used dynamic taint analysis to reconstruct the control flow graph of Tigress-obfuscated binaries, though it was limited to pure functions and single execution paths.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42245170">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>LLVM-powered devirtualization improves performance by optimizing virtual function calls, which are typically slower due to their dynamic nature.</li>
<li>Bochs, a CPU emulator, can efficiently emulate a Pentium 4 processor on an i7, even bypassing virtual machine detectors.</li>
<li>The Bochs debugger is particularly effective in analyzing and countering malware and code obfuscators, making it a valuable tool for security research.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Amazon S3 Adds Put-If-Match (Compare-and-Swap)" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Amazon%20S3%20Adds%20Put-If-Match%20(Compare-and-Swap)&subheading=Tuesday%2C%20November%2026%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/11/26</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-11-26T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-11-25]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/11/25&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-11-25</h1>
<h2><a href="https://www.5snb.club/posts/2023/do-not-stab/">RFC 35140: HTTP Do-Not-Stab (2023)</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42232040">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>RFC 35140 humorously critiques the deprecation of the &quot;Do-Not-Stab&quot; HTTP header, which was abandoned after a browser&#39;s default setting negatively impacted the fictional stabbing industry.</li>
<li>The introduction of a &quot;General Assault Control&quot; header, requiring explicit opt-out, satirizes user consent mechanisms and the shift of responsibility from institutions to individuals.</li>
<li>The satire addresses broader societal issues, including privacy, data tracking, and the difficulties of enforcing regulations against corporate interests.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.starlink.com/business/direct-to-cell">Starlink Direct to Cell</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Starlink Direct to Cell is a new service by SpaceX offering global text, voice, and data access for LTE phones, ensuring connectivity on land, lakes, and coastal waters.</li>
<li>The service will begin with text services in 2024, followed by voice, data, and IoT (Internet of Things) support in 2025, without needing hardware changes or special apps.</li>
<li>This development highlights SpaceX&#39;s expansion into telecommunications, providing seamless connectivity without additional equipment.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42230103">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Starlink&#39;s vertical integration and cost-effective launches position it as a leading force in the satellite internet industry, facing minimal competition.</li>
<li>While some view Starlink&#39;s dominance as monopolistic, others believe innovation and foreign military support might foster future competition.</li>
<li>The high cost of satellite launches is a major hurdle, but advancements in reusable rocket technology could alter the competitive landscape.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://danielmangum.com/posts/this-website-is-hosted-on-bluesky/">This website is hosted on Bluesky</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The AT Protocol, used by Bluesky, supports hosting via Personal Data Servers (PDS), showcasing its flexibility beyond intended uses.- Content on Bluesky is organized into records and blobs, with blobs being larger data like media, which must be uploaded before being referenced in records.- The protocol&#39;s extensibility allows for creative applications, such as hosting websites, potentially leading to new use cases in the future.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42230392">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The website hosted on Bluesky has initiated discussions about its potential uses, including hosting RSS feeds and storing data like DOOM WADs, as well as concerns about content moderation and legal issues.</li>
<li>Comparisons are being made to past platforms like MySpace, highlighting the AT Protocol&#39;s public nature and its potential for decentralized data storage.</li>
<li>Users are divided, with some skeptical about Bluesky&#39;s moderation capabilities, while others view it as a promising new platform.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.benji.dog/articles/git-config/">How I configure my Git identities</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The post discusses configuring Git identities using <code>includeIf</code> for conditional configurations, allowing different settings based on directory paths or remote URLs.</li>
<li>The author shares a method to manage multiple Git identities and SSH keys by using different <code>Host</code> values in <code>~/.ssh/config</code> and adjusting Git configurations with <code>insteadOf</code>.</li>
<li>The post highlights a new approach using <code>hasconfig:remote.*.url:!</code> for conditional Git configurations based on remote URLs, enhancing flexibility in managing Git identities.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42233524">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The <code>includeIf</code> directive in Git config allows automatic application of different settings based on the repository&#39;s URL, streamlining identity management.</li>
<li>This method enables users to set specific user details and SSH keys for work-related repositories, facilitating seamless switching between personal and work projects.</li>
<li>Maintaining security and privacy can be further enhanced by using separate machines or user accounts for work and personal projects.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://sqlitestudio.pl/">SQLiteStudio: Create, edit, browse SQLite databases</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>SQLiteStudio has released version 3.4.6, addressing the &quot;black SQL code line&quot; issue from the previous version 3.4.5 and resolving two additional issues.</li>
<li>This software is open-source, cross-platform, and portable, available for free under the GPL license, and compatible with Windows, Linux, and MacOS X.</li>
<li>Notably, SQLiteStudio requires no installation, making it convenient for users to create, edit, and browse SQLite databases.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42232000">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>SQLiteStudio is a user-friendly tool designed for creating, editing, and browsing SQLite databases, praised for its portability and powerful features.</li>
<li>It includes support for Entity-Relationship Diagrams (ERD), which aids in handling complex database tasks and offers visual feedback, benefiting both professionals and students.</li>
<li>While some users have encountered platform-specific issues, SQLiteStudio is generally regarded as a reliable and efficient SQLite management tool.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://herecomesthemoon.net/2024/11/two-factions-of-cpp/">The two factions of C++</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The C++ community is split between modern tech companies seeking advanced features and legacy users reliant on outdated systems, creating a tension in the language&#39;s evolution.- The C++ Evolution Working Group&#39;s focus on backward compatibility conflicts with the demand for modern features and safety, leading to dissatisfaction among some major tech players.- In response to these challenges, the US government and companies like Google are exploring or developing alternative languages, such as Rust, which prioritize safety and modern capabilities over backward compatibility.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42231489">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The C++ community is divided between maintaining legacy codebases and adopting modern, safer language features, with a focus on the challenges of refactoring without automated testing.</li>
<li>The article highlights Google&#39;s significant influence in the C++ standards committee and the difficulty of evolving the language without disrupting existing code.</li>
<li>Similar factional divides and complexities in language evolution are noted in other programming languages like Python and Rust.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://mashable.com/article/bluesky-gaining-ground-on-competitor-meta-threads">Bluesky is on the verge of overtaking Threads in all the ways that matter</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Bluesky, a decentralized platform initially associated with Jack Dorsey, is gaining traction and now has 3.5 million daily active users, closing in on Meta&#39;s Threads.</li>
<li>The platform experienced a 300% user increase since the November 5 election, as journalists and academics migrate from Elon Musk&#39;s X, seeking more open public discourse.</li>
<li>Bluesky&#39;s growth is challenged by issues such as outages and scams, but its appeal is strengthened by Meta CEO Mark Zuckerberg&#39;s decision to limit political content on Threads.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42231148">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Bluesky is attracting users with features such as custom labels, algorithm choice, and a chronological feed, offering a more user-controlled experience compared to Threads.</li>
<li>It is viewed as a potential alternative to X (formerly Twitter) due to its focus on user choice and reduced algorithmic interference.</li>
<li>Despite its growing popularity, concerns about Bluesky&#39;s sustainability and monetization persist, as it is still in its early development stages compared to more established platforms.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://chipsandcheese.com/p/pushing-amds-infinity-fabric-to-its">Pushing AMD&#39;s Infinity Fabric to Its Limit</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>AMD&#39;s Infinity Fabric, part of the Zen architecture, connects CPU cores and manages memory latency, with Zen 5 showing improved bandwidth handling due to faster DDR5 and better traffic management.</li>
<li>Zen 2 provides insights into Core Complex (CCX) and Core Complex Die (CCD) bottlenecks, though it&#39;s an older architecture.</li>
<li>While typical applications like games don&#39;t stress bandwidth, demanding workloads like RawTherapee can reveal latency management strengths and limitations, particularly in Zen 4 under heavy load.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42230355">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion centers on AMD&#39;s Infinity Fabric and the constraints of memory bandwidth, with comparisons to Apple&#39;s Silicon capabilities.</li>
<li>Users debate the feasibility of claims like Apple&#39;s M1 Max achieving 400GB/s bandwidth, noting differences in core utilization between AMD&#39;s Zen 3 and Apple&#39;s architecture.</li>
<li>The conversation also highlights the significance of Non-Uniform Memory Access (NUMA) configuration and the complexities of optimizing software for emerging CPU architectures.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.sqlite.org/lang_with.html#outlandish_recursive_query_examples">SQLite: Outlandish Recursive Query Examples</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Common Table Expressions (CTEs) in SQL serve as temporary views for a single statement, with two types: ordinary and recursive, simplifying complex queries and handling hierarchical data, respectively.</li>
<li>CTEs are created using a WITH clause and can include multiple CTEs in a single statement, with recursive CTEs requiring specific rules like using UNION or UNION ALL operators.</li>
<li>Materialization hints, available in SQLite version 3.35.0 and later, guide the query planner on CTE implementation, with limitations such as the inability to use WITH in CREATE TRIGGER.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42230384">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>SQLite&#39;s recursive Common Table Expressions (CTEs) function like loops, allowing queries to reference themselves, which is useful for complex tasks such as solving Sudoku puzzles or calculating transitive closures.</li>
<li>Mastery of the syntax, particularly &quot;WITH&quot; and &quot;WITH RECURSIVE,&quot; is essential for effectively utilizing recursive CTEs, which operate by seeding a query and executing recursively until no new results are generated.</li>
<li>For those finding recursive CTEs challenging, resources like the O&#39;Reilly SQL Pocket Guide and a solid understanding of relational algebra can be beneficial in simplifying complex SQL queries.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://timdellinger.substack.com/p/hey-wait-is-employee-performance">Hey, wait – is employee performance Gaussian distributed?</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42236841">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article challenges the assumption that employee performance follows a Gaussian (normal) distribution, suggesting that this view may lead to outdated performance management practices in corporations.</li>
<li>It critiques the practice of trimming the bottom 5% of employees, advocating for a focus on combined productivity rather than individual performance, and proposes that performance might follow a Pareto distribution, where a few employees contribute significantly more to output.</li>
<li>The discussion encompasses various perspectives on performance evaluation, hiring practices, and the role of management in influencing employee success.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://articles.foletta.org/post/2024-01-08-a-day-in-the-life-the-bgp-table/">A Day in the Life: The Global BGP Table</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article delves into the daily fluctuations of the global BGP (Border Gateway Protocol) table, focusing on short-term behaviors such as unusual path attributes and flapping paths.</li>
<li>Using a tool called bgpsee, the author analyzes BGP messages to uncover insights into path updates, cyclic behaviors, and extreme AS (Autonomous System) path lengths.</li>
<li>The exploration highlights the complexity and resilience of the BGP system, emphasizing the intricate dynamics of global internet routing despite raising more questions than answers.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42233565">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article addresses the global Border Gateway Protocol (BGP) table, focusing on issues such as route flapping and the practice of route dampening to mitigate excessive BGP churn.</li>
<li>A user highlights the flapping of the EpicUp 140.99.244.0/23 prefix, suggesting it should be dampened, while another notes that route dampening is less common now due to past misconfigurations and enhanced router capabilities.</li>
<li>The discussion includes BGP quirks, historical insights from Internet Service Providers (ISPs), and resources for those interested in analyzing BGP data, with suggestions for potential projects.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.cam.ac.uk/research/news/wildlife-monitoring-technologies-used-to-intimidate-and-spy-on-women-study-finds">Wildlife monitoring technologies used to intimidate and spy on women</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Cambridge researchers discovered that wildlife monitoring technologies, such as camera traps and drones, are being misused in India to spy on women, impacting their mental health and safety.- These technologies, originally intended for conservation purposes, are reportedly used by local authorities to intimidate women, infringing on their rights.- The study emphasizes the need for careful consideration of the social impacts of deploying such technologies.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42232289">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Wildlife monitoring technologies, such as camera traps, are being misused in Indian forests to intimidate and spy on women, raising significant privacy and mental health concerns.- This misuse underscores broader global issues of surveillance and privacy, particularly in regions with existing women&#39;s rights challenges, and is not confined to India alone.- Addressing these issues requires complex solutions, including the implementation of stricter laws and cultural shifts to safeguard privacy and ensure safety for all individuals.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="RFC 35140: HTTP Do-Not-Stab (2023)" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=RFC%2035140%3A%20HTTP%20Do-Not-Stab%20(2023)&subheading=Monday%2C%20November%2025%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/11/25</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-11-25T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
