<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0"
>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 19:19:44 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/newsletter/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <copyright><![CDATA[2023 Sunghyun Cho]]></copyright>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-07]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/07&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-07</h1>
<h2><a href="https://crawshaw.io/blog/programming-with-llms">How I program with LLMs</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author has integrated Large Language Models (LLMs) into their programming workflow, finding them beneficial for tasks like autocomplete, search, and chat-driven programming.</li>
<li>They are developing a tool called sketch.dev, a Go programming Integrated Development Environment (IDE) designed to enhance productivity by automating repetitive tasks and improving programming efficiency.</li>
<li>LLMs are effective in generating code drafts and handling exam-style questions, although they can occasionally make errors, and they shift tradeoffs in programming by enabling more specialized code and comprehensive tests.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42617645">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) are recognized by some software engineers for enhancing productivity, particularly in drafting new ideas and performing tasks like autocomplete and chat-driven programming. - While some developers appreciate the efficiency LLMs provide, others remain skeptical about their effectiveness, especially for complex or novel problems. - The discussion underscores a divide among developers regarding the adoption of LLMs, with some embracing them for iterative tasks and others favoring traditional methods.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2025/01/06/nvidias-project-digits-is-a-personal-ai-computer/">Nvidia&#39;s Project Digits is a &#39;personal AI supercomputer&#39;</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Nvidia unveiled Project Digits at CES 2025, a compact &quot;personal AI supercomputer&quot; built on the Grace Blackwell hardware platform, featuring the GB10 Grace Blackwell Superchip.</li>
<li>The device offers up to a petaflop of performance, suitable for AI researchers, data scientists, and students, and can handle models with up to 200 billion parameters.</li>
<li>Priced at $3,000, Project Digits will be available in May and can connect to Windows or Mac PCs, running on Nvidia&#39;s Linux-based DGX OS.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42619139">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Nvidia&#39;s Project Digits is a &#39;personal AI supercomputer&#39; priced at $3,000, featuring a Blackwell GPU with 1 PFLOP (PetaFLOP) of FP4 compute, 128GB unified DDR5X memory, 20 ARM cores, and ConnectX for stacking. - It targets startups and enthusiasts, providing a local alternative to cloud AI solutions, with a focus on memory capacity and efficiency for AI development and inference tasks. - The device operates on Nvidia&#39;s DGX OS, based on Ubuntu, and is considered a potential game-changer for local AI computing.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://nicholas.carlini.com/writing/2025/regex-chess.html">A minimax chess engine in regular expressions</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Nicholas Carlini developed a chess engine named Regex Chess, utilizing 84,688 regular expressions to execute valid chess moves, showcasing regex&#39;s potential in unconventional applications. - The engine functions like a regular expression CPU, featuring a unique instruction set for stack operations, variable handling, and conditional execution, and supports parallel move generation. - Regex Chess employs a simplified minimax search to evaluate and score pseudo-legal moves, highlighting a creative exploration of regex capabilities, with the code accessible on GitHub for public viewing.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42619652">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Nicholas Carlini developed a minimax chess engine using regular expressions, showcasing regex&#39;s capability in handling complex tasks like chess. - The project, despite having bugs like issues with pawn promotion and a-file moves, demonstrates the educational and entertaining aspects of unconventional programming challenges. - The engine&#39;s 2-ply search occasionally fails to avoid mate-in-1 threats, highlighting its limitations but also its innovative approach.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.scottredig.com/blog/bonkers_comptime/">Zig&#39;s comptime is bonkers good</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Scott Redig explores Zig&#39;s &#39;comptime&#39; feature, which enhances productivity by enabling metaprogramming, allowing code execution during compile time. - He provides six perspectives on &#39;comptime&#39;, highlighting its ability to simplify code reading and debugging, and compares it to generics, partial evaluation, and code generation. - Redig concludes that Zig&#39;s &#39;comptime&#39; is both powerful and simple, recommending further exploration through Zig&#39;s official resources and standard library.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42618130">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Zig&#39;s compile-time programming (comptime) is recognized for its efficiency, enabling features like generics, complex data initialization, and target-specific code generation. - Critics highlight potential issues such as misuse akin to Lisp macros, breaking parametricity, and challenges with recursive generic types and type checking during compile-time computation. - Despite these concerns, Zig&#39;s simplicity and compile-time execution are considered major advantages, with some interest in integrating its metaprogramming capabilities with Rust&#39;s ecosystem.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24337396/nvidia-rtx-5080-5090-5070-ti-5070-price-release-date">Nvidia announces next-gen RTX 5090 and RTX 5080 GPUs</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Nvidia unveiled its next-generation RTX 50-series GPUs at CES, featuring the high-end RTX 5090 and RTX 5080, priced at $1,999 and $999, respectively. - The RTX 5090 includes 32GB of GDDR7 memory and 21,760 CUDA cores, offering double the speed of its predecessor, the RTX 4090, while the RTX 5080 provides 16GB of memory and is twice as fast as the RTX 4080. - The series introduces new DLSS 4 technology, improving performance and image quality, and will be available for laptops starting in March.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42618761">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Nvidia has unveiled the RTX 5090 and RTX 5080 GPUs, with the RTX 5090 featuring 32GB of GDDR7 memory and a 575W Thermal Design Power (TDP), aimed at consumer AI workloads.</li>
<li>The RTX 5080 is designed for high-end gaming, offering a more affordable option with less memory compared to the RTX 5090.</li>
<li>The high demand for these GPUs, particularly for AI applications, may lead to availability issues, reminiscent of previous shortages driven by cryptocurrency mining.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/ABoringDystopia/comments/1ht7fft/used_meta_ai_to_edit_a_selfie_now_instagram_is/">Used Meta AI, now Instagram is using my face on ads targeted at me</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42615538">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A Reddit user experienced Instagram ads featuring their own face after using Meta AI&#39;s &quot;imagine me&quot; feature, raising concerns about personalized advertising. - The incident sparked a debate comparing this level of ad personalization to the movie &quot;Minority Report,&quot; with opinions divided between seeing it as innovative or invasive. - The discussion underscores privacy concerns and the ethical implications of AI in advertising, with calls for stricter regulations to protect personal data.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.congestion-pricing-tracker.com/">NYC Congestion Pricing Tracker</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Congestion Pricing Tracker is a project by Benjamin and Joshua Moshes, under the supervision of Brown University Professor Emily Oster, focusing on congestion pricing in New York. - The project includes web scripts and stylesheets, indicating a comprehensive digital approach to presenting information. - The webpage is optimized for search engines (SEO) and includes a 404 error page for handling not found content.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42616700">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>NYC&#39;s congestion pricing policy is designed to reduce traffic congestion and generate revenue for transit improvements.</li>
<li>While some observe immediate benefits, others argue it&#39;s premature to assess its effectiveness due to variables like weather and holiday travel.</li>
<li>Critics point out that unchanged taxi and ride-sharing fees and the need for enhanced public transit remain significant concerns.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://variety.com/2025/film/columns/flow-golden-globe-win-independent-animation-1236266805/">First time a Blender-made production has won the Golden Globe</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Latvian director Gints Zilbalodis&#39; indie animation &quot;Flow&quot; won the Golden Globe for best animated feature, highlighting a significant achievement for independent films. - &quot;Flow,&quot; created with a modest $3.7 million budget using Blender, a free software, competed against major studio productions, showcasing the democratization of animation. - The film&#39;s victory reflects the Golden Globes&#39; growing inclusivity towards international titles and could impact the animated feature Oscar race, challenging Disney&#39;s traditional dominance.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42620656">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A Blender-made production has won a Golden Globe, marking a milestone for the open-source software and challenging perceptions of its readiness for professional use. - The film, noted for its storytelling and visuals, has gained popularity in Latvia and stands out for its low budget compared to other animated winners. - The success of the film, utilizing Blender&#39;s EEVEE engine, has ignited discussions about Blender&#39;s potential impact on the animation industry and its capabilities in diverse production settings.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://tla.systems/blog/2025/01/04/i-live-my-life-a-quarter-century-at-a-time/">I live my life a quarter century at a time</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>On January 5, 2000, Steve Jobs introduced the Aqua user interface of Mac OS X, including the Dock, at Macworld Expo, with significant contributions from an engineer based in Apple Cork, Ireland.</li>
<li>The engineer, who had previously worked on DragThing, was instrumental in transforming Bas Ording&#39;s prototypes into functional code for the Dock, but eventually resigned due to relocation pressures.</li>
<li>After leaving Apple, the engineer revived DragThing and PCalc, which continue to be popular, and discovered an unsigned Non-Disclosure Agreement (NDA) in their possession.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42616699">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses Apple&#39;s Dock development, emphasizing Steve Jobs&#39; eccentricity and secretive nature, including flying an employee between Ireland and the US to maintain a facade.</li>
<li>Despite significant efforts, the project was ultimately canceled due to issues related to office location.</li>
<li>The narrative also delves into Jobs&#39; controversial decisions, his legacy compared to current tech leaders, and broader themes like career paths and ageism in the tech industry.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://alexanderpetros.com/triptych/">Triptych Proposals</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Triptych Proposals by Alexander Petros and Carson Gross aim to improve HTML&#39;s ability to handle network requests by supporting additional HTTP methods like PUT, PATCH, and DELETE in forms.</li>
<li>The proposals also include enabling buttons to make HTTP requests without forms and allowing partial page replacements, aligning HTML more closely with REST principles.</li>
<li>These proposals were introduced at Big Sky Dev Con and are detailed in the Triptych Polyfill on GitHub, with ongoing updates to the fetch and navigation specifications to support these enhancements.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42615646">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Alex Petros&#39; Triptych Proposals seek to incorporate HTMX concepts into the HTML specification, enabling HTML to handle HTTP methods like PUT and DELETE.</li>
<li>The proposal is receiving positive feedback from the Web Hypertext Application Technology Working Group (WHATWG), but its adoption by major browsers such as Chrome and Safari is still uncertain.</li>
<li>The initiative aims to reduce JavaScript dependency by enhancing HTML&#39;s capabilities, contributing to the broader discussion on RESTful APIs and a hypermedia-driven web.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://racenis.github.io/tram-sdk/why.html">Tramway SDK – The Unholy Union Between Half-Life and Morrowind Engines</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A new free, open-source game engine is being developed, similar to popular engines like Unreal and Source, with support for open-world streaming. - The engine is optimized for modern hardware, offering high performance, but is not yet ready for production use. - The developer intends to complete several large projects using this engine, although the current name is likely temporary.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42624116">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Tramway SDK is a project that merges the Half-Life and Morrowind game engines to create a low-budget, open-world streaming game engine that is free and open source. - Although optimized for modern hardware, Tramway SDK is not yet ready for production use, but it aims to reduce software bloat and environmental impact by supporting older hardware. - The project, licensed under MIT, is appreciated for its retro aesthetic and potential for indie game development, with the creator welcoming feedback and progress updates.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2025/jan/06/roman-empires-use-of-lead-lowered-iq-levels-across-europe-study-finds">Roman Empire&#39;s use of lead lowered IQ levels across Europe, study finds</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A study indicates that the Roman Empire&#39;s use of lead in metalworking caused a 2- to 3-point drop in IQ across Europe during the Pax Romana.</li>
<li>Researchers used Arctic ice cores to track lead pollution from 500BC to AD600, showing a significant increase during the Roman Empire&#39;s peak.</li>
<li>The study suggests that widespread lead exposure may have contributed to the decline of the Roman Empire, with pollution levels decreasing post-Roman era but rising again during the Industrial Revolution.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42618625">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A study indicates that the Roman Empire&#39;s use of lead could have reduced IQ levels in Europe, though this is based on historical lead levels and modern models rather than direct ancient IQ measurements.</li>
<li>There is debate over whether the advantages of Roman infrastructure might have surpassed the detrimental effects of lead exposure.</li>
<li>The study also explores the potential effects of contemporary substances, such as fluoride and plastics, on IQ, emphasizing the complexity of assessing historical health impacts from indirect evidence.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.crisesnotes.com/content/files/2023/12/NYFRB-2006.--Doomsday-Book--Searchable.pdf">Federal Reserve Bank of NY &quot;Doomsday Book&quot; 2022 via FOIA [pdf]</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42623144">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Federal Reserve Bank of New York&#39;s &quot;Doomsday Book&quot; is a legal guide designed to assist lawyers in managing legal uncertainties during financial crises, ensuring prompt and effective responses. - Initially intended for select lawyers, the guide is now available to all FRBNY lawyers, serving as a crisis playbook akin to tech incident response plans. - The document is not shared outside the Legal Function, and its name signifies preparation for severe financial disruptions, with the Fed maintaining independence from the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) due to its unique role, while still being accountable to Congress.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2025/01/meta-more-speech-fewer-mistakes/">Ending our third party fact-checking program and moving to Community Notes model</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Meta is prioritizing free expression by simplifying its content moderation systems, which have been criticized for being overly complex and restrictive. - The company is ending its third-party fact-checking program in the U.S. and introducing a Community Notes system, similar to X, to provide context to potentially misleading posts through user contributions. - Meta is reducing restrictions on political content, simplifying enforcement processes to focus on severe violations, and personalizing political content visibility based on user preferences, aligning with Mark Zuckerberg&#39;s vision of free expression.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42621627">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Meta is transitioning from its third-party fact-checking program to a Community Notes model, akin to Twitter&#39;s strategy, to potentially align with political changes and cut moderation expenses.</li>
<li>Critics express concerns that this shift may result in more misinformation and harmful content, whereas supporters argue it could bolster free speech.</li>
<li>This decision highlights ongoing discussions about content moderation, free speech, and the influence of social media platforms in shaping public discourse.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="How I program with LLMs" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=How%20I%20program%20with%20LLMs&subheading=Tuesday%2C%20January%207%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/07</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-07T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-06]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/06&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-06</h1>
<h2><a href="https://bobatealee.itch.io/doom-the-gallery-experience">Doom, the Gallery Experience</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>&quot;DOOM: The Gallery Experience&quot; is an art parody game by bobatealee, set in a reimagined version of the classic DOOM (1993) level E1M1, where players explore a gallery setting. - The game is compatible with HTML5, Windows, mobile devices, and gamepads, and was created using the Construct game development platform. - It has received a 5-star rating and is praised for its cultural satire and design, with contributions from Filippo Meozzi and Liam Stone.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42607794">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>&quot;Doom, the Gallery Experience&quot; is a virtual museum game allowing players to explore art pieces, akin to a real museum visit, created using Construct 3.</li>
<li>The game is available on multiple platforms, though some users report technical issues on mobile devices.</li>
<li>It combines cultural exploration with nostalgia, drawing inspiration from classic games like Doom, and has sparked discussions on potential humorous modifications.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://twitter.com/3blue1brown/status/1876291319955398799">3blue1brown YouTube Bitcoin video taken down as copyright violation</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Grant Sanderson, known for his educational content, reported that his 2017 video on Bitcoin was removed, and his channel received a copyright strike.</li>
<li>The copyright claim was made by Chainpatrol on behalf of Arbitrum, despite the video being entirely Sanderson&#39;s original content.</li>
<li>This incident highlights ongoing issues with copyright enforcement on digital platforms, where creators can face strikes even for their own work.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42612494">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A 3blue1brown YouTube video on Bitcoin was erroneously removed due to a copyright claim by ChainPatrol, which later acknowledged it as a false positive.</li>
<li>This incident highlighted flaws in YouTube&#39;s copyright system, sparking discussions about the potential for abuse and the lack of accountability for false claims.</li>
<li>Users suggested stricter penalties for companies issuing false takedown requests and discussed broader issues of content moderation and free speech challenges online.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://jessitron.com/2025/01/05/hitting-okrs-vs-doing-your-job/">Hitting OKRs vs. Doing Your Job</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>In Engineering, quarterly Objectives and Key Results (OKRs) often seem redundant as they tend to mirror product roadmaps, leading to potential conflicts if they differ.</li>
<li>Marketing finds OKRs beneficial for defining quarterly focus, aligning with project timelines, and highlighting new campaigns or audiences, while ongoing tasks are tracked by Key Performance Indicators (KPIs).</li>
<li>Effective OKRs should emphasize unique or changing priorities each quarter, rather than routine tasks, to avoid stagnation and ensure they provide value beyond the roadmap.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42607623">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>OKRs (Objectives and Key Results) can sometimes misalign with actual work, emphasizing metrics over meaningful contributions and potentially leading to gaming the system rather than addressing real issues.</li>
<li>Effective implementation of OKRs requires alignment with customer needs and company goals, but this alignment is often difficult to achieve, leading to bureaucratic processes and a lack of trust in employees&#39; intrinsic motivation.</li>
<li>In large organizations, OKRs can foster competition instead of collaboration, focusing on visible rather than valuable work, thus failing to capture the complexity of tasks.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.20512">Time-Series Anomaly Detection: A Decade Review</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The paper &quot;Dive into Time-Series Anomaly Detection: A Decade Review&quot; highlights the significance of anomaly detection in time-series data due to advancements in data collection and the rise of streaming data. - It introduces a process-centric taxonomy to categorize existing anomaly detection methods and offers a meta-analysis of research trends in this domain. - The research is pertinent to various fields, including cybersecurity, finance, law enforcement, and healthcare, and is accessible on arXiv under the Machine Learning category.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42609595">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Time-series anomaly detection uses forecasting and historical data to identify pattern deviations, with tools like Prometheus and Grafana aiding in practical applications. - These tools enable dynamic threshold setting based on weekly cycles and time of day, but challenges include managing holidays and defining anomalies. - The field is promising for development across industries but currently lacks comprehensive off-the-shelf solutions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://neal.fun/stimulation-clicker/">Stimulation Clicker</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42611536">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Stimulation Clicker on neal.fun is a popular clicker game that has generated user discussions, with comparisons to other games like Cookie Clicker and commentary on modern web habits. - Users have shared strategies for faster progress, such as automating clicks or resizing windows, and noted both addictive fun and issues like bugs or overstimulation. - The game has inspired creativity, including speedruns, with players appreciating its short length and engaging elements.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://xeiaso.net/blog/2025/squandered-holy-grail/">Apple squandered the Holy Grail</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Apple Intelligence, intended to enhance smartphone capabilities, did not meet expectations, with some features like Math Notes praised, but others criticized for being underwhelming.</li>
<li>Despite promising privacy and security through on-device processing and Private Cloud Compute, the product felt more like a tech demo than a groundbreaking tool.</li>
<li>The open-source community often surpasses corporate efforts like Apple Intelligence, which left users with only marginal improvements instead of transformative advancements.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42607151">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Apple&#39;s innovation strategy focuses on refining existing technologies, which sometimes disappoints fans expecting groundbreaking inventions. - Apple&#39;s AI features, such as Apple Intelligence, have faced criticism for being less impressive compared to competitors, despite Apple&#39;s history of product improvement. - Apple&#39;s strong emphasis on secure and private systems provides optimism for future enhancements in their AI offerings, though debate persists on whether they will meet user expectations.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://futureboy.us/blog/twofifty.html">Engineer eats efficiently for $2.50 a day (2016)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>An engineer embarks on a 46-day challenge to spend under $2.50 daily on food, documenting meals, costs, and cooking experiments. - Inspired by cooking shows, he sets rules to ensure fun, nutrition, and sharing, exploring recipes like cabbage rolls and ramen while managing costs and minimizing waste. - The experiment involves creative cooking with limited ingredients, using techniques such as brining and sous vide, and experimenting with emulsifiers, ultimately sharing insights on cost-effective cooking.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42606773">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>An engineer successfully reduced their daily food expenses to $2.50 in 2016 by purchasing bulk staples like rice, beans, and oats, and carefully managing fresh produce to prevent spoilage.</li>
<li>The strategy included diluting high-sodium packaged foods and shopping at budget-friendly stores, though it may not be sustainable or nutritionally adequate over time.</li>
<li>Alternatives such as buying discounted produce at farmers markets or using frozen vegetables can offer convenience and maintain nutritional value, but ensuring sufficient calorie and protein intake is crucial for health.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://r0bk.github.io/killedbyllm/">Killed by LLM</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>&quot;Killed by LLM&quot; is a project documenting AI benchmarks that have been surpassed by AI advancements, showcasing progress in areas like reasoning, mathematics, and coding. - The site, inspired by &quot;Killed by Google,&quot; provides details on original and final scores of benchmarks and the AI models that surpassed them, highlighting the rapid evolution of AI capabilities. - The term &quot;Saturation&quot; is used to describe benchmarks that can no longer effectively measure the cutting-edge capabilities of AI, and the project invites contributions to ensure data accuracy.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42606231">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion focuses on the Turing Test and its modern interpretations, especially concerning AI and Large Language Models (LLMs).</li>
<li>Modern versions of the Turing Test often simplify the challenge to identifying if a conversation partner is human, which LLMs can sometimes pass by mimicking non-native speakers.</li>
<li>The conversation highlights the limitations of current AI benchmarks and the potential for AI to be misused or misunderstood, questioning the true measure of intelligence in AI systems.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/live/clyjmy7vl64t">Justin Trudeau resigns</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Liberal Party of Canada is initiating the process to select a new leader, as announced by party president Sachit Mehra.</li>
<li>Justin Trudeau, praised for his decade-long leadership and efforts in rebuilding and making the party more inclusive, will remain in his role until a successor is chosen.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42611730">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Justin Trudeau has announced his plan to resign as Canada&#39;s Prime Minister, remaining in office until the Liberal Party selects a new leader.</li>
<li>His decision follows low approval ratings and internal party pressure, with controversies surrounding his handling of the trucker protest and other issues.</li>
<li>Trudeau&#39;s resignation is viewed as a strategic effort to allow the Liberal Party to regroup ahead of a potentially challenging election, with the possibility of a Conservative victory.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42604529">Favorite blog in 2024?</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42604529">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Simon Willison&#39;s blog is highlighted for its insightful content on artificial intelligence (AI) in 2024.</li>
<li>Other recommended blogs include Julia Evans, Fabien Sanglard, and Ethan Mollick&#39;s &quot;One Useful Thing,&quot; offering unique perspectives and diverse topics.</li>
<li>For those interested in economics, Noah Smith and Paul Krugman are suggested, while Dynomight and Not Boring provide a blend of tech and lifestyle content.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.bingeclock.com/blog/post/republishing-my-simpsons-fan-site-twenty-years-later">Republishing my Simpsons fan site, twenty years later</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42605707">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The relaunch of a Simpsons fan site after 20 years has evoked nostalgia for the early internet era, characterized by personal fan sites and creative freedom. - Many people recall the 90s and 2000s as a time of unregulated and non-commercialized internet, contrasting with today&#39;s more regulated and commercial landscape. - Some original fan sites still exist, serving as a reminder of the joy and creativity of creating content for enjoyment rather than financial gain.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/srsran">SrsRAN: Open-Source 4G/5G</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The srsRAN software suite is an open-source collection of 4G and 5G radio applications developed by SRS, implemented in C++ with minimal dependencies, and runs on Linux with standard hardware.</li>
<li>It is licensed under AGPLv3, which is a free software license ensuring that the software remains open-source.</li>
<li>The suite includes a 5G RAN (Radio Access Network) CU+DU (Central Unit and Distributed Unit) with a complete ORAN-native stack, and a 4G suite providing full network implementation for User Equipment (UE), eNodeB (evolved Node B), and EPC (Evolved Packet Core).</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42605201">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>SrsRAN is an open-source initiative that enables users to create their own 4G/5G networks using software and hardware such as Software Defined Radios (SDRs) and blank SIM cards.</li>
<li>The project provides an alternative to proprietary Radio Access Network (RAN) solutions, targeting telecom companies and offering flexibility for testing, emergency connectivity, and educational purposes.</li>
<li>Users should be aware of potential legal and technical challenges, particularly concerning spectrum licensing, as the legality of setting up personal networks varies by region.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.wi-fi.org/regulations-enabling-6-ghz-wi-fi">Regulations Enabling 6 GHz Wi-Fi</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Several countries, including Argentina, Brazil, Canada, and the United States, have adopted the full 5925-7125 MHz spectrum range for use.</li>
<li>The European Union has adopted a portion of this range, specifically 5925-6425 MHz, with a focus on 5945-6425 MHz.</li>
<li>Other countries, such as Andorra, Austria, and Belgium, are considering adopting specific portions of the spectrum, while countries like Egypt, Oman, and Tunisia are still evaluating their options.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42606484">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The debate centers on whether the 6 GHz band should be licensed for 5G by telecom companies or remain unlicensed for Wi-Fi use, with significant implications for spectrum allocation. - The 6 GHz band is seen as a solution to congestion in existing Wi-Fi bands, but there is hesitance to allocate more ISM (Industrial, Scientific, and Medical) bandwidth. - Discussions also cover Wi-Fi 7&#39;s technical aspects, such as hardware availability and compatibility, highlighting the broader impact on future wireless technology development.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.usmint.gov/paper-currency/uncut-currency/">Uncut Currency</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42608155">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Uncut currency sheets were once misused by cutting them into off-center pieces and selling them as error notes, prompting the Treasury to make serial numbers recognizable to prevent this.</li>
<li>For $1 bills, serial numbers on uncut sheets start with 99, allowing collectors to verify authenticity when purchasing &quot;miscut dollar errors.&quot;</li>
<li>The US Mint sells uncut currency sheets at a premium, and they are popular among collectors for novelty, often being framed or given as gifts, despite being legal tender.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://crowdhailer.me/2025-01-02/the-evolution-of-a-structural-code-editor/">The evolution of a structural code editor</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The post outlines the development of a structural editor for the eyg programming language, which treats code as a structured tree to prevent syntax errors and improve code comprehension.</li>
<li>Initially built with Gleam and Svelte, the editor now uses Gleam and Lustre, with a terminal version in Go, and has evolved to simplify the Abstract Syntax Tree (AST) for better navigation.</li>
<li>The latest version features a menu and icon-based user interface, enhancing usability across devices, and encourages user feedback to improve the coding experience.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42608923">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion focuses on structural code editors, which view code as a structured tree, offering potential benefits like eliminating syntax errors and improving type information.</li>
<li>Challenges for structural editors include compatibility with existing tools like Git and managing invalid code states during editing.</li>
<li>There is interest in how structural editors could improve programming accessibility and efficiency, particularly in non-traditional environments like mobile devices, though concerns about practicality and integration remain.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Doom, the Gallery Experience" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Doom%2C%20the%20Gallery%20Experience&subheading=Monday%2C%20January%206%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/06</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-06T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-05]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/05&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-05</h1>
<h2><a href="https://uwaterloo.ca/news/media/no-more-needles-tracking-blood-sugar-your-wrist">Researchers design wearable tech that can sense glucose levels more accurately</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Researchers at the University of Waterloo have created a wearable device that uses radar technology to monitor glucose levels non-invasively, removing the need for needles.</li>
<li>The device, led by Dr. George Shaker, incorporates a radar chip, a meta-surface for enhanced signal accuracy, and AI algorithms for precise glucose readings.</li>
<li>Currently USB-powered, the device aims to become battery-operated for improved portability and may eventually monitor additional health metrics, with efforts underway to commercialize the technology.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42599189">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Researchers have created wearable technology for non-invasive glucose monitoring, offering an alternative to finger pricking and Continuous Glucose Monitors (CGMs).</li>
<li>The technology aims to provide accurate glucose readings without direct contact with the bloodstream, which could be significant for clinical applications.</li>
<li>While promising, there is skepticism about its accuracy compared to existing CGMs, and further data and clinical trials are needed to confirm its effectiveness.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://nmn.gl/blog/ai-senior-developer">The day I taught AI to read code like a Senior Developer</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The AI was initially challenged with analyzing React codebases, approaching them like a novice developer. - By emulating senior developers&#39; strategies, such as focusing on core files and grouping changes by feature, the AI&#39;s code analysis improved significantly. - The focus is on enhancing code understanding rather than generation, with future plans to identify technical debt and comprehend team conventions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42601847">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article explores the challenges of training AI to read and analyze code with the proficiency of a senior developer, noting the difficulty in achieving consistent and accurate results.</li>
<li>It stresses the importance of providing context and structuring inputs to enhance AI performance in code analysis, while acknowledging skepticism about AI&#39;s current capabilities.</li>
<li>The discussion highlights the need for further experimentation and evaluation to validate AI&#39;s performance and considers the broader implications and potential advancements of AI in software development.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="http://rachelbythebay.com/w/2025/01/04/cruft/">Web page annoyances that I don&#39;t inflict on you here</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42599102">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The author avoids using certain web features like sticky bars, forced SSL/TLS, pop-ups, and unnecessary tracking to enhance user experience.</li>
<li>There is an ongoing debate about the necessity of HTTPS for security versus its compatibility issues with older browsers.</li>
<li>The discussion highlights the challenge of balancing user experience with modern web practices.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://tailscale.com/blog/how-nat-traversal-works">How Nat Traversal Works (2020)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>NAT traversal enables direct device connections despite the presence of Network Address Translators (NATs) and firewalls, using UDP-based protocols and direct socket control.</li>
<li>Techniques such as STUN (Session Traversal Utilities for NAT) help in discovering public IP addresses, while relays like TURN (Traversal Using Relays around NAT) or Tailscale&#39;s DERP are used for more challenging NATs.</li>
<li>The ICE (Interactive Connectivity Establishment) protocol optimizes connection paths by evaluating all possible options and selecting the most efficient one, ensuring robust NAT traversal with end-to-end encryption and authentication.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42600846">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article explores NAT (Network Address Translation) traversal, emphasizing the differences between TCP (Transmission Control Protocol) and UDP (User Datagram Protocol) hole punching, noting TCP&#39;s slightly higher complexity.</li>
<li>It challenges the perception of NAT as a security feature and discusses Tailscale&#39;s method for NAT traversal, raising concerns about depending solely on software ACLs (Access Control Lists) for security.</li>
<li>The discussion highlights the importance of secure endpoints and critiques the limitations of conventional network security strategies in the context of NAT traversal.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://amanvir.com/guten">Guten: A Tiny Newspaper Printer</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42599599">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Guten is a small-scale newspaper printer project designed to minimize screen time by delivering news in printed form. - Discussions around the project include concerns about the BPA content in thermal paper and suggestions for using BPA-free alternatives or different printing technologies like impact or dot-matrix printers. - Comparisons are made to the discontinued Little Printer, with recommendations for enhancing Guten&#39;s developer-friendliness and customization options, alongside considerations of environmental and health impacts of thermal paper.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Researchers design wearable tech that can sense glucose levels more accurately" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Researchers%20design%20wearable%20tech%20that%20can%20sense%20glucose%20levels%20more%20accurately&subheading=Sunday%2C%20January%205%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/05</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-05T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-04]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/04&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-04</h1>
<h2><a href="https://practicapp.com/carbagepilot-part1/">Self driving 1993 Volvo with open pilot</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A group of friends participated in the Carbage Run 2025 Winter edition, a 6-day rally through Sweden to the polar circle and back to Helsinki, requiring cars to be at least 20 years old and valued under €1000.</li>
<li>They transformed a 1993 Volvo 940 Estate into a self-driving vehicle using openpilot from comma.ai, incorporating modern components like electric power steering, a Bosch iBooster, and a Tesla radar sensor.</li>
<li>Future updates will include details on wiring, a custom Engine Control Unit (ECU), and plans to open-source the code, highlighting the project&#39;s innovative approach to retrofitting older vehicles with autonomous technology.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42592910">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A 1993 Volvo 940 was retrofitted with OpenPilot, a self-driving technology, highlighting the intersection of classic car design and modern tech.</li>
<li>The project faced challenges, including updating the brake and steering systems, raising legal and safety concerns, particularly with DIY modifications like welding the steering column.</li>
<li>The discussion extended to car regulations in Europe, the decline of hotrods in the US, and cultural differences in car modification freedoms, with the project viewed as an inspiring DIY effort despite safety concerns.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/s-macke/VoxelSpace">VoxelSpace: Terrain rendering algorithm in less than 20 lines of code (2020)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>NovaLogic&#39;s 1992 game Comanche utilized the Voxel Space engine, a 2.5D rendering technique based on ray casting, to create detailed terrains with shading and shadows.</li>
<li>The Voxel Space engine used height and color maps and a simple rendering algorithm, drawing vertical lines from back to front, which could be optimized for performance.</li>
<li>The engine&#39;s code is available under the MIT license, but the technology may still be patented in certain regions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42588956">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>VoxelSpace is a terrain rendering algorithm notable for its simplicity, requiring less than 20 lines of code, and evokes nostalgia for innovative game development during hardware-limited eras.</li>
<li>Modern AAA games focus on complex optimizations and market trends, often at the expense of originality, whereas indie games and platforms like PICO-8 provide more creative freedom.</li>
<li>Despite technological advancements, some developers and players feel that the &quot;magic&quot; of older games is missing, though innovative projects like voxel rendering continue to inspire creativity.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://ameye.dev/notes/rendering-outlines/">How to draw an outline in a video game</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses five techniques for rendering outlines in Unity, a popular game development platform, highlighting their use in games like Sable and The Last of Us. - Techniques include Rim Effects, Vertex Extrusion, Blurred Buffer, Jump Flood Algorithm, and Edge Detection, each with unique advantages and trade-offs in terms of performance and visual quality. - The article provides insights into balancing these methods for optimal game aesthetics and gameplay support, with additional resources and credits for 3D models included.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42593614">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article explores advanced techniques for drawing outlines in video games, emphasizing the efficiency of the Jump Flood Algorithm (JFA) and Signed Distance Fields (SDFs) over traditional methods. - It delves into stylized 3D graphics, discussing rendering techniques and the potential use of neural networks for lighting and styling. - Contributors provide insights into the historical development of cel shading in games, such as Jet Set Radio, highlighting the evolving intersection of technology and art in 3D graphics.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://anntelnaes.substack.com/p/why-im-quitting-the-washington-post">I&#39;m quitting the Washington Post</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42591221">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The author is leaving the Washington Post due to its failure to adapt to the evolving media landscape and its approach to presenting issues, which they believe is ineffective for critical topics like democracy.</li>
<li>Traditional media, particularly local newspapers, are struggling financially, leading to biased reporting and a decline in public trust, while social media cannot replace the rigorous work of journalism.</li>
<li>Concerns are raised about the influence of wealthy individuals, such as Jeff Bezos, on media outlets, and the impact of corporate interests on the media&#39;s role in holding power accountable.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://twitter.com/damengchen/status/1875296442417607072">Perplexity got ads</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42589863">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Perplexity has introduced advertisements, leading to discussions about the inevitability of ads in online services due to consumer reluctance to pay for ad-free experiences. - Some users find ads intrusive and prefer subscription-based services like Kagi, which offer ad-free search, while others continue to choose free, ad-supported options. - This situation underscores the ongoing debate between ad-supported and subscription-based models in digital services.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Self driving 1993 Volvo with open pilot" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Self%20driving%201993%20Volvo%20with%20open%20pilot&subheading=Saturday%2C%20January%204%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/04</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-04T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-03]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/03&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-03</h1>
<h2><a href="https://vinay.sh/i-am-rich-and-have-no-idea-what-to-do-with-my-life/">I am rich and have no idea what to do</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42579873">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The post discusses the common struggle of finding purpose after achieving financial success, which can lead to feelings of disillusionment and isolation. - It suggests that fulfillment can be found in developing others, building connections, or pursuing new interests, emphasizing the importance of purpose beyond financial wealth. - The discussion also highlights the challenges of maintaining relationships when wealth creates a social divide, underscoring the need for meaningful activities and connections to foster a sense of belonging.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://iterm2.com/downloads/stable/iTerm2-3_5_11.changelog">iTerm2 critical security release</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>iTerm2 version 3.5.11, released on January 2, 2025, addresses a critical security vulnerability related to the SSH integration feature in previous versions. - The bug involved logging input/output to a file on the remote host, which could be accessed by others, affecting users of versions 3.5.6 to 3.5.10 and certain beta versions. - Users are advised to update to version 3.5.11 immediately, delete the /tmp/framer.txt file, and verify the update using the provided SHA-256 and PGP signature for security assurance.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42579472">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>iTerm2 released a critical security update to address a bug in its SSH integration, which logged input and output to a file on the remote host, potentially exposing data to other users.</li>
<li>The issue was caused by verbose logging being accidentally enabled in production, prompting discussions on the importance of pre-commit hooks and safeguards to prevent similar errors.</li>
<li>The incident sparked debate on switching to alternatives like Ghostty or Terminal.app, while also highlighting the balance between feature-rich software and security risks.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://minimaxir.com/2025/01/write-better-code/">Can LLMs write better code if you keep asking them to “write better code”?</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>In November 2023, a meme trend involved users asking ChatGPT to iteratively enhance images, which was then applied to code using Claude 3.5 Sonnet to improve a Python program. - Initial attempts with vague prompts like &quot;write better code&quot; showed some improvements, but structured prompt engineering with specific optimization goals led to significant performance enhancements. - The experiment underscored the importance of human oversight, as while Large Language Models (LLMs) can offer innovative ideas, they may also introduce subtle bugs during code optimization.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42584400">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) often generate basic code due to their training on numerous tutorials, potentially missing simple optimizations that could enhance code performance. - Iteratively prompting LLMs to improve code can yield better results, but this process may be as time-consuming as manual coding. - The discussion underscores the limitations of LLMs in grasping complex optimizations and highlights the importance of providing context and specific instructions for improved code quality.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="http://databasearchitects.blogspot.com/2024/12/advent-of-code-2024-in-pure-sql.html">Advent of Code 2024 in pure SQL</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Thomas Neumann shared his experience of solving the Advent of Code 2024 challenges using pure SQL, highlighting it as an exercise in alternative problem-solving approaches. - Neumann successfully completed all challenges, though he noted SQL&#39;s limitations in handling complex algorithms and state updates, suggesting potential improvements for SQL&#39;s efficiency. - The blog post includes a detailed SQL solution for one challenge and discusses the possibility of enhancing SQL to better support complex algorithm execution directly within databases.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42577736">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Advent of Code 2024 in pure SQL highlights SQL&#39;s ability to handle complex challenges, sparking interest in its performance and logical structure.</li>
<li>The discussion reveals varied experiences with SQL, from optimizing stored procedures to using it for business logic, showcasing both its strengths and challenges.</li>
<li>The conversation also explores the potential of SQL-like languages and the balance between database logic and application code, reflecting diverse opinions on SQL&#39;s role in software development.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.tvtechnology.com/news/sixth-circuit-of-appeals-strikes-down-fccs-net-neutrality-rules">U.S. appeals court strikes down FCC&#39;s net neutrality rules</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A U.S. Appeals Court has invalidated the FCC&#39;s net neutrality rules, which mandated equal treatment of internet traffic by broadband providers, citing the FCC&#39;s overreach of legal authority.</li>
<li>The decision references a Supreme Court ruling that restricts the powers of regulatory agencies, impacting the FCC&#39;s ability to enforce net neutrality.</li>
<li>FCC Chair Jessica Rosenworcel called for Congress to legislate net neutrality, while Commissioner Brendan Carr supported the court&#39;s decision as a check on regulatory overreach.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42578237">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A U.S. appeals court has invalidated the FCC&#39;s net neutrality rules, citing insufficient legal authority under current law. - The decision follows the Supreme Court&#39;s overturning of Chevron deference, which had permitted agencies like the FCC to broadly interpret statutes. - The court classified broadband providers as offering an &quot;information service,&quot; not a &quot;telecommunications service,&quot; thus restricting the FCC&#39;s regulatory power and ending federal net neutrality rules, potentially allowing ISPs to throttle or prioritize internet traffic.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://den.dev/blog/be-a-property-owner-not-a-renter-on-the-internet/">Be a property owner and not a renter on the internet</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article stresses the importance of owning your digital space instead of relying solely on major internet platforms, which often prioritize their growth over user interests. - Strategies for maintaining control over your online presence include owning a domain, diversifying content across multiple platforms, and building direct connections with audiences through email lists. - By creating your own web property, you ensure flexibility and resilience in your digital endeavors, reducing dependency on any single network.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42581119">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion emphasizes the importance of owning one&#39;s digital presence instead of depending on social media platforms, addressing concerns about AI exploiting user-generated content. - It explores the complexities of copyright, AI ethics, and the significance of having a personal website or domain for better control over online data. - The conversation also considers the practicality and limitations of self-hosting, given the dependence on external services like domain registrars and hosting providers, advocating for more independence in managing one&#39;s online presence.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blogscroll.com/">BlogScroll – An open directory of personal sites and blogs</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>BlogScroll is an open directory of personal sites and blogs, emphasizing digital spaces outside major technology companies, and is maintained on GitHub by Den Delimarsky. - Users can contribute to BlogScroll through GitHub or by emailing the creator, and updates are available via an RSS feed. - The directory includes various categories such as design-and-ux, personal, photo-video-production, and technology, showcasing contributions from numerous individuals.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42583086">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>BlogScroll is an open directory for personal sites and blogs, focusing on sharing digital gardens, which are debated as any personal site by some users.</li>
<li>Hosted on GitHub, BlogScroll has sparked discussions about its &quot;walled garden&quot; nature, with suggestions for OPML export and scalability improvements.</li>
<li>The project encourages submissions to expand its list, reflecting a renewed interest in personal web spaces and the challenges of maintaining independent, curated content online.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://tavianator.com/2025/shlx.html">The Alder Lake SHLX Anomaly</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Harold Aptroot discovered that the SHLX instruction on Intel&#39;s Alder Lake processors exhibits a &quot;medium latency&quot; of 3 cycles, which is atypical for left-shift operations that usually take 1 cycle. - This latency issue is specific to Alder Lake&#39;s performance cores and does not affect the efficiency cores, contradicting Intel&#39;s claims of a 1-cycle latency. - The latency varies based on the initialization of the shift count register, with 32-bit instructions or 64-bit instructions without immediates achieving 1-cycle latency, while 64-bit instructions with immediates result in 3-cycle latency.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42579969">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Alder Lake SHLX Anomaly is a performance issue where specific instructions, such as <code>mov rcx, 1</code>, cause the <code>SHLX</code> instruction to execute slower, potentially due to the register renamer&#39;s handling of small immediates.</li>
<li>This anomaly can lead to a 3x slowdown and is challenging to reproduce because context switches may reset the register state, inadvertently speeding up the code.</li>
<li>The issue is newly discovered and primarily affects shift counts, impacting instructions like <code>SHL</code>, but not others like <code>ANDN</code>, and is not typically accounted for by compilers.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="I am rich and have no idea what to do" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=I%20am%20rich%20and%20have%20no%20idea%20what%20to%20do&subheading=Friday%2C%20January%203%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/03</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-03T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-02]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/02&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-02</h1>
<h2><a href="https://mathstodon.xyz/@tao/113721192051328193">One of my papers got declined today</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42568399">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A paper by renowned mathematician Terence Tao was rejected, illustrating that even top academics encounter rejection, sparking a broader discussion on the prevalence of paper rejections in academia. - The discourse highlighted issues within the peer review process, including biases and the pressure to publish frequently, with many sharing personal experiences of rejection. - Suggestions for improvement included exploring alternative evaluation and publication systems, such as open internet-centric reviews, while acknowledging that rejection is a standard aspect of the academic journey.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/alufers/mitmproxy2swagger">MitmProxy2Swagger: Automagically reverse-engineer REST APIs</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>mitmproxy2swagger is a tool that converts mitmproxy captures into OpenAPI 3.0 specifications, facilitating the reverse-engineering of REST APIs by capturing application traffic. - The tool now supports HTTP Archive (HAR) files from browser Developer Tools, expanding its usability for developers. - Installation can be done using Python3 and pip or Docker, and the project employs tools like poetry, pre-commit, and pytest for development, with an MIT license.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42572662">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>MitmProxy2Swagger is a tool designed to reverse-engineer REST APIs by analyzing traffic captured with mitmproxy, a popular tool for intercepting HTTP/HTTPS traffic.</li>
<li>Users have successfully utilized it to recreate private servers for games and reverse-engineer APIs for Android applications, highlighting its effectiveness in identifying API endpoints.</li>
<li>The tool is particularly beneficial for working with legacy systems or undocumented APIs, though it may face challenges with non-standard APIs and discussions include methods to protect APIs from reverse engineering, such as CAPTCHAs and certificate pinning.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://mjg59.dreamwidth.org/70954.html">The GPU, not the TPM, is the root of hardware DRM</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42570988">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The core of hardware Digital Rights Management (DRM) is associated with Graphics Processing Units (GPUs) rather than Trusted Platform Modules (TPMs), with media DRM currently linked to GPU vendors.</li>
<li>DRM&#39;s long-term goal may be to exert total control over devices, potentially impacting software like adblockers, raising concerns about the future of personal computing.</li>
<li>The Free Software Foundation (FSF) may be misdirected in focusing on TPMs, as GPU vendors have already integrated DRM technology, highlighting the need for legislative intervention to protect user rights.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/zasper-io/zasper">Zasper: A Modern and Efficient Alternative to JupyterLab, Built in Go</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Zasper is a high-performance Integrated Development Environment (IDE) inspired by Jupyter, optimized for massive concurrency and minimal memory usage. - It is built with the Go programming language for enhanced concurrency and performance, offering both Electron and Web App versions, and is open-source under the AGPL-3.0 license. - Zasper supports REPL-style (Read-Eval-Print Loop) data applications and aims to expand beyond Jupyter Notebooks to support custom data applications, with full support on Mac and limited support on Linux.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42572057">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Zasper is a new alternative to JupyterLab, developed in the Go programming language, promising enhanced efficiency with reduced RAM and CPU usage.</li>
<li>It utilizes Go coroutines for improved kernel management, contrasting with JupyterLab&#39;s Python-based approach, and aims to tackle issues like kernel management and package installation.</li>
<li>The project is in its early stages, with support from the Jupyter community, and is open to feedback and collaboration, highlighting the benefits of diverse frontends and potential integration with tools like Emacs.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://literallythevoid.com/blog/rails_for_everything.html">Rails for everything</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Rails 8 is optimized for small projects and single developers, offering a comprehensive &quot;Getting Started with Rails&quot; guide to build full-featured applications.</li>
<li>SQLite is now production-ready in Rails 8, reducing the dependency on PostgreSQL or Redis, and includes basic continuous integration (CI) configuration with 2000 free GitHub action minutes.</li>
<li>The new authentication generator and straightforward deployment with Kamal make user sign-in and live app setup with SSL easier, promoting best practices.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42569236">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Rails is a popular framework for web app development, known for its simplicity and efficiency compared to other modern stacks like Spring Boot or Micronaut. - It is favored for quickly building full-stack web apps, with integrated features like ActiveStorage and system tests, making it ideal for solo developers and small teams. - Despite ongoing debates about its relevance, Rails continues to evolve with recent updates, enhancing its capabilities and maintaining its appeal in the development community.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42573875">Where to Work After 40?</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42573875">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Career paths after 40 can differ significantly, with options including joining mid-sized B2B (Business-to-Business) companies, consulting, or professional services.</li>
<li>Personal goals, financial needs, and interests should guide the decision, with networking and past experiences playing a crucial role in discovering new opportunities.</li>
<li>The ideal career path is subjective and varies based on individual preferences and circumstances.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.jacobvosmaer.nl/0036-beeper/">My favourite computer ergonomics hack</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Jacob Vosmaer introduces &quot;The Beeper,&quot; a DIY device designed to encourage movement by beeping if the computer screen remains unlocked for too long. - The Beeper is composed of hardware (Adafruit Feather Huzzah ESP8266, switch, piezo buzzer), firmware (Lua script), and software that manages activation. - Despite its simplicity, the device effectively promotes regular movement, and Jacob acknowledges his wife&#39;s support in the project.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42569109">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Users expressed frustration with mandatory RSIGuard software at work, which enforces breaks with fixed timing and disruptive pop-ups. - The discussion included various ergonomic hacks, such as drinking water for regular breaks, using tight clothing, and relying on Apple Watch reminders. - Alternatives like AntiRSI, Workrave, custom solutions, and smartwatches like Bangle.js2 were suggested to manage repetitive strain injury (RSI) and improve ergonomics.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/uBlockOrigin/comments/1hr6xjc/ubo_quick_filters_list_being_stolen_by_team/">UBlockOrigin GPL code being stolen by team behind Honey browser extension</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42576443">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Honey browser extension team is accused of using GPL (General Public License) code from UBlockOrigin without proper attribution, sparking controversy.</li>
<li>Reddit users express concerns about deceptive business practices, emphasizing the negative impact on customers and the tech industry.</li>
<li>The discussion highlights broader issues, including corporate ethics, the influence of money in politics, and challenges in maintaining business integrity, with skepticism about the future of open-source projects due to potential exploitation by companies.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://j3s.sh/thought/blogs-rot-wikis-wait.html">Blogs rot. Wikis wait</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The post contrasts the enduring nature of wikis with the transient nature of blogs, suggesting that by 2025, wikis will become more personal and meaningful.</li>
<li>Wikis are described as dynamic and reflective of the writer&#39;s evolving thoughts, whereas blogs are likened to static, forgotten storefronts.</li>
<li>The author is transitioning from a traditional website to a wiki format, indicating a shift in how personal content is managed and shared.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42571367">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Blogs offer a time-specific snapshot of an author&#39;s thoughts, allowing for updates through new posts, but often lack timestamps for context. - Wikis, such as Wikipedia, can struggle with clarity on update timing and reliability, leading to potential outdated information. - Both blogs and wikis have unique advantages and can coexist, serving different purposes in content creation and knowledge sharing.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://nymag.com/intelligencer/article/meta-wants-more-ai-bots-on-facebook-and-instagram.html">Meta Wants More AI Bots on Facebook and Instagram</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Meta is set to launch AI bots on Facebook and Instagram to engage younger users and leverage its investment in generative AI technology. - These AI bots will have profiles and create content, functioning similarly to regular social media accounts, following Meta&#39;s acquisition of SocialAI. - This initiative reflects Meta&#39;s broader strategy of automating social interactions and content curation, aligning with trends seen in apps like Character.ai.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42571608">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Meta is introducing more AI bots on Facebook and Instagram to boost user engagement by simulating interactions, reflecting a broader industry trend of using AI to enhance user experience.</li>
<li>There are concerns about the authenticity of interactions, as AI-generated content might overshadow genuine human connections on these platforms.</li>
<li>Critics worry that increased AI presence could lead to a less authentic social media experience, potentially alienating users who value real interactions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://austinhenley.com/blog/25yearsofai.html">My 25-year adventure in AI and ML</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Austin Z. Henley, an Associate Teaching Professor at Carnegie Mellon University, shares his 25-year journey in AI (Artificial Intelligence) and ML (Machine Learning), highlighting his transition from initial disinterest to active involvement through various projects.</li>
<li>His career path includes developing simple games, studying AI and neural networks, and applying decision trees and clustering during his PhD to analyze code editor data.</li>
<li>Henley joined Microsoft&#39;s program synthesis team in 2022, working on AI projects, including tools based on LLMs (Large Language Models), and continues to explore AI tools independently while teaching.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42569913">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>There is a growing trend in the AI (Artificial Intelligence) and ML (Machine Learning) fields to use AI even when simpler solutions might be more effective. - Some professionals argue against this trend, emphasizing the need for practical approaches and questioning the necessity of AI in every application. - The debate underscores the importance of communication within engineering teams to balance innovation with practicality, while also considering the societal impact of AI on traditional human roles and creativity.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="One of my papers got declined today" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=One%20of%20my%20papers%20got%20declined%20today&subheading=Thursday%2C%20January%202%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/02</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-02T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-01]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/01&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-01</h1>
<h2><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42562750">Happy New Year 2025</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42562750">Reactions</a></h3>
<h2><a href="https://doom-captcha.vercel.app/">DOOM CAPTCHA</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42566112">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>DOOM CAPTCHA is a creative project requiring users to play a level of the classic game DOOM as a CAPTCHA test, highlighting technical skills and nostalgia. - Users find it challenging due to the absence of modern controls, leading to mixed reactions about its practicality and accessibility. - The project, although novel, underscores the persistent dissatisfaction with traditional CAPTCHA systems, despite being built with Vercel&#39;s AI assistant and manual game integration.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://curiouscoding.nl/posts/static-search-tree/">Static search trees: faster than binary search</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses the implementation and optimization of static search trees (S+ trees) for significantly faster searching of sorted data, achieving speeds 40 times faster than traditional binary search. - Optimization techniques such as batching, prefetching, and manual SIMD (Single Instruction, Multiple Data) are employed to enhance query throughput. - The article also explores various tree layouts, node sizes, and memory management strategies, with a discussion on future work like branchy search and interpolation search to further improve search efficiency.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42562847">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion highlights a shift from C/C++ to Rust for algorithmic content, especially in static search trees, due to Rust&#39;s safety and performance benefits.</li>
<li>Rust&#39;s growing popularity in low-level programming is noted, with some users preferring C or pseudocode for accessibility, while others value Rust&#39;s modern features.</li>
<li>The conversation also explores the potential of the Zig programming language and the challenges associated with learning new languages, reflecting the evolving landscape of programming languages.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://openreview.net/forum?id=YXnwlZe0yf&noteId=yrsGpHd0Sf">30% Drop In o1-Preview Accuracy When Putnam Problems Are Slightly Variated</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Putnam-AXIOM is a benchmark designed to assess large language models (LLMs) on advanced mathematical reasoning using problems from the Putnam Mathematical Competition. - The benchmark includes 236 original problems and a variation with 52 altered problems to avoid data contamination. - OpenAI&#39;s top-performing model achieved 41.95% accuracy on the original problems but experienced a significant performance drop of approximately 30% on the altered problems, highlighting challenges in adapting to variations.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42565606">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A study revealed a 30% decrease in the accuracy of the o1-Preview model on Putnam problems when minor variations were introduced, indicating challenges for Large Language Models (LLMs) with small changes. - The findings fuel the debate on whether LLMs can genuinely reason or if they primarily depend on pattern matching and memorization, similar to human errors under pressure. - Despite these challenges, models like o1 and o3 continue to perform well on complex mathematical problems, though their capacity to generalize is still under scrutiny.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.cs.cmu.edu/~pavlo/blog/2025/01/2024-databases-retrospective.html">Databases in 2024: A Year in Review</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The database landscape in 2024 experienced significant changes, including major acquisitions, license shifts, and ongoing rivalries among key players like Redis, Elasticsearch, Databricks, and Snowflake. - DuckDB gained popularity for analytical queries, with integrations into Postgres, while notable releases included Amazon Aurora DSQL and Microsoft Garnet. - Acquisitions such as Tabular by Databricks and OrioleDB by Supabase were significant, and despite setbacks like OtterTune&#39;s closure, the industry remains dynamic with new projects and funding.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42566192">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion critiques Redis&#39; API, with some arguing that the criticism lacks a deep understanding of Redis&#39; design and its unique data model.</li>
<li>Redis is recognized for its effective use in specific applications like leaderboards and real-time systems, despite some API criticisms.</li>
<li>The conversation also explores the broader database landscape, including challenges for startups, the role of SQL, and the evolution of database technologies, emphasizing the importance of understanding systems before critiquing them.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://thoughts.wyounas.com/p/books-i-enjoyed-most-in-2024">Books I Loved Reading in 2024</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The list features a diverse range of books, including historical, philosophical, scientific, and personal narratives, each offering unique insights and enriching experiences.</li>
<li>Highlights include Cicero&#39;s letters for insights into Roman life, Ben-Ari&#39;s works on computer science logic and program verification, and Steve Martin&#39;s memoir on comedic success.</li>
<li>The collection also includes philosophical explorations by Pierre Hadot and Nietzsche, Greek tragedies by Aeschylus, and literary works by Ursula Le Guin and Rabindranath Tagore.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42564687">Reactions</a></h3>
<h2><a href="https://mathstodon.xyz/@tao/113721192051328193">Terence Tao: One of my papers got declined today</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42568399">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Terence Tao, a prominent mathematician, shared an experience of having a paper rejected, underscoring the frequent occurrence of rejections in academia. - His story sparked discussions on the arbitrary nature of peer reviews and the challenges faced in academic publishing. - The conversation highlighted that rejection is a normal part of the academic process, even for leading researchers, and stressed the importance of sharing failures to address imposter syndrome.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://apiparrot.com/">API Parrot – Automatically Reverse Engineer HTTP APIs</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>API Parrot is a new tool designed to simplify the automation of business processes by automatically identifying data correlations between API requests and providing a graphical flow representation. - It allows users to record requests, define inputs and outputs, and export these flows as JavaScript code, making the process more efficient than manual reverse engineering or using less optimal technologies like Robotic Process Automation (RPA). - The tool is built on Electron and is available for both Windows and Linux platforms, with a tutorial available for reverse engineering the USPS API.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42565821">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>API Parrot is a tool that automates the reverse engineering of HTTP APIs, facilitating the automation of business processes by identifying data correlations between requests. - It offers features such as recording requests, defining inputs and outputs, and exporting flows as JavaScript code, with a graphical flow representation. - Currently available for Windows and Linux, API Parrot is free, with a potential &quot;pro&quot; version for businesses, and plans for a macOS release in the future.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://thehill.com/national-security/5061535-virginia-man-arrested-explosives/">FBI: Largest homemade explosives cache in agency history found in Virginia</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42562529">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The FBI uncovered the largest cache of homemade explosives in its history in Virginia, leading to significant legal and public debate.</li>
<li>The suspect is currently only charged with possessing a short-barreled rifle, as the legality of his firearms is being examined.</li>
<li>The case has ignited discussions on gun laws, the Second Amendment, and the balance between government regulation and individual rights.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://dgl.cx/2024/12/ghostty-terminal-title">Déjà vu: Ghostly CVEs in my terminal title</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Ghostty, a new terminal emulator, had a security vulnerability similar to one from 2003, allowing ASCII escape characters to execute commands like opening applications. - The issue was notably problematic with Zsh and Bash in vi mode, but Ghostty 1.0.1 has resolved this by disabling the feature by default. - Despite the security flaw, Ghostty is commended for its features, and the developer promptly addressed the issue, providing fixes and workarounds for users.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42562743">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion centers on terminal security vulnerabilities, particularly those related to escape sequences, and explores ways to mitigate these risks. - Suggestions for enhancing terminal security include adopting systems akin to CPU protection rings or OpenBSD’s pledge() syscall, which limit capabilities to prevent exploits. - Participants acknowledge the challenge of balancing security with functionality in terminal applications and express interest in further exploration and collaboration to improve security practices.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/facebookresearch/large_concept_model">Large Concept Models: Language modeling in a sentence representation space</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The repository offers implementations for Large Concept Models (LCM), which utilize &quot;concepts&quot; as a higher-level semantic representation for language modeling.</li>
<li>LCM supports 200 text languages and 57 speech languages using the SONAR embedding space, and is trained for auto-regressive sentence prediction with methods like MSE regression and diffusion-based generation.</li>
<li>The repository provides installation instructions, data preparation, training, finetuning, and evaluation guidelines, and is released under the MIT license, using fairseq2 with UV and pip installation options.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42563534">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large Concept Models focus on representing language in terms of &quot;concepts&quot; rather than individual tokens, aiming to enhance semantic chunking and prediction.</li>
<li>This method proposes using higher-level representations to mimic human planning and communication, potentially offering advantages over traditional token-based models.</li>
<li>The approach addresses limitations in current Large Language Model (LLM) architectures by emphasizing explicit hierarchical structures to better replicate human reasoning.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Happy New Year 2025" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Happy%20New%20Year%202025&subheading=Wednesday%2C%20January%201%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/01</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-01T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
