<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0"
>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 19:11:53 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/newsletter/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <copyright><![CDATA[2023 Sunghyun Cho]]></copyright>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-28]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/28&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-28</h1>
<h2><a href="https://repebble.com/">We&#39;re bringing Pebble back</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42845091">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Pebble is being revived with support from Google, focusing on its original strengths such as hackability, long battery life, and serving as a phone extension. The revival aims to maintain Pebble&#39;s open-source nature and avoid mandatory cloud subscriptions, appealing to hackers and tech enthusiasts. The community is excited about Pebble&#39;s return, reflecting on its unique features and influence on wearable technology. </p>
<h2><a href="https://opensource.googleblog.com/2025/01/see-code-that-powered-pebble-smartwatches.html">Google open-sources the Pebble OS</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42845070">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Google has open-sourced the Pebble OS, generating enthusiasm among fans and developers for potential new developments in smartwatch technology. The release on GitHub does not include proprietary components such as system fonts and the Bluetooth stack, so it cannot be compiled in its current form. This move is viewed as a positive gesture from Google, attributed to internal efforts, and is seen as a step towards reviving the Pebble smartwatch ecosystem. </p>
<h2><a href="https://unsloth.ai/blog/deepseekr1-dynamic">Run DeepSeek R1 Dynamic 1.58-bit</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42850222">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>DeepSeek R1 Dynamic 1.58-bit achieves an 80% size reduction and operates at 140 tokens per second using dual H100s, but its slow speed and repetition issues raise questions about its practicality. Dynamic quantization aids in performance, yet concerns about accessibility, cost, and the model&#39;s training cost claims persist, leading to scrutiny. The model has a notable impact on the market, with efforts underway to replicate its results, though its performance is debated compared to larger models. </p>
<h2><a href="https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/27/llamacpp-pr/">Promising results from DeepSeek R1 for code</a></h2>
<p>A pull request (PR) by Xuan-Son Nguyen for llama.cpp enhances WebAssembly (WASM) speed using Single Instruction, Multiple Data (SIMD) instructions, with significant contributions from DeekSeek-R1. The PR includes a dynamic model_map built from API responses, removing the necessity for hardcoded versions, showcasing innovation in plugin development. Simon Willison’s Weblog also covers recent topics such as open source projects, Anthropic&#39;s Citations API, and Large Language Model (LLM) projects, indicating a focus on cutting-edge technology discussions. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42852866">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>DeepSeek R1 demonstrates AI&#39;s potential in coding by writing 99% of a pull request (PR) for llama.cpp, showcasing AI&#39;s increasing role in software development. Tools like aider are now responsible for generating 70-82% of new code in releases, indicating a significant boost in productivity through AI assistance. Despite these advancements, AI still requires human oversight for complex problem-solving and integration with existing codebases, suggesting a shift in job dynamics and skill requirements in the industry. </p>
<h2><a href="https://newsletter.languagemodels.co/p/the-illustrated-deepseek-r1">The Illustrated DeepSeek-R1</a></h2>
<p>DeepSeek-R1 is a newly released AI model emphasizing enhanced reasoning capabilities through a structured three-step training process: language modeling, supervised fine-tuning (SFT), and preference tuning. The model incorporates long chains of reasoning data, an interim reasoning model, and large-scale reinforcement learning (RL), excelling in reasoning tasks by generating thinking tokens. It utilizes a mixture-of-experts architecture, which allows it to efficiently handle complex reasoning tasks, marking a significant advancement in AI model design. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42845488">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>DeepSeek-R1 is generating discussion due to its performance and cost efficiency compared to models like GPT and Gemini, with some users noting typical large language model (LLM) issues. The model is notable for its low compute requirements and open-source nature, potentially disrupting the AI landscape and making AI development more accessible. Developed by a Chinese hedge fund, DeepSeek-R1 raises questions about its training data and geopolitical implications, despite mixed reviews on its coding capabilities. </p>
<h2><a href="https://mlip-cmu.github.io/s2025/">Machine Learning in Production (CMU Course)</a></h2>
<p>Carnegie Mellon University offers a course titled &quot;Machine Learning in Production/AI Engineering&quot; for Spring 2025, focusing on building, deploying, and maintaining machine learning-enabled software products. The course emphasizes responsible AI practices and MLOps (Machine Learning Operations), covering the entire lifecycle from prototype to production. It is designed for students with data science and basic programming skills, featuring lectures, labs, and a group project, with resources available on GitHub. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42847834">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The CMU course on Machine Learning in Production introduces practical tools such as Kafka, Docker, Kubernetes, and Jenkins, emphasizing MLOps (Machine Learning Operations), explainability, fairness, and monitoring. It serves as a bridge between machine learning and production systems, although some view it as entry-level and more focused on tool integration than mastery. Concerns are raised about the long-term relevance of certain tools and the course&#39;s limited emphasis on data quality, yet it is considered a new entry point for computer science students. </p>
<h2><a href="https://huggingface.co/blog/open-r1">Open-R1: an open reproduction of DeepSeek-R1</a></h2>
<p>Open-R1 is an initiative to replicate DeepSeek-R1, a reasoning model comparable to OpenAI&#39;s o1, focusing on transparency and open-source collaboration. The project seeks to recreate DeepSeek-R1&#39;s datasets and training pipeline, which are currently undisclosed, using reinforcement learning (RL) without human supervision. Open-R1 encourages community contributions to expand the model&#39;s applications beyond mathematics, including fields like coding and medicine. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42849536">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Open-R1 is an initiative aimed at recreating the DeepSeek-R1 model using open-source principles, though it is not yet an actual model. The discussion emphasizes the challenges and potential benefits of reproducing AI models on a limited budget, as well as the impact of AI on education and broader societal implications. The conversation also highlights the excitement surrounding technological advancements and the role of the open-source movement in making AI more accessible to a wider audience. </p>
<h2><a href="https://rebble.io/2025/01/27/the-future-of-rebble.html">The future of Rebble</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42845017">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The discussion highlights nostalgia for Pebble smartwatches, appreciated for their e-ink-like screens and long battery life, and questions why similar technology hasn&#39;t been more widely adopted. There is interest in the potential for new hardware from Rebble, a community-driven project, and the open-source nature of related smartwatch projects. Alternatives like Watchy and PineTime are mentioned, with users noting the software challenges faced in the open-source smartwatch space. </p>
<h2><a href="https://anthonydavidadams.substack.com/p/the-alpha-myth-how-captive-wolves">The Alpha Myth: How captive wolves led us astray</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42844619">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The &quot;alpha male&quot; concept in wolves, originally based on captive studies, has been debunked; wild wolf packs function more like family units rather than hierarchical structures. Despite being debunked, the &quot;alpha&quot; idea persists due to its appeal in competitive environments, such as Silicon Valley, and its resonance with certain societal and psychological needs. The continued belief in the &quot;alpha&quot; myth underscores how narratives can influence our perception of social dynamics, even when they are founded on incorrect assumptions. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.jvt.me/posts/2025/01/27/go-tools-124/">Go 1.24&#39;s go tool is one of the best additions to the ecosystem in years</a></h2>
<p>Go 1.24 introduces a new <code>go tool</code> command and <code>tool</code> directive in <code>go.mod</code>, enhancing the management of project tools in the Go ecosystem. This update addresses issues with the <code>tools.go</code> pattern, such as performance impacts and dependency tree bloat, by allowing more efficient tool management and reducing unnecessary dependencies. While the <code>go tool</code> command improves performance by caching <code>go run</code> invocations, there are concerns about tool dependencies being treated as indirect, potentially leading to dependency clashes. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42845323">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The introduction of &quot;go tool&quot; in Go 1.24 has led to debates about its impact on dependency management, with concerns about merging tool and project dependencies causing conflicts. Critics propose alternatives such as separate module files or using tools like Nix for improved version control. Supporters of Go&#39;s approach argue it offers simplicity and effectiveness, reflecting broader challenges in dependency management across programming languages. </p>
<h2><a href="https://nemo.foo/blog/day-4-of-an-afternoon-project">I trusted an LLM, now I&#39;m on day 4 of an afternoon project</a></h2>
<p>The author embarked on a project called Deskthang, intending to create a desk device using a Raspberry Pi Pico, LCD display, and RGB LEDs, while testing AI&#39;s capabilities. AI tools like ChatGPT and Claude initially assisted but ultimately led to a buggy implementation, causing issues like buffer conflicts and data corruption. Key lessons learned include recognizing AI as a tool rather than a co-pilot, understanding the value of friction and mistakes in learning, and the importance of patience over overconfidence. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42845933">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Large Language Models (LLMs) can be beneficial for simple tasks but may extend project timelines if relied upon for complex problems without proper oversight. They are effective at synthesizing information but may struggle with niche topics or new knowledge, requiring users to have strong fundamentals and experience. Users must maintain control by providing clear prompts and critically reviewing outputs to harness the full potential of LLMs effectively. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/01/27/nvidia-sheds-almost-600-billion-in-market-cap-biggest-drop-ever.html">Nvidia sheds almost $600B in market cap</a></h2>
<p>Nvidia&#39;s market cap suffered a historic loss of nearly $600 billion, with shares dropping 17% due to competition concerns from Chinese AI lab DeepSeek. The sell-off impacted the broader U.S. tech sector, causing declines in companies like Dell and Oracle, and contributing to a 3.1% fall in the Nasdaq index. DeepSeek&#39;s new AI model, developed using Nvidia&#39;s H800 chips, has heightened competition fears, affecting Nvidia&#39;s stock despite its previous gains, and reducing CEO Jensen Huang&#39;s net worth by $21 billion. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42845681">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Nvidia&#39;s market cap experienced a significant drop of nearly $600 billion, leading to debates about the company&#39;s valuation and whether it was overvalued. Despite the market reaction, Nvidia&#39;s GPUs continue to be crucial for AI-related tasks, underscoring their importance in the tech industry. The media&#39;s focus on large financial losses without considering inflation can be misleading, but Nvidia&#39;s decline is notable even among major corporations. </p>
<h2><a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/LocalLLaMA/comments/1ibnso0/janus_pro_1b_running_100_locally_inbrowser_on/">Janus Pro 1B running 100% locally in-browser on WebGPU</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42852400">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Janus Pro 1B is a model running locally in-browser using WebGPU, showcasing the capability of executing AI models in a browser environment. Despite its low parameter count, which limits its capabilities, the model can run on low-end GPUs, highlighting its accessibility. While image generation results are inconsistent, the ability to run such models locally in a browser is a significant technological advancement, though it currently does not support mobile devices. </p>
<h2><a href="https://xyzlabs.substack.com/p/berkeley-researchers-replicate-deepseek">Berkeley Researchers Replicate DeepSeek R1&#39;s Core Tech for Just $30: A Small Mod</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42855283">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Berkeley researchers have successfully replicated DeepSeek R1&#39;s core technology for just $30, focusing on specific tasks such as playing the game Countdown. The innovation involves using reinforcement learning, a type of machine learning where an agent learns by interacting with its environment, to enhance reasoning models, though its application is limited to areas with verifiable solutions. The discussion emphasizes the potential for AI self-improvement and its implications for future AI development, despite criticisms of the article&#39;s misleading title and lack of proper source links. </p>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="We're bringing Pebble back" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=We're%20bringing%20Pebble%20back&subheading=Tuesday%2C%20January%2028%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/28</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-28T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-27]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/27&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-27</h1>
<h2><a href="https://mertbulan.com/2025/01/26/once-you-are-laid-off-you-will-never-be-the-same-again/">A layoff fundamentally changed how I perceive work</a></h2>
<p>The author received an unexpected layoff notice from their company&#39;s COO, despite previous assurances that layoffs wouldn&#39;t occur, indicating a disconnect between company communication and actions. The experience led to a loss of trust in modern work environments, where employees feel disposable even when companies are financially stable, prompting a shift towards minimal effort and job security skepticism. In Germany, labor laws prioritize protecting vulnerable employees during layoffs, but this does not guarantee job security for all, leading to advice for employees to adhere strictly to contract hours and seek other job opportunities. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42838700">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The author reflects on their experience in the tech industry, emphasizing that maintaining a positive attitude and strong work ethic is crucial for future job opportunities. Building and nurturing professional relationships can lead to new opportunities, as contacts from past jobs often play a role in securing future roles. While employment is transactional, the author suggests focusing on personal pride in work and relationships with coworkers rather than expecting loyalty from companies. </p>
<h2><a href="https://marginalia-search.com/">Marginalia – A search engine that prioritizes non-commercial content</a></h2>
<p>Marginalia Search has launched a new site focusing on non-commercial content and discovery tools, emphasizing user privacy and data protection. The search engine operates using open-source technology, without AI or cloud services, and complies with GDPR and the EU Cookie Directive. The source code is available under an AGPL license, promoting transparency and community collaboration. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42836405">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Marginalia is a search engine that emphasizes non-commercial content and has transitioned from using Personalized PageRank to BM25 for ranking. The search engine has incorporated cosine similarity for discovering websites and has moved to a new domain, marginalia-search.com. Marginalia is open source, recrawls sites every 10 weeks, uses an RSS crawler for daily updates, and plans to expand beyond English content, though it currently struggles with navigational queries. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.cjonline.com/story/news/politics/government/2025/01/24/kansas-tuberculosis-outbreak-is-largest-in-recorded-history-in-u-s/77881467007/">Kansas tuberculosis outbreak is America&#39;s largest recorded since the 1950s</a></h2>
<p>Kansas is facing the largest tuberculosis outbreak in U.S. history, with 66 active cases and 79 latent infections reported in the Kansas City metro area since 2024, primarily in Wyandotte County. The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) is aiding local health officials in managing the outbreak, which is ongoing but has seen a reduction in active cases to approximately 32. Tuberculosis is a bacterial infection affecting the lungs, spread through the air, and treatable with antibiotics, with the risk to the general public considered low. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42835183">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The Kansas tuberculosis outbreak is the largest in the U.S. since the 1950s, as reported by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC). The outbreak has prompted discussions on the BCG vaccine, which is not routinely administered in the U.S. due to inconsistent efficacy and possible side effects. This situation emphasizes the need for effective public health policies and the role of government agencies in disease monitoring and prevention. </p>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/seemoo-lab/openhaystack">Openhaystack: Build &#39;AirTags&#39; – track Bluetooth devices via Apple&#39;s network</a></h2>
<p>OpenHaystack is a framework that enables tracking of personal Bluetooth devices using Apple&#39;s Find My network, developed by the Secure Mobile Networking Lab at TU Darmstadt. It is based on reverse-engineering Apple&#39;s Find My network and requires macOS 11 and a Bluetooth device, such as a BBC micro:bit, to function. OpenHaystack is open-source under the GNU Affero General Public License v3.0, supports various devices, and includes a mobile version for Android and iOS, though it remains experimental and unaffiliated with Apple. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42835772">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Openhaystack enables users to create custom &#39;AirTags&#39; for tracking Bluetooth devices via Apple&#39;s network, offering an alternative to Apple&#39;s proprietary solution. Google&#39;s version of Bluetooth tracking is criticized for subpar performance and privacy issues, while Samsung&#39;s network is noted for better performance despite Google&#39;s larger Android user base. The conversation highlights privacy concerns and technical challenges in developing custom tracking devices, with third-party alternatives lacking advanced features like Ultra-Wideband (UWB) for precise tracking. </p>
<h2><a href="https://estherschindler.medium.com/the-old-family-photos-project-lessons-in-creating-family-photos-that-people-want-to-keep-ea3909129943">Lessons in creating family photos that people want to keep (2018)</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42835282">Reactions</a></h3>
<h2><a href="https://www.jasonthorsness.com/20">DeepSeek My User Agent</a></h2>
<p>DeepSeek R1 is a new model designed to reveal the chain-of-thought to users, available for free at chat.deepseek.com or through a more affordable API compared to OpenAI. Following the article&#39;s release, the DeepSeek API encountered issues, with platform.deepseek.com returning 404 errors, indicating potential disruptions caused by DeepSeek My User Agent. Users can explore top judgments on Hacker News and utilize the &quot;Judge Me&quot; prompt at chat.deepseek.com for a personalized experience. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42834648">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>A user shared a humorous roast from DeepSeek, an AI tool that analyzes browser data, highlighting quirks like outdated OS and unusual screen resolution. The roast humorously connected these traits to the user&#39;s location in Calgary, Canada, sparking discussions on the tool&#39;s occasional inaccuracies and entertainment value. The conversation also explored the potential of AI in enhancing web browsing experiences, such as filtering ads and irrelevant content, and creating novel internet interactions. </p>
<h2><a href="https://purelymail.com/">Purelymail: Cheap, no-nonsense email</a></h2>
<p>Purelymail provides cost-effective email hosting with compatibility for IMAP and POP3, allowing use with most mail applications or through Roundcube webmail. The service is notably affordable, offering a single email account with 3 GB of storage for $10 annually, which is cheaper than competitors such as Protonmail, Fastmail, and Google Workspace. While Purelymail is in beta and may have occasional issues like email blocking and lack of 24/7 support, it emphasizes security and does not sell user data. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42836818">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Purelymail is recognized as a budget-friendly email service, appreciated for its simplicity and reliability, especially for custom domains. Users compare it to services like mxroute, Fastmail, and Proton, highlighting its affordability but noting concerns about its one-person operation and lack of features like calendar syncing. Despite some limitations, Purelymail&#39;s straightforward pricing and functionality make it a viable option for users seeking a basic email solution, with alternatives like Zoho and self-hosting also considered. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.astronomy.com/science/astronomers-just-deleted-an-asteroid-because-it-turned-out-to-be-elon-musks-tesla-roadster/">Astronomers delete asteroid because it turned out to be Tesla Roadster</a></h2>
<p>Astronomers initially misclassified Elon Musk&#39;s Tesla Roadster as an asteroid, emphasizing the need for improved transparency in tracking deep-space objects. The Minor Planet Center corrected the classification error, highlighting the difficulty in distinguishing between natural and artificial objects in space. The incident points to the absence of a central repository for tracking deep-space objects, complicating efforts to monitor potential asteroid threats, with amateur astronomers playing a vital role in identification. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42834043">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Astronomers initially misclassified a Tesla Roadster as an asteroid, labeling it &quot;2018 CN41,&quot; before realizing it was a man-made object already tracked as &quot;2018-017A.&quot; This incident underscores the necessity for improved tracking and classification systems for artificial objects in space to prevent similar errors. The mix-up highlights challenges in distinguishing between natural celestial bodies and human-made objects in space exploration. </p>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/deepseek-ai/Janus/blob/main/janus_pro_tech_report.pdf">DeepSeek releases Janus Pro, a text-to-image generator [pdf]</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42843131">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>DeepSeek has introduced Janus Pro, a text-to-image generator using a 7 billion parameter &quot;unified model&quot; that reportedly surpasses Dall-E 3 and Stable Diffusion Medium in performance. The model is noted for its heavy censorship on sensitive topics and limited image resolution of 384x384, sparking debates on AI development implications. Janus Pro&#39;s lower training costs compared to competitors could impact companies like Nvidia, and it is available for commercial use with restrictions on military applications. </p>
<h2><a href="https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/tech/technology/brazil-bans-sam-altmans-tech-firm-tools-for-humanity-from-paying-for-iris-scans/articleshow/117540826.cms?from=mdr">Brazil bans Sam Altman&#39;s tech firm Tools for Humanity from paying for iris scans</a></h2>
<p>Brazil&#39;s data protection authority has prohibited Tools for Humanity from offering compensation, including cryptocurrency, for iris scans to prevent undue influence on individuals&#39; decisions to share biometric data. Tools for Humanity, co-founded by OpenAI CEO Sam Altman, aims to develop a global identity system through iris scans under its World project. The company asserts compliance with Brazilian laws and is engaging with the authority to resolve concerns following an investigation that began last November. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42834432">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Brazil has prohibited Tools for Humanity, led by Sam Altman, from compensating individuals for iris scans to safeguard personal autonomy. This decision has ignited debates on privacy and the ethical implications of collecting biometric data, such as those involved in Altman&#39;s Worldcoin project. The situation underscores the ongoing conflict between technological progress and ethical concerns regarding data privacy and potential misuse. </p>
<h2><a href="https://evanhahn.com/my-failed-attempt-to-shrink-all-npm-packages-by-5-percent/">My failed attempt to shrink all NPM packages by 5%</a></h2>
<p>In 2022, a proposal was made to use the Zopfli compressor to reduce npm package sizes by 5%, aiming to enhance performance and lower storage costs. The proposal was rejected by npm maintainers due to concerns about Zopfli&#39;s slow compression speed, decompression time, lockfile issues, and integration complexity. The experience provided insights into proposal writing and evaluating trade-offs, despite the proposal&#39;s withdrawal. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42840548">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>An initiative to reduce NPM package sizes by 5% using Zopfli compression encountered issues like increased publish times and complexity. Despite potential bandwidth savings, drawbacks such as slower compression and lack of native support made the proposal less viable. The discussion underscored the challenge of balancing innovation with practicality in open-source projects, leading to the proposal&#39;s closure and consideration of alternatives like Brotli or ZSTD. </p>
<h2><a href="https://sf.gazetteer.co/a-former-tech-ceo-is-on-a-crusade-to-get-the-record-of-his-arrest-removed-from-the-internet">Former tech CEO suing to get the record of his arrest removed from the internet</a></h2>
<p>Former tech CEO Maury Blackman is suing journalist Jack Poulson for $25 million to remove a 2021 domestic violence arrest from the internet, despite the record being sealed by a judge. The lawsuit has ignited First Amendment debates, with the Electronic Frontier Foundation defending Poulson, emphasizing the public interest in the publication. The First Amendment Coalition has filed a lawsuit challenging the California law that prevents the publication of sealed arrest records, highlighting the tension between privacy and free speech rights. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42833193">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>A former tech CEO is suing to have his arrest record removed from the internet, bringing attention to the reputational damage caused by public arrest records. The case highlights the debate between the need for transparency to prevent secret arrests and the potential harm to individuals&#39; futures when arrest details are published without a conviction. The lawsuit also involves the Streisand effect, where efforts to suppress information can inadvertently increase its visibility. </p>
<h2><a href="https://finance.yahoo.com/news/asml-sinks-china-ai-startup-081823609.html">Nvidia, ASML Plunge as DeepSeek Triggers Tech Stock Selloff</a></h2>
<p>Nvidia&#39;s stock value dropped by $560 billion, marking the largest decline in market history, primarily due to concerns over the Chinese AI startup DeepSeek. DeepSeek&#39;s competitive low-cost AI model has raised fears about the future of US companies&#39; AI investments, affecting Nvidia&#39;s shares and major indexes like the S&amp;P 500 and Nasdaq 100. Despite Nvidia&#39;s challenges, Meta plans to boost AI project spending, and OpenAI, SoftBank, and Oracle have announced a significant $100 billion AI infrastructure venture. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42839650">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Nvidia and ASML stocks declined following a tech selloff initiated by Chinese AI startup DeepSeek, which created a model outperforming ChatGPT using older Nvidia hardware. DeepSeek&#39;s open-source model, being cheaper to train, raises concerns about the profitability of AI companies like OpenAI and Anthropic, potentially impacting future demand for Nvidia&#39;s GPUs. The market&#39;s response indicates fears of reduced margins and increased competition, despite the potential for broader AI adoption. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.theindex.media/this-man-is-a-coward/">Mark Zuckerberg: This Man Is a Coward</a></h2>
<p>Mark Zuckerberg faces criticism for his silence as former President Donald Trump dismantles the National Institutes of Health, affecting $40 billion in research funding, despite Zuckerberg&#39;s previous commitments to disease research. Zuckerberg&#39;s actions at Meta, including reducing fact-checking, content moderation, and diversity initiatives, while promoting Republican executives, suggest a shift in principles, aligning with Trump&#39;s demands. Critics argue that Zuckerberg&#39;s compliance with Trump&#39;s authoritarian tendencies reflects a lack of courage, influencing other tech companies like Amazon to potentially adopt similar stances, thus impacting his legacy. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42834911">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The article critiques Mark Zuckerberg for his actions at Meta, suggesting his decisions are influenced by self-interest and a lack of principles, particularly under political pressures. It explores themes of corporate responsibility, the impact of wealth on politics, and the difficulties of maintaining integrity in leadership roles. The discussion is divided, with some defending Zuckerberg as possibly adapting to external pressures, while others express disappointment in tech leaders&#39; perceived lack of courage. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.pa3fwm.nl/technotes/tn28-heaviside-transmission-lines.html">Oliver Heaviside and the theory of transmission lines (2021)</a></h2>
<p>PA3FWM&#39;s amateur radio website delves into technical topics such as single-sideband FM, software-defined radio (SDR) soundcards, and antenna design. The site highlights Oliver Heaviside&#39;s contributions to transmission line theory, including his improvements to Maxwell&#39;s equations and telegraph cable models. Content is adapted from a November 2021 article in the Dutch amateur radio magazine Electron, providing historical and technical insights into signal transmission and cable design. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42840352">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Oliver Heaviside, a self-taught physicist, made notable contributions to electromagnetism and transmission line theory, despite facing opposition from established figures like William Henry Preece. Heaviside&#39;s work, including the simplification of Maxwell&#39;s equations, was crucial to the field, yet he lived in poverty due to professional obstacles. The post highlights the challenges in understanding transmission lines and impedance, referencing educational resources and historical anecdotes for context. </p>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="A layoff fundamentally changed how I perceive work" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=A%20layoff%20fundamentally%20changed%20how%20I%20perceive%20work&subheading=Monday%2C%20January%2027%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/27</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-27T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-26]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/26&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-26</h1>
<h2><a href="https://crastinator-pro.github.io/steam-brick/">Steam Brick: No screen, no controller, just a power button and a USB port</a></h2>
<p>The Steam Brick Mod is a custom project that modifies a Steam Deck to be smaller and lighter by removing the screen and controller, leaving only essential components. The modification uses a 1TB OLED Steam Deck and involves creating a custom case with a 3D printer, resulting in a device about a third the size and 24% lighter than the original. Despite its portability benefits, the mod has limitations, such as no BIOS access and difficulty determining if the device is on, and it is not officially supported by Valve, posing risks of damage. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42825441">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The Steam Brick is a modified version of the Steam Deck, featuring no screen or controller, only a power button and USB port, designed for portability and ease of use. It utilizes XReal glasses for display, offering a unique approach to gaming without the need for traditional screen protection. This mod is a personal project and not officially supported by Valve, sparking discussions on various tech setups and educational systems. </p>
<h2><a href="https://pluralistic.net/2025/01/25/potatotrac/#carbo-loading">It&#39;s not a crime if we do it with an app</a></h2>
<p>Big food companies are allegedly using apps to engage in price-fixing, a practice termed &quot;greedflation,&quot; by coordinating pricing through third-party data brokers like Potatotrac. This issue is not limited to the food industry but also affects housing and other sectors, drawing attention from antitrust authorities. Cory Doctorow&#39;s new book, &quot;Picks and Shovels,&quot; delves into these themes, with the author making several appearances to promote it. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42830646">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The US justice system often shows leniency towards corporations, allowing them to avoid significant penalties for misconduct, while individuals face harsher consequences for minor infractions. Corporations exploit legal loopholes and employ lobbyists and lawyers to reduce fines and manipulate systems, as seen in Uber&#39;s use of algorithms to avoid paying drivers a minimum wage. The complexity of proving corporate crimes compared to individual offenses makes it challenging for the justice system to hold corporations accountable effectively. </p>
<h2><a href="https://iamwillwang.com/dollar/every-html-element/">Every HTML Element</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42823722">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The blog post provides an analysis of HTML tags and attributes using a large dataset, offering a downloadable SQLite database of popular tag-attribute combinations. It compares different approaches to exploring HTML elements, discussing topics like HTML parsing, deprecated tags, and the use of labels in forms. The post also delves into the history of XHTML, the semantics of HTML, and the use of custom elements, with some users reminiscing about older web design practices. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.historynet.com/maj-buang-lys-daring-feat-to-save-his-family/">The South Vietnamese pilot who landed a Cessna on a carrier to save his family (2019)</a></h2>
<p>In April 1975, Maj. Buang-Ly, a South Vietnamese pilot, executed a daring escape with his family in a small plane during the fall of South Vietnam. Captain Lawrence Chambers of the USS Midway made the unprecedented decision to clear the deck for Buang&#39;s landing, even discarding helicopters, allowing Buang to land safely. This event was part of Operation Frequent Wind, the final phase of the evacuation of American civilians and &quot;at-risk&quot; Vietnamese from Saigon, and Buang&#39;s plane is now displayed at the National Naval Aviation Museum. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42826536">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>A South Vietnamese pilot landed a Cessna on a U.S. carrier to save his family during the fall of Saigon, illustrating personal struggles and resilience during the Vietnam War. Many South Vietnamese soldiers fled using any available aircraft, highlighting the desperation and chaos of the time. The USS Midway, now a museum, was pivotal in these events, reflecting the broader human impact of war and complex geopolitical issues. </p>
<h2><a href="https://ycgraveyard.iamwillwang.com/">YC Graveyard: 821 inactive Y Combinator startups</a></h2>
<p>The YC Graveyard lists 821 inactive startups from Y Combinator, a prominent startup accelerator, highlighting the challenges faced by new ventures. These startups, from 39 batches and 50 industries, include sectors like finance, healthcare, retail, and technology, demonstrating the broad scope of Y Combinator&#39;s influence. Notable companies such as Blume Benefits, Fileforge, and Celest are among those that have ceased operations, reflecting the high-risk nature of startup ventures. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42828198">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>YC Graveyard has identified 821 inactive Y Combinator startups, underscoring the high failure rate in the startup ecosystem. Investors often prefer a definitive failure over a &quot;lifestyle business&quot; that doesn&#39;t scale, as it allows them to write off losses, while some startups are &quot;acqui-hired&quot; for their talent or assets. The discussion delves into the nature of small businesses, investor roles, startup success challenges, and the broader implications of venture capital, including startup funding dynamics and founder compensation. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.downtowndougbrown.com/2025/01/the-invalid-68030-instruction-that-accidentally-allowed-the-mac-classic-ii-to-successfully-boot-up/">An invalid 68030 instruction accidentally allowed the Mac Classic II to boot</a></h2>
<p>Doug Brown identified a bug in the Macintosh Classic II&#39;s ROM that should have stopped it from booting, but an undefined instruction on the Motorola MC68030 CPU allowed it to proceed. Using the MAME emulator, Doug discovered that the Classic II failed to boot in 32-bit mode due to a bus error from an invalid address, corrected by an undocumented instruction on actual hardware. This finding underscores the role of emulators in uncovering hidden hardware bugs and the intricacies of undocumented CPU instructions, with real hardware tests confirming the undocumented instruction&#39;s importance for booting. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42824562">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>An undocumented instruction in the MC68030 CPU allowed the Mac Classic II to boot by bypassing illegal instruction detection, altering the A1 register unexpectedly. This discovery underscores the existence of undocumented instructions in CPUs, akin to those found in 6502 and x86 architectures, which can lead to unexpected behavior. The 68030 architecture, known for its elegance, was used in various systems, but its complexity eventually hindered its scalability. </p>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Steam Brick: No screen, no controller, just a power button and a USB port" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Steam%20Brick%3A%20No%20screen%2C%20no%20controller%2C%20just%20a%20power%20button%20and%20a%20USB%20port&subheading=Sunday%2C%20January%2026%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/26</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-26T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-25]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/25&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-25</h1>
<h2><a href="https://www.caltrain.com/news/caltrains-electric-fleet-more-efficient-expected">Caltrain&#39;s electric fleet more efficient than expected</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42818692">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Caltrain&#39;s new electric fleet surpasses expectations in efficiency, operating quieter, faster, and more frequently, contributing to a transit renaissance in the Bay Area. The electric trains utilize regenerative braking, which returns energy to the grid, and operate on 100% renewable power, highlighting a commitment to sustainability. Despite these advancements, challenges like the need for increased urban density and improved transit-oriented development persist, alongside criticisms of BART&#39;s management and governance. </p>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/lightpanda-io/browser">Lightpanda, an open-source headless browser in Zig</a></h2>
<p>Lightpanda is a new open-source headless browser developed in Zig, designed to be faster and more efficient than existing options like Chrome headless, particularly for web scraping and automation tasks. It features an HTTP loader, HTML parser, DOM tree, JavaScript runtime, and a CDP server, making it compatible with tools like Puppeteer and Playwright, while being approximately 10 times faster and using 10 times less memory than Chrome headless. Currently in beta, Lightpanda supports limited web APIs, with plans for expansion, and offers a Managed Cloud service as part of its business model. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42817439">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Lightpanda is an open-source headless browser developed in Zig, providing a lightweight alternative to Chrome and Firefox for non-graphical tasks such as web scraping and AI automation. It includes essential components like an HTTP loader, HTML parser, JavaScript runtime, and partial web API support, focusing on speed and memory efficiency. Currently in beta, Lightpanda plans to enhance its web API coverage and operates on a business model offering a Managed Cloud service, inviting community feedback for improvements. </p>
<h2><a href="https://hallofdreams.org/posts/physicsforums/">PhysicsForums and the Dead Internet Theory</a></h2>
<p>&quot;Hall of Impossible Dreams&quot; is a repository featuring diverse content, including code and literature, and recently discussed the decline of PhysicsForums due to AI-generated content. PhysicsForums, established in 2001, was a thriving science forum until the rise of centralized platforms like StackExchange and the infiltration of AI-generated posts by 2025. The post raises concerns about the &quot;Dead Internet Theory,&quot; which posits that much of the internet is now non-human content, highlighting the challenges and ethical implications of sustaining online communities in the face of evolving technology. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42816284">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>There is increasing frustration with AI-generated content on the internet, especially in forums and blogs, due to its perceived lack of depth and reliability. Users are calling for solutions like identity verification or trust systems to ensure genuine human interaction and address ethical concerns about AI impersonating real users. The discussion underscores a broader tension between technological advancement and the desire for authentic, human-driven content online. </p>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/helix-editor/helix/pull/11285">File Explorer is merged to Helix editor</a></h2>
<p>The Helix editor has introduced a new file explorer feature, inspired by the telescope-file-browser, allowing users to navigate files like a file picker. Developed by contributor drybalka, the feature has been positively received, with feedback for enhancements such as directory slashes and icons. Some users on MacOS reported issues with the command palette, but the file explorer functions effectively with keybindings, and future updates may address .gitignore file exclusions. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42818278">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Helix editor has introduced an integrated File Explorer, sparking discussions on its necessity versus faster alternatives like fuzzy finders and ripgrep. Users share personal preferences and experiences with file navigation tools and plugins for editors such as Vim and Emacs. The new feature has generated excitement among some users, while others debate the merits of various file management methods. </p>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Caltrain's electric fleet more efficient than expected" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Caltrain's%20electric%20fleet%20more%20efficient%20than%20expected&subheading=Saturday%2C%20January%2025%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/25</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-25T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-24]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/24&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-24</h1>
<h2><a href="https://mstdn.social/@isziaui/113874436953157913">A QR code that sends you to a different destination – lenticular and adversarial</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42809268">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>QR codes can be manipulated to direct users to different destinations by creating overlapping patterns that change based on scanning conditions. This technique can be used for targeted attacks or to serve varied content, but simpler methods like server-side redirection are often more effective. Despite its intriguing nature, the practical use of this QR code manipulation is limited due to its complexity and visibility. </p>
<h2><a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1002342/">The State of Vim</a></h2>
<p>Following the death of Bram Moolenaar, Vim&#39;s founder, in 2023, the community has reorganized to ensure the continuation of Vim&#39;s development, with Christian Brabandt taking a more active role. The project is addressing challenges such as managing the Vim GitHub organization, updating the website, and considering changes like XDG support, while remaining in maintenance mode. VimConf 2024 in Tokyo highlighted international collaboration, with presentations in English and Japanese, and emphasized community input and careful testing over a single leader approach. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42810176">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Vim&#39;s success under new leadership has sparked discussions on governance models, such as BDFL (Benevolent Dictator For Life), with differing opinions on single leadership versus committee-based approaches. Neovim, a modern alternative to Vim, has gained traction due to its features and community support, though some users remain loyal to Vim for its stability. The conversation highlights the challenges of sustaining open-source projects and the advantages of plugin architectures, with Vim and Emacs continuing to be resilient in the evolving landscape of developer tools. </p>
<h2><a href="https://lcamtuf.substack.com/p/ui-is-hell-four-function-calculators">UI is hell: four-function calculators</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42810300">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The article explores the complexities in designing user interfaces for basic calculators, focusing on challenges with operations and edge cases. It highlights historical quirks in calculator design, such as the combined &quot;x÷&quot; key and non-intuitive behaviors in some apps. The discussion includes the benefits of Reverse Polish Notation (RPN) for simplifying calculations and reducing ambiguity, alongside user experiences and preferences. </p>
<h2><a href="https://lucumr.pocoo.org/2025/1/24/build-it-yourself/">Build It Yourself</a></h2>
<p>Armin Ronacher addresses the problem of dependency churn in software development, especially in JavaScript and Rust ecosystems, where frequent updates and numerous dependencies can lead to security vulnerabilities and complexity. He suggests a shift towards writing code with minimal dependencies, emphasizing the advantages of stable, self-written functions over extensive dependency graphs. Ronacher calls for a cultural change in both corporate and open-source communities to prioritize simplicity and stability in coding practices, which can lead to reduced maintenance and faster implementation. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42812641">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The text highlights the challenges of managing dependencies in programming, comparing Rust&#39;s tendency to accumulate dependencies with C++&#39;s control over them. It discusses security concerns related to package management systems, contrasting Debian/Ubuntu&#39;s systems with Docker/Python/Rust, and raises trust issues with unknown maintainers. The conversation emphasizes the importance of balancing the use of existing libraries with writing custom code to minimize complexity and security risks, considering long-term implications. </p>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="A QR code that sends you to a different destination – lenticular and adversarial" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=A%20QR%20code%20that%20sends%20you%20to%20a%20different%20destination%20%E2%80%93%20lenticular%20and%20adversarial&subheading=Friday%2C%20January%2024%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/24</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-24T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-23]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/23&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-23</h1>
<h2><a href="https://www.byran.ee/posts/creation/">I made an open-source laptop from scratch</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42797260">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>A high school student successfully built an open-source laptop from scratch in six months, and the project is fully available on GitHub. The project gained significant attention, ranking as a top post on Show HN, highlighting discussions on education, talent, and the potential of young engineers. Although not a polished product, the laptop functions as a daily driver, demonstrating the possibilities of open-source hardware development. </p>
<h2><a href="https://rustle.ca/posts/articles/work-from-home-lighting">How to improve your WFH lighting to reduce eye strain</a></h2>
<p>To minimize eye strain while working from home, create a balanced lighting environment using natural light, sheer curtains, and flicker-free artificial lights. Implement the 20/20/20 rule: every 20 minutes, look at something 20 feet away for 20 seconds to relax your eyes. Complement your workspace with light-filtering curtains and desk lighting that matches monitor brightness, while also taking regular breaks to maintain overall health. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42796950">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>To enhance work-from-home (WFH) lighting and reduce eye strain, use diffuse light from multiple sources and maintain a consistent color temperature. Consider the impact of wall color on lighting and aim for a &quot;Golden Hour&quot; effect—diffuse, warm, and gentle lighting for a photogenic and comfortable environment. Explore LED lighting options, such as high Color Rendering Index (CRI) bulbs, for improved light quality. </p>
<h2><a href="https://tailwindcss.com/blog/tailwindcss-v4">Tailwind CSS v4.0</a></h2>
<p>Tailwind CSS v4.0 introduces a high-performance engine, achieving builds up to 5x faster and incremental builds over 100x faster, enhancing performance and flexibility for developers. The update includes modern CSS features such as cascade layers, color-mix(), and built-in container queries, along with a first-party Vite plugin for improved integration and simplified installation. New features like 3D transform utilities, expanded gradient APIs, and CSS-first configuration with design tokens as CSS variables make it easier and faster to build modern web projects, with an upgrade guide available for existing projects. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42799136">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Tailwind CSS v4.0 introduces significant enhancements, such as native CSS variable access and a CSS-only configuration, reducing dependency on JavaScript and increasing versatility. The update is noted for its compatibility with AI workflows and utility in design systems, although some designers find it challenging for systematic design. The release has sparked discussions due to breaking changes, affecting integration with existing projects and tools, while maintaining popularity for its ease of use and styling efficiency. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2025/01/victory-federal-court-finally-rules-backdoor-searches-702-data-unconstitutional">Federal Court (Finally) Rules Backdoor Searches of Data Unconstitutional</a></h2>
<p>A federal district court has ruled that backdoor searches of databases containing Americans&#39; private communications under Section 702 require a warrant, marking a significant legal decision in United States v. Hasbajrami. Despite Congress reauthorizing Section 702, evidence shows misuse by the FBI and intelligence community, with 3.4 million warrantless searches conducted in 2021, prompting calls for reform to ensure constitutional protections. The court&#39;s decision highlights the unconstitutional nature of warrantless searches under Section 702, urging Congress to mandate warrants for searches involving U.S. persons&#39; data before its expiration in 2026. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42797756">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>A federal court has declared backdoor searches of data unconstitutional, igniting debates on government surveillance and privacy rights. The ruling challenges the constitutionality of Section 702 spying, highlighting the roles of Congress and the Supreme Court in safeguarding privacy. Despite the ruling, skepticism persists about its impact, as critics believe federal agencies like the FBI may continue such practices until internal regulations are revised. </p>
<h2><a href="https://terriblesoftware.org/2025/01/22/the-7-most-influential-papers-in-computer-science-history/">Most Influential Papers in Computer Science History</a></h2>
<p>The list highlights seven seminal papers in computer science history, each contributing foundational concepts that underpin modern technology, such as the Turing Machine, information theory, and the relational database model. These papers introduced groundbreaking ideas like NP-completeness, TCP/IP, the World Wide Web, and PageRank, which have significantly influenced computation, communication, and internet development. Bonus mentions include influential works on Lisp, distributed systems, and the &quot;Attention Is All You Need&quot; paper, showcasing the evolution and diversity of computer science research. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42799103">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The discussion centers on influential computer science papers, including classics like Hoare&#39;s &quot;Communicating Sequential Processes&quot; and Turing&#39;s work on computability. Participants debate the inclusion of more recent works, such as the PageRank paper, and suggest other impactful papers in cryptography and distributed systems. A Harvard course is mentioned, which examines these foundational papers to offer a comprehensive understanding of the evolution of computer science. </p>
<h2><a href="https://f-droid.org/2025/01/21/a-look-back-at-2024-f-droids-progress-and-whats-coming-in-2025.html">F-Droid&#39;s Progress and What&#39;s Coming in 2025</a></h2>
<p>In 2024, F-Droid made notable advancements in decentralizing app distribution, enhancing its infrastructure, and expanding its ecosystem, largely due to community support and funding. Significant achievements included infrastructure upgrades and the expansion of tools like Repomaker and Mobifree, with over 7205 app updates and 402 new apps added. Looking forward to 2025, F-Droid plans to utilize an Open Technology Fund grant to further improve infrastructure and continue focusing on decentralizing app distribution and promoting open-source alternatives. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42798108">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>F-Droid users are advocating for a download counter to identify popular and reliable apps, as the platform lacks a rating system. Challenges include navigation difficulties due to incomplete or outdated apps, prompting suggestions for better search filters and UI updates. Despite these challenges, F-Droid is valued for its open-source apps, with discussions on app submission processes and the potential integration of progressive web apps (PWAs). </p>
<h2><a href="https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/api-management/understanding-grpc-openapi-and-rest-and-when-to-use-them">Understanding gRPC, OpenAPI and REST and when to use them in API design (2020)</a></h2>
<p>API design primarily uses two models: gRPC (Remote Procedure Call) and REST (Representational State Transfer), both often mapped to HTTP, with gRPC using HTTP/2 for efficient communication. REST APIs are known for their simplicity and stability, while gRPC offers efficient client libraries and server implementations, making it suitable for internal APIs or when using specific tools like Cloud Endpoints. OpenAPI, similar to RPC, requires constructing URLs from templates, exposing HTTP details, and may involve complex custom HTTP mappings, offering broader HTTP tool compatibility compared to gRPC. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42799245">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Developers often find gRPC challenging due to tooling issues, particularly in Java, and difficulties with debugging and configuration, despite its advantages like bidirectional streaming and efficient transport. OpenAPI is a documentation standard for APIs, facilitating easier client generation and testing, and is often confused with REST, which is rarely implemented in its pure form. The decision to use gRPC, OpenAPI, or REST depends on specific use cases, team expertise, and project requirements, highlighting the importance of understanding each technology&#39;s strengths and limitations. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.science.org/content/article/trump-hits-nih-devastating-freezes-meetings-travel-communications-and-hiring">NIH hit with freezes on meetings, travel, communications, and hiring</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42798960">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The NIH (National Institutes of Health) is experiencing restrictions on meetings, travel, communications, and hiring, potentially affecting the US&#39;s scientific reputation. Critics claim these measures are punitive and politically driven, targeting researchers perceived as liberal, which could disrupt public health research, including cancer and infectious diseases. This situation highlights broader issues regarding the politicization of science and concerns about the decline of US soft power. </p>
<h2><a href="https://bun.sh/blog/bun-v1.2">Bun 1.2 Is Released</a></h2>
<p>Bun 1.2 is a significant update for JavaScript and TypeScript development, enhancing Node.js compatibility and adding built-in support for S3 and Postgres. The update introduces Bun.sql for SQL databases, a faster package manager, and a built-in test runner, alongside improved performance and new JavaScript features. Bun 1.2 also enhances bundling with HTML imports, standalone executables, and a new CSS parser, while remaining free and open-source with ongoing community contributions. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42801370">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Bun 1.2 has been released, introducing features such as HTML imports and built-in Amazon S3 support, which enhance its &quot;batteries-included&quot; approach. The release aims to simplify JavaScript development by integrating tools like TypeScript, Jest, and Webpack, appealing to developers seeking a streamlined setup. While Bun&#39;s speed and ease of use are praised, concerns about potential lock-in, third-party library inclusion, and long-term compatibility with Node.js persist among users. </p>
<h2><a href="https://bobbylox.com/blog/tech-takes-the-pareto-principle-too-far/">Tech takes the Pareto principle too far</a></h2>
<p>Bobby Lockhart critiques the tech industry&#39;s reliance on the Pareto Principle and MVPs, which often result in unfinished products due to insufficient incentives to complete them. He contrasts this with the gaming industry&#39;s &#39;vertical slice&#39; approach, which focuses on creating a polished product from the start. Lockhart advocates for a craftsmanlike approach to software development, emphasizing the importance of completing and refining products for a polished final outcome. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42800557">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The Pareto principle, or the 80/20 rule, is being discussed in the context of tech, particularly in software and product development, suggesting that 80% of effects come from 20% of causes. Critics argue that this principle results in products being marketed as complete despite lacking the final 20% polish, while supporters claim it enables efficient resource use and rapid market entry. The debate spans multiple industries, including gaming and AI, with differing views on whether the principle fosters innovation or leads to mediocrity. </p>
<h2><a href="https://ertu.dev/posts/i-made-an-online-shooter-game-in-lisp/">I made a multiplayer shooter game in Lisp, here is my journey</a></h2>
<p>The game &quot;Wizard Masters,&quot; a multiplayer third-person shooter, was developed using Clojure, a Lisp dialect, and is available on CrazyGames. Clojure was chosen for its full-stack capabilities and interactive REPL system, while Babylon.js was used for graphics due to its features and community support. Challenges included complex networking with Clojure async libraries, state management with Clojure&#39;s immutability, and the lack of a strong Clojure game development community, highlighting the potential benefits of transitioning to mainstream engines like Unity or Unreal for future projects. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42796906">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>A multiplayer shooter game was developed using Lisp, with ClojureScript and Babylon.JS for the frontend, and Clojure for the backend, utilizing Websockets for coordination. Despite challenges with Babylon.JS tooling, the game was successfully released and is compatible with multiple devices, including iPhones, receiving positive feedback for gameplay and polish. Some users experienced control issues in Firefox, and the developer is contemplating expanding the game based on its performance, highlighting the project&#39;s solo development and community support. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.trae.ai/home">Trae: An AI-powered IDE by ByteDance</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42799540">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Trae, an AI-powered Integrated Development Environment (IDE) by ByteDance, has initiated discussions about the trend towards subscription-based coding tools and associated costs. Concerns are raised about data privacy, particularly with Chinese companies like ByteDance, and the potential impact on traditional programming skills. The debate underscores differing views on AI&#39;s role in software development and the geopolitical implications of using tools from Chinese companies. </p>
<h2><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.09223">Foundations of Large Language Models</a></h2>
<p>The book &quot;Foundations of Large Language Models&quot; by Tong Xiao and Jingbo Zhu explores key concepts such as pre-training, generative models, prompting techniques, and alignment methods in large language models. It targets college students, professionals, and practitioners in the field of natural language processing, making it a valuable resource for those interested in Computation and Language, Artificial Intelligence, and Machine Learning. The book is available for further reading on arXiv under the identifier 2501.09223 [cs.CL]. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42799629">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>A book titled &quot;Foundations of Large Language Models&quot; by authors from Northeastern University, Shenyang, China, is available on Arxiv, noted for its comprehensive 231 pages. The discussion highlights ChatGPT&#39;s capabilities in reading PDFs, with some users pointing out its limitations in analyzing visual content. Arxiv is explained as a platform for pre-prints, which means the content is not necessarily peer-reviewed, and users express surprise at the book&#39;s availability there. </p>
<h2><a href="https://samcurry.net/hacking-subaru">Hacking Subaru: Tracking and Controlling Cars via the Starlink Admin Panel</a></h2>
<p>A security vulnerability in Subaru&#39;s STARLINK service was discovered on November 20, 2024, allowing unauthorized access to vehicles and customer accounts in the US, Canada, and Japan. The flaw enabled attackers to remotely control vehicles and access personal information using minimal data, such as a last name and ZIP code, due to issues in the STARLINK admin panel. The vulnerability was reported and patched within 24 hours without any malicious exploitation, underscoring the challenges in securing connected car systems due to broad access permissions. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42803279">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>A vulnerability in Subaru&#39;s Starlink system was discovered, allowing hackers to track and control vehicles, but it was patched within 24 hours without any malicious exploitation. Concerns persist regarding data collection and remote access by Subaru and its partners, with some users reporting battery drain issues linked to the system. The incident underscores the risks associated with internet-connected cars, emphasizing the need for improved user privacy protections and clearer opt-out processes for data collection. </p>
<h2><a href="https://diamondgeezer.blogspot.com/2025/01/londons-most-central-sheep.html">Where is London&#39;s most central sheep?</a></h2>
<p>Vauxhall City Farm, established in 1976, is the closest city farm to central London, located just over a mile from Trafalgar Square. The farm houses several sheep, including a Shetland and a Herdwick named Daffodil, showcasing the rural charm within the urban environment. Spitalfields City Farm, the second closest to central London, hosts a Herdwick ewe named Beatrix and several Castlemilk Moorits, emphasizing the unique appeal of city farms in London. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42802498">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The &quot;time to sheep&quot; metric, which gauges the duration to reach the countryside from a city center, initiated a debate on urban versus rural living preferences. The conversation highlighted cities like London, Bristol, and Toronto, focusing on their accessibility to nature or farms. Humorous city metrics such as &quot;time to chaos&quot; and &quot;time to cow&quot; were also part of the discussion, adding a light-hearted perspective. </p>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="I made an open-source laptop from scratch" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=I%20made%20an%20open-source%20laptop%20from%20scratch&subheading=Thursday%2C%20January%2023%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/23</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-23T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-22]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/22&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-22</h1>
<h2><a href="https://twitter.com/Free_Ross/status/1881851923005165704">Ross Ulbricht granted a full pardon</a></h2>
<p>Ross has been granted a full pardon by former President Donald Trump, resulting in his release. The pardon has been met with significant gratitude, with Trump being commended for fulfilling his promise. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42786962">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Ross Ulbricht, creator of the Silk Road marketplace, received a full pardon, sparking debate over the justice of his original sentence. Ulbricht&#39;s initial punishment was considered excessive by many, consisting of two life sentences plus 40 years for non-violent charges. The case underscores broader issues within the justice system and the implications of online black markets. </p>
<h2><a href="https://apnews.com/article/trump-ai-openai-oracle-softbank-son-altman-ellison-be261f8a8ee07a0623d4170397348c41">Stargate Project: SoftBank, OpenAI, Oracle, MGX to build data centers</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42785891">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The Stargate Project is a collaboration between SoftBank, OpenAI, Oracle, and MGX to build data centers, highlighting the role of private capital in large-scale tech projects. This initiative has sparked debates on economic centralization and the potential power concentration of major corporations in the tech industry. The project is perceived as a strategic investment in AI infrastructure, possibly aimed at countering China&#39;s advancements in AI and influencing global tech leadership. </p>
<h2><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42784365">Is anyone doing anything cool with tiny language models?</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42784365">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Small language models, ranging from 0.5 to 3 billion parameters, are being utilized for diverse applications such as filtering academic papers in Excel, identifying cookie notices, and generating Magic the Gathering cards. These models are also applied in summarizing meetings, parsing job listings, and creating playlists, demonstrating their versatility and effectiveness when fine-tuned for specific tasks. Despite their potential, challenges persist in terms of processing speed, the expertise required for fine-tuning, and distribution logistics. </p>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/Tencent/Hunyuan3D-2">Hunyuan3D 2.0 – High-Resolution 3D Assets Generation</a></h2>
<p>Hunyuan3D Studio has launched 3D generation capabilities on their website and released inference code and pretrained models for Hunyuan3D 2.0. Hunyuan3D 2.0 is an advanced system for creating high-resolution 3D assets, featuring a shape generation model (Hunyuan3D-DiT) and a texture synthesis model (Hunyuan3D-Paint), offering superior geometry details and texture quality. Users can access Hunyuan3D 2.0 through code or the Gradio App, with more information available on their official site and open-source plan. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42786040">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Hunyuan3D 2.0 is a tool designed for creating high-resolution 3D assets, with discussions focusing on its potential applications, particularly in photogrammetry. Users compare it with other software like RealityCapture and instant-ngp, noting both skepticism about AI-generated content&#39;s consistency and quality, and optimism about its marketing applications. While there are concerns about licensing and technical challenges, many acknowledge the promising advancements in AI for 3D modeling and content creation. </p>
<h2><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/mastercard-dns-error-went-unnoticed-for-years/">Mastercard DNS error went unnoticed for years</a></h2>
<p>MasterCard resolved a DNS (Domain Name System) error that could have led to traffic interception by registering an unused domain, which had been a vulnerability for nearly five years. Security researcher Philippe Caturegli identified the issue, involving a typo in a DNS server name, and registered the domain for $300 to prevent potential misuse, despite MasterCard&#39;s claim of no security risk. Caturegli&#39;s actions and public disclosure highlighted potential vulnerabilities and criticized MasterCard&#39;s response, revealing a history of similar DNS typos with the domain. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42793783">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>A DNS error at Mastercard remained undetected for years, sparking concerns about the company&#39;s security practices and oversight. Despite acknowledging the error, Mastercard asserted that their systems were not at risk, highlighting the difficulty in motivating large corporations to address security issues without public pressure. Criticism of Bugcrowd&#39;s role in managing the narrative suggests that some platforms may prioritize corporate interests over responsible disclosure, raising questions about corporate accountability and the effectiveness of security practices. </p>
<h2><a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/whatisthisthing/comments/1i5ztq4/comment/m8a7m8m/">What are these bumps on the top of a pull-tab can?</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42788455">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The bumps on a pull-tab can are engineered to focus pressure, aiding in the efficient opening of the seal. A Reddit discussion explored the complexity of everyday objects, including aluminum production and beverage can design, revealing the illusion of explanatory depth—where people underestimate the complexity of simple objects. The conversation also diverged into topics like Ethernet connectors, showcasing the diverse interests and knowledge-sharing among users. </p>
<h2><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/ericjgeller.com/post/3lgbpqmxeok2f">DHS removes all members of cyber security advisory boards, halts investigations</a></h2>
<p>The splash screen&#39;s minimal styles are defined, with additional styles located in a separate CSS file, ensuring a consistent and optimized user interface. The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) has ended all advisory committee memberships, impacting cybersecurity panels such as the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA). The Cyber Safety Review Board&#39;s investigation into the Salt Typhoon incident has been discontinued, indicating a halt in progress on this cybersecurity issue. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42790207">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) has disbanded all members of its cybersecurity advisory boards and paused ongoing investigations, impacting multiple advisory committees beyond just technology. This decision has ignited debates regarding the importance and function of these committees, with opinions divided between reducing bureaucracy and potentially diminishing oversight and safety. The long-term effects on cybersecurity and other sectors are currently unclear, leaving stakeholders uncertain about future developments. </p>
<h2><a href="https://v5.chriskrycho.com/journal/essence-of-successful-abstractions/">Isolating complexity is the essence of successful abstractions</a></h2>
<p>Complexity in software development should be managed and isolated rather than eliminated, as emphasized by Fred Hebert. In microservices, complexity is often hidden within individual services, while programming languages like Rust and TypeScript manage complexity through type systems and tools like Rust&#39;s borrow checker. Rust and TypeScript are favored by developers for their ability to reveal and manage complexity, allowing for successful abstractions by isolating complexity in well-defined areas. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42787531">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Isolating complexity is essential for creating effective abstractions in software engineering, as it determines where complexity is managed and how it impacts cognitive load. Rust&#39;s type system requires programmers to handle memory complexity, contrasting with garbage collection systems that manage it at runtime, illustrating different tradeoffs in complexity management. The decision to expose or hide complexity through abstractions is crucial, with types and tests serving different purposes; types can constrain code behavior but also introduce their own complexities. </p>
<h2><a href="https://allthatjazz.me/posts/doom-scrolling-struggles">My Struggle with Doom Scrolling</a></h2>
<p>The author addresses their doom scrolling habit by removing distracting apps like YouTube and Instagram and disabling the browser on their phone. They experienced some inconveniences, such as limited access to services, but found it beneficial for setting boundaries and reducing distractions. Reintroducing a restricted browser with a minimal user interface helped them regain control over media consumption, leading to more reading time and a calmer mindset. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42791428">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Many individuals find that apps designed to block distractions are not effective in combating doom scrolling, leading them to explore alternative methods. Strategies such as physically distancing oneself from the phone, using browser extensions that introduce friction, or opting for simpler devices can help break the habit. The focus is on creating intentional barriers, practicing moderation, and engaging in alternative activities to reduce mindless scrolling. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.jofreeman.com/joreen/tyranny.htm">The Tyranny of Structurelessness (1970)</a></h2>
<p>Jo Freeman, also known as Joreen, critiques the concept of &quot;structurelessness&quot; in the women&#39;s liberation movement, arguing that all groups form structures, whether formal or informal. The article highlights issues with informal structures, such as elitism and lack of accountability, and suggests principles for democratic structuring. Emphasizes the necessity of formal structures to prevent power imbalances and to help the movement achieve its goals effectively and inclusively. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42793483">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>&quot;The Tyranny of Structurelessness&quot; critiques unstructured groups, highlighting how they can lead to informal hierarchies and inefficiencies. Jo Freeman advocates for &quot;democratic structuring,&quot; where clear roles and processes prevent power imbalances, suggesting methods like rotating leadership and transparent information sharing. The essay emphasizes the importance of balancing structure and flexibility, particularly in startups and activist groups, to maintain effective organization and adapt to specific goals. </p>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Ross Ulbricht granted a full pardon" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Ross%20Ulbricht%20granted%20a%20full%20pardon&subheading=Wednesday%2C%20January%2022%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/22</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-22T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-21]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/21&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-21</h1>
<h2><a href="https://gist.github.com/hackermondev/45a3cdfa52246f1d1201c1e8cdef6117">0-click deanonymization attack targeting Signal, Discord, other platforms</a></h2>
<p>A 15-year-old high school student discovered a 0-click deanonymization attack using Cloudflare&#39;s caching system, which can locate users within a 250-mile radius. This vulnerability affects popular apps like Signal and Discord, enabling attackers to track users without their consent. Despite reporting the issue, only a related bug was patched by Cloudflare, leaving the core vulnerability unaddressed, highlighting the need for users, particularly journalists and activists, to be vigilant about their privacy. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42780816">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>A 0-click deanonymization attack exploits Cloudflare&#39;s caching system on platforms like Signal and Discord, potentially revealing a recipient&#39;s rough location by checking cache status. The attack does not require server control, only a unique URL, and can expose important metadata, raising privacy concerns for users of these secure communication platforms. Mitigation strategies include using Virtual Private Networks (VPNs) or disabling auto-downloads to protect user privacy. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.vincentschmalbach.com/startup-winter-hacker-news-lost-its-faith/">Startup Winter: Hacker News Lost Its Faith</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42778266">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Hacker News has transitioned from a startup-centric community to a broader tech forum, reflecting a change in user interests towards general tech topics. This shift has resulted in decreased enthusiasm for startups, with users expressing skepticism about the venture capital (VC) model and the scarcity of innovative ideas. The perceived financial benefits of working at startups are often questioned, as many employees do not experience substantial returns, indicating a shift in priorities within the tech community. </p>
<h2><a href="https://ssno.cc/posts/reversing-tac-1-4-2025/">Reverse engineering Call of Duty anti-cheat</a></h2>
<p>The Treyarch Anti-Cheat (TAC) in Black Ops Cold War is a user-mode anti-cheat system, lacking the kernel-mode component found in Modern Warfare&#39;s Ricochet. TAC employs Arxan for obfuscation, which complicates reverse engineering through techniques like runtime executable decryption, executable checksums, and pointer encryption. Key anti-cheat features include detection of API hooking, debug registers, network traffic monitoring, and external overlays, alongside various anti-debugging techniques and custom syscall stubs to bypass hooks. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42774221">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Users are experiencing anti-cheat issues in games like CS:GO and Call of Duty, particularly affecting Linux users with specific hardware. The discussion highlights challenges such as false bans, ethical concerns, and the effectiveness of current anti-cheat systems, impacting fair gameplay. Personal stories emphasize the need for improved solutions to address false accusations and enhance gaming experiences. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.jpost.com/international/article-838444">Did Elon Musk Appear to Sieg Heil at Trump Inauguration?</a></h2>
<p>Elon Musk was observed making a gesture at Trump&#39;s inauguration that some interpreted as a Nazi salute, leading to social media controversy. The Anti-Defamation League (ADL) suggested the gesture was likely an awkward moment rather than an intentional salute, with some attributing it to Musk&#39;s Asperger&#39;s syndrome. Musk responded to the controversy with a laughing emoji and expressed enthusiasm about Trump&#39;s mention of Mars, which aligns with his space exploration goals. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42772995">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Elon Musk was accused of making a Nazi salute at Trump&#39;s inauguration, leading to a debate on Hacker News about the appropriateness of discussing such topics on tech platforms. Some users argued that Musk&#39;s influence in the tech industry made the topic relevant, while others felt it was inappropriate for the forum. The discussion underscored differing opinions on censorship and the implications of Musk&#39;s actions within the tech community. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2025/jan/20/trump-elon-musk-salute">Elon Musk appears to make back-to-back fascist salutes at inauguration rally</a></h2>
<p>Elon Musk faced backlash for making a gesture resembling a fascist-style salute during Donald Trump&#39;s inauguration celebrations, which some interpreted as a Nazi salute. The Anti-Defamation League acknowledged the gesture&#39;s resemblance to a Nazi salute but later suggested it was an awkward moment of enthusiasm, drawing criticism from Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez. Musk&#39;s actions were celebrated by some far-right figures, fueling debates about his political affiliations and intentions. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42773778">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Elon Musk&#39;s gestures at an inauguration rally, perceived by some as fascist salutes, have ignited controversy and online debate. The incident led to a flagged discussion on Hacker News, sparking a debate about the platform&#39;s moderation and censorship policies. The situation raises questions about the role of influential tech figures in political discourse and the consistency of moderation policies on platforms like Hacker News. </p>
<h2><a href="https://mstdn.chrisalemany.ca/@chris/113864600222476627">Meta Censoring &#39;#Democrat&#39; on Instagram</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42777938">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Meta is reportedly censoring the hashtag &#39;#Democrat&#39; on Instagram, leading to discussions about censorship and its implications on social media platforms. Users from multiple countries, such as the UK, Spain, and Germany, have experienced this issue, although some report it has been resolved. The incident highlights concerns about the influence of social media platforms and the delicate balance between content moderation and censorship, with debates on free speech and potential political bias. </p>
<h2><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42779776">Organize local communities without Facebook?</a></h2>
<p>The individual is seeking to transition local community interactions from Facebook to a self-hosted, federated platform, which allows for decentralized control and management. They are looking for off-the-shelf solutions or collaborators to facilitate this move, indicating a need for accessible and customizable options. The context involves rural areas with multiple small towns, each with a population of around 50,000, highlighting the importance of connectivity and community engagement. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42779776">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The author seeks to transition local communities from Facebook to a self-hosted, federated platform, emphasizing the need for features like event calendars and messaging. Alternatives such as Mastodon may not fully replicate Facebook&#39;s functionality, prompting consideration of other platforms like Discourse, Nextdoor, or groups.io. It&#39;s crucial to evaluate community interest in moving and ensure the new platform aligns with their needs, with options like local newspapers and email lists also being considered. </p>
<h2><a href="https://bera-journals.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/bjet.13544">Metacognitive laziness: Effects of generative AI on learning motivation</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42780022">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>A study highlights that generative AI tools, such as ChatGPT, can lead to &quot;metacognitive laziness,&quot; where users depend too much on AI, reducing self-regulated learning. This reliance on AI may decrease deep learning and critical thinking skills, as learners might not engage actively in understanding and evaluating information. While AI can enhance task efficiency, the study emphasizes the importance of learners actively participating in the learning process to develop essential cognitive skills. </p>
<h2><a href="https://ollama.com/library/deepseek-r1">Official DeepSeek R1 Now on Ollama</a></h2>
<p>DeepSeek has introduced its first-generation reasoning models, which perform on par with OpenAI-o1 in tasks involving math, code, and reasoning. The models vary significantly in size, from 1.5 billion to 671 billion parameters, indicating diverse storage needs. These models are accessible under the MIT License, allowing for broad usage and modification. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42772983">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>DeepSeek R1, a new language model, is now available on Ollama, sparking discussions about its censorship, especially on sensitive political topics like Tiananmen Square. The debate centers on the balance between political correctness and historical accuracy, with comparisons drawn between Western and Chinese approaches to political bias in language models. Open-source models are suggested as a potential solution to counteract censorship, though opinions differ on the effectiveness and implications of such measures. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.science.org/content/article/people-are-bad-reporting-what-they-eat-s-problem-dietary-research">People are bad at reporting what they eat. That&#39;s a problem for dietary research</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42779147">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Accurately reporting food intake is challenging, with people often misjudging portion sizes by an average of 53%, even among trained professionals. Hidden ingredients like oils and fats are less problematic than portion size errors, highlighting the need for precise measurement tools like food scales. New technologies and apps, such as SnapCalorie, aim to improve diet tracking accuracy, though they often require subscriptions due to high operational costs, potentially aiding users in making more mindful dietary choices. </p>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/ROCm/ROCm/discussions/4276">ROCm Device Support Wishlist</a></h2>
<p>ROCm is gathering community feedback to determine which GPUs to support in future updates, with current compatibility details available on their website. Users are advocating for broader support, particularly for older and consumer-grade GPUs, and improved integration with Windows systems. There is a strong demand for consistent support across all architectures, emphasizing the significance of VRAM for AI applications, and calls for enhancements in AMD&#39;s APU support and a development process similar to NVIDIA&#39;s CUDA. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42772170">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>ROCm, AMD&#39;s software platform for GPU programming, faces criticism for its hardware-specific code compilation, resulting in inconsistent GPU support compared to Nvidia&#39;s CUDA. Users are frustrated with AMD&#39;s lack of long-term support for GPUs, with some experiencing dropped support soon after purchase, leading to calls for improved cross-platform support and better documentation. The community urges AMD to support all GPUs, akin to Nvidia, and some users have shifted their hopes to Intel for better competition in the GPU market. </p>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/astral-sh/ruff">Ruff: Python linter and code formatter written in Rust</a></h2>
<p>Ruff DocsPlayground is a Python linter and code formatter written in Rust, offering speeds 10-100 times faster than traditional tools like Flake8 and Black. It supports Python 3.13, integrates with editors such as VS Code, and can replace multiple tools like Flake8, Black, and isort, while being monorepo-friendly. Ruff is widely adopted in major projects like Apache Airflow, FastAPI, and Pandas, and is available for installation via pip, pipx, and other package managers, with configuration support through pyproject.toml. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42775029">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Ruff is a Python linter and code formatter developed in Rust, noted for its speed and efficiency, which simplifies Python development by integrating multiple tools into one. The tool has sparked interest and debate within the Python community, with some developers appreciating its performance and simplicity, while others remain skeptical of new tools. Ruff&#39;s development by Astral, a venture capital-backed organization, adds to its intrigue and discussion, particularly regarding its impact on Python&#39;s dynamic typing and the use of type checkers and linters in large projects. </p>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/MoonshotAI/Kimi-k1.5">Kimi K1.5: Scaling Reinforcement Learning with LLMs</a></h2>
<p>Kimi k1.5 is a cutting-edge multi-modal model that significantly outperforms GPT-4o and Claude Sonnet 3.5 in short-chain-of-thought (CoT) tasks, with improvements up to 550% on benchmarks such as AIME, MATH-500, and LiveCodeBench. It matches OpenAI&#39;s o1 in long-CoT performance across various modalities, utilizing reinforcement learning with long context scaling and enhanced policy optimization, while avoiding complex methods like Monte Carlo tree search. Kimi k1.5 is trained on both text and vision data, allowing for joint reasoning, and will soon be accessible via the Kimi OpenPlatform at <a href="https://kimi.ai">https://kimi.ai</a>. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42777857">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Companies, including some from China, are using GitHub to promote products by posting &quot;research papers&quot; and code samples without delivering actual Software Development Kits (SDKs) or libraries. This practice is considered misleading, similar to false advertising, as promised APIs (Application Programming Interfaces) or model weights often do not materialize. The trend of using GitHub repositories as promotional tools, sometimes lacking source code, raises concerns about transparency and authenticity in AI research and development. </p>
<h2><a href="https://torrentfreak.com/authors-seek-metas-torrent-client-logs-and-seeding-data-in-ai-piracy-probe-250120/">Authors seek Meta&#39;s torrent client logs and seeding data in AI piracy probe</a></h2>
<p>Meta is facing a lawsuit for allegedly using pirated materials, specifically copyrighted books from LibGen, to train its AI models via BitTorrent. Authors, including Richard Kadrey and Sarah Silverman, accuse Meta of copyright infringement, while Meta claims its actions fall under fair use. The court has permitted new allegations about Meta&#39;s torrenting activities, with authors seeking access to Meta&#39;s torrent client logs and seeding data, underscoring the legal challenges surrounding AI training data and copyright issues. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42772771">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Authors are examining Meta&#39;s potential use of pirated content for AI training, utilizing torrent client logs and seeding data as evidence. There is a debate on whether large-scale AI training depends on pirated content due to the challenges of legally obtaining large text datasets, versus the possibility of negotiating legal access with publishers. The legal implications, including fair use and copyright infringement, are under discussion, highlighting the conflict between tech companies&#39; data requirements and existing copyright laws. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e2bbb-6Clhs">Elon Gives Nazi Salute During Inauguration Speech</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42774621">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Elon Musk is at the center of controversy after allegedly giving a Nazi salute during an inauguration speech, leading to debates about his intentions and political affiliations. The incident has sparked discussions about Musk&#39;s associations and the tech community&#39;s response, highlighting the political dynamics within the tech industry. Critics are divided on whether the gesture was a misguided act or a deliberate move, with some referencing Musk&#39;s past actions and affiliations as potential evidence of his intentions. </p>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="0-click deanonymization attack targeting Signal, Discord, other platforms" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=0-click%20deanonymization%20attack%20targeting%20Signal%2C%20Discord%2C%20other%20platforms&subheading=Tuesday%2C%20January%2021%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/21</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-21T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-20]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/20&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-20</h1>
<h2><a href="https://www.vintagecomputing.com/index.php/archives/3292/the-pc-is-dead-its-time-to-make-computing-personal-again">It&#39;s time to make computing personal again</a></h2>
<p>The article highlights the decline of personal computing freedom due to surveillance capitalism and Digital Rights Management (DRM), which have transferred control from users to corporations. It contrasts the past era of personal computing, which offered more user freedom, with today&#39;s tech environment dominated by business models that erode privacy. The author advocates for reclaiming digital autonomy through supporting open-source projects, pushing for privacy legislation, and reforming DRM laws to restore personal computing values. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42763095">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The article emphasizes the need to return to personal computing, expressing dissatisfaction with corporate influence in the tech industry. It highlights the challenge of community computing, where network effects lock users into specific software ecosystems, such as iOS and Android. Alternatives like Linux and open-source software are discussed, focusing on user control and the difficulties of achieving it in a corporate-dominated environment. </p>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/deepseek-ai/DeepSeek-R1">DeepSeek-R1</a></h2>
<p>DeepSeek-R1 and DeepSeek-R1-Zero are first-generation reasoning models, with DeepSeek-R1 addressing issues like repetition and language mixing seen in DeepSeek-R1-Zero. The models, including six distilled versions, are open-sourced, with DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Qwen-32B achieving state-of-the-art results in reasoning, code, and math tasks. These models are available for download on HuggingFace, and users can interact with them via a chat website or an OpenAI-Compatible API, with instructions for local deployment provided. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42768072">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>DeepSeek-R1 is an advanced reasoning model that improves upon issues like repetition and language mixing by using cold-start data before reinforcement learning. It outperforms the QwQ model in experiments, providing a better user experience and more diverse answer strategies, and is open-sourced under the MIT license for broad evaluation. The model introduces a pipeline for teaching existing models reasoning and alignment with human preferences, with fine-tuned Llama and Qwen models also open-sourced, potentially rivaling OpenAI&#39;s offerings, though data usage and censorship concerns persist. </p>
<h2><a href="https://josef.cn/blog/uk-talent">UK&#39;s hardware talent is being wasted</a></h2>
<p>The UK is experiencing a talent drain as top engineering graduates from prestigious universities face lower salaries compared to Silicon Valley, prompting many to switch to higher-paying fields like consulting or finance. This talent misallocation hinders innovation and economic growth, with issues such as geographical constraints, lack of venture capital for hardware, and stagnant traditional engineering firms contributing to the problem. The UK risks losing its best talent to overseas markets, missing the chance to create tech giants, and must act now to leverage its research institutions and engineering talent for a hardware revolution. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42763386">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>UK hardware talent is underutilized as many engineers transition to software or finance due to the higher barriers and costs associated with hardware startups. This challenge is not exclusive to the UK; globally, hardware startups face slow iteration cycles and high costs, making them less attractive to investors compared to software. UK planning laws and economic policies further impede hardware growth, causing talent to shift to other sectors or countries, while the tech industry often overlooks hardware innovation potential. </p>
<h2><a href="https://wiki.rossmanngroup.com/wiki/Reverse_Engineering_Bambu_Connect">Reverse Engineering Bambu Connect</a></h2>
<p>The guide discusses extracting a private key from the Bambu Connect app, an Electron application with known security vulnerabilities. Users are cautioned that the guide may be incomplete or outdated and should be followed at their own risk. The process involves using tools like Ghidra and asarfix to locate and decrypt the obfuscated private key and certificates, with a Python script provided for extraction. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42764602">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Bambu Lab is under criticism for implementing restrictions on their 3D printers, mandating the use of their software and Digital Rights Management (DRM) system. Users are concerned that these changes, justified by Bambu as security measures, might lead to subscription models or additional limitations, reducing the printers&#39; openness and hackability. In response, Bambu Lab introduced a &quot;Developer Mode&quot; for advanced users, providing more control over network security, but apprehensions about vendor lock-in and effects on third-party integrations persist. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/cu2E8wgmbdZbqeWqb/meemi-s-shortform">FrontierMath was funded by OpenAI</a></h2>
<p>The post highlights a lack of transparency in the collaboration between OpenAI and FrontierMath, with funding details only disclosed after a delay, causing confusion among contributors. Concerns are raised about OpenAI&#39;s potential access to and use of the dataset for training, despite verbal agreements suggesting otherwise, emphasizing the need for written agreements. The discussion underscores the importance of transparency and trust in collaborations, especially those involving AI capabilities, with commitments to improve transparency in future projects. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42763231">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>FrontierMath, funded by OpenAI, faces scrutiny over potential data contamination in its benchmarks, raising concerns about the integrity of their results. Critics emphasize the importance of transparency and proper separation of training and test data to prevent benchmarks from being manipulated. This situation underscores the necessity for independent and transparent evaluations in AI to maintain credibility. </p>
<h2><a href="https://blog.gitbutler.com/why-is-git-autocorrect-too-fast-for-formula-one-drivers/">Why is Git Autocorrect too fast for Formula One drivers?</a></h2>
<p>Git&#39;s autocorrect feature executes a mistyped command after a default delay of 0.1 seconds, which is often too quick for users to cancel. Introduced in 2008, the feature uses a modified Levenshtein distance algorithm to guess the intended command, but defaults to not running any command if mistyped. A proposed patch suggests interpreting a setting of &quot;1&quot; as &quot;immediately&quot; to enhance usability, allowing users to configure the delay or prompt for confirmation. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42760620">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Git&#39;s autocorrect feature has a default delay of 100 milliseconds, which is often too quick for users to cancel a mistyped command. Originally intended to interpret a boolean value, the feature now accepts a time delay in deciseconds, causing some confusion among users. This situation underscores the need for clear configuration settings and the difficulties in updating software features without disrupting existing functionality. </p>
<h2><a href="http://okayfail.com/2025/i-met-pg-once.html">I Met Paul Graham Once</a></h2>
<p>The author attended Y Combinator in 2015, where they met Paul Graham and received advice on their startup, Appcanary, which was later acquired by GitHub. The author, now a transgender woman, expresses concern over Paul Graham&#39;s recent essay on &quot;Wokeness,&quot; feeling it reflects a rejection of inclusivity in the tech industry. The author is worried about increasing intolerance and potential discrimination in the tech industry but remains committed to living with respect and kindness. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42767507">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The discussion centers on Paul Graham&#39;s influence and the perceived shift in values within the tech industry, highlighting disillusionment with tech leaders once seen as visionaries. It addresses the complexities of identity politics, the impact of &quot;wokeness,&quot; and challenges faced by marginalized groups in the tech sector. The text critiques the performative aspects of social justice efforts and the difficulty of balancing personal identity with professional roles, reflecting a broader cultural debate on progress and privilege. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.johnwalker.nl/posts/escape-the-walled-garden-with-rss">Escape the walled garden and algorithm black boxes with RSS feeds</a></h2>
<p>RSS (Really Simple Syndication) and Atom provide decentralized alternatives to centralized social media, allowing users to control their content consumption. Feed readers such as Miniflux, NetNewsWire, and Newsboat enable subscriptions to diverse content sources, including YouTube channels, podcasts, and blogs. Tools like PolitePol can create feeds for websites lacking them, promoting user autonomy in media consumption. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42761219">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>RSS feeds provide a way to escape algorithm-driven content by allowing users to subscribe to specific topics through &quot;planets,&quot; which aggregate related blogs. While RSS readers like Feedly and Feedbin help manage these feeds, some users find them complex, leading to alternatives like Feedmail that deliver content directly to inboxes. Despite its niche appeal, RSS remains popular among tech enthusiasts for its customizable and user-controlled content experience, with platforms like Mastodon and Bluesky supporting RSS feeds. </p>
<h2><a href="https://iamvishnu.com/posts/please-dont-force-dark-mode">Please don&#39;t force dark mode</a></h2>
<p>Website designers are advised not to enforce dark mode on users, as it can cause eye strain, especially with high contrast settings like white text on a black background. The Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) currently suggest a minimum contrast ratio but do not address maximum contrast, which may lead to discomfort; this might be addressed in the upcoming WCAG 3.0. Dark mode is beneficial in specific scenarios, such as reading on OLED screens in dark environments or coding with Integrated Development Environments (IDEs) that offer comfortable contrast settings. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42762054">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The ongoing debate between dark mode and light mode centers around user comfort, with some finding dark mode straining and others considering light mode too harsh. There is a general agreement that websites should provide both dark and light mode options, respecting individual user preferences. This discussion underscores the significance of customizable settings to cater to diverse user needs and environments. </p>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="It's time to make computing personal again" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=It's%20time%20to%20make%20computing%20personal%20again&subheading=Monday%2C%20January%2020%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/20</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-20T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-19]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/19&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-19</h1>
<h2><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2025/01/18/tiktok-goes-dark-in-the-u-s/">TikTok goes dark in the US</a></h2>
<p>TikTok experienced a temporary shutdown in the U.S. due to a federal ban, but service began to be restored by midday Sunday. The ban was driven by concerns over potential Chinese surveillance, with bipartisan support for requiring ByteDance, TikTok&#39;s owner, to sell the app. President-elect Donald Trump suggested delaying the ban and proposed a joint venture with U.S. ownership as a potential solution, while alternative apps gained popularity during the ban. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42753396">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>TikTok&#39;s ban in the US has ignited discussions on data privacy and geopolitical influence, with concerns centered around its Chinese ownership. The ban is seen by some as a national security measure, while others perceive it as a limitation on free speech and a potential advantage for American tech companies. This situation has prompted debates on balancing security with freedom and the impact of foreign entities on domestic media. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.kalmanfilter.net/default.aspx">Kalman Filter Tutorial</a></h2>
<p>KalmanFilter.NET provides a tutorial on the Kalman Filter, a mathematical tool for estimating and predicting system states in uncertain conditions, commonly used in tracking and navigation. The tutorial, initiated in 2017, includes numerical examples and intuitive explanations, covering both univariate and multivariate Kalman Filters, and has expanded to advanced topics like non-linear Kalman Filters. A book based on the tutorial offers a comprehensive guide from basics to advanced topics, with illustrative examples and practical applications, making the Kalman Filter accessible and understandable, with some parts available for free. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42751690">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>To grasp the Kalman Filter, it&#39;s beneficial to first study Least Squares, recursive Least Squares, and the Information Filter, as the Kalman Filter is an efficient reformulation of recursive Least Squares. The Kalman Filter is a powerful tool for state estimation in systems with noise and dynamic changes, and it can be understood from both procedural and Bayesian perspectives. While mathematical rigor is crucial for a deep understanding, those without a strong math background can still explore the concepts through intuitive means, supported by various resources like PDFs and online tutorials. </p>
<h2><a href="https://forgejo.org/">Forgejo: A self-hosted lightweight software forge</a></h2>
<p>Forgejo is a self-hosted software forge that emphasizes security, scalability, federation, and privacy, developed by the community under Codeberg e.V. It serves as a Free Software alternative to GitHub, offering an easy installation process and low maintenance for efficient project management. Forgejo is designed to be resource-efficient, fostering collaboration and productivity, and supports innovation in decentralized software development. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42753523">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Forgejo is a self-hosted, lightweight software forge, serving as an alternative to GitHub, and is managed by a non-profit organization without premium upsells. It originated as a fork of Gitea, following Gitea&#39;s shift towards commercialization, and emphasizes being freely licensed and community-driven. Forgejo is noted for its low resource usage, ease of updates, and development of federation features, making it ideal for personal or small-scale hosting. </p>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="TikTok goes dark in the US" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=TikTok%20goes%20dark%20in%20the%20US&subheading=Sunday%2C%20January%2019%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/19</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-19T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
