<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0"
>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 19:11:08 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/newsletter/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <copyright><![CDATA[2023 Sunghyun Cho]]></copyright>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-20]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/20&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-20</h1>
<h2><a href="https://www.vintagecomputing.com/index.php/archives/3292/the-pc-is-dead-its-time-to-make-computing-personal-again">It&#39;s time to make computing personal again</a></h2>
<p>The article highlights the decline of personal computing freedom due to surveillance capitalism and Digital Rights Management (DRM), which have transferred control from users to corporations. It contrasts the past era of personal computing, which offered more user freedom, with today&#39;s tech environment dominated by business models that erode privacy. The author advocates for reclaiming digital autonomy through supporting open-source projects, pushing for privacy legislation, and reforming DRM laws to restore personal computing values. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42763095">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The article emphasizes the need to return to personal computing, expressing dissatisfaction with corporate influence in the tech industry. It highlights the challenge of community computing, where network effects lock users into specific software ecosystems, such as iOS and Android. Alternatives like Linux and open-source software are discussed, focusing on user control and the difficulties of achieving it in a corporate-dominated environment. </p>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/deepseek-ai/DeepSeek-R1">DeepSeek-R1</a></h2>
<p>DeepSeek-R1 and DeepSeek-R1-Zero are first-generation reasoning models, with DeepSeek-R1 addressing issues like repetition and language mixing seen in DeepSeek-R1-Zero. The models, including six distilled versions, are open-sourced, with DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Qwen-32B achieving state-of-the-art results in reasoning, code, and math tasks. These models are available for download on HuggingFace, and users can interact with them via a chat website or an OpenAI-Compatible API, with instructions for local deployment provided. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42768072">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>DeepSeek-R1 is an advanced reasoning model that improves upon issues like repetition and language mixing by using cold-start data before reinforcement learning. It outperforms the QwQ model in experiments, providing a better user experience and more diverse answer strategies, and is open-sourced under the MIT license for broad evaluation. The model introduces a pipeline for teaching existing models reasoning and alignment with human preferences, with fine-tuned Llama and Qwen models also open-sourced, potentially rivaling OpenAI&#39;s offerings, though data usage and censorship concerns persist. </p>
<h2><a href="https://josef.cn/blog/uk-talent">UK&#39;s hardware talent is being wasted</a></h2>
<p>The UK is experiencing a talent drain as top engineering graduates from prestigious universities face lower salaries compared to Silicon Valley, prompting many to switch to higher-paying fields like consulting or finance. This talent misallocation hinders innovation and economic growth, with issues such as geographical constraints, lack of venture capital for hardware, and stagnant traditional engineering firms contributing to the problem. The UK risks losing its best talent to overseas markets, missing the chance to create tech giants, and must act now to leverage its research institutions and engineering talent for a hardware revolution. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42763386">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>UK hardware talent is underutilized as many engineers transition to software or finance due to the higher barriers and costs associated with hardware startups. This challenge is not exclusive to the UK; globally, hardware startups face slow iteration cycles and high costs, making them less attractive to investors compared to software. UK planning laws and economic policies further impede hardware growth, causing talent to shift to other sectors or countries, while the tech industry often overlooks hardware innovation potential. </p>
<h2><a href="https://wiki.rossmanngroup.com/wiki/Reverse_Engineering_Bambu_Connect">Reverse Engineering Bambu Connect</a></h2>
<p>The guide discusses extracting a private key from the Bambu Connect app, an Electron application with known security vulnerabilities. Users are cautioned that the guide may be incomplete or outdated and should be followed at their own risk. The process involves using tools like Ghidra and asarfix to locate and decrypt the obfuscated private key and certificates, with a Python script provided for extraction. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42764602">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Bambu Lab is under criticism for implementing restrictions on their 3D printers, mandating the use of their software and Digital Rights Management (DRM) system. Users are concerned that these changes, justified by Bambu as security measures, might lead to subscription models or additional limitations, reducing the printers&#39; openness and hackability. In response, Bambu Lab introduced a &quot;Developer Mode&quot; for advanced users, providing more control over network security, but apprehensions about vendor lock-in and effects on third-party integrations persist. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/cu2E8wgmbdZbqeWqb/meemi-s-shortform">FrontierMath was funded by OpenAI</a></h2>
<p>The post highlights a lack of transparency in the collaboration between OpenAI and FrontierMath, with funding details only disclosed after a delay, causing confusion among contributors. Concerns are raised about OpenAI&#39;s potential access to and use of the dataset for training, despite verbal agreements suggesting otherwise, emphasizing the need for written agreements. The discussion underscores the importance of transparency and trust in collaborations, especially those involving AI capabilities, with commitments to improve transparency in future projects. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42763231">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>FrontierMath, funded by OpenAI, faces scrutiny over potential data contamination in its benchmarks, raising concerns about the integrity of their results. Critics emphasize the importance of transparency and proper separation of training and test data to prevent benchmarks from being manipulated. This situation underscores the necessity for independent and transparent evaluations in AI to maintain credibility. </p>
<h2><a href="https://blog.gitbutler.com/why-is-git-autocorrect-too-fast-for-formula-one-drivers/">Why is Git Autocorrect too fast for Formula One drivers?</a></h2>
<p>Git&#39;s autocorrect feature executes a mistyped command after a default delay of 0.1 seconds, which is often too quick for users to cancel. Introduced in 2008, the feature uses a modified Levenshtein distance algorithm to guess the intended command, but defaults to not running any command if mistyped. A proposed patch suggests interpreting a setting of &quot;1&quot; as &quot;immediately&quot; to enhance usability, allowing users to configure the delay or prompt for confirmation. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42760620">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Git&#39;s autocorrect feature has a default delay of 100 milliseconds, which is often too quick for users to cancel a mistyped command. Originally intended to interpret a boolean value, the feature now accepts a time delay in deciseconds, causing some confusion among users. This situation underscores the need for clear configuration settings and the difficulties in updating software features without disrupting existing functionality. </p>
<h2><a href="http://okayfail.com/2025/i-met-pg-once.html">I Met Paul Graham Once</a></h2>
<p>The author attended Y Combinator in 2015, where they met Paul Graham and received advice on their startup, Appcanary, which was later acquired by GitHub. The author, now a transgender woman, expresses concern over Paul Graham&#39;s recent essay on &quot;Wokeness,&quot; feeling it reflects a rejection of inclusivity in the tech industry. The author is worried about increasing intolerance and potential discrimination in the tech industry but remains committed to living with respect and kindness. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42767507">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The discussion centers on Paul Graham&#39;s influence and the perceived shift in values within the tech industry, highlighting disillusionment with tech leaders once seen as visionaries. It addresses the complexities of identity politics, the impact of &quot;wokeness,&quot; and challenges faced by marginalized groups in the tech sector. The text critiques the performative aspects of social justice efforts and the difficulty of balancing personal identity with professional roles, reflecting a broader cultural debate on progress and privilege. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.johnwalker.nl/posts/escape-the-walled-garden-with-rss">Escape the walled garden and algorithm black boxes with RSS feeds</a></h2>
<p>RSS (Really Simple Syndication) and Atom provide decentralized alternatives to centralized social media, allowing users to control their content consumption. Feed readers such as Miniflux, NetNewsWire, and Newsboat enable subscriptions to diverse content sources, including YouTube channels, podcasts, and blogs. Tools like PolitePol can create feeds for websites lacking them, promoting user autonomy in media consumption. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42761219">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>RSS feeds provide a way to escape algorithm-driven content by allowing users to subscribe to specific topics through &quot;planets,&quot; which aggregate related blogs. While RSS readers like Feedly and Feedbin help manage these feeds, some users find them complex, leading to alternatives like Feedmail that deliver content directly to inboxes. Despite its niche appeal, RSS remains popular among tech enthusiasts for its customizable and user-controlled content experience, with platforms like Mastodon and Bluesky supporting RSS feeds. </p>
<h2><a href="https://iamvishnu.com/posts/please-dont-force-dark-mode">Please don&#39;t force dark mode</a></h2>
<p>Website designers are advised not to enforce dark mode on users, as it can cause eye strain, especially with high contrast settings like white text on a black background. The Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) currently suggest a minimum contrast ratio but do not address maximum contrast, which may lead to discomfort; this might be addressed in the upcoming WCAG 3.0. Dark mode is beneficial in specific scenarios, such as reading on OLED screens in dark environments or coding with Integrated Development Environments (IDEs) that offer comfortable contrast settings. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42762054">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The ongoing debate between dark mode and light mode centers around user comfort, with some finding dark mode straining and others considering light mode too harsh. There is a general agreement that websites should provide both dark and light mode options, respecting individual user preferences. This discussion underscores the significance of customizable settings to cater to diverse user needs and environments. </p>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="It's time to make computing personal again" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=It's%20time%20to%20make%20computing%20personal%20again&subheading=Monday%2C%20January%2020%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/20</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-20T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-19]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/19&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-19</h1>
<h2><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2025/01/18/tiktok-goes-dark-in-the-u-s/">TikTok goes dark in the US</a></h2>
<p>TikTok experienced a temporary shutdown in the U.S. due to a federal ban, but service began to be restored by midday Sunday. The ban was driven by concerns over potential Chinese surveillance, with bipartisan support for requiring ByteDance, TikTok&#39;s owner, to sell the app. President-elect Donald Trump suggested delaying the ban and proposed a joint venture with U.S. ownership as a potential solution, while alternative apps gained popularity during the ban. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42753396">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>TikTok&#39;s ban in the US has ignited discussions on data privacy and geopolitical influence, with concerns centered around its Chinese ownership. The ban is seen by some as a national security measure, while others perceive it as a limitation on free speech and a potential advantage for American tech companies. This situation has prompted debates on balancing security with freedom and the impact of foreign entities on domestic media. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.kalmanfilter.net/default.aspx">Kalman Filter Tutorial</a></h2>
<p>KalmanFilter.NET provides a tutorial on the Kalman Filter, a mathematical tool for estimating and predicting system states in uncertain conditions, commonly used in tracking and navigation. The tutorial, initiated in 2017, includes numerical examples and intuitive explanations, covering both univariate and multivariate Kalman Filters, and has expanded to advanced topics like non-linear Kalman Filters. A book based on the tutorial offers a comprehensive guide from basics to advanced topics, with illustrative examples and practical applications, making the Kalman Filter accessible and understandable, with some parts available for free. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42751690">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>To grasp the Kalman Filter, it&#39;s beneficial to first study Least Squares, recursive Least Squares, and the Information Filter, as the Kalman Filter is an efficient reformulation of recursive Least Squares. The Kalman Filter is a powerful tool for state estimation in systems with noise and dynamic changes, and it can be understood from both procedural and Bayesian perspectives. While mathematical rigor is crucial for a deep understanding, those without a strong math background can still explore the concepts through intuitive means, supported by various resources like PDFs and online tutorials. </p>
<h2><a href="https://forgejo.org/">Forgejo: A self-hosted lightweight software forge</a></h2>
<p>Forgejo is a self-hosted software forge that emphasizes security, scalability, federation, and privacy, developed by the community under Codeberg e.V. It serves as a Free Software alternative to GitHub, offering an easy installation process and low maintenance for efficient project management. Forgejo is designed to be resource-efficient, fostering collaboration and productivity, and supports innovation in decentralized software development. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42753523">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Forgejo is a self-hosted, lightweight software forge, serving as an alternative to GitHub, and is managed by a non-profit organization without premium upsells. It originated as a fork of Gitea, following Gitea&#39;s shift towards commercialization, and emphasizes being freely licensed and community-driven. Forgejo is noted for its low resource usage, ease of updates, and development of federation features, making it ideal for personal or small-scale hosting. </p>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="TikTok goes dark in the US" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=TikTok%20goes%20dark%20in%20the%20US&subheading=Sunday%2C%20January%2019%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/19</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-19T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-18]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/18&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-18</h1>
<h2><a href="https://blog.railway.com/p/data-center-build-part-one">So you want to build your own data center</a></h2>
<p>Railway transitioned from Google Cloud Platform to their own data centers due to issues with pricing, service limitations, and support, launching the Railway Metal project. - After nine months, they successfully went live with their first data center in California and are planning further regional expansions, focusing on efficient infrastructure management. - They developed tools such as Railyard and MetalCP to streamline operations and are currently hiring for Infrastructure Engineering roles. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42743019">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The text explores the challenges and benefits of using major cloud services like AWS, Google Cloud, and Microsoft Azure, particularly focusing on customer support and service quality. - It shares experiences related to data center operations, highlighting issues such as hardware and cooling, and stresses the importance of owning infrastructure for enhanced control and cost efficiency. - The discussion also delves into the complexities of building and managing data centers, including aspects like power, networking, and hardware management, offering insights into the pros and cons of cloud services versus physical infrastructure ownership. </p>
<h2><a href="https://lcamtuf.substack.com/p/investigating-an-evil-rj45-dongle">Investigating an “evil” RJ45 dongle</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42743033">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>An article on lcamtuf.substack.com examines an RJ45 dongle initially suspected of being malicious due to counterfeit FTDI chips, but it was found to be a result of outdated engineering practices. - The article emphasizes the challenges in verifying claims of malicious intent and how sensational stories can spread rapidly, highlighting the need for skepticism. - It also discusses broader issues such as xenophobia and provides insights into USB-to-Ethernet adapters, their performance, and potential misuse. </p>
<h2><a href="https://reedybear.bearblog.dev/ive-been-advocating-for-rss-support-and-you-should-too/">I&#39;ve been advocating for RSS support, and you should too</a></h2>
<p>The post advocates for the use of RSS (Really Simple Syndication) feeds, which allow users to receive updates from various platforms without ads or algorithms. - The author highlights successful requests for RSS support from platforms like GovTrack.us and encourages others to request RSS from organizations they are interested in. - Many platforms, such as NPR, YouTube, Substack, and Blogger, already support RSS, making it a valuable tool for staying informed. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42746222">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>RSS feeds provide a way to stay updated on content from favorite creators without the interference of ads or algorithms, offering a more streamlined and personalized experience. Although platforms like YouTube offer RSS feeds, they are often not prominently featured, leading to concerns about their potential discontinuation if they become too popular. Advocating for increased RSS support can help ensure its continued availability and encourage more organizations to adopt and maintain this valuable tool for content management. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.nutraingredients-asia.com/Article/2025/01/07/higher-potassium-intake-at-dinner-linked-to-fewer-sleep-disturbances/">Higher potassium intake at dinner linked to fewer sleep disturbances – study</a></h2>
<p>A Japanese study using data from the Asken food-logging app investigated the relationship between potassium and sodium intake and insomnia in 4,568 adults. - Findings indicated that higher potassium intake, particularly at dinner, was associated with fewer sleep disturbances, as measured by the Athens Insomnia Scale (AIS). - While sodium intake has been previously linked to sleep issues, this study found no significant association with AIS scores, highlighting the need for further research on dietary impacts on sleep. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42742161">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>A study suggests that higher potassium intake at dinner is associated with fewer sleep disturbances, potentially due to its ability to neutralize stomach acid reflux. - The findings are debated, with some arguing that more stomach acidity is necessary to prevent reflux, indicating the need for further research. - While potassium may improve sleep, excessive intake can pose heart risks, particularly for individuals on specific medications; magnesium supplements are also mentioned for enhancing sleep quality. </p>
<h2><a href="https://andymasley.substack.com/p/individual-ai-use-is-not-bad-for">Using ChatGPT is not bad for the environment</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42745847">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The article contends that the environmental impact of using ChatGPT, a large language model (LLM), is relatively minor compared to larger issues such as transportation and industrial emissions. - It emphasizes the need to weigh both the emissions and benefits of activities, suggesting that personal use of ChatGPT is not a significant environmental concern. - The broader debate continues on AI and data center energy use, with some advocating for increased efficiency and sustainability in technology. </p>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="So you want to build your own data center" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=So%20you%20want%20to%20build%20your%20own%20data%20center&subheading=Saturday%2C%20January%2018%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/18</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-18T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-17]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/17&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-17</h1>
<h2><a href="https://romanzipp.com/blog/no-you-cant-use-your-6299-canon-camera-as-a-webcam">Canon wants us to pay for using our own camera as a webcam</a></h2>
<p>The author expresses frustration with Canon&#39;s software for using the Canon G5 X II camera as a webcam on macOS, highlighting issues with compatibility and server errors. - By macOS 15, the software issues were resolved, but many features required a subscription, raising concerns about additional charges for using owned hardware. - The post critiques the trend of hardware companies charging for software features, questioning the fairness of such practices. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42735393">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Canon&#39;s decision to charge users for using their cameras as webcams has caused frustration among consumers, drawing parallels to other instances where companies impose fees for certain functionalities. This situation is similar to the 30-minute video recording limit on cameras due to EU tariffs, where users often resort to third-party firmware or additional hardware to bypass such restrictions. The issue underscores a broader trend in consumer electronics, where companies may restrict features for financial or regulatory reasons, despite the technical feasibility of offering them without additional cost. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.spacex.com/launches/mission/?missionId=starship-flight-7?submit">Starship Flight 7</a></h2>
<p>SpaceX&#39;s Dragon spacecraft successfully completes a series of maneuvers to dock with the International Space Station (ISS), showcasing its advanced capabilities in space operations. The docking process involves multiple stages, including liftoff by Falcon 9, orbit activation, and a series of burns to align and approach the ISS. This event highlights SpaceX&#39;s continued role in supporting ISS missions and advancing commercial spaceflight technology. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42731091">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Starship Flight 7 broke up over the Caribbean due to a suspected oxygen/fuel leak causing pressure buildup, leading to failure. - The incident has reignited discussions on rocket safety and the inherent challenges of space travel, drawing comparisons to past NASA missions. - SpaceX remains committed to its iterative development approach, viewing failures as steps toward eventual success, and plans to proceed with the next launch soon. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2025/01/17/supreme-court-rules-to-uphold-tiktok-ban.html">Supreme Court rules to uphold TikTok ban, setting stage for shutdown</a></h2>
<p>The Supreme Court has upheld a law mandating ByteDance to divest TikTok by a specified deadline, or the app will face a ban in the U.S. There is uncertainty regarding whether service providers like Apple and Google will continue to support TikTok if the divestment does not occur. The future of TikTok in the U.S. remains uncertain, with users exploring alternative platforms and the Chinese government considering strategies to maintain its operations. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42738464">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The Supreme Court has upheld a ban on TikTok, which could lead to its shutdown in the U.S., raising questions about the future of global social networks without American content. The ruling is based on national security concerns related to TikTok&#39;s foreign ownership, rather than First Amendment issues, potentially impacting TikTok&#39;s financial viability due to the loss of American ad revenue. This situation underscores broader concerns about data privacy and the influence of foreign-owned technology companies. </p>
<h2><a href="https://charleshughsmith.substack.com/p/is-the-world-becoming-uninsurable">Is the world becoming uninsurable?</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42732728">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The notion that the world is becoming uninsurable is countered by the existence of areas less susceptible to natural disasters, where insurance remains viable. - Proper building regulations and practices like controlled burning can mitigate risks from events such as hurricanes and wildfires, maintaining insurability. - Although climate change is increasing extreme weather events, engineering solutions and improved risk management can help address these challenges, though insurance costs may rise in high-risk areas. </p>
<h2><a href="https://learn.yjs.dev/">Learn Yjs Interactively</a></h2>
<p>Learn Yjs is an interactive tutorial designed to teach users how to build real-time collaborative applications using the Yjs CRDT (Conflict-free Replicated Data Type) library. - The tutorial includes live examples, demos, and code exercises, covering Yjs basics, state handling in distributed apps, and challenges in collaborative app development. - Developed by Jamsocket, the tutorial utilizes Y-Sweet and is built with Astro, React, and Yjs, offering users a hands-on experience with automatic syncing and network interaction adjustments. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42731582">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>&quot;Learn Yjs Interactively&quot; is a tutorial designed to simplify learning Yjs, a Conflict-free Replicated Data Type (CRDT) library for collaborative applications, through interactive demos and coding exercises. - The tutorial addresses common shortcomings in existing resources by providing a deeper understanding of distributed state management. - Y-Sweet, an open-source Rust server, is highlighted as a backend solution for Yjs, offering storage capabilities via Amazon S3. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.answer.ai/posts/2025-01-08-devin.html">Thoughts on a Month with Devin</a></h2>
<p>In March 2024, a new AI company introduced Devin, an AI software engineer, with a substantial $21 million investment, aiming to automate tasks from learning new technologies to deploying applications. - Initial demonstrations of Devin were impressive, but testing by Answer.AI revealed mixed results, with Devin excelling in simple tasks like API integrations but struggling with complex projects. - Despite a user-friendly interface, Devin&#39;s autonomous nature led to inefficiencies, succeeding in only 3 out of 20 tasks, underscoring the disparity between AI expectations and practical performance. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42734681">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>AI agents, such as Devin, enhance productivity by managing simple tasks but cannot yet replace software engineers due to the need for thorough code review and testing. - Companies relying solely on AI for engineering have encountered problems with code quality, highlighting the current limitations of AI in complex problem-solving. - While AI tools are rapidly advancing, they are presently most effective as supportive tools for human developers, with potential for handling more significant tasks in the future. </p>
<h2><a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/1003780/">Some things to expect in 2025</a></h2>
<p>LWN.net predicts the rise of the extensible scheduling class (sched-ext) in more distributions and an increase in Rust code within the Linux kernel by 2025. - Potential security threats, similar to the XZ backdoor, and challenges from AI-generated code are anticipated, alongside concerns about single-maintainer projects. - The year may witness more open hardware, a resurgence in mobile device distributions, and security issues in cloud-based products, with global conflicts potentially affecting the development community. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42731962">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>By 2025, major projects may face challenges as developers integrate AI-generated code without fully understanding it, similar to past issues with code copied from StackOverflow. The increasing use of AI tools in coding can lead to &quot;learning debt,&quot; where developers rely on AI without grasping the underlying code, highlighting the need for responsible code comprehension. The tech industry must adapt to these changes, balancing the advantages of AI with the necessity for skilled and knowledgeable developers to ensure code quality and accountability. </p>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Canon wants us to pay for using our own camera as a webcam" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Canon%20wants%20us%20to%20pay%20for%20using%20our%20own%20camera%20as%20a%20webcam&subheading=Friday%2C%20January%2017%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/17</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-17T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-16]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/16&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-16</h1>
<h2><a href="https://hindenburgresearch.com/gratitude/">I have made the decision to disband Hindenburg Research</a></h2>
<p>Hindenburg Research, known for challenging fraud and corruption, is disbanding as announced by founder Nate Anderson. - The decision to disband is driven by Anderson&#39;s desire for personal relief and to share their investigative methods with the public by open-sourcing their process. - Anderson expresses gratitude to his team, family, and readers, highlighting the impact and support received throughout their journey. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42717234">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Hindenburg Research is disbanding, with founder Nate Anderson citing personal reasons and a desire to publicly share their investigative methods. - Despite their success in exposing frauds such as Nikola Motors, Anderson states there is no specific threat causing the closure. - Anderson plans to release educational materials to inspire similar investigative efforts, while the diverse team will pursue new independent ventures. </p>
<h2><a href="https://keygen.sh/blog/no-calls/">No Calls</a></h2>
<p>Zeke Gabrielse, founder of Keygen, initially avoided sales calls due to his introverted nature, implementing a &#39;no calls&#39; policy, which led to more direct interactions and his first enterprise sale. Gabrielse identified four key issues to address for a successful &#39;no calls&#39; approach: unclear offerings, poor onboarding, hidden pricing, and lack of trust, suggesting clear messaging, transparent pricing, self-serve onboarding, and trust-building documentation. While some enterprises still expect calls, Keygen uses brief &#39;discovery calls&#39; to transition to email discussions, and Gabrielse encourages others to consider a #nocalls approach if it aligns with their style. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42725385">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The post criticizes companies that mandate phone calls for basic product information, advocating for transparent online communication to save time and reduce frustration. Commenters largely agree, suggesting that some companies use phone calls to obscure information or employ manipulative sales tactics. While some argue that calls are necessary for complex enterprise sales, the general consensus emphasizes the importance of transparency and efficient communication. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=itpcsQQvgAQ">Nintendo announces the Switch 2 [video]</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42724621">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Nintendo has announced the Switch 2, emphasizing iterative improvements over radical changes, maintaining its hybrid design for both portable and docked play. Potential enhancements include OLED screens and improved controllers, aiming to offer better specifications and features. The Switch 2 seeks to balance innovation with familiarity, appealing to both new and existing fans by focusing on stable gameplay experiences. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/gaza-ceasefire-appears-close-us-egyptian-leaders-put-focus-coming-hours-2025-01-14/">Israel, Hamas reach ceasefire deal to end 15 months of war in Gaza</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42716440">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Israel and Hamas have agreed to a ceasefire, ending 15 months of conflict in Gaza, marking a significant development in the region. Concerns persist that Western media and politicians may prematurely declare the crisis resolved, overlooking ongoing issues like Gaza&#39;s destruction and West Bank annexation. The situation remains complex, with debates on security, territorial claims, and how to achieve lasting peace, reflecting differing perspectives and parallels with other geopolitical conflicts. </p>
<h2><a href="https://apnews.com/article/sweden-digital-education-backlash-reading-writing-1dd964c628f76361c43dbf3964f7dbf4">Sweden brings more books and handwriting practice back to its schools (2023)</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42715841">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Sweden is reintroducing physical books and handwriting practice in schools, shifting from a fully digital educational approach. There is a growing recognition of the emotional and tactile benefits of physical books, despite the convenience of digital formats. The ongoing debate focuses on finding a balanced integration of digital and physical learning tools in education. </p>
<h2><a href="https://nokia-apple-iphone-was-launched-presentation.tiiny.site/">Nokia&#39;s internal presentation after iPhone was launched (2007) [pdf]</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42724761">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Nokia&#39;s internal presentation post-iPhone launch in 2007 acknowledged the threat from Apple&#39;s innovation, yet management failed to adapt effectively. Despite having strong software and engineering talent, Nokia underestimated the importance of software, sticking with Symbian and missing opportunities with Linux-based platforms like Meego and Meltemi. Ultimately, Nokia&#39;s decision to back Windows Phone, which couldn&#39;t compete with iOS and Android, highlighted their struggle to shift from hardware to software-focused strategies, a challenge for many large organizations facing disruptive innovation. </p>
<h2><a href="https://fortune.com/2025/01/15/ftc-pbms-unitedhealth-brian-thompson-cvs-caremark-cigna-pharmacy-benefit-managers/">UnitedHealth overcharged cancer patients for drugs by over 1,000%</a></h2>
<p>UnitedHealth has been discovered to have overcharged certain cancer patients for medications by over 1,000%. FTC Chair Lina Khan is focusing on major pharmacy benefit managers, including UnitedHealth&#39;s OptumRx, Cigna&#39;s Express Scripts, and CVS Caremark Rx, as part of a broader investigation. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42716428">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>UnitedHealth has been accused of overcharging cancer patients for medications by over 1,000%, leveraging its dual role as an insurer and a pharmacy benefit manager (PBM). This vertical integration enables UnitedHealth to inflate drug prices, affecting patient expenses and bypassing profit limitations, raising concerns about prioritizing profits over patient care. The situation underscores the complexity and lack of transparency in the healthcare system, prompting calls for regulatory reform to address rising costs and inefficiencies and to focus on patient welfare. </p>
<h2><a href="https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/01/blue-origin-reaches-orbit-on-first-flight-of-its-titanic-new-glenn-rocket/">Blue Origin reaches orbit on first flight of its titanic New Glenn rocket</a></h2>
<p>Blue Origin&#39;s New Glenn rocket successfully reached orbit for the first time, marking a significant milestone for the company. - The launch faced initial challenges, including engine chill issues and a stray boat, but ultimately achieved an orbital velocity of 28,800 kph. - Although the first stage booster did not return to Earth, the successful launch demonstrates Blue Origin&#39;s progress and the impact of Jeff Bezos&#39;s investments. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42722756">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Blue Origin&#39;s New Glenn rocket successfully reached orbit on its first flight, marking a significant milestone for the company. Although the first stage did not land successfully, this is typical for initial attempts and does not overshadow the achievement. The New Glenn rocket offers competitive launch pricing and payload capacity, positioning it as a rival to established companies like SpaceX and ULA (United Launch Alliance). </p>
<h2><a href="https://cerebras.ai/blog/100x-defect-tolerance-how-cerebras-solved-the-yield-problem">100x defect tolerance: How we solved the yield problem</a></h2>
<p>Cerebras has developed a wafer-scale chip, significantly larger than standard chips, by reimagining the relationship between chip size and fault tolerance. - The Wafer Scale Engine (WSE) includes 970,000 small, fault-tolerant cores and a sophisticated routing architecture, achieving high yields and 93% silicon utilization. - This innovation demonstrates that wafer-scale computing is commercially viable, offering greater defect tolerance compared to traditional GPUs like Nvidia&#39;s H100. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42717165">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Cerebras has introduced a fault-tolerant routing architecture in chip manufacturing, allowing for larger chips by using die space for routing instead of transistors, which helps bypass defective cores. - This innovative approach contrasts with traditional methods that discard defective chips, as Cerebras uses a single large wafer-scale chip with built-in redundancy to maintain functionality. - The development is significant in the context of AI, where opinions are divided on its potential, with some viewing it as a bubble and others seeing transformative industry potential. </p>
<h2><a href="https://zadzmo.org/code/nepenthes/">Nepenthes is a tarpit to catch AI web crawlers</a></h2>
<p>Nepenthes is a tarpit software designed to trap and deter web crawlers, particularly those collecting data for Large Language Models (LLMs), by generating endless, looping pages. - The software can create significant CPU load and is used to protect real content or to overwhelm AI models with irrelevant data, potentially affecting search engine visibility. - Installation options include Docker or manual setup, with configuration managed through a YAML file, but users should exercise caution due to its potential to be considered malicious. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42725147">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Nepenthes is a tarpit designed to trap AI web crawlers, potentially exploiting a vulnerability in the ChatGPT API that could lead to excessive HTTP requests and a denial of service. - The vulnerability has been ignored by OpenAI and Microsoft, and reporting it to OpenAI and BugCrowd proved difficult due to their lack of responsiveness. - The tarpit does not differentiate between AI and legitimate search engine crawlers, posing a risk to both, and highlights the challenges in managing aggressive crawlers and the ineffectiveness of current solutions like robots.txt. </p>
<h2><a href="https://joeyehand.com/blog/2025/01/15/i-ditched-the-algorithm-for-rssand-you-should-too/">I Ditched the Algorithm for RSS–and You Should Too</a></h2>
<p>The article advocates for using RSS (Really Simple Syndication) as an alternative to social media algorithms, emphasizing its ability to deliver content without ads or unnecessary distractions. RSS allows users to subscribe directly to their favorite websites, including YouTube and Reddit, providing a streamlined and personalized content experience. The ease of setting up RSS feeds and the availability of feed generators for sites without native RSS support make it a practical tool for staying informed and saving time. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42724284">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The article emphasizes the advantages of RSS feeds, which deliver content directly without the influence of algorithms, offering a more personalized and controlled experience. Users express dissatisfaction with modern websites that lack RSS support, while others suggest tools and projects to improve RSS usage. The discussion includes recommendations for various RSS readers and tools, advocating for a return to RSS for a more genuine web experience. </p>
<h2><a href="https://petapixel.com/2025/01/06/openai-fails-to-deliver-opt-out-system-for-photographers/">OpenAI fails to deliver opt-out system for photographers</a></h2>
<p>OpenAI missed its 2025 deadline for releasing Media Manager, a tool designed to help photographers opt out of having their work used in AI training data. The tool aimed to identify copyrighted content and address copyright disputes, but it appears to have been deprioritized, with no updates since August. Photographers currently face a cumbersome process of submitting each work they want excluded, leading to criticism that the system is unfair and unlikely to be widely adopted. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42718850">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>OpenAI currently lacks an opt-out system for photographers to exclude their work from AI training datasets, raising concerns about creators&#39; rights. Critics suggest that companies like OpenAI may only implement opt-out systems if legally mandated, drawing parallels to past copyright issues in the music industry. The existing process requires photographers to individually submit works for exclusion, which is seen as a cumbersome deterrent, potentially necessitating legal action to ensure creators&#39; rights are respected. </p>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/dnSpyEx/dnSpy">dnSpyEx: .NET debugger and assembly editor</a></h2>
<p>dnSpyEx is an unofficial continuation of the dnSpy project, providing a debugger and .NET assembly editor for editing and debugging .NET and Unity assemblies without source code. The tool supports debugging .NET Framework, .NET, and Unity game assemblies, and includes features like setting breakpoints, evaluating expressions, and metadata editing. The latest stable release and beta builds are available on GitHub, and it uses open-source libraries like ILSpy and Roslyn, licensed under GPLv3. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42716072">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>dnSpyEx is a .NET debugger and assembly editor, now maintained by electrokill after the original author, d4d, archived their repositories. - It is an open-source tool used for .NET reversing, binary analysis, debugging, game modding, and application patching, with features like decompiling and setting breakpoints on runtime Intermediate Language (IL) code. - The continued development of dnSpyEx highlights the resilience and sustainability of open-source projects, even after the original version is archived. </p>
<h2><a href="https://drewdevault.com/2025/01/16/2025-01-16-No-Billionares-at-FOSDEM-please.html">No Billionares at FOSDEM</a></h2>
<p>Jack Dorsey, former CEO of Twitter, is scheduled to deliver a keynote at FOSDEM, a significant event for free software enthusiasts, due to his blockchain company&#39;s sponsorship. - Despite his substantial net worth and controversial history, including the sale of Twitter to Elon Musk, Dorsey&#39;s participation has sparked criticism and plans for a protest sit-in during his talk. - The protest is organized to occur at 11:45 AM outside the venue, with interested participants encouraged to contact the organizer via email. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42725057">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The controversy centers on whether billionaires like Jack Dorsey should speak at FOSDEM, a free and open-source software event, due to their wealth and influence. - Critics question the ethics of wealth and the impact of centralized social media platforms, while others defend the contributions of billionaires to technology and innovation. - The debate also explores differing opinions on free speech and the appropriateness of protest tactics at such events. </p>
<h2><a href="https://p4.org/intels-tofino-p4-software-is-now-open-source/">Intel&#39;s Tofino P4 Software Is Now Open Source</a></h2>
<p>Intel has open-sourced its Tofino P4 software, previously proprietary, to transform programmable networks and foster innovation within the P4 community. - This initiative democratizes access to advanced network programming tools, benefiting startups, academic institutions, and developers globally. - The source code is accessible in the p4lang structure, with components in the p4c and open-p4studio repositories, encouraging contributions and community engagement. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42721442">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Intel has open-sourced its Tofino P4 software, aiming to support the community even though the Tofino hardware is discontinued. This move is appreciated but considered overdue, as the platform is nearing obsolescence, raising questions about the relevance of P4 and Tofino&#39;s future. The release is a positive step, allowing continued use of existing hardware and potentially inspiring new developments and hardware vendors. </p>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="I have made the decision to disband Hindenburg Research" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=I%20have%20made%20the%20decision%20to%20disband%20Hindenburg%20Research&subheading=Thursday%2C%20January%2016%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/16</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-16T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-15]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/15&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-15</h1>
<h2><a href="https://p.migdal.pl/blog/2025/01/dont-use-cosine-similarity/">Don&#39;t use cosine similarity carelessly</a></h2>
<p>Cosine similarity, a method for comparing vectors, can be misleading if used without understanding the context, as it may not accurately capture semantic similarities. - Embeddings, such as those from word2vec or sentence embeddings from Large Language Models (LLMs), require careful and intentional use to ensure they reflect the desired relationships. - To improve vector similarity results, consider using LLMs directly, creating task-specific embeddings through fine-tuning, and ensuring text is clean and prompts are well-engineered before embedding. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42704078">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>In Retrieval-Augmented Generation (RAG) applications, using a &quot;semantic re-ranker&quot; can enhance the matching of user queries when employing cosine similarity. - Avoid storing vector embeddings of empty content, as they can lead to false matches; some projects use special encodings to represent &quot;nothingness&quot; to prevent this issue. - Exploring alternatives such as Large Language Models (LLMs), cross-encoders, L2 re-ranking models, or graph-based methods can provide more accurate retrieval results than relying solely on cosine similarity. </p>
<h2><a href="https://ij.org/press-release/nevada-court-shuts-down-police-use-of-federal-loophole-for-civil-forfeiture/">Nevada Court Shuts Down Police Use of Federal Loophole for Civil Forfeiture</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42707573">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>A Nevada court has ruled against police using a federal loophole for civil forfeiture, where assets are seized without charging the owner with a crime. This decision underscores the debate over civil forfeiture laws, criticized for assuming guilt and potentially leading to corruption. The case involved a man&#39;s life savings seized during a traffic stop, highlighting the need for legal action and media attention to protect citizens&#39; rights. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.reuters.com/technology/tiktok-preparing-us-shut-off-sunday-information-reports-2025-01-15/">TikTok preparing for U.S. shut-off on Sunday</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42710339">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>TikTok is facing a potential shutdown in the U.S., prompting users to explore alternatives like Xiaohongshu, YouTube Shorts, and Instagram Reels. - Xiaohongshu, popular in China, is not tailored for Western audiences, raising concerns about direct interactions between Chinese and U.S. users. - The U.S. government cites national security concerns, including fears of foreign influence and propaganda, as reasons for considering a TikTok ban. </p>
<h2><a href="https://claudio.uk/posts/epub-to-audiobook.html">Generate audiobooks from E-books with Kokoro-82M</a></h2>
<p>Kokoro v0.19 is a new text-to-speech model with 82 million parameters, providing high-quality audio output in multiple languages, including American and British English, French, Korean, Japanese, and Mandarin. Claudio Santini developed Audiblez, a tool that converts e-books into audiobooks using Kokoro, processing .epub files and generating audio files, with a conversion time of about 2 hours for a 100,000-word book on an M2 MacBook Pro. Audiblez requires installation via pip, supports various languages and voices, and needs ffmpeg for .m4b file creation, with the tool available on GitHub for further development and improvements. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42708773">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Kokoro-82M is an AI tool designed to convert e-books into audiobooks, offering convenience, particularly for non-fiction works. While AI-generated audiobooks can fill gaps where no human-narrated versions exist, they currently lack the emotional depth and character provided by human narrators. The tool sparks debate on AI&#39;s impact on creative professions, drawing parallels to historical technological shifts, and raises concerns about diminishing opportunities for training and experience in these fields. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.theautopian.com/if-you-ever-see-this-speed-sign-youre-probably-going-to-die/">Road signs to help people limit radiation exposure in contaminated areas</a></h2>
<p>The Manual on Uniform Traffic Control Devices (MUTCD) contains Cold War-era signs, such as &quot;MAINTAIN TOP SAFE SPEED,&quot; intended for radiological contamination zones. These signs were part of Civil Defense strategies to safeguard citizens during a potential nuclear apocalypse, though they were never utilized. Some of these signs are still included in the MUTCD as Emergency Management signs, highlighting historical fears and preparedness efforts from that period. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42704491">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Authorities are considering road signs to advise high-speed travel through contaminated areas to reduce radiation exposure by minimizing time spent in these zones. - The discussion draws parallels to Chernobyl and Fukushima, emphasizing concerns about inhalation and contamination from radioactive dust. - Broader geopolitical issues, including nationalism and nuclear deterrence, are also part of the conversation, reflecting on historical and current global tensions. </p>
<h2><a href="https://wtfhappenedin1971.com/">WTF Happened in 1971? (2019)</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42711781">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The website &quot;WTF Happened in 1971?&quot; examines significant economic and societal changes beginning in 1971, often linked to the end of the gold standard. The discussion includes diverse viewpoints on the causes of these changes, such as increased executive compensation, the oil crisis, and changes in economic policies. The debate also considers the effects of the Nixon Shock, the role of credit and fiat currency, and broader factors like urbanization and energy prices. </p>
<h2><a href="https://philipotoole.com/how-is-rqlite-tested/">How rqlite is tested</a></h2>
<p>rqlite is a lightweight distributed database that combines SQLite and Raft, focusing on reliability and quality through a structured testing strategy. - The testing strategy follows the testing pyramid, emphasizing unit tests for isolated components, integration tests for system-level validation, and minimal end-to-end tests for basic operation checks. - Key lessons from rqlite&#39;s testing approach include starting testing early, simplifying test code, and ensuring determinism, which helps maintain high quality with minimal overhead. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42703282">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The discussion focuses on testing strategies for rqlite, a distributed database based on SQLite, emphasizing initial tests, the testing pyramid, and parametrized and property tests. Challenges with end-to-end (E2E) testing in complex systems are highlighted, along with the choice of the Go programming language for rqlite and security concerns. Deterministic simulation testing is mentioned as a high standard for database reliability, with references to other databases like FoundationDB, showcasing diverse perspectives on effective testing practices. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.vijayp.dev/blog/rewrite-plain-html/">Rewriting my website in plain HTML and CSS</a></h2>
<p>The author rebuilt their website using plain HTML and CSS, moving away from SvelteKit, to simplify the site and host it on Cloudflare Pages. - They used Pandoc for converting Markdown to HTML and Python for scripting, resulting in a smaller website, reducing asset size from ~356kb to ~88kb. - The project highlighted challenges such as code duplication and lack of live reloading, with plans to explore web components and FastAPI to address these issues, potentially serving as a template for others seeking a framework-free website with Markdown posts. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42705077">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The author maintains a personal website using plain HTML and CSS, appreciating the minimal time commitment and skill sharpening it provides. The website is hosted on GitHub Pages, and content is drafted in MS Word before being manually updated. Despite suggestions to use server-side includes or static site generators like Jekyll or Hugo, the author values the control and simplicity of their current method. </p>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Don't use cosine similarity carelessly" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Don't%20use%20cosine%20similarity%20carelessly&subheading=Wednesday%2C%20January%2015%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/15</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-15T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-14]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/14&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-14</h1>
<h2><a href="https://sourcecodered.com/snyk-malicious-npm-package/">Snyk security researcher deploys malicious NPM packages targeting cursor.com</a></h2>
<p>A Snyk security researcher released malicious NPM packages targeting Cursor.com, an AI coding company, to collect system data and send it to an attacker-controlled service. The packages, identified as &quot;cursor-retrieval,&quot; &quot;cursor-always-local,&quot; and &quot;cursor-shadow-workspace,&quot; were flagged by the OpenSSF package analysis scanner, resulting in advisories MAL-2025-27, MAL-2025-28, and MAL-2025-29. This incident highlights the importance of scrutinizing NPM packages before installation to avoid potential security threats. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42690473">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>A Snyk security researcher released malicious NPM (Node Package Manager) packages aimed at cursor.com, highlighting dependency confusion vulnerabilities. - The incident has sparked a debate on the ethics of security research, particularly regarding the public exposure of environment variables. - Cursor.com clarified they did not authorize the action, and Snyk has since apologized, underscoring the challenges in balancing offensive security research with ethical standards. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.howtogeek.com/why-i-switched-to-firefox-and-never-looked-back/">I Switched to Firefox and Never Looked Back</a></h2>
<p>Firefox is praised for its superior tab management, built-in Pocket feature for saving links, and a privacy-focused email relay, making it a strong alternative to Chrome. - Additional features like a user-friendly screenshot tool, a ChatGPT button, Picture-in-Picture, customizable search options, and smooth scrolling enhance the browsing experience. - Although Firefox lacks Chrome&#39;s web app feature, its thoughtful design and reduced resource demands make it a preferred choice for some users. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42696081">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Firefox users face challenges from platforms like YouTube, which may intentionally degrade the experience for non-Google browsers or users employing adblockers. - This trend raises concerns about user autonomy, as it penalizes those opting for an ad-free and surveillance-free web experience. - Firefox offers unique features, such as container tabs, which enhance privacy and usability, making it a favored choice for users seeking independence from major corporate-controlled browsers. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/sonos-ceo-patrick-spence-steps-down-after-app-update-debacle-2025-01-13/">Sonos CEO steps down after app update debacle</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42687932">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The Sonos CEO has resigned following a controversial app update that required users to replace costly sound systems, causing customer dissatisfaction. - The update introduced a cloud-based system, moving away from the reliable Universal Plug and Play (UPnP), which led to connectivity issues and increased complexity. - This situation underscores the conflict between business strategies and maintaining customer trust, as the CEO transitions to an advisory role with a severance package. </p>
<h2><a href="https://kevinmunger.substack.com/p/in-the-belly-of-the-mrbeast">In the belly of the MrBeast</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42696691">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The essay examines how YouTube&#39;s algorithm influences content creation, using MrBeast as a case study, highlighting a shift towards engagement-driven rather than meaningful content. - It discusses the broader implications for media literacy and the cultural impact of platforms like YouTube and TikTok, suggesting a trend towards superficial and reactionary content. - Various perspectives are considered on the role of algorithms in shaping content and the influence of popular creators on cultural norms. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.githubstatus.com/incidents/qd96yfgvmcf9">GitHub Git Operations Are Down</a></h2>
<p>GitHub faced a Git operations outage on January 13, 2025, due to a configuration change affecting the internal load balancer, lasting from 23:35 to 00:24 UTC. - The issue was resolved by reverting the configuration change, and GitHub is working on improving monitoring and deployment processes to prevent similar incidents. - The outage also affected GitHub&#39;s Actions and Pages services, highlighting the interconnected nature of their platform services. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42691184">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>GitHub faced a major outage impacting git operations, leading to confusion among developers who initially suspected issues with their SSH keys or local configurations. - The incident underscored the challenges of relying on centralized services, prompting discussions on the advantages of self-hosting and decentralized systems. - Although the issue was resolved, it highlighted concerns about GitHub&#39;s reliability and the risks of depending on third-party platforms for essential tasks. </p>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/openzfs/zfs/releases/tag/zfs-2.3.0">ZFS 2.3 released with ZFS raidz expansion</a></h2>
<p>OpenZFS 2.3.0 has been released, introducing significant features such as RAIDZ Expansion, Fast Deduplication, Direct Input/Output, JSON output, and support for long file names. - The release includes essential bug fixes and performance enhancements, compatible with Linux kernels 4.18 - 6.12 and FreeBSD versions 13.3, 14.0 - 14.2. - The update is a collaborative effort from 134 contributors, with comprehensive documentation and a change log available for review. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42694596">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>ZFS 2.3 has been released, introducing features like RAIDZ expansion, fast deduplication, direct IO, JSON output, and support for long file names. - RAIDZ expansion is particularly notable as it allows users to add new devices to an existing RAIDZ pool without downtime, enhancing storage capacity. - The release is considered a significant advancement for ZFS users, drawing comparisons with other filesystems like Btrfs and Windows Storage Spaces, despite some limitations like the inability to shrink pools. </p>
<h2><a href="https://docs.linuxserver.io/images/docker-webtop/">Webtop – Alpine,Ubuntu,Fedora,and Arch containers containing full desktop envs</a></h2>
<p>Linuxserver/webtop provides containers based on Alpine, Ubuntu, Fedora, and Arch with full desktop environments accessible through web browsers, supporting both x86-64 and arm64 architectures. Users can select from various desktop environments such as XFCE, KDE, MATE, i3, Openbox, and IceWM by using specific image tags, and access the Webtop via designated URLs. Security features include Docker&#39;s seccomp option and authentication setup, with customization options available through environment variables, and support for GPU acceleration with open-source drivers. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42690983">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Webtop provides containers with full desktop environments for Alpine, Ubuntu, Fedora, and Arch, suitable for quick setups behind a VPN. Users commend Webtop for its speed and ease of use, particularly when used with the Gluetun container for secure connections, but caution against exposing containers to the internet without security measures due to lack of default authentication. The project is valued for being open-source and flexible, with users sharing configurations, and alternatives like Kasm and Selkies are noted for similar purposes. </p>
<h2><a href="https://gizmodo.com/1-in-5-online-job-postings-are-either-fake-or-never-filled-study-finds-2000549706">1 in 5 online job postings are either fake or never filled, study finds</a></h2>
<p>A recent study indicates that 20% of online job postings are either fake or remain unfilled, adding to job seekers&#39; frustration. - This &quot;ghost job&quot; trend might be a tactic for companies to project an image of growth. - Job platforms such as Greenhouse and LinkedIn have introduced job verification services to assist users in identifying genuine job opportunities. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42697783">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>A study reveals that 20% of online job postings are either fake or remain unfilled, often due to companies needing to comply with US immigration policies. - Companies may also leave job postings up to find ideal candidates, change requirements, or have pre-selected internal candidates. - The job market is difficult for applicants, who frequently encounter ghosting and automated rejections, prompting calls for regulatory intervention. </p>
<h2><a href="https://collegetowns.substack.com/p/making-an-intersection-unsafe-for">Making an intersection unsafe for pedestrians to save seconds for drivers</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42698557">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The debate centers around whether intersections should prioritize pedestrian safety or driver efficiency, with some favoring light-controlled intersections and pedestrian scrambles over 4-way stops. Opinions vary on traffic laws and infrastructure design, with discussions on the safety of jaywalking and the risks associated with right turns on red. Some advocate for alternative solutions like roundabouts or adopting Dutch traffic engineering standards to enhance both safety and efficiency. </p>
<h2><a href="https://db-engines.com/en/blog_post/109">PostgreSQL is the Database Management System of the Year 2024</a></h2>
<p>PostgreSQL has been awarded DBMS of the Year 2024 by DB-Engines, achieving this recognition for the fifth time, surpassing 423 other database management systems. PostgreSQL, with a history spanning nearly 35 years, continues to innovate, as seen in the recent enhancements of PostgreSQL 17, released in September 2024. Snowflake and Microsoft secured second and third places, respectively, with Snowflake noted for its cloud-based data warehousing and multi-cloud support, while Microsoft offers robust managed relational databases through Azure SQL Database and SQL Server. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42696080">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>PostgreSQL has been awarded Database Management System of the Year 2024 by db-engines.com, highlighting its growing popularity and recognition in the industry. Users are considering switching from Microsoft SQL Server to PostgreSQL due to high licensing costs and resource limitations, despite potential migration challenges. PostgreSQL is favored for its robust features and cost-effectiveness, making it a preferred choice for future projects, although some users explore alternatives like Babelfish to reduce costs. </p>
<h2><a href="https://trufflesecurity.com/blog/millions-at-risk-due-to-google-s-oauth-flaw">Google’s OAuth login doesn’t protect against purchasing a failed startup domain</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42699099">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The discussion highlights a vulnerability in Google’s OAuth login system when a failed startup&#39;s domain is acquired by a new owner, potentially allowing unauthorized access to services. This issue arises because Google may not distinguish between the original and new domain owners, affecting any system that uses domain-based authentication. A proposed solution is to use unique identifiers that remain constant over time, though the implementation of this solution varies among identity providers. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.coryzue.com/writing/solopreneur/">Using coding skills to make passive income</a></h2>
<p>The author transitioned from a CTO role to a solopreneur, successfully earning more through a portfolio of software products. Key strategies include focusing on deep work, starting with small projects, iterating quickly, and dedicating time to marketing efforts. The journey emphasizes resilience due to uncertainties, but highlights the unmatched autonomy and freedom of this career path, encouraging those with coding skills to consider it for passive income. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42696822">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>A user described generating passive income through SEO spam websites using expiring domain names, earning approximately $30k annually, despite ethical concerns and Google&#39;s eventual crackdown. The post sparked a debate on passive income, with some users arguing it&#39;s more akin to running a business than truly passive earnings. Participants shared experiences and challenges in side projects, highlighting the importance of time, resilience, and strategic planning. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/jan/13/spain-proposes-100-tax-on-homes-bought-by-non-eu-residents">Spain proposes 100% tax on homes bought by non-EU residents</a></h2>
<p>Spain is considering a 100% tax on real estate purchases by non-EU residents, aiming to address the housing crisis and curb speculative buying. Prime Minister Pedro Sánchez&#39;s proposal includes expanding social housing and regulating tourist rentals to tackle the disparity between housing prices and incomes. The proposal&#39;s future as law is uncertain, with some analysts viewing it as a deterrent to foreign investors rather than a guaranteed legislative change. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42690781">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Spain is considering a 100% tax on homes purchased by non-EU residents to tackle housing affordability problems. - Critics suggest that foreign buyers are not the primary cause of high housing prices, citing slow bureaucracy and zoning laws as more significant factors. - The proposal has ignited a debate on the role of foreign ownership in housing markets and its effectiveness in resolving affordability issues. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.tomshardware.com/tech-industry/apple-will-soon-receive-made-in-america-chips-from-tsmcs-arizona-fab-company-in-final-stages-of-quality-verification">Apple will soon receive &#39;made in America&#39; chips from TSMC&#39;s Arizona fab</a></h2>
<p>Apple is testing processors from TSMC&#39;s Arizona facility, with plans for mass production by the first quarter, potentially becoming TSMC&#39;s first U.S. customer for locally manufactured chips. - This initiative aims to bolster U.S. silicon independence, reducing dependency on Taiwan, which is vulnerable to geopolitical and natural risks. - TSMC&#39;s Arizona fab is set to produce advanced 3nm and 2nm chips, with ongoing efforts to enhance local recruitment and partnerships with U.S. universities, although packaging will initially occur in Taiwan until the Peoria facility is operational. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42699977">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Apple will receive chips from TSMC&#39;s Arizona plant, but they need to be sent back to Taiwan for packaging due to insufficient U.S. facilities. - Over 50% of the workforce at the Arizona plant is from Taiwan, indicating a gap in the U.S. STEM (Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics) field. - The CHIPS Act initiative, aimed at enhancing U.S. semiconductor manufacturing, faces challenges as the &quot;Made in America&quot; label is questioned due to the packaging process occurring in Taiwan, with plans for U.S. packaging capabilities by 2027. </p>
<h2><a href="https://gothamist.com/news/43k-fewer-drivers-on-manhattan-roads-after-congestion-pricing-turned-on-mta-says">43K fewer drivers on Manhattan roads after congestion pricing turned on</a></h2>
<p>After congestion pricing was implemented, there was a 7.5% reduction in drivers entering Manhattan below 60th Street, equating to 43,000 fewer drivers each weekday. The reduction in traffic has improved traffic flow and increased bus speeds, with some express buses experiencing higher ridership. The Metropolitan Transportation Authority (MTA) uses the toll revenue, estimated at $500 million annually, for transit improvements, despite some political opposition. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42692730">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The implementation of congestion pricing in Manhattan has resulted in 43,000 fewer drivers, leading to increased bus speeds and potentially better emergency response times. The policy is designed to reduce traffic congestion and improve air quality, though it has sparked debate over its impact on lower-income individuals. Proponents argue that the benefits include more efficient public transit and cleaner air, while discussions continue on balancing these advantages with the needs of drivers. </p>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Snyk security researcher deploys malicious NPM packages targeting cursor.com" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Snyk%20security%20researcher%20deploys%20malicious%20NPM%20packages%20targeting%20cursor.com&subheading=Tuesday%2C%20January%2014%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/14</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-14T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-13]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/13&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-13</h1>
<h2><a href="https://valatka.dev/2025/01/12/on-killer-uv-feature.html">Uv&#39;s killer feature is making ad-hoc environments easy</a></h2>
<p>Uv offers a unique feature that simplifies ad-hoc scripting in Python by streamlining dependency and environment management. - Users can execute a single command, <code>uv run --python 3.12 --with pandas python</code>, to run scripts without altering the global environment. - This ease of use and memorability makes uv an attractive option for Python package management. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42676432">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Uv is a package manager that simplifies managing Python dependencies and versions, offering advantages over traditional tools like pip, pyenv, and poetry. - It features inline script dependencies, rapid environment creation, and pre-compiled Python binaries, contributing to its popularity. - Despite concerns about its venture capital backing and reliance on non-Python Software Foundation (PSF) binaries, users value its speed and user-friendliness for Python project management. </p>
<h2><a href="https://asylumsquare.com/backstage/2025-01-12/why-i-deleted-my-social-media-accounts">I deleted my social media accounts</a></h2>
<p>The author deleted their social media accounts due to concerns about platforms like Meta and Twitter prioritizing profit over ethical considerations. Highlighted issues include Mark Zuckerberg&#39;s decision to drop fact-checkers and collaborate with Trump, and Elon Musk&#39;s controversial actions, contributing to a toxic environment. The author emphasizes the negative impact of social media on mental health, particularly for teenagers, and is exploring alternatives like blogging and new platforms cautiously. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42677587">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Deleting social media accounts can result in missing life updates from acquaintances, highlighting the platform&#39;s role in maintaining connections. While some believe important relationships will persist through direct communication, social media often facilitates shallow connections that may be lost when quitting. The choice to leave social media is subjective, influenced by personal priorities and the value placed on different types of relationships. </p>
<h2><a href="https://medhir.com/blog/right-to-root-access">Right to root access</a></h2>
<p>Consumers should have the right to install any software on devices they own, but companies often lock bootloaders and restrict root access, limiting user control. - While security is a valid concern, these restrictions are seen as anti-consumer and anti-competitive, contributing to e-waste and limiting repair options. - Advocates suggest that a &quot;right to root access&quot; should be included in right to repair discussions, with exceptions for critical systems where risks are too high. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42677835">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The debate on root access in devices underscores the conflict between consumer freedom and vendor control, with many advocating for the right to install any software on owned devices. - Critics argue that vendor-imposed restrictions prioritize profit over consumer control and privacy, limiting users&#39; ability to modify their devices. - The discussion extends to broader themes of property rights and the autonomy to manage one&#39;s own devices, with differing views on the security benefits of locked devices versus informed consumer choice. </p>
<h2><a href="https://doompdf.pages.dev/doom.pdf">Doom (1993) in a PDF</a></h2>
<p>A developer has created a Doom source port that operates within a PDF file, inspired by a similar Tetris project. - The project uses an older version of Emscripten to compile C code to asm.js, allowing it to run in the PDF&#39;s JavaScript runtime. - The implementation includes a 6-color monochrome display and is compatible only with Chromium-based browsers using the PDFium engine. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42678754">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>A developer has created a Doom source port that operates within a PDF file, following a similar project that ran Tetris in a PDF. - The project uses Emscripten to compile C to asm.js, allowing it to run in the PDF&#39;s limited JavaScript runtime, and employs the doomgeneric fork of the original Doom source. - This innovation has sparked discussions about the potential and security implications of executing code within PDFs, with the source code available on GitHub and functionality limited to Chromium-based browsers using the PDFium engine. </p>
<h2><a href="https://dwheeler.com/essays/debugging-agans.html">Debugging: Indispensable rules for finding even the most elusive problems (2004)</a></h2>
<p>David A. Wheeler reviews &quot;Debugging: The 9 Indispensable Rules for Finding Even the Most Elusive Software and Hardware Problems&quot; by David J. Agans, highlighting it as a classic resource for developers. The book emphasizes fundamental debugging principles applicable to both novice and experienced developers, using practical examples and real-life &quot;war stories&quot; to illustrate its nine key rules. Wheeler commends the book for its focus on data gathering and handling intermittent problems, though he notes a desire for more specific tool advice, ultimately recommending it for its timeless debugging insights. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42682602">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Debugging is essential for resolving complex issues, emphasizing the importance of staying calm, understanding the system, and verifying assumptions. - Tools like <code>git bisect</code> can aid in efficient problem-solving by identifying the specific change that introduced a bug. - It&#39;s important to verify fixes and consider writing tests to prevent future regressions, highlighting the need for a systematic approach and sometimes using techniques like rubber duck debugging. </p>
<h2><a href="https://movies.stackexchange.com/questions/79161/how-did-they-make-cars-fall-apart-in-old-movies">How did they make cars fall apart in old movies (2017)</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42679127">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>In older films, practical effects were used to make cars fall apart, as seen in the 1965 French film &quot;Le Corniaud,&quot; where a car was disassembled and reassembled with hooks and explosive bolts for a scene. These stunts required detailed planning and engineering, facilitated by the simpler construction of cars at the time. Modern films would likely use CGI (Computer-Generated Imagery) for similar scenes due to the complexity and safety standards of contemporary vehicles. </p>
<h2><a href="https://heterogenoustasks.wordpress.com/2015/01/26/standard-patterns-in-choice-based-games/">Standard patterns in choice-based games (2015)</a></h2>
<p>The blog post by Sam Kabo Ashwell explores recurring design patterns in choice-based games, including Time Cave, Gauntlet, Branch and Bottleneck, and others, which affect gameplay and narrative structure. These patterns influence player experience and story progression, with examples from interactive fiction illustrating their application. The post notes that these patterns are flexible and can overlap, rather than being strict categories in game design. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42678647">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Choice-based games use narrative branching to enhance player agency, but this can lead to &quot;Time Caves,&quot; where some paths are overly detailed, and others are underdeveloped, causing players to miss key content. Tools can assist in creating a main story trunk with side paths that rejoin, but branching remains complex and resource-intensive, prompting some to advocate for linear stories or sandbox mechanics. Games like Disco Elysium and Nier Automata are noted for their successful use of branching, and there is discussion on AI&#39;s potential to dynamically generate story paths, though current technology may not yet achieve coherent narratives. </p>
<h2><a href="https://thefreemovie.buzz/">The Free Movie: Frame-by-frame, handrawn reproduction of &quot;The Bee Movie&quot; (2023)</a></h2>
<p>MSCHF Interactive has launched &quot;The FREE Movie,&quot; a collaborative project where users recreate the BEE Movie frame-by-frame, with 92% of frames already completed. Participants can actively engage by drawing, erasing, and previewing their contributions to the project. The next ambitious project planned by MSCHF Interactive is a frame-by-frame recreation of the movie DUNE. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42678584">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>A fan-made, frame-by-frame hand-drawn version of &quot;The Bee Movie&quot; has been created, following the trend of collaborative projects like &quot;Shrek Retold&quot; and &quot;Star Wars Uncut.&quot; These projects involve multiple creators contributing short segments, leading to a mix of quality and humorous results, reflecting a meme-centric approach. Opinions on &quot;The Free Movie&quot; vary, with some viewers finding the low-quality frames off-putting, while others enjoy the chaotic and crowd-sourced nature of the project. </p>
<h2><a href="http://134.0.119.41">Disco Elysium Explorer</a></h2>
<p>The Disco Elysium Explorer Project allows users to visualize and listen to dialogues from the game Disco Elysium, with all rights reserved by the studio ZA/UM. - The project offers features such as searching dialogues, building conversations, and visualizing them, enhancing the interactive experience. - It supports multiple languages, including Chinese, German, and Korean, making it accessible to a broader audience. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42679679">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Disco Elysium utilizes Articy:draft, a middleware tool, to construct its complex conversation graphs, showcasing a technical achievement despite performance challenges on large projects. The game is acclaimed for its storytelling and intricate dialogue systems, drawing comparisons to other narrative-focused games like Pentiment and Alpha Protocol. Notable for its unique RPG mechanics that emphasize dialogue and story over combat, Disco Elysium garners mixed opinions on its political themes but is recognized as a significant accomplishment in story-driven gaming. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.jamesshore.com/v2/blog/2025/the-best-product-engineering-org-in-the-world">If we had the best product engineering organization, what would it look like?</a></h2>
<p>The keynote at the Regional Scrum Gathering Tokyo by the VP of Engineering focused on key elements of a successful product engineering organization: People, Internal Quality, Lovability, Visibility, Agility, and Profitability. Emphasized the importance of attracting top talent, maintaining internal quality by reducing waste, and ensuring product lovability by understanding stakeholder needs. Highlighted the use of Extreme Programming (XP) and Fluid Scaling Technology (FaST) to enhance agility and adaptability, while aligning products with business goals for profitability. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42676123">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The discussion explores the characteristics of an ideal product engineering organization, focusing on management styles, decision-making processes, and productivity. - Opinions vary, with some advocating for distributed decision-making over hierarchical structures, while others emphasize the importance of CEOs in making decisive choices. - The conversation also addresses the challenges of measuring productivity and the influence of organizational culture on innovation and employee satisfaction, referencing companies like Meta and Amazon as examples. </p>
<h2><a href="https://traintimes.org.uk/map/tube/">Live London Underground / bus maps taken down by TfL trademark complaint</a></h2>
<p>In June 2010, a live London Underground map was created using Transport for London&#39;s (TfL) open data API, gaining popularity and media attention. On January 7, 2025, TfL requested the removal of the map due to trademark concerns, leading to its discontinuation despite potential adjustments. The creator&#39;s site, traintimes.org.uk, remains active, and live bus information is available on bustimes.org. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42682876">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Transport for London (TfL) removed live London Underground and bus maps from the website traintimes.org.uk following a trademark complaint. - The complaint email from TfL was criticized for its lack of clarity and for referencing U.S. law, despite the website being based in the UK. - The incident underscores ongoing tensions between hobbyist developers and trademark enforcement, with debates on whether TfL should provide free licenses for non-commercial use. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.qubes-os.org/">Qubes OS: A reasonably secure operating system</a></h2>
<p>Qubes OS is a highly secure operating system endorsed by experts, including Edward Snowden, for its strong isolation capabilities, making it suitable for sensitive tasks. - It supports running multiple operating systems and integrates with Whonix to enhance user privacy, appealing to journalists and organizations like the Freedom of the Press Foundation. - The Qubes community is welcoming to newcomers, providing support, resources, and opportunities to contribute or donate. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42677608">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Qubes OS is a security-focused operating system that uses virtualization to compartmentalize tasks, enhancing security by isolating applications and tasks. - Users have reported issues with graphics performance and battery life due to its reliance on software rendering, impacting video playback and overall system performance. - While praised for its security features, Qubes OS may not be suitable for users with high graphics or battery demands, though it is recommended for those needing high security, such as journalists or IT security professionals. </p>
<h2><a href="https://surfingcomplexity.blog/2024/12/21/the-canva-outage-another-tale-of-saturation-and-resilience/">The Canva outage: another tale of saturation and resilience</a></h2>
<p>The Canva outage was caused by a deployment of a new editor page version, leading to a &quot;thundering herd&quot; effect with 1.5 million requests per second overwhelming the API Gateway. - A stale traffic rule routed user traffic over the public internet, causing high latency and a backlog, while a known performance issue in the API Gateway worsened the situation. - Canva engineers manually intervened by increasing capacity and using Cloudflare&#39;s firewall to block traffic temporarily, highlighting the importance of human intervention in managing system performance issues during crises. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42676529">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The Canva outage underscores challenges with Content Delivery Network (CDN) saturation and resilience, common when many users access servers simultaneously, leading to overloads. - Proposed solutions like tiered distribution and preheating often fall short, while P2P (Peer-to-Peer) protocols like BitTorrent face piracy and control concerns, leading companies like Spotify and Blizzard to abandon them. - Effective load management strategies, such as capping connections and using exponential backoff, are crucial for mitigating these issues, highlighting the importance of robust infrastructure and strategic planning for handling high traffic efficiently. </p>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Uv's killer feature is making ad-hoc environments easy" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Uv's%20killer%20feature%20is%20making%20ad-hoc%20environments%20easy&subheading=Monday%2C%20January%2013%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/13</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-13T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-12]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/12&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-12</h1>
<h2><a href="https://matduggan.com/stop-trying-to-schedule-a-call-with-me/">Stop Trying to Schedule a Call with Me</a></h2>
<p>New service trials often result in persistent follow-ups and marketing emails, turning initial outreach into relentless sales pitches. The sales process is often tedious and time-consuming, especially in large companies, with products frequently not meeting expectations and offering limited support. Customers often switch to better open-source alternatives, leading to a quiet departure from the original service despite retention efforts. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42669754">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Small startup owners face challenges when dealing with large businesses, such as unnecessary demos, price comparisons, and lengthy procurement processes, leading to increased charges for big businesses. - The sales process is often inefficient, involving unnecessary meetings and frustrating tactics, highlighting the need for transparency, straightforward communication, and flexible options. - A successful approach involves creating a service that is easy to integrate, delights customers, and offers a simple pricing model, despite the common issues of unread documentation and unethical sales tactics. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.kenney.nl/">Kenney.nl: Free Game Assets</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42671472">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Kenney.nl is renowned for providing high-quality, free game assets that are particularly useful for game development and quick prototyping. The platform has gained a strong following, earning Kenney the nickname &quot;Asset Jesus&quot; for his contributions to the game development community. Additional resources for free game assets include OpenGameArt.org and Itch.io, while royalty-free music can be found from artists like Kevin MacLeod and Heatly Bros. </p>
<h2><a href="https://matt.might.net/articles/phd-school-in-pictures/?_nospa=true">The Illustrated Guide to a PhD</a></h2>
<p>An illustrated guide is used to explain to new Ph.D. students how a Ph.D. expands the boundary of human knowledge, symbolized as a small dent. Proceeds from the printed guide support research on genetic disorders, motivated by the author&#39;s personal connection to his son&#39;s rare condition. The guide is licensed under Creative Commons, permitting sharing with attribution, and is available in multiple languages. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42671512">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The Illustrated Guide to a PhD by Matt Might emphasizes the importance of pursuing a problem you love and the continuous quest for knowledge in the PhD journey. The discussion addresses challenges in academia, such as the pressure to publish and the risk of prioritizing quantity over quality in research. The guide highlights the value of the PhD experience for personal growth and career opportunities, stressing the importance of choosing the right advisor and exploring interdisciplinary work. </p>
<h2><a href="https://blog.djhaskin.com/blog/why-i-chose-common-lisp/">Why I Chose Common Lisp</a></h2>
<p>The author transitioned from Clojure to Common Lisp due to frustrations with Clojure&#39;s slow startup times for command-line interface (CLI) applications and perceived lack of community concern. Common Lisp was chosen for its ability to create fast-starting standalone executables, compatibility with the Vim text editor, support across Windows, Mac, and Linux, and its strong community and ecosystem. The author shares their experience to assist newcomers in understanding the benefits of Common Lisp and how they adapted to using it effectively. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42671105">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The author highlights Common Lisp&#39;s dynamic system, which allows problem-solving even without the original source code, showcasing its flexibility and robustness. SBCL, a Common Lisp implementation, is praised for enabling quick issue resolution, even in scenarios where the source code is unavailable. The discussion also covers the importance and limitations of version control, particularly when the repository is lost, and includes comparisons of Lisp with languages like Clojure and Julia. </p>
<h2><a href="https://lukaspetersson.com/blog/2025/bitter-vertical/">AI founders will learn the bitter lesson</a></h2>
<p>Historically, general AI approaches have outperformed specialized ones, as seen in fields like speech recognition and computer vision. - Richard Sutton&#39;s &quot;The Bitter Lesson&quot; emphasizes that general methods using computation are more effective than those relying on human domain knowledge. - The post suggests that AI founders should focus on creating products that leverage model improvements rather than compensating for current model limitations, as this is a more sustainable strategy. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42672790">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>AI startups encounter a fundamental challenge in providing context, as AI systems require specific information and steps to function effectively. - Successful AI startups will likely focus on ETL (Extract, Transform, Load) processes to supply necessary context, emphasizing the importance of training data and search capabilities. - The AI industry may evolve similarly to the smartphone sector, with large companies dominating due to data ownership, but startups can succeed by developing domain-specific models and managing complex systems integration and data management. </p>
<h2><a href="https://journa.host/@jeremiak/113811327999722586">Aaron Swartz and Sam Altman</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42671427">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Aaron Swartz was a renowned technical genius and activist, contributing to projects like RSS, Markdown, and Creative Commons, but faced legal challenges for downloading academic articles from JSTOR. The post contrasts Swartz&#39;s activism with Sam Altman&#39;s corporate success at OpenAI, raising questions about legality and ethics in the tech industry. The discussion highlights differing perspectives on the positive contributions of both individuals to tech culture and the disparity in legal treatment between individuals and corporations. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.digitalmars.com/articles/Cobvious.html">Obvious things C should do</a></h2>
<p>The Dlang community has integrated a C compiler within the D compiler, known as ImportC, to address unresolved issues in Standard C, now at C23. - ImportC enables functions to be executed at compile time, facilitating compile-time unit testing without the need for separate builds. - It also supports forward referencing and importing declarations without .h files, simplifying the development process. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42669637">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Header files in C distinguish between public and private interfaces, appreciated by some developers for simplicity and ease of use. - Modern tools like Rust&#39;s <code>cargo doc</code> provide efficient management of documentation and interfaces without code duplication, appealing to others. - The choice between these methods often depends on personal preference, project needs, and team workflow. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.eso.org/public/news/eso2501/">World&#39;s darkest and clearest skies at risk from industrial megaproject</a></h2>
<p>The European Southern Observatory (ESO) is worried about a proposed industrial complex by AES Andes near its Paranal Observatory in Chile, which may cause light pollution affecting astronomical research. - The Paranal Observatory is vital for projects like the Extremely Large Telescope (ELT), emphasizing the importance of preserving the dark skies. - ESO is advocating for the relocation of the industrial project to safeguard the observatory&#39;s environment. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42668953">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>An industrial megaproject in Chile, led by AES Andes, aims to produce hydrogen, electricity, and ammonia using wind and solar power, potentially impacting the world&#39;s darkest and clearest skies. Critics express concern that the project, situated near a key telescope site, could hinder astronomical observations, sparking a debate on whether to relocate the project. The situation underscores the conflict between industrial development and the preservation of unique natural resources, with some advocating for economic benefits while others prioritize environmental conservation. </p>
<h2><a href="https://eieio.games/blog/bad-apple-with-regex-in-vim/">Bad Apple but it&#39;s 6,500 regexes that I search for in Vim</a></h2>
<p>A &quot;Bad Apple&quot; video was recreated in the text editor Vim using search queries, with each of the 6,500 frames represented as a 120x90 grid of binary digits. Python was utilized to process the frames, and various algorithms were tested to optimize the search strings for better performance in Vim. The project was a creative experiment conducted at The Recurse Center, showcasing the use of Vim macros to play the video by cycling through search patterns. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42674116">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>A project using 6,500 regular expressions (regexes) in Vim to animate &quot;Bad Apple&quot; initiated a lively discussion, showcasing creative and technical prowess. Participants shared similar projects, such as running &quot;Bad Apple&quot; on a Nintendo Entertainment System (NES) and utilizing Vim macros, highlighting algorithmic challenges and tech demos. The conversation also explored the cultural impact of &quot;Bad Apple&quot; and included debates about the content of Touhou games, reflecting diverse opinions and interests. </p>
<h2><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matthewraifman.bsky.social/post/3lfaqbygva22j">Adobe Lightroom&#39;s AI Remove feature added a Bitcoin to bird in flight photo</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42670132">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Adobe Lightroom&#39;s AI Remove feature mistakenly inserted a Bitcoin image into a bird photo, prompting discussions on AI&#39;s influence in photography. - Users criticized the AI&#39;s &quot;shimmer&quot; effect, preferring the original photo, which underscores challenges in digital photography, such as managing clipped highlights and AI tool limitations. - This incident highlights broader concerns regarding AI&#39;s role in creative tools and the quality of AI-generated content. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.therepository.email/mullenweg-shuts-down-wordpress-sustainability-team-igniting-backlash">Mullenweg Shuts Down WordPress Sustainability Team, Igniting Backlash</a></h2>
<p>Matt Mullenweg, co-founder of WordPress, has disbanded the WordPress Sustainability Team, leading to significant backlash from the community. The team was dissolved following the resignation of team representative Thijs Buijs, who cited leadership issues, and Mullenweg&#39;s claim that the team was not meeting its objectives. Critics have accused Mullenweg of hypocrisy, as he initially supported the team&#39;s formation, and the disbandment has raised concerns about the future of sustainability initiatives within WordPress. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42672675">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Matt Mullenweg disbanded the WordPress Sustainability Team, leading to criticism and concerns about the impact on WordPress&#39;s brand and community. Critics highlight Mullenweg&#39;s significant control over WordPress as problematic, suggesting a potential need for changes in governance. The disbanded team was working on initiatives such as a carbon footprint plugin, raising questions about WordPress&#39;s commitment to sustainability and leadership stability. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.potaroo.net/ispcol/2025-01/addr2024.html">IP addresses through 2024</a></h2>
<p>The article by Geoff Huston provides an annual update on IP addresses, focusing on the slow transition from IPv4 to IPv6 despite the predicted need for a larger address space. It discusses the exhaustion of IPv4 addresses, the role of address transfers, and challenges in adopting IPv6, highlighting the fragmentation and market dynamics of IPv4 addresses. The piece examines IPv6 allocation trends, noting regional differences and the impact of large allocations, and reflects on broader implications for the Internet&#39;s future, including network neutrality and market consolidation. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42670468">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The discussion highlights the vastness of IPv6 address space compared to IPv4, noting that IPv6 provides significantly more addresses. - Concerns are raised about inefficient allocation practices, with large corporations receiving excessively large IPv6 blocks, which could lead to future shortages. - Challenges in IPv6 adoption are discussed, including technical limitations and companies&#39; reluctance to allow direct device connections, alongside ongoing issues with IPv4 scarcity and market pricing dynamics. </p>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Stop Trying to Schedule a Call with Me" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Stop%20Trying%20to%20Schedule%20a%20Call%20with%20Me&subheading=Sunday%2C%20January%2012%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/12</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-12T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-11]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/11&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-11</h1>
<h2><a href="https://blog.yossarian.net/2025/01/10/Be-aware-of-the-Makefile-effect">Be Aware of the Makefile Effect</a></h2>
<p>The &quot;Makefile effect&quot; describes the practice of engineers copying and modifying existing complex configurations, like Makefiles, instead of creating new ones from scratch. - This approach is prevalent in various systems, such as Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment (CI/CD) configurations and build systems, and can indicate overly complex or poorly designed tools. - While not inherently negative, the Makefile effect can impede learning, complicate security, and lead to inefficient debugging, highlighting the need for thoughtful tool design that considers configurability and ease of use. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42663231">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The &quot;Makefile Effect&quot; describes developers&#39; tendency to copy and modify code or configurations without fully understanding them, often due to tool complexity or infrequent use. This phenomenon is widespread across programming and configuration tasks, where developers use known solutions to save time and effort, potentially leading to difficult-to-maintain code. The discussion emphasizes the need to balance using templates and existing solutions with gaining a deeper understanding of the tools and systems involved. </p>
<h2><a href="https://30fps.net/pages/pvs-portals-and-quake/">Portals and Quake</a></h2>
<p>The article is the first in the &quot;Demystifying the PVS&quot; series, focusing on Quake&#39;s precomputed visibility system to address overdraw, where pixels are rendered multiple times. - Quake uses portal culling and potentially visible sets (PVS) by dividing the world into cells and portals, precomputing visibility to optimize rendering. - The article introduces the Portal and Leaf classes in vis.py, a Python reimplementation of Quake&#39;s visibility algorithm, highlighting the use of a leaf-to-leaf visibility matrix. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42661185">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Quake level designers utilized &quot;hint&quot; brushes and &quot;area portals&quot; to optimize game performance, a technique that has been foundational in 3D graphics. - Games like Prey and Portal brought portals into the spotlight for gameplay mechanics, though the concept has been used in rendering since early 3D graphics. - Unreal Engine 1 employed zones for optimization, and contemporary engines like Unreal Engine 5 continue to use similar methods to enhance rendering efficiency. </p>
<h2><a href="https://unsloth.ai/blog/phi4">Phi-4 Bug Fixes</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42660335">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Daniel Hanchen discovered and addressed bugs in Microsoft&#39;s Phi-4 Large Language Model (LLM), such as sentence-ending issues and chat template prompts. - He converted Phi-4 to the Llama architecture, enhancing performance, and shared the fixes on Hugging Face, a platform for machine learning models. - A Colab notebook for finetuning Phi-4 is available, and while the fixes improved performance on some benchmarks, they decreased it on others; the Phi-4 team is working to integrate these improvements into the original model. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.charlespetzold.com/blog/2025/01/Very-Wrong-Math.html">Very Wrong Math</a></h2>
<p>A design and construction company made a math error on Facebook, incorrectly calculating the Earth&#39;s radius as 4,333 feet, leading to a vastly underestimated circumference of just over 5 miles. The error stemmed from calculating arc lengths without using the Earth&#39;s actual radius, which is approximately 3,959 miles. The post highlighted that the outer arc was less than 1% longer than the inner arc, suggesting a potential reduction in flight time due to decreased air resistance. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42661432">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>A YouTube builder incorrectly claimed that plumb lines would be parallel on a flat Earth, misunderstanding the Earth&#39;s curvature, which is negligible in such measurements. - The discussion highlighted the failure of intuition in understanding large-scale concepts and addressed flat Earth theories, gravity misconceptions, and Earth&#39;s rotation effects on flight. - The conversation humorously examined the persistence of incorrect beliefs and the difficulty of explaining scientific concepts to those who reject established science. </p>
<h2><a href="https://ianthehenry.com/posts/bauble/building-bauble/">Building Bauble</a></h2>
<p>Bauble is a 3D modeling and rendering tool that utilizes signed distance functions (SDFs) to create complex shapes and animations. - Initially a basic system for generating GLSL shaders, Bauble has been rewritten to include features like 3D model export, interactive editing, and custom lighting. - The tool now supports web embedding, interactive vector editing, and offers comprehensive documentation, making it accessible for creative projects and users interested in 3D design. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42660942">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Building Bauble, a project featured on ianthehenry.com, has generated excitement by showcasing the magic and enjoyment of programming, particularly in coding and graphics. The project is praised for its creativity and detailed writeup, inspiring readers to revisit unfinished projects and explore new technologies such as Janet (a programming language) and GLSL (OpenGL Shading Language). Despite some technical issues on Safari, the project is celebrated for its impressive execution and engaging development story, sparking discussions about personal projects and the use of RSS readers. </p>
<h2><a href="https://research.google/blog/extra-extra-read-all-about-it-nearly-all-binary-searches-and-mergesorts-are-broken/">Nearly all binary searches and mergesorts are broken (2006)</a></h2>
<p>In 2006, Joshua Bloch identified a bug in the binary search algorithm, initially noted in Jon Bentley&#39;s &quot;Programming Pearls,&quot; where an overflow occurs when &#39;low&#39; and &#39;high&#39; exceed the maximum int value. This bug, affecting arrays with lengths of 2^30 or more, was rare in the 1980s but is more common today, also impacting mergesort and other divide-and-conquer algorithms. Bloch recommends fixing the issue by calculating the midpoint as <code>int mid = low + ((high - low) / 2);</code>, highlighting the challenges of writing error-free code and the necessity of thorough testing. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42664400">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Many binary searches and mergesorts are prone to integer overflow issues, especially in older implementations, as highlighted in a 2006 article.&quot; The article emphasizes the importance of considering edge cases and hardware limitations in programming, which remains relevant today.&quot; Developers are advised to use built-in functions or larger integer types to prevent such bugs, underscoring the need for caution with data types and input sizes.&quot; </p>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/hybridgroup/go-haystack">Track your devices via Apple FindMy network in Go/TinyGo</a></h2>
<p>Go Haystack enables tracking of personal Bluetooth devices via Apple&#39;s &quot;Find My&quot; network without requiring Apple hardware, utilizing OpenHaystack and Macless-Haystack with Go/TinyGo tools. Users can create their own beacons using TinyGo firmware on hardware like Adafruit Bluefruit boards and BBC Microbit, with setup requiring an Apple ID with two-factor authentication (2FA). The process involves installing the go-haystack tool, using commands like <code>haystack scan</code> to locate devices, generating keys, flashing the device, and uploading a JSON file to macless-haystack for device visibility in the web UI. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42665367">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The Apple FindMy network can be utilized with Go/TinyGo to track devices, offering a way to expand the network without needing an Apple account. Privacy concerns are mitigated by Apple&#39;s design, and the company has a strong reputation for maintaining user privacy, although some users remain wary of potential surveillance. The FindMy network operates in two parts: Apple devices locating items and user devices uploading location data to Apple, with an option for users to disable the feature if desired. </p>
<h2><a href="https://lwn.net/SubscriberLink/1002342/a8d8a17f30968b93/">The State of Vim</a></h2>
<p>Following the passing of Vim founder Bram Moolenaar in 2023, the Vim community has reorganized to ensure the project&#39;s continued development, with Christian Brabandt as the current maintainer. - At VimConf 2024, it was discussed that the team has expanded, focusing on updating the Vim website, managing security, and enhancing communication channels. - Vim remains in maintenance mode, prioritizing community needs and integrating new features carefully, while continuing to support ICCF Holland, a charity established by Moolenaar. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42665222">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>Long-time Vim users are reflecting on the editor&#39;s future following the passing of its creator, Bram Moolenaar, with some content with its current stability and others exploring alternatives like Neovim for modern features. Neovim is gaining attention for its support of Lua scripting and modern enhancements, while some users are considering Emacs due to perceived fragmentation between Vim and Neovim. Discussions among users include topics like Treesitter&#39;s performance, Language Server Protocol (LSP) support, and comparisons with Visual Studio Code (VSCode), highlighting the flexibility and stability of these editors. </p>
<h2><a href="https://www.cs.cornell.edu/~asampson/blog/flattening.html">Flattening ASTs and other compiler data structures (2023)</a></h2>
<p>The post discusses data structure flattening, a technique for compilers that optimizes abstract syntax trees (ASTs) by using a single array with indices instead of pointers. - This method enhances performance by improving memory locality, reducing reference size, and simplifying memory management, resulting in a 2.4× speedup in a microbenchmark. - The technique is notably used in Rust projects and offers ergonomic benefits, such as easier memory management, and is compared to bytecode interpreters for further performance improvements. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42659061">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The discussion focuses on optimizing Abstract Syntax Trees (ASTs) by storing them in flat, contiguous arrays to improve performance and memory efficiency. This method enhances cache locality and simplifies memory management, drawing comparisons to techniques in languages like Lisp and the Zig compiler. The conversation also references historical methods and similar techniques in other programming languages, emphasizing the benefits of flat data structures for composability and ease of manipulation. </p>
<h2><a href="https://tomscii.sig7.se/2025/01/De-smarting-the-Marshall-Uxbridge">De-smarting the Marshall Uxbridge Bluetooth speaker</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42666572">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>The discussion focuses on modifying the Marshall Uxbridge Bluetooth speaker to eliminate its &quot;smart&quot; features, involving technical aspects like designing a Printed Circuit Board (PCB) for digital I2S input. Users debate the role of Digital Signal Processing (DSP) in achieving good sound quality, with some emphasizing its necessity to compensate for hardware limitations. The conversation also covers the challenges of modifying smart devices and the affordability of modern PCB production and components. </p>
<h2><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2025/01/10/how-openais-bot-crushed-this-seven-person-companys-web-site-like-a-ddos-attack/">OpenAI&#39;s bot crushed this seven-person company&#39;s web site &#39;like a DDoS attack&#39;</a></h2>
<p>Triplegangers&#39; e-commerce site experienced a DDoS-like attack due to OpenAI&#39;s bot making tens of thousands of requests to scrape over 65,000 product pages. - The site lacked a properly configured robots.txt file to block such bots, leading to increased AWS costs and concerns about data security. - This incident underscores the importance of AI companies obtaining permission before data scraping and serves as a warning for small businesses to monitor for AI bot activity. </p>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42660377">Reactions</a></h3>
<p>OpenAI&#39;s bot caused excessive traffic on a small company&#39;s website, similar to a Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) attack, highlighting issues with AI bots overwhelming websites. Companies like Read the Docs have experienced similar challenges with AI bots generating massive traffic, despite using &quot;robots.txt&quot; to manage web crawlers. The incident underscores the ongoing debate on balancing web accessibility with protection against aggressive data scraping by AI companies, as some bots ignore &quot;robots.txt,&quot; leading to potential legal and financial issues for small site owners. </p>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Be Aware of the Makefile Effect" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Be%20Aware%20of%20the%20Makefile%20Effect&subheading=Saturday%2C%20January%2011%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/11</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-11T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
