<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0"
>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 19:11:49 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/newsletter/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <copyright><![CDATA[2023 Sunghyun Cho]]></copyright>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-13]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/13&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-13</h1>
<h2><a href="https://valatka.dev/2025/01/12/on-killer-uv-feature.html">Uv&#39;s killer feature is making ad-hoc environments easy</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Uv offers a unique feature that simplifies ad-hoc scripting in Python by streamlining dependency and environment management. - Users can execute a single command, <code>uv run --python 3.12 --with pandas python</code>, to run scripts without altering the global environment. - This ease of use and memorability makes uv an attractive option for Python package management.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42676432">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Uv is a package manager that simplifies managing Python dependencies and versions, offering advantages over traditional tools like pip, pyenv, and poetry. - It features inline script dependencies, rapid environment creation, and pre-compiled Python binaries, contributing to its popularity. - Despite concerns about its venture capital backing and reliance on non-Python Software Foundation (PSF) binaries, users value its speed and user-friendliness for Python project management.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://asylumsquare.com/backstage/2025-01-12/why-i-deleted-my-social-media-accounts">I deleted my social media accounts</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author deleted their social media accounts due to concerns about platforms like Meta and Twitter prioritizing profit over ethical considerations.</li>
<li>Highlighted issues include Mark Zuckerberg&#39;s decision to drop fact-checkers and collaborate with Trump, and Elon Musk&#39;s controversial actions, contributing to a toxic environment.</li>
<li>The author emphasizes the negative impact of social media on mental health, particularly for teenagers, and is exploring alternatives like blogging and new platforms cautiously.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42677587">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Deleting social media accounts can result in missing life updates from acquaintances, highlighting the platform&#39;s role in maintaining connections.</li>
<li>While some believe important relationships will persist through direct communication, social media often facilitates shallow connections that may be lost when quitting.</li>
<li>The choice to leave social media is subjective, influenced by personal priorities and the value placed on different types of relationships.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://medhir.com/blog/right-to-root-access">Right to root access</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Consumers should have the right to install any software on devices they own, but companies often lock bootloaders and restrict root access, limiting user control. - While security is a valid concern, these restrictions are seen as anti-consumer and anti-competitive, contributing to e-waste and limiting repair options. - Advocates suggest that a &quot;right to root access&quot; should be included in right to repair discussions, with exceptions for critical systems where risks are too high.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42677835">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The debate on root access in devices underscores the conflict between consumer freedom and vendor control, with many advocating for the right to install any software on owned devices. - Critics argue that vendor-imposed restrictions prioritize profit over consumer control and privacy, limiting users&#39; ability to modify their devices. - The discussion extends to broader themes of property rights and the autonomy to manage one&#39;s own devices, with differing views on the security benefits of locked devices versus informed consumer choice.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://doompdf.pages.dev/doom.pdf">Doom (1993) in a PDF</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A developer has created a Doom source port that operates within a PDF file, inspired by a similar Tetris project. - The project uses an older version of Emscripten to compile C code to asm.js, allowing it to run in the PDF&#39;s JavaScript runtime. - The implementation includes a 6-color monochrome display and is compatible only with Chromium-based browsers using the PDFium engine.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42678754">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A developer has created a Doom source port that operates within a PDF file, following a similar project that ran Tetris in a PDF. - The project uses Emscripten to compile C to asm.js, allowing it to run in the PDF&#39;s limited JavaScript runtime, and employs the doomgeneric fork of the original Doom source. - This innovation has sparked discussions about the potential and security implications of executing code within PDFs, with the source code available on GitHub and functionality limited to Chromium-based browsers using the PDFium engine.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://dwheeler.com/essays/debugging-agans.html">Debugging: Indispensable rules for finding even the most elusive problems (2004)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>David A. Wheeler reviews &quot;Debugging: The 9 Indispensable Rules for Finding Even the Most Elusive Software and Hardware Problems&quot; by David J. Agans, highlighting it as a classic resource for developers.</li>
<li>The book emphasizes fundamental debugging principles applicable to both novice and experienced developers, using practical examples and real-life &quot;war stories&quot; to illustrate its nine key rules.</li>
<li>Wheeler commends the book for its focus on data gathering and handling intermittent problems, though he notes a desire for more specific tool advice, ultimately recommending it for its timeless debugging insights.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42682602">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Debugging is essential for resolving complex issues, emphasizing the importance of staying calm, understanding the system, and verifying assumptions. - Tools like <code>git bisect</code> can aid in efficient problem-solving by identifying the specific change that introduced a bug. - It&#39;s important to verify fixes and consider writing tests to prevent future regressions, highlighting the need for a systematic approach and sometimes using techniques like rubber duck debugging.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://movies.stackexchange.com/questions/79161/how-did-they-make-cars-fall-apart-in-old-movies">How did they make cars fall apart in old movies (2017)</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42679127">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>In older films, practical effects were used to make cars fall apart, as seen in the 1965 French film &quot;Le Corniaud,&quot; where a car was disassembled and reassembled with hooks and explosive bolts for a scene.</li>
<li>These stunts required detailed planning and engineering, facilitated by the simpler construction of cars at the time.</li>
<li>Modern films would likely use CGI (Computer-Generated Imagery) for similar scenes due to the complexity and safety standards of contemporary vehicles.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://heterogenoustasks.wordpress.com/2015/01/26/standard-patterns-in-choice-based-games/">Standard patterns in choice-based games (2015)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The blog post by Sam Kabo Ashwell explores recurring design patterns in choice-based games, including Time Cave, Gauntlet, Branch and Bottleneck, and others, which affect gameplay and narrative structure.</li>
<li>These patterns influence player experience and story progression, with examples from interactive fiction illustrating their application.</li>
<li>The post notes that these patterns are flexible and can overlap, rather than being strict categories in game design.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42678647">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Choice-based games use narrative branching to enhance player agency, but this can lead to &quot;Time Caves,&quot; where some paths are overly detailed, and others are underdeveloped, causing players to miss key content.</li>
<li>Tools can assist in creating a main story trunk with side paths that rejoin, but branching remains complex and resource-intensive, prompting some to advocate for linear stories or sandbox mechanics.</li>
<li>Games like Disco Elysium and Nier Automata are noted for their successful use of branching, and there is discussion on AI&#39;s potential to dynamically generate story paths, though current technology may not yet achieve coherent narratives.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://thefreemovie.buzz/">The Free Movie: Frame-by-frame, handrawn reproduction of &quot;The Bee Movie&quot; (2023)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>MSCHF Interactive has launched &quot;The FREE Movie,&quot; a collaborative project where users recreate the BEE Movie frame-by-frame, with 92% of frames already completed.</li>
<li>Participants can actively engage by drawing, erasing, and previewing their contributions to the project.</li>
<li>The next ambitious project planned by MSCHF Interactive is a frame-by-frame recreation of the movie DUNE.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42678584">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A fan-made, frame-by-frame hand-drawn version of &quot;The Bee Movie&quot; has been created, following the trend of collaborative projects like &quot;Shrek Retold&quot; and &quot;Star Wars Uncut.&quot;</li>
<li>These projects involve multiple creators contributing short segments, leading to a mix of quality and humorous results, reflecting a meme-centric approach.</li>
<li>Opinions on &quot;The Free Movie&quot; vary, with some viewers finding the low-quality frames off-putting, while others enjoy the chaotic and crowd-sourced nature of the project.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="http://134.0.119.41">Disco Elysium Explorer</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Disco Elysium Explorer Project allows users to visualize and listen to dialogues from the game Disco Elysium, with all rights reserved by the studio ZA/UM. - The project offers features such as searching dialogues, building conversations, and visualizing them, enhancing the interactive experience. - It supports multiple languages, including Chinese, German, and Korean, making it accessible to a broader audience.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42679679">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Disco Elysium utilizes Articy:draft, a middleware tool, to construct its complex conversation graphs, showcasing a technical achievement despite performance challenges on large projects.</li>
<li>The game is acclaimed for its storytelling and intricate dialogue systems, drawing comparisons to other narrative-focused games like Pentiment and Alpha Protocol.</li>
<li>Notable for its unique RPG mechanics that emphasize dialogue and story over combat, Disco Elysium garners mixed opinions on its political themes but is recognized as a significant accomplishment in story-driven gaming.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.jamesshore.com/v2/blog/2025/the-best-product-engineering-org-in-the-world">If we had the best product engineering organization, what would it look like?</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The keynote at the Regional Scrum Gathering Tokyo by the VP of Engineering focused on key elements of a successful product engineering organization: People, Internal Quality, Lovability, Visibility, Agility, and Profitability.</li>
<li>Emphasized the importance of attracting top talent, maintaining internal quality by reducing waste, and ensuring product lovability by understanding stakeholder needs.</li>
<li>Highlighted the use of Extreme Programming (XP) and Fluid Scaling Technology (FaST) to enhance agility and adaptability, while aligning products with business goals for profitability.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42676123">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion explores the characteristics of an ideal product engineering organization, focusing on management styles, decision-making processes, and productivity. - Opinions vary, with some advocating for distributed decision-making over hierarchical structures, while others emphasize the importance of CEOs in making decisive choices. - The conversation also addresses the challenges of measuring productivity and the influence of organizational culture on innovation and employee satisfaction, referencing companies like Meta and Amazon as examples.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://traintimes.org.uk/map/tube/">Live London Underground / bus maps taken down by TfL trademark complaint</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>In June 2010, a live London Underground map was created using Transport for London&#39;s (TfL) open data API, gaining popularity and media attention.</li>
<li>On January 7, 2025, TfL requested the removal of the map due to trademark concerns, leading to its discontinuation despite potential adjustments.</li>
<li>The creator&#39;s site, traintimes.org.uk, remains active, and live bus information is available on bustimes.org.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42682876">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Transport for London (TfL) removed live London Underground and bus maps from the website traintimes.org.uk following a trademark complaint. - The complaint email from TfL was criticized for its lack of clarity and for referencing U.S. law, despite the website being based in the UK. - The incident underscores ongoing tensions between hobbyist developers and trademark enforcement, with debates on whether TfL should provide free licenses for non-commercial use.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.qubes-os.org/">Qubes OS: A reasonably secure operating system</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Qubes OS is a highly secure operating system endorsed by experts, including Edward Snowden, for its strong isolation capabilities, making it suitable for sensitive tasks. - It supports running multiple operating systems and integrates with Whonix to enhance user privacy, appealing to journalists and organizations like the Freedom of the Press Foundation. - The Qubes community is welcoming to newcomers, providing support, resources, and opportunities to contribute or donate.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42677608">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Qubes OS is a security-focused operating system that uses virtualization to compartmentalize tasks, enhancing security by isolating applications and tasks. - Users have reported issues with graphics performance and battery life due to its reliance on software rendering, impacting video playback and overall system performance. - While praised for its security features, Qubes OS may not be suitable for users with high graphics or battery demands, though it is recommended for those needing high security, such as journalists or IT security professionals.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://surfingcomplexity.blog/2024/12/21/the-canva-outage-another-tale-of-saturation-and-resilience/">The Canva outage: another tale of saturation and resilience</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Canva outage was caused by a deployment of a new editor page version, leading to a &quot;thundering herd&quot; effect with 1.5 million requests per second overwhelming the API Gateway. - A stale traffic rule routed user traffic over the public internet, causing high latency and a backlog, while a known performance issue in the API Gateway worsened the situation. - Canva engineers manually intervened by increasing capacity and using Cloudflare&#39;s firewall to block traffic temporarily, highlighting the importance of human intervention in managing system performance issues during crises.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42676529">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Canva outage underscores challenges with Content Delivery Network (CDN) saturation and resilience, common when many users access servers simultaneously, leading to overloads. - Proposed solutions like tiered distribution and preheating often fall short, while P2P (Peer-to-Peer) protocols like BitTorrent face piracy and control concerns, leading companies like Spotify and Blizzard to abandon them. - Effective load management strategies, such as capping connections and using exponential backoff, are crucial for mitigating these issues, highlighting the importance of robust infrastructure and strategic planning for handling high traffic efficiently.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Uv's killer feature is making ad-hoc environments easy" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Uv's%20killer%20feature%20is%20making%20ad-hoc%20environments%20easy&subheading=Monday%2C%20January%2013%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/13</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-13T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-12]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/12&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-12</h1>
<h2><a href="https://matduggan.com/stop-trying-to-schedule-a-call-with-me/">Stop Trying to Schedule a Call with Me</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>New service trials often result in persistent follow-ups and marketing emails, turning initial outreach into relentless sales pitches.</li>
<li>The sales process is often tedious and time-consuming, especially in large companies, with products frequently not meeting expectations and offering limited support.</li>
<li>Customers often switch to better open-source alternatives, leading to a quiet departure from the original service despite retention efforts.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42669754">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Small startup owners face challenges when dealing with large businesses, such as unnecessary demos, price comparisons, and lengthy procurement processes, leading to increased charges for big businesses. - The sales process is often inefficient, involving unnecessary meetings and frustrating tactics, highlighting the need for transparency, straightforward communication, and flexible options. - A successful approach involves creating a service that is easy to integrate, delights customers, and offers a simple pricing model, despite the common issues of unread documentation and unethical sales tactics.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.kenney.nl/">Kenney.nl: Free Game Assets</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42671472">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Kenney.nl is renowned for providing high-quality, free game assets that are particularly useful for game development and quick prototyping.</li>
<li>The platform has gained a strong following, earning Kenney the nickname &quot;Asset Jesus&quot; for his contributions to the game development community.</li>
<li>Additional resources for free game assets include OpenGameArt.org and Itch.io, while royalty-free music can be found from artists like Kevin MacLeod and Heatly Bros.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://matt.might.net/articles/phd-school-in-pictures/?_nospa=true">The Illustrated Guide to a PhD</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>An illustrated guide is used to explain to new Ph.D. students how a Ph.D. expands the boundary of human knowledge, symbolized as a small dent.</li>
<li>Proceeds from the printed guide support research on genetic disorders, motivated by the author&#39;s personal connection to his son&#39;s rare condition.</li>
<li>The guide is licensed under Creative Commons, permitting sharing with attribution, and is available in multiple languages.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42671512">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Illustrated Guide to a PhD by Matt Might emphasizes the importance of pursuing a problem you love and the continuous quest for knowledge in the PhD journey.</li>
<li>The discussion addresses challenges in academia, such as the pressure to publish and the risk of prioritizing quantity over quality in research.</li>
<li>The guide highlights the value of the PhD experience for personal growth and career opportunities, stressing the importance of choosing the right advisor and exploring interdisciplinary work.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.djhaskin.com/blog/why-i-chose-common-lisp/">Why I Chose Common Lisp</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author transitioned from Clojure to Common Lisp due to frustrations with Clojure&#39;s slow startup times for command-line interface (CLI) applications and perceived lack of community concern.</li>
<li>Common Lisp was chosen for its ability to create fast-starting standalone executables, compatibility with the Vim text editor, support across Windows, Mac, and Linux, and its strong community and ecosystem.</li>
<li>The author shares their experience to assist newcomers in understanding the benefits of Common Lisp and how they adapted to using it effectively.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42671105">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The author highlights Common Lisp&#39;s dynamic system, which allows problem-solving even without the original source code, showcasing its flexibility and robustness.</li>
<li>SBCL, a Common Lisp implementation, is praised for enabling quick issue resolution, even in scenarios where the source code is unavailable.</li>
<li>The discussion also covers the importance and limitations of version control, particularly when the repository is lost, and includes comparisons of Lisp with languages like Clojure and Julia.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://lukaspetersson.com/blog/2025/bitter-vertical/">AI founders will learn the bitter lesson</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Historically, general AI approaches have outperformed specialized ones, as seen in fields like speech recognition and computer vision. - Richard Sutton&#39;s &quot;The Bitter Lesson&quot; emphasizes that general methods using computation are more effective than those relying on human domain knowledge. - The post suggests that AI founders should focus on creating products that leverage model improvements rather than compensating for current model limitations, as this is a more sustainable strategy.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42672790">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>AI startups encounter a fundamental challenge in providing context, as AI systems require specific information and steps to function effectively. - Successful AI startups will likely focus on ETL (Extract, Transform, Load) processes to supply necessary context, emphasizing the importance of training data and search capabilities. - The AI industry may evolve similarly to the smartphone sector, with large companies dominating due to data ownership, but startups can succeed by developing domain-specific models and managing complex systems integration and data management.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://journa.host/@jeremiak/113811327999722586">Aaron Swartz and Sam Altman</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42671427">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Aaron Swartz was a renowned technical genius and activist, contributing to projects like RSS, Markdown, and Creative Commons, but faced legal challenges for downloading academic articles from JSTOR.</li>
<li>The post contrasts Swartz&#39;s activism with Sam Altman&#39;s corporate success at OpenAI, raising questions about legality and ethics in the tech industry.</li>
<li>The discussion highlights differing perspectives on the positive contributions of both individuals to tech culture and the disparity in legal treatment between individuals and corporations.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.digitalmars.com/articles/Cobvious.html">Obvious things C should do</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Dlang community has integrated a C compiler within the D compiler, known as ImportC, to address unresolved issues in Standard C, now at C23. - ImportC enables functions to be executed at compile time, facilitating compile-time unit testing without the need for separate builds. - It also supports forward referencing and importing declarations without .h files, simplifying the development process.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42669637">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Header files in C distinguish between public and private interfaces, appreciated by some developers for simplicity and ease of use. - Modern tools like Rust&#39;s <code>cargo doc</code> provide efficient management of documentation and interfaces without code duplication, appealing to others. - The choice between these methods often depends on personal preference, project needs, and team workflow.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.eso.org/public/news/eso2501/">World&#39;s darkest and clearest skies at risk from industrial megaproject</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The European Southern Observatory (ESO) is worried about a proposed industrial complex by AES Andes near its Paranal Observatory in Chile, which may cause light pollution affecting astronomical research. - The Paranal Observatory is vital for projects like the Extremely Large Telescope (ELT), emphasizing the importance of preserving the dark skies. - ESO is advocating for the relocation of the industrial project to safeguard the observatory&#39;s environment.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42668953">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>An industrial megaproject in Chile, led by AES Andes, aims to produce hydrogen, electricity, and ammonia using wind and solar power, potentially impacting the world&#39;s darkest and clearest skies.</li>
<li>Critics express concern that the project, situated near a key telescope site, could hinder astronomical observations, sparking a debate on whether to relocate the project.</li>
<li>The situation underscores the conflict between industrial development and the preservation of unique natural resources, with some advocating for economic benefits while others prioritize environmental conservation.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://eieio.games/blog/bad-apple-with-regex-in-vim/">Bad Apple but it&#39;s 6,500 regexes that I search for in Vim</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A &quot;Bad Apple&quot; video was recreated in the text editor Vim using search queries, with each of the 6,500 frames represented as a 120x90 grid of binary digits.</li>
<li>Python was utilized to process the frames, and various algorithms were tested to optimize the search strings for better performance in Vim.</li>
<li>The project was a creative experiment conducted at The Recurse Center, showcasing the use of Vim macros to play the video by cycling through search patterns.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42674116">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A project using 6,500 regular expressions (regexes) in Vim to animate &quot;Bad Apple&quot; initiated a lively discussion, showcasing creative and technical prowess.</li>
<li>Participants shared similar projects, such as running &quot;Bad Apple&quot; on a Nintendo Entertainment System (NES) and utilizing Vim macros, highlighting algorithmic challenges and tech demos.</li>
<li>The conversation also explored the cultural impact of &quot;Bad Apple&quot; and included debates about the content of Touhou games, reflecting diverse opinions and interests.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/matthewraifman.bsky.social/post/3lfaqbygva22j">Adobe Lightroom&#39;s AI Remove feature added a Bitcoin to bird in flight photo</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42670132">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Adobe Lightroom&#39;s AI Remove feature mistakenly inserted a Bitcoin image into a bird photo, prompting discussions on AI&#39;s influence in photography. - Users criticized the AI&#39;s &quot;shimmer&quot; effect, preferring the original photo, which underscores challenges in digital photography, such as managing clipped highlights and AI tool limitations. - This incident highlights broader concerns regarding AI&#39;s role in creative tools and the quality of AI-generated content.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.therepository.email/mullenweg-shuts-down-wordpress-sustainability-team-igniting-backlash">Mullenweg Shuts Down WordPress Sustainability Team, Igniting Backlash</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Matt Mullenweg, co-founder of WordPress, has disbanded the WordPress Sustainability Team, leading to significant backlash from the community.</li>
<li>The team was dissolved following the resignation of team representative Thijs Buijs, who cited leadership issues, and Mullenweg&#39;s claim that the team was not meeting its objectives.</li>
<li>Critics have accused Mullenweg of hypocrisy, as he initially supported the team&#39;s formation, and the disbandment has raised concerns about the future of sustainability initiatives within WordPress.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42672675">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Matt Mullenweg disbanded the WordPress Sustainability Team, leading to criticism and concerns about the impact on WordPress&#39;s brand and community.</li>
<li>Critics highlight Mullenweg&#39;s significant control over WordPress as problematic, suggesting a potential need for changes in governance.</li>
<li>The disbanded team was working on initiatives such as a carbon footprint plugin, raising questions about WordPress&#39;s commitment to sustainability and leadership stability.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.potaroo.net/ispcol/2025-01/addr2024.html">IP addresses through 2024</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article by Geoff Huston provides an annual update on IP addresses, focusing on the slow transition from IPv4 to IPv6 despite the predicted need for a larger address space.</li>
<li>It discusses the exhaustion of IPv4 addresses, the role of address transfers, and challenges in adopting IPv6, highlighting the fragmentation and market dynamics of IPv4 addresses.</li>
<li>The piece examines IPv6 allocation trends, noting regional differences and the impact of large allocations, and reflects on broader implications for the Internet&#39;s future, including network neutrality and market consolidation.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42670468">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion highlights the vastness of IPv6 address space compared to IPv4, noting that IPv6 provides significantly more addresses. - Concerns are raised about inefficient allocation practices, with large corporations receiving excessively large IPv6 blocks, which could lead to future shortages. - Challenges in IPv6 adoption are discussed, including technical limitations and companies&#39; reluctance to allow direct device connections, alongside ongoing issues with IPv4 scarcity and market pricing dynamics.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Stop Trying to Schedule a Call with Me" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Stop%20Trying%20to%20Schedule%20a%20Call%20with%20Me&subheading=Sunday%2C%20January%2012%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/12</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-12T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-11]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/11&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-11</h1>
<h2><a href="https://blog.yossarian.net/2025/01/10/Be-aware-of-the-Makefile-effect">Be Aware of the Makefile Effect</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The &quot;Makefile effect&quot; describes the practice of engineers copying and modifying existing complex configurations, like Makefiles, instead of creating new ones from scratch. - This approach is prevalent in various systems, such as Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment (CI/CD) configurations and build systems, and can indicate overly complex or poorly designed tools. - While not inherently negative, the Makefile effect can impede learning, complicate security, and lead to inefficient debugging, highlighting the need for thoughtful tool design that considers configurability and ease of use.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42663231">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The &quot;Makefile Effect&quot; describes developers&#39; tendency to copy and modify code or configurations without fully understanding them, often due to tool complexity or infrequent use.</li>
<li>This phenomenon is widespread across programming and configuration tasks, where developers use known solutions to save time and effort, potentially leading to difficult-to-maintain code.</li>
<li>The discussion emphasizes the need to balance using templates and existing solutions with gaining a deeper understanding of the tools and systems involved.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://30fps.net/pages/pvs-portals-and-quake/">Portals and Quake</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article is the first in the &quot;Demystifying the PVS&quot; series, focusing on Quake&#39;s precomputed visibility system to address overdraw, where pixels are rendered multiple times. - Quake uses portal culling and potentially visible sets (PVS) by dividing the world into cells and portals, precomputing visibility to optimize rendering. - The article introduces the Portal and Leaf classes in vis.py, a Python reimplementation of Quake&#39;s visibility algorithm, highlighting the use of a leaf-to-leaf visibility matrix.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42661185">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Quake level designers utilized &quot;hint&quot; brushes and &quot;area portals&quot; to optimize game performance, a technique that has been foundational in 3D graphics. - Games like Prey and Portal brought portals into the spotlight for gameplay mechanics, though the concept has been used in rendering since early 3D graphics. - Unreal Engine 1 employed zones for optimization, and contemporary engines like Unreal Engine 5 continue to use similar methods to enhance rendering efficiency.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://unsloth.ai/blog/phi4">Phi-4 Bug Fixes</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42660335">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Daniel Hanchen discovered and addressed bugs in Microsoft&#39;s Phi-4 Large Language Model (LLM), such as sentence-ending issues and chat template prompts. - He converted Phi-4 to the Llama architecture, enhancing performance, and shared the fixes on Hugging Face, a platform for machine learning models. - A Colab notebook for finetuning Phi-4 is available, and while the fixes improved performance on some benchmarks, they decreased it on others; the Phi-4 team is working to integrate these improvements into the original model.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.charlespetzold.com/blog/2025/01/Very-Wrong-Math.html">Very Wrong Math</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A design and construction company made a math error on Facebook, incorrectly calculating the Earth&#39;s radius as 4,333 feet, leading to a vastly underestimated circumference of just over 5 miles.</li>
<li>The error stemmed from calculating arc lengths without using the Earth&#39;s actual radius, which is approximately 3,959 miles.</li>
<li>The post highlighted that the outer arc was less than 1% longer than the inner arc, suggesting a potential reduction in flight time due to decreased air resistance.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42661432">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A YouTube builder incorrectly claimed that plumb lines would be parallel on a flat Earth, misunderstanding the Earth&#39;s curvature, which is negligible in such measurements. - The discussion highlighted the failure of intuition in understanding large-scale concepts and addressed flat Earth theories, gravity misconceptions, and Earth&#39;s rotation effects on flight. - The conversation humorously examined the persistence of incorrect beliefs and the difficulty of explaining scientific concepts to those who reject established science.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://ianthehenry.com/posts/bauble/building-bauble/">Building Bauble</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Bauble is a 3D modeling and rendering tool that utilizes signed distance functions (SDFs) to create complex shapes and animations. - Initially a basic system for generating GLSL shaders, Bauble has been rewritten to include features like 3D model export, interactive editing, and custom lighting. - The tool now supports web embedding, interactive vector editing, and offers comprehensive documentation, making it accessible for creative projects and users interested in 3D design.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42660942">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Building Bauble, a project featured on ianthehenry.com, has generated excitement by showcasing the magic and enjoyment of programming, particularly in coding and graphics.</li>
<li>The project is praised for its creativity and detailed writeup, inspiring readers to revisit unfinished projects and explore new technologies such as Janet (a programming language) and GLSL (OpenGL Shading Language).</li>
<li>Despite some technical issues on Safari, the project is celebrated for its impressive execution and engaging development story, sparking discussions about personal projects and the use of RSS readers.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://research.google/blog/extra-extra-read-all-about-it-nearly-all-binary-searches-and-mergesorts-are-broken/">Nearly all binary searches and mergesorts are broken (2006)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>In 2006, Joshua Bloch identified a bug in the binary search algorithm, initially noted in Jon Bentley&#39;s &quot;Programming Pearls,&quot; where an overflow occurs when &#39;low&#39; and &#39;high&#39; exceed the maximum int value.</li>
<li>This bug, affecting arrays with lengths of 2^30 or more, was rare in the 1980s but is more common today, also impacting mergesort and other divide-and-conquer algorithms.</li>
<li>Bloch recommends fixing the issue by calculating the midpoint as <code>int mid = low + ((high - low) / 2);</code>, highlighting the challenges of writing error-free code and the necessity of thorough testing.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42664400">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Many binary searches and mergesorts are prone to integer overflow issues, especially in older implementations, as highlighted in a 2006 article.&quot;</li>
<li>The article emphasizes the importance of considering edge cases and hardware limitations in programming, which remains relevant today.&quot;</li>
<li>Developers are advised to use built-in functions or larger integer types to prevent such bugs, underscoring the need for caution with data types and input sizes.&quot;</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/hybridgroup/go-haystack">Track your devices via Apple FindMy network in Go/TinyGo</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Go Haystack enables tracking of personal Bluetooth devices via Apple&#39;s &quot;Find My&quot; network without requiring Apple hardware, utilizing OpenHaystack and Macless-Haystack with Go/TinyGo tools.</li>
<li>Users can create their own beacons using TinyGo firmware on hardware like Adafruit Bluefruit boards and BBC Microbit, with setup requiring an Apple ID with two-factor authentication (2FA).</li>
<li>The process involves installing the go-haystack tool, using commands like <code>haystack scan</code> to locate devices, generating keys, flashing the device, and uploading a JSON file to macless-haystack for device visibility in the web UI.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42665367">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Apple FindMy network can be utilized with Go/TinyGo to track devices, offering a way to expand the network without needing an Apple account.</li>
<li>Privacy concerns are mitigated by Apple&#39;s design, and the company has a strong reputation for maintaining user privacy, although some users remain wary of potential surveillance.</li>
<li>The FindMy network operates in two parts: Apple devices locating items and user devices uploading location data to Apple, with an option for users to disable the feature if desired.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://lwn.net/SubscriberLink/1002342/a8d8a17f30968b93/">The State of Vim</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Following the passing of Vim founder Bram Moolenaar in 2023, the Vim community has reorganized to ensure the project&#39;s continued development, with Christian Brabandt as the current maintainer. - At VimConf 2024, it was discussed that the team has expanded, focusing on updating the Vim website, managing security, and enhancing communication channels. - Vim remains in maintenance mode, prioritizing community needs and integrating new features carefully, while continuing to support ICCF Holland, a charity established by Moolenaar.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42665222">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Long-time Vim users are reflecting on the editor&#39;s future following the passing of its creator, Bram Moolenaar, with some content with its current stability and others exploring alternatives like Neovim for modern features.</li>
<li>Neovim is gaining attention for its support of Lua scripting and modern enhancements, while some users are considering Emacs due to perceived fragmentation between Vim and Neovim.</li>
<li>Discussions among users include topics like Treesitter&#39;s performance, Language Server Protocol (LSP) support, and comparisons with Visual Studio Code (VSCode), highlighting the flexibility and stability of these editors.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.cs.cornell.edu/~asampson/blog/flattening.html">Flattening ASTs and other compiler data structures (2023)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The post discusses data structure flattening, a technique for compilers that optimizes abstract syntax trees (ASTs) by using a single array with indices instead of pointers. - This method enhances performance by improving memory locality, reducing reference size, and simplifying memory management, resulting in a 2.4× speedup in a microbenchmark. - The technique is notably used in Rust projects and offers ergonomic benefits, such as easier memory management, and is compared to bytecode interpreters for further performance improvements.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42659061">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion focuses on optimizing Abstract Syntax Trees (ASTs) by storing them in flat, contiguous arrays to improve performance and memory efficiency.</li>
<li>This method enhances cache locality and simplifies memory management, drawing comparisons to techniques in languages like Lisp and the Zig compiler.</li>
<li>The conversation also references historical methods and similar techniques in other programming languages, emphasizing the benefits of flat data structures for composability and ease of manipulation.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://tomscii.sig7.se/2025/01/De-smarting-the-Marshall-Uxbridge">De-smarting the Marshall Uxbridge Bluetooth speaker</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42666572">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion focuses on modifying the Marshall Uxbridge Bluetooth speaker to eliminate its &quot;smart&quot; features, involving technical aspects like designing a Printed Circuit Board (PCB) for digital I2S input.</li>
<li>Users debate the role of Digital Signal Processing (DSP) in achieving good sound quality, with some emphasizing its necessity to compensate for hardware limitations.</li>
<li>The conversation also covers the challenges of modifying smart devices and the affordability of modern PCB production and components.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2025/01/10/how-openais-bot-crushed-this-seven-person-companys-web-site-like-a-ddos-attack/">OpenAI&#39;s bot crushed this seven-person company&#39;s web site &#39;like a DDoS attack&#39;</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Triplegangers&#39; e-commerce site experienced a DDoS-like attack due to OpenAI&#39;s bot making tens of thousands of requests to scrape over 65,000 product pages. - The site lacked a properly configured robots.txt file to block such bots, leading to increased AWS costs and concerns about data security. - This incident underscores the importance of AI companies obtaining permission before data scraping and serves as a warning for small businesses to monitor for AI bot activity.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42660377">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>OpenAI&#39;s bot caused excessive traffic on a small company&#39;s website, similar to a Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) attack, highlighting issues with AI bots overwhelming websites.</li>
<li>Companies like Read the Docs have experienced similar challenges with AI bots generating massive traffic, despite using &quot;robots.txt&quot; to manage web crawlers.</li>
<li>The incident underscores the ongoing debate on balancing web accessibility with protection against aggressive data scraping by AI companies, as some bots ignore &quot;robots.txt,&quot; leading to potential legal and financial issues for small site owners.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Be Aware of the Makefile Effect" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Be%20Aware%20of%20the%20Makefile%20Effect&subheading=Saturday%2C%20January%2011%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/11</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-11T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-10]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/10&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-10</h1>
<h2><a href="https://danielwirtz.com/blog/spot-the-difference-superpower">I&#39;ve Acquired a New Superpower</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A Reddit user discovered a technique to easily spot differences in &quot;spot-the-difference&quot; puzzles by crossing their eyes to create a third, shimmering image.</li>
<li>This method allows differences to become more apparent, and the user felt it was like gaining a new skill or &quot;superpower&quot; after practicing.</li>
<li>The user shared this technique with others, encouraging them to try it by focusing on the middle image created when crossing their eyes.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42655870">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A technique to spot differences between two images by crossing one&#39;s eyes, akin to viewing stereograms, was used to win a game machine high score and a free bar tab.</li>
<li>This method highlights differences as shimmering or unstable areas, sparking discussions on its applications and challenges, including eye strain and vision difficulties.</li>
<li>The conversation expanded to related topics such as stereoscopic vision and the use of similar techniques in different fields.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://annas-archive.org/blog/all-isbns.html">Visualizing All ISBNs</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Anna&#39;s Archive, the largest open library, has visualized all ISBNs to track the progress of book backups, revealing that only 16% of books are backed up so far.</li>
<li>A $10,000 bounty is offered for improving the visualization&#39;s zoomability, interactivity, and usability, with prizes for the top three submissions, and all code must be open source.</li>
<li>This initiative is crucial for preserving rare books, as Anna&#39;s Archive holds the largest open collection of book metadata.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42652577">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion on Hacker News revolves around visualizing ISBNs (International Standard Book Numbers) from Anna&#39;s Archive, with suggestions like using a Hilbert Curve for improved data representation.</li>
<li>Users debate the effectiveness of ISBNs for hierarchical data visualization, proposing alternatives such as the Library of Congress system.</li>
<li>The conversation also addresses the legality and ethics of Anna&#39;s Archive, which hosts copyrighted material, and the use of Monero cryptocurrency for bounties due to privacy concerns.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://rodneybrooks.com/predictions-scorecard-2025-january-01/">Predictions Scorecard, 2025 January 01</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author provides an annual update on predictions made in 2018 about self-driving cars, robotics, AI, machine learning, and human space travel, with plans to make new predictions for 2026-2036.</li>
<li>Despite significant developments in AI and self-driving cars in 2024, full autonomy and the replacement of human jobs with AI remain distant, with remote human monitoring still necessary for self-driving cars.</li>
<li>Human spaceflight progress is slow, with SpaceX&#39;s Starship and NASA&#39;s Artemis facing delays, while Blue Origin&#39;s New Glenn is nearing launch, and suborbital tourism shows limited progress.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42651275">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article examines Rodney Brooks&#39; predictions on AI and robotics, particularly focusing on self-driving cars and AI advancements. - Critics claim Brooks&#39; predictions are vague and self-congratulatory, especially concerning Waymo&#39;s self-driving technology, which some argue is not fully autonomous due to human interventions. - Brooks aims to temper the hype around AI and robotics by highlighting realistic timelines and challenges, while the discussion also considers the economic viability of self-driving technology and its impact on jobs.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="I've Acquired a New Superpower" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=I've%20Acquired%20a%20New%20Superpower&subheading=Friday%2C%20January%2010%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/10</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-10T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-09]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/09&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-09</h1>
<h2><a href="https://www.linkedin.com/posts/jdkaim_github-jdkaimhuskyswap-huskyswap-project-activity-7282609173316415488-1jdb">I had to take down my course-swapping site or be expelled</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>JD Kaim, a computer science student, developed HuskySwap, an app designed to facilitate class spot trading among students at the University of Washington. - Despite its initial purpose as a class project, Kaim faced a &quot;Notice of Violation&quot; from the university when attempting to integrate the app with the official registration system. - The situation has generated mixed reactions, with some criticizing the university&#39;s actions and others providing support and advice to Kaim, who remains optimistic about future endeavors and job prospects.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42638626">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The creator of a course-swapping site was forced to shut it down after receiving an ultimatum from their university, the University of Washington (UW), threatening expulsion. - Despite compliance, the university placed a hold on the student&#39;s account, blocking registration for their final quarter unless they develop a similar solution for the university without compensation. - The student finds the situation demoralizing and is seeking a fair resolution from UW leadership, while also considering legal advice.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://substack.evancarroll.com/p/the-erasure-of-luigi-mangione">Luigi Mangione&#39;s account has been renamed on Stack Overflow</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Evan Carroll highlights the erasure of Luigi Mangione&#39;s identity on Stack Overflow, where his account was renamed to &quot;user4616250&quot; without clear justification, raising concerns about attribution under the Creative Commons license.</li>
<li>Carroll&#39;s inquiry into this issue resulted in a year-long ban from Stack Exchange, which he perceives as retaliatory, contrasting with other platforms like GitHub and LinkedIn that have not erased Mangione.</li>
<li>The situation underscores a unique stance by Stack Exchange and calls for fair treatment of Mangione, who has not been convicted of any crime.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42642089">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Luigi Mangione&#39;s Stack Overflow account was renamed, leading to discussions about moderation and attribution rights on the platform.</li>
<li>Critics argue that removing his name may violate the Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike (CC-BY-SA) license, which requires proper attribution.</li>
<li>The debate extends to broader concerns about corporate control over user content and the implications of moderation practices on individual rights and societal justice.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.consumer.org.nz/articles/you-don-t-have-to-pay-the-microsoft-365-price-increase">You don&#39;t have to pay the Microsoft 365 price increase</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Microsoft 365 has increased its subscription prices by approximately 40%, citing the integration of its AI tool, Copilot, though full access to Copilot requires an additional subscription. - Customers can avoid the price hike by selecting a hidden &quot;Microsoft 365 Classic&quot; plan, which retains the old pricing but is not openly advertised. - This situation highlights the use of &quot;dark patterns,&quot; where user interfaces are designed to manipulate consumer choices, raising ethical concerns about transparency and consumer rights.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42640180">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Microsoft 365&#39;s price increase has led users to explore alternatives, such as older versions like Office 2010 or free services like Google Docs, due to concerns over paying monthly for software with minimal recurring costs. - Businesses often feel compelled to stick with Software as a Service (SaaS) like Microsoft 365 for integration and continuity, despite the high costs, while some consider self-hosting, which can be expensive and risky. - Microsoft offers a one-time purchase option for Office 2024, limited to one PC, appealing to those who prefer not to commit to a subscription model.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.theregister.com/2025/01/08/los_angeles_fires_jpl/">LA wildfires force thousands to evacuate, NASA JPL closed</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Wildfires in Los Angeles County have led to the evacuation of 70,000 people and power outages affecting 400,000 residents, with over 1,000 structures destroyed and two fatalities reported. - California Governor Gavin Newsom declared a state of emergency, deploying the National Guard and firefighters, including prisoners, to address the crisis. - NASA&#39;s Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) is under threat, with emergency measures in place, and contingency plans to transfer Mars mission control if necessary.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42638735">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Wildfires in Los Angeles have led to mass evacuations and the closure of NASA&#39;s Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL), highlighting the severity of the situation.</li>
<li>Strong winds are complicating firefighting efforts, and there are concerns about budget cuts to the fire department, which may impact response capabilities.</li>
<li>The community is actively supporting those affected by the fires through donations and assistance, demonstrating solidarity in the face of disaster.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://th0mas.nl/downloads/pdftris.pdf">A playable game of Tetris inside a PDF</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Modern desktop browsers&#39; PDF engines, such as PDFium and PDF.js, can support JavaScript with sufficient input/output capabilities to create simple games like Tetris.</li>
<li>The project demonstrates the versatility of PDF scripting by using annotation fields for monochrome pixels and a text input box for keyboard input, despite some limitations.</li>
<li>The PDF is available in ASCII format, allowing users to open it in a text editor or view the source code on GitHub.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42645218">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A Tetris game has been developed within a PDF using JavaScript, showcasing the capabilities of modern PDF engines such as PDFium and PDF.js. - The game utilizes annotation fields for pixel display and text input for controls, but it is not functional when printed or in certain PDF viewers like Evince. - This project demonstrates the flexibility of PDF scripting, while also raising security concerns about executing code within PDFs; the source code is accessible on GitHub.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.salesforceben.com/salesforce-will-hire-no-more-software-engineers-in-2025-says-marc-benioff/">Salesforce will hire no more software engineers in 2025, says Marc Benioff</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Salesforce plans to halt hiring more software engineers in 2025, attributing a 30% productivity increase to AI advancements, as stated by CEO Marc Benioff. - The company will focus on its AI product, Agentforce, and increase hiring of salespeople to communicate AI&#39;s value to clients. - Despite recent layoffs due to over-hiring during the pandemic, Benioff anticipates company growth over the next five years, with upcoming events like Japan Dreamin’ and Architect Dreamin’ on the horizon.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42639417">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Salesforce CEO Marc Benioff announced a hiring freeze for software engineers in 2025, focusing on AI-driven productivity and cost control.</li>
<li>This decision follows a previous hiring freeze and layoffs in early 2023, influenced by shareholder pressure, and is perceived as a marketing strategy for Salesforce&#39;s AI products.</li>
<li>Despite claims of a 30% productivity boost from AI, skepticism persists, and Salesforce plans to expand its sales team to promote AI offerings, raising questions about AI&#39;s role in replacing human jobs.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://thenewstack.io/steve-langasek-one-of-ubuntu-linuxs-leading-lights-has-died/">Steve Langasek, one of Ubuntu Linux&#39;s leading lights, has died</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Steve Langasek, a prominent contributor to the Linux community, particularly Debian and Ubuntu, passed away on January 1, 2025, at the age of 45. - Langasek was known for his significant contributions to system administration, software development, and package maintenance, impacting projects like Linux-PAM, Samba, and OpenLDAP. - His leadership, mentorship, and dedication to open-source principles were highly regarded, with notable figures like Mark Shuttleworth and Dustin Kirkland praising his technical insight and spirit.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42639563">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Steve Langasek, a prominent contributor to Ubuntu Linux and Debian, has passed away at the age of 45 due to stage 4 colon cancer. - His death has initiated conversations about the critical importance of early medical screenings and the difficulties in accessing them. - The tech community remembers him for his extensive knowledge and supportive nature.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/piebro/factorio-blueprint-visualizer">Factorio Blueprint Visualizer</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A new website has been developed to visualize Factorio blueprints using vector graphics (SVG), allowing users to import and modify blueprints artfully. - The tool supports Factorio 2.0 and Factorio: Space Age, with improved performance after being ported from Python to JavaScript. - Users can adjust drawing settings and utilize the tool for text-to-image generation or pen plotting, with contributions and feedback encouraged.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42644168">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Factorio Blueprint Visualizer, a fan-created website, has been updated to support Factorio 2.0 and the Space Age DLC, allowing users to modify drawing styles.</li>
<li>The project was rewritten from Python to JavaScript to improve performance, and the creator is open to feedback on bugs and feature ideas.</li>
<li>While the visualizer does not natively support mods, it can be customized by adding mod buildings, and the community remains actively engaged with the game.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="I had to take down my course-swapping site or be expelled" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=I%20had%20to%20take%20down%20my%20course-swapping%20site%20or%20be%20expelled&subheading=Thursday%2C%20January%209%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/09</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-09T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-08]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/08&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-08</h1>
<h2><a href="https://www.seangoedecke.com/large-established-codebases/">Mistakes engineers make in large established codebases</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Working in large, established codebases, often with millions of lines of code and involving hundreds of engineers, presents significant challenges for software engineers. - A common mistake is inconsistency, where engineers ignore existing code patterns and implement features in isolation, which can lead to maintenance issues and hinder future improvements. - To effectively work within large codebases, engineers should research existing patterns, understand the codebase&#39;s production impact, be cautious with dependencies, and carefully remove unnecessary code to maintain quality and value.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42627227">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Engineers in large, established codebases often encounter challenges with inconsistency and undocumented practices, necessitating a focus on personal code quality and documentation. - Balancing improvements with maintaining local consistency is key, especially when the existing codebase is inconsistent, while engaging with the wider team can help align practices. - The ultimate goal is to enhance the codebase&#39;s functionality and maintainability, requiring pragmatism and adaptation to existing patterns.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://recyclebin.zip/posts/annoyinglinks/">Magic/tragic email links: don&#39;t make them the only option</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Magic Links provide a passwordless login method via email links, offering enhanced security but can be inconvenient due to email delays and multi-device use.</li>
<li>They may pose security risks by encouraging users to access personal emails on work devices, highlighting the need for alternatives like One-Time Passwords (OTPs).</li>
<li>For improved user experience, especially for tech-savvy users, passkeys are recommended as a more flexible and secure option.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42627453">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Magic links, used for authentication, face reliability issues due to email problems and can push users towards biometrics, which may be legally compelled unlike passwords. - Passkeys are proposed as a more secure and user-friendly alternative to magic links, but their adoption is still ongoing, with many services yet to implement them. - The discussion on balancing security and usability in authentication methods remains active, highlighting the challenges in finding an optimal solution.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://operating-system-in-1000-lines.vercel.app/en">Operating System in 1,000 Lines – Intro</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The book guides readers through building a small operating system from scratch, covering essential functions like context switching, paging, and file operations in C, all within approximately 1,000 lines of code.</li>
<li>It emphasizes learning new debugging techniques, particularly for challenges like the boot process and paging, and provides downloadable examples on GitHub.</li>
<li>The book is licensed under CC BY 4.0, with code under the MIT license, and requires familiarity with C and a UNIX-like environment as prerequisites.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42631873">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Operating System in 1,000 Lines&quot; is a book that guides readers in creating an operating system from scratch using any programming language, not limited to C.</li>
<li>The book emphasizes essential components of an OS, steering clear of a traditional UNIX-like structure, and aims to be an engaging and creative project.&quot;</li>
<li>It invites contributions and feedback, offering content in Markdown format, and serves as a valuable resource for learning and experimenting with OS development.&quot;</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://dmarcchecker.app/articles/crack-512-bit-dkim-rsa-key">Cracking a 512-bit DKIM key for less than $8 in the cloud</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A study of the SPF (Sender Policy Framework), DKIM (DomainKeys Identified Mail), and DMARC (Domain-based Message Authentication, Reporting, and Conformance) records of the top 1 million websites revealed over 1,700 public DKIM keys shorter than 1,024 bits, which are deemed insecure. - Researchers successfully cracked a 512-bit DKIM key from redfin.com using Python and CADO-NFS for under $8 on a cloud server, demonstrating the vulnerability of short keys. - The study emphasizes the need for email providers to reject DKIM signatures with keys shorter than 1,024 bits, as some providers like Yahoo Mail, Mailfence, and Tuta accepted the compromised signature.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42633501">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Cracking a 512-bit DKIM (DomainKeys Identified Mail) key is now affordable, costing less than $8 using cloud services, highlighting the vulnerability of outdated encryption methods.</li>
<li>The discussion emphasizes the necessity for stronger DKIM keys and the challenges in balancing security with usability, as many systems still rely on outdated keys, posing significant security risks.</li>
<li>The conversation underscores the broader implications for email security and the urgent need for updated standards to protect against evolving threats.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.pcworld.com/article/2568916/microsoft-disguises-bing-as-google-to-fool-inattentive-searchers.html">Microsoft disguises Bing as Google to fool inattentive searchers</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Microsoft is reportedly altering Bing&#39;s appearance to resemble Google&#39;s interface, potentially misleading users into using Bing unintentionally. - This strategy underscores Microsoft&#39;s challenges in competing with Google&#39;s substantial market share in the search engine industry. - Critics suggest that this tactic may prioritize Microsoft&#39;s business objectives over providing a genuine user experience.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42626431">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Microsoft is altering Bing&#39;s appearance to resemble Google when users search for &quot;Google&quot; on Bing, leveraging Google&#39;s brand recognition.</li>
<li>This tactic is controversial, with some viewing it as deceptive and others as a strategic move to retain users who may not notice the difference.</li>
<li>Legal experts indicate that while Google could potentially sue, proving deception without clear trademark infringement would be difficult, highlighting Microsoft&#39;s competitive strategy in the search engine market.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://dillonshook.com/laid-off/">Laid off for the first time in my career, and twice in one year</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author shares their experience of being laid off twice in one year, emphasizing the importance of maintaining good relationships with former employers and being prepared for job searches. - Key signs of potential layoffs include a lack of company vision, distractions, low product usage, and sudden company meetings, suggesting employees should stay vigilant. - Advice for those laid off includes updating resumes, filing for unemployment, leveraging LinkedIn and networking, understanding business models, and maintaining self-worth beyond employment.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42627567">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The author, having experienced two layoffs in a year, emphasizes the importance of using a simple, linear resume format to improve response rates from Applicant Tracking Systems (ATS). - ATS often misinterpret modern resume formats, which can negatively impact job application outcomes; simplifying resumes and focusing on role responsibilities can mitigate this issue. - Networking, maintaining good relationships, and building a diverse skill set are crucial strategies for career stability and security in a challenging job market.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.mattkeeter.com/projects/fidget/">Fidget</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Fidget is a Rust-based library designed for handling large-scale mathematical expressions, particularly for implicit surfaces, which are compact and support operations like union and intersection. - The library is structured into three layers: frontend (converts scripts to bytecode), backend (efficiently evaluates expressions), and demos, with support for SIMD (Single Instruction, Multiple Data) and automatic differentiation. - Fidget is now publicly available on GitHub under the MPL 2.0 license, with future plans for GPU integration and improved meshing, encouraging exploration and development by users.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42634624">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Fidget, a project by Matt Keeter, explores diverse areas of computer science, including data structures, algorithms, compilers, and graphics, generating interest for its potential applications in fields like 3D printing and CAD (Computer-Aided Design).</li>
<li>Although it does not support STEP (Standard for the Exchange of Product model data) export due to differing data representations, Fidget offers other functionalities and includes bindings for Rhai, a scripting language for Rust.</li>
<li>The project has inspired creative coding initiatives and discussions, highlighting its versatility and innovative potential in the tech community.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blogs.igalia.com/mrego/servo-revival-2023-2024/">Servo Revival: 2023-2024</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Igalia revitalized the Servo project, an experimental browser engine initially created by Mozilla, by taking over its maintenance in January 2023. - Significant progress includes upgrading dependencies, enhancing continuous integration (CI) and tooling, expanding community support, and adding support for Android and OpenHarmony. - The project has raised over $24,500 in donations, with future goals of becoming a default web engine for Rust applications and developing a full-featured web browser, despite challenges like competition and funding.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42628414">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Servo, a browser engine, is experiencing a revival with updates and is now accepting donations through Open Collective and GitHub sponsors. - Igalia, a significant contributor to Servo, is also involved in Chromium development, emphasizing the importance of diverse browser engines. - Despite previous setbacks, such as Mozilla halting its development, Servo remains active, with discussions on the benefits of rewriting in Rust and hopes for future funding.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/a-day-in-the-life-of-a-prolific-voice-phishing-crew/">A day in the life of a prolific voice phishing crew</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Apple and Google have issued warnings about phone scams, yet a group called &quot;Crypto Chameleon&quot; exploits their services to conduct phishing attacks, resulting in significant financial losses for victims like cryptocurrency investor Tony, who lost $4.7 million.</li>
<li>The phishing gang uses sophisticated methods, including phishing kits that mimic authentication pages and fake Apple support calls, with roles such as Caller, Operator, Drainer, and Owner to execute their scams.</li>
<li>Despite internal betrayals, these cybercriminal groups continue to thrive on platforms like Telegram and Discord, with a focus on targeting wealthy individuals, particularly those with cryptocurrency assets.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42629163">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A rural Ohio gas station fell victim to a voice phishing scam, where scammers impersonated the station to solicit credit card payments over the phone using fake caller ID. - The incident underscores the potential rise of such scams with the use of automation tools, emphasizing the need for improved security measures. - Cybersecurity journalist Brian Krebs, known for uncovering online scams, experienced difficulties when Akamai ceased DDoS protection for his site, prompting Google to provide support, highlighting ongoing cybersecurity challenges.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://streets.gl/#47.35245,8.50958,21.25,42.00,459.10">Streets GL – 3D OpenStreetMap</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42626964">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Streets GL is a 3D OpenStreetMap project enabling users to explore detailed 3D maps, though some users have noted that the OSM data is outdated and certain features, like bridges, have issues.</li>
<li>Users have suggested improvements, including using Cloudflare for faster loading, updating building data, and integrating elevation data to enhance the visual experience.</li>
<li>The project supports GPX and FIT file uploads for GPS tracks, allowing interaction with the map via keyboard and mouse controls.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/01/bye-bye-windows-gaming-steamos-officially-expands-past-the-steam-deck/">Bye-bye Windows gaming? SteamOS officially expands past the Steam Deck</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Lenovo&#39;s Legion Go S will be the first non-Valve device officially &quot;Powered by SteamOS,&quot; indicating a significant shift from Windows for gaming PCs.</li>
<li>The SteamOS version of the device will be more affordable, starting at $500, compared to the Windows version priced at $730.</li>
<li>Valve&#39;s plan to release a beta version of SteamOS for personal installs could challenge Windows&#39; dominance in PC gaming, promoting a broader shift towards Linux-based gaming.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42633269">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>SteamOS is extending its reach beyond the Steam Deck, presenting itself as a credible alternative to Windows for gaming enthusiasts.</li>
<li>The use of Proton, a compatibility layer, enables most games to run efficiently on Linux, although some multiplayer games with kernel-level anti-cheat systems may face issues.</li>
<li>With tools like Heroic and Lutris simplifying access to games from different platforms, SteamOS offers a streamlined, console-like experience, potentially challenging Windows&#39; dominance in the gaming sector as more devices adopt it.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Mistakes engineers make in large established codebases" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Mistakes%20engineers%20make%20in%20large%20established%20codebases&subheading=Wednesday%2C%20January%208%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/08</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-08T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-07]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/07&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-07</h1>
<h2><a href="https://crawshaw.io/blog/programming-with-llms">How I program with LLMs</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author has integrated Large Language Models (LLMs) into their programming workflow, finding them beneficial for tasks like autocomplete, search, and chat-driven programming.</li>
<li>They are developing a tool called sketch.dev, a Go programming Integrated Development Environment (IDE) designed to enhance productivity by automating repetitive tasks and improving programming efficiency.</li>
<li>LLMs are effective in generating code drafts and handling exam-style questions, although they can occasionally make errors, and they shift tradeoffs in programming by enabling more specialized code and comprehensive tests.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42617645">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Large Language Models (LLMs) are recognized by some software engineers for enhancing productivity, particularly in drafting new ideas and performing tasks like autocomplete and chat-driven programming. - While some developers appreciate the efficiency LLMs provide, others remain skeptical about their effectiveness, especially for complex or novel problems. - The discussion underscores a divide among developers regarding the adoption of LLMs, with some embracing them for iterative tasks and others favoring traditional methods.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2025/01/06/nvidias-project-digits-is-a-personal-ai-computer/">Nvidia&#39;s Project Digits is a &#39;personal AI supercomputer&#39;</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Nvidia unveiled Project Digits at CES 2025, a compact &quot;personal AI supercomputer&quot; built on the Grace Blackwell hardware platform, featuring the GB10 Grace Blackwell Superchip.</li>
<li>The device offers up to a petaflop of performance, suitable for AI researchers, data scientists, and students, and can handle models with up to 200 billion parameters.</li>
<li>Priced at $3,000, Project Digits will be available in May and can connect to Windows or Mac PCs, running on Nvidia&#39;s Linux-based DGX OS.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42619139">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Nvidia&#39;s Project Digits is a &#39;personal AI supercomputer&#39; priced at $3,000, featuring a Blackwell GPU with 1 PFLOP (PetaFLOP) of FP4 compute, 128GB unified DDR5X memory, 20 ARM cores, and ConnectX for stacking. - It targets startups and enthusiasts, providing a local alternative to cloud AI solutions, with a focus on memory capacity and efficiency for AI development and inference tasks. - The device operates on Nvidia&#39;s DGX OS, based on Ubuntu, and is considered a potential game-changer for local AI computing.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://nicholas.carlini.com/writing/2025/regex-chess.html">A minimax chess engine in regular expressions</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Nicholas Carlini developed a chess engine named Regex Chess, utilizing 84,688 regular expressions to execute valid chess moves, showcasing regex&#39;s potential in unconventional applications. - The engine functions like a regular expression CPU, featuring a unique instruction set for stack operations, variable handling, and conditional execution, and supports parallel move generation. - Regex Chess employs a simplified minimax search to evaluate and score pseudo-legal moves, highlighting a creative exploration of regex capabilities, with the code accessible on GitHub for public viewing.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42619652">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Nicholas Carlini developed a minimax chess engine using regular expressions, showcasing regex&#39;s capability in handling complex tasks like chess. - The project, despite having bugs like issues with pawn promotion and a-file moves, demonstrates the educational and entertaining aspects of unconventional programming challenges. - The engine&#39;s 2-ply search occasionally fails to avoid mate-in-1 threats, highlighting its limitations but also its innovative approach.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.scottredig.com/blog/bonkers_comptime/">Zig&#39;s comptime is bonkers good</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Scott Redig explores Zig&#39;s &#39;comptime&#39; feature, which enhances productivity by enabling metaprogramming, allowing code execution during compile time. - He provides six perspectives on &#39;comptime&#39;, highlighting its ability to simplify code reading and debugging, and compares it to generics, partial evaluation, and code generation. - Redig concludes that Zig&#39;s &#39;comptime&#39; is both powerful and simple, recommending further exploration through Zig&#39;s official resources and standard library.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42618130">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Zig&#39;s compile-time programming (comptime) is recognized for its efficiency, enabling features like generics, complex data initialization, and target-specific code generation. - Critics highlight potential issues such as misuse akin to Lisp macros, breaking parametricity, and challenges with recursive generic types and type checking during compile-time computation. - Despite these concerns, Zig&#39;s simplicity and compile-time execution are considered major advantages, with some interest in integrating its metaprogramming capabilities with Rust&#39;s ecosystem.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24337396/nvidia-rtx-5080-5090-5070-ti-5070-price-release-date">Nvidia announces next-gen RTX 5090 and RTX 5080 GPUs</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Nvidia unveiled its next-generation RTX 50-series GPUs at CES, featuring the high-end RTX 5090 and RTX 5080, priced at $1,999 and $999, respectively. - The RTX 5090 includes 32GB of GDDR7 memory and 21,760 CUDA cores, offering double the speed of its predecessor, the RTX 4090, while the RTX 5080 provides 16GB of memory and is twice as fast as the RTX 4080. - The series introduces new DLSS 4 technology, improving performance and image quality, and will be available for laptops starting in March.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42618761">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Nvidia has unveiled the RTX 5090 and RTX 5080 GPUs, with the RTX 5090 featuring 32GB of GDDR7 memory and a 575W Thermal Design Power (TDP), aimed at consumer AI workloads.</li>
<li>The RTX 5080 is designed for high-end gaming, offering a more affordable option with less memory compared to the RTX 5090.</li>
<li>The high demand for these GPUs, particularly for AI applications, may lead to availability issues, reminiscent of previous shortages driven by cryptocurrency mining.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/ABoringDystopia/comments/1ht7fft/used_meta_ai_to_edit_a_selfie_now_instagram_is/">Used Meta AI, now Instagram is using my face on ads targeted at me</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42615538">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A Reddit user experienced Instagram ads featuring their own face after using Meta AI&#39;s &quot;imagine me&quot; feature, raising concerns about personalized advertising. - The incident sparked a debate comparing this level of ad personalization to the movie &quot;Minority Report,&quot; with opinions divided between seeing it as innovative or invasive. - The discussion underscores privacy concerns and the ethical implications of AI in advertising, with calls for stricter regulations to protect personal data.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.congestion-pricing-tracker.com/">NYC Congestion Pricing Tracker</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Congestion Pricing Tracker is a project by Benjamin and Joshua Moshes, under the supervision of Brown University Professor Emily Oster, focusing on congestion pricing in New York. - The project includes web scripts and stylesheets, indicating a comprehensive digital approach to presenting information. - The webpage is optimized for search engines (SEO) and includes a 404 error page for handling not found content.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42616700">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>NYC&#39;s congestion pricing policy is designed to reduce traffic congestion and generate revenue for transit improvements.</li>
<li>While some observe immediate benefits, others argue it&#39;s premature to assess its effectiveness due to variables like weather and holiday travel.</li>
<li>Critics point out that unchanged taxi and ride-sharing fees and the need for enhanced public transit remain significant concerns.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://variety.com/2025/film/columns/flow-golden-globe-win-independent-animation-1236266805/">First time a Blender-made production has won the Golden Globe</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Latvian director Gints Zilbalodis&#39; indie animation &quot;Flow&quot; won the Golden Globe for best animated feature, highlighting a significant achievement for independent films. - &quot;Flow,&quot; created with a modest $3.7 million budget using Blender, a free software, competed against major studio productions, showcasing the democratization of animation. - The film&#39;s victory reflects the Golden Globes&#39; growing inclusivity towards international titles and could impact the animated feature Oscar race, challenging Disney&#39;s traditional dominance.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42620656">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A Blender-made production has won a Golden Globe, marking a milestone for the open-source software and challenging perceptions of its readiness for professional use. - The film, noted for its storytelling and visuals, has gained popularity in Latvia and stands out for its low budget compared to other animated winners. - The success of the film, utilizing Blender&#39;s EEVEE engine, has ignited discussions about Blender&#39;s potential impact on the animation industry and its capabilities in diverse production settings.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://tla.systems/blog/2025/01/04/i-live-my-life-a-quarter-century-at-a-time/">I live my life a quarter century at a time</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>On January 5, 2000, Steve Jobs introduced the Aqua user interface of Mac OS X, including the Dock, at Macworld Expo, with significant contributions from an engineer based in Apple Cork, Ireland.</li>
<li>The engineer, who had previously worked on DragThing, was instrumental in transforming Bas Ording&#39;s prototypes into functional code for the Dock, but eventually resigned due to relocation pressures.</li>
<li>After leaving Apple, the engineer revived DragThing and PCalc, which continue to be popular, and discovered an unsigned Non-Disclosure Agreement (NDA) in their possession.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42616699">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses Apple&#39;s Dock development, emphasizing Steve Jobs&#39; eccentricity and secretive nature, including flying an employee between Ireland and the US to maintain a facade.</li>
<li>Despite significant efforts, the project was ultimately canceled due to issues related to office location.</li>
<li>The narrative also delves into Jobs&#39; controversial decisions, his legacy compared to current tech leaders, and broader themes like career paths and ageism in the tech industry.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://alexanderpetros.com/triptych/">Triptych Proposals</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Triptych Proposals by Alexander Petros and Carson Gross aim to improve HTML&#39;s ability to handle network requests by supporting additional HTTP methods like PUT, PATCH, and DELETE in forms.</li>
<li>The proposals also include enabling buttons to make HTTP requests without forms and allowing partial page replacements, aligning HTML more closely with REST principles.</li>
<li>These proposals were introduced at Big Sky Dev Con and are detailed in the Triptych Polyfill on GitHub, with ongoing updates to the fetch and navigation specifications to support these enhancements.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42615646">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Alex Petros&#39; Triptych Proposals seek to incorporate HTMX concepts into the HTML specification, enabling HTML to handle HTTP methods like PUT and DELETE.</li>
<li>The proposal is receiving positive feedback from the Web Hypertext Application Technology Working Group (WHATWG), but its adoption by major browsers such as Chrome and Safari is still uncertain.</li>
<li>The initiative aims to reduce JavaScript dependency by enhancing HTML&#39;s capabilities, contributing to the broader discussion on RESTful APIs and a hypermedia-driven web.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://racenis.github.io/tram-sdk/why.html">Tramway SDK – The Unholy Union Between Half-Life and Morrowind Engines</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A new free, open-source game engine is being developed, similar to popular engines like Unreal and Source, with support for open-world streaming. - The engine is optimized for modern hardware, offering high performance, but is not yet ready for production use. - The developer intends to complete several large projects using this engine, although the current name is likely temporary.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42624116">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Tramway SDK is a project that merges the Half-Life and Morrowind game engines to create a low-budget, open-world streaming game engine that is free and open source. - Although optimized for modern hardware, Tramway SDK is not yet ready for production use, but it aims to reduce software bloat and environmental impact by supporting older hardware. - The project, licensed under MIT, is appreciated for its retro aesthetic and potential for indie game development, with the creator welcoming feedback and progress updates.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/science/2025/jan/06/roman-empires-use-of-lead-lowered-iq-levels-across-europe-study-finds">Roman Empire&#39;s use of lead lowered IQ levels across Europe, study finds</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A study indicates that the Roman Empire&#39;s use of lead in metalworking caused a 2- to 3-point drop in IQ across Europe during the Pax Romana.</li>
<li>Researchers used Arctic ice cores to track lead pollution from 500BC to AD600, showing a significant increase during the Roman Empire&#39;s peak.</li>
<li>The study suggests that widespread lead exposure may have contributed to the decline of the Roman Empire, with pollution levels decreasing post-Roman era but rising again during the Industrial Revolution.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42618625">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A study indicates that the Roman Empire&#39;s use of lead could have reduced IQ levels in Europe, though this is based on historical lead levels and modern models rather than direct ancient IQ measurements.</li>
<li>There is debate over whether the advantages of Roman infrastructure might have surpassed the detrimental effects of lead exposure.</li>
<li>The study also explores the potential effects of contemporary substances, such as fluoride and plastics, on IQ, emphasizing the complexity of assessing historical health impacts from indirect evidence.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.crisesnotes.com/content/files/2023/12/NYFRB-2006.--Doomsday-Book--Searchable.pdf">Federal Reserve Bank of NY &quot;Doomsday Book&quot; 2022 via FOIA [pdf]</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42623144">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Federal Reserve Bank of New York&#39;s &quot;Doomsday Book&quot; is a legal guide designed to assist lawyers in managing legal uncertainties during financial crises, ensuring prompt and effective responses. - Initially intended for select lawyers, the guide is now available to all FRBNY lawyers, serving as a crisis playbook akin to tech incident response plans. - The document is not shared outside the Legal Function, and its name signifies preparation for severe financial disruptions, with the Fed maintaining independence from the Freedom of Information Act (FOIA) due to its unique role, while still being accountable to Congress.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://about.fb.com/news/2025/01/meta-more-speech-fewer-mistakes/">Ending our third party fact-checking program and moving to Community Notes model</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Meta is prioritizing free expression by simplifying its content moderation systems, which have been criticized for being overly complex and restrictive. - The company is ending its third-party fact-checking program in the U.S. and introducing a Community Notes system, similar to X, to provide context to potentially misleading posts through user contributions. - Meta is reducing restrictions on political content, simplifying enforcement processes to focus on severe violations, and personalizing political content visibility based on user preferences, aligning with Mark Zuckerberg&#39;s vision of free expression.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42621627">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Meta is transitioning from its third-party fact-checking program to a Community Notes model, akin to Twitter&#39;s strategy, to potentially align with political changes and cut moderation expenses.</li>
<li>Critics express concerns that this shift may result in more misinformation and harmful content, whereas supporters argue it could bolster free speech.</li>
<li>This decision highlights ongoing discussions about content moderation, free speech, and the influence of social media platforms in shaping public discourse.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="How I program with LLMs" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=How%20I%20program%20with%20LLMs&subheading=Tuesday%2C%20January%207%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/07</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-07T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-06]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/06&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-06</h1>
<h2><a href="https://bobatealee.itch.io/doom-the-gallery-experience">Doom, the Gallery Experience</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>&quot;DOOM: The Gallery Experience&quot; is an art parody game by bobatealee, set in a reimagined version of the classic DOOM (1993) level E1M1, where players explore a gallery setting. - The game is compatible with HTML5, Windows, mobile devices, and gamepads, and was created using the Construct game development platform. - It has received a 5-star rating and is praised for its cultural satire and design, with contributions from Filippo Meozzi and Liam Stone.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42607794">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>&quot;Doom, the Gallery Experience&quot; is a virtual museum game allowing players to explore art pieces, akin to a real museum visit, created using Construct 3.</li>
<li>The game is available on multiple platforms, though some users report technical issues on mobile devices.</li>
<li>It combines cultural exploration with nostalgia, drawing inspiration from classic games like Doom, and has sparked discussions on potential humorous modifications.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://twitter.com/3blue1brown/status/1876291319955398799">3blue1brown YouTube Bitcoin video taken down as copyright violation</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Grant Sanderson, known for his educational content, reported that his 2017 video on Bitcoin was removed, and his channel received a copyright strike.</li>
<li>The copyright claim was made by Chainpatrol on behalf of Arbitrum, despite the video being entirely Sanderson&#39;s original content.</li>
<li>This incident highlights ongoing issues with copyright enforcement on digital platforms, where creators can face strikes even for their own work.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42612494">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A 3blue1brown YouTube video on Bitcoin was erroneously removed due to a copyright claim by ChainPatrol, which later acknowledged it as a false positive.</li>
<li>This incident highlighted flaws in YouTube&#39;s copyright system, sparking discussions about the potential for abuse and the lack of accountability for false claims.</li>
<li>Users suggested stricter penalties for companies issuing false takedown requests and discussed broader issues of content moderation and free speech challenges online.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://jessitron.com/2025/01/05/hitting-okrs-vs-doing-your-job/">Hitting OKRs vs. Doing Your Job</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>In Engineering, quarterly Objectives and Key Results (OKRs) often seem redundant as they tend to mirror product roadmaps, leading to potential conflicts if they differ.</li>
<li>Marketing finds OKRs beneficial for defining quarterly focus, aligning with project timelines, and highlighting new campaigns or audiences, while ongoing tasks are tracked by Key Performance Indicators (KPIs).</li>
<li>Effective OKRs should emphasize unique or changing priorities each quarter, rather than routine tasks, to avoid stagnation and ensure they provide value beyond the roadmap.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42607623">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>OKRs (Objectives and Key Results) can sometimes misalign with actual work, emphasizing metrics over meaningful contributions and potentially leading to gaming the system rather than addressing real issues.</li>
<li>Effective implementation of OKRs requires alignment with customer needs and company goals, but this alignment is often difficult to achieve, leading to bureaucratic processes and a lack of trust in employees&#39; intrinsic motivation.</li>
<li>In large organizations, OKRs can foster competition instead of collaboration, focusing on visible rather than valuable work, thus failing to capture the complexity of tasks.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.20512">Time-Series Anomaly Detection: A Decade Review</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The paper &quot;Dive into Time-Series Anomaly Detection: A Decade Review&quot; highlights the significance of anomaly detection in time-series data due to advancements in data collection and the rise of streaming data. - It introduces a process-centric taxonomy to categorize existing anomaly detection methods and offers a meta-analysis of research trends in this domain. - The research is pertinent to various fields, including cybersecurity, finance, law enforcement, and healthcare, and is accessible on arXiv under the Machine Learning category.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42609595">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Time-series anomaly detection uses forecasting and historical data to identify pattern deviations, with tools like Prometheus and Grafana aiding in practical applications. - These tools enable dynamic threshold setting based on weekly cycles and time of day, but challenges include managing holidays and defining anomalies. - The field is promising for development across industries but currently lacks comprehensive off-the-shelf solutions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://neal.fun/stimulation-clicker/">Stimulation Clicker</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42611536">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Stimulation Clicker on neal.fun is a popular clicker game that has generated user discussions, with comparisons to other games like Cookie Clicker and commentary on modern web habits. - Users have shared strategies for faster progress, such as automating clicks or resizing windows, and noted both addictive fun and issues like bugs or overstimulation. - The game has inspired creativity, including speedruns, with players appreciating its short length and engaging elements.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://xeiaso.net/blog/2025/squandered-holy-grail/">Apple squandered the Holy Grail</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Apple Intelligence, intended to enhance smartphone capabilities, did not meet expectations, with some features like Math Notes praised, but others criticized for being underwhelming.</li>
<li>Despite promising privacy and security through on-device processing and Private Cloud Compute, the product felt more like a tech demo than a groundbreaking tool.</li>
<li>The open-source community often surpasses corporate efforts like Apple Intelligence, which left users with only marginal improvements instead of transformative advancements.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42607151">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Apple&#39;s innovation strategy focuses on refining existing technologies, which sometimes disappoints fans expecting groundbreaking inventions. - Apple&#39;s AI features, such as Apple Intelligence, have faced criticism for being less impressive compared to competitors, despite Apple&#39;s history of product improvement. - Apple&#39;s strong emphasis on secure and private systems provides optimism for future enhancements in their AI offerings, though debate persists on whether they will meet user expectations.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://futureboy.us/blog/twofifty.html">Engineer eats efficiently for $2.50 a day (2016)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>An engineer embarks on a 46-day challenge to spend under $2.50 daily on food, documenting meals, costs, and cooking experiments. - Inspired by cooking shows, he sets rules to ensure fun, nutrition, and sharing, exploring recipes like cabbage rolls and ramen while managing costs and minimizing waste. - The experiment involves creative cooking with limited ingredients, using techniques such as brining and sous vide, and experimenting with emulsifiers, ultimately sharing insights on cost-effective cooking.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42606773">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>An engineer successfully reduced their daily food expenses to $2.50 in 2016 by purchasing bulk staples like rice, beans, and oats, and carefully managing fresh produce to prevent spoilage.</li>
<li>The strategy included diluting high-sodium packaged foods and shopping at budget-friendly stores, though it may not be sustainable or nutritionally adequate over time.</li>
<li>Alternatives such as buying discounted produce at farmers markets or using frozen vegetables can offer convenience and maintain nutritional value, but ensuring sufficient calorie and protein intake is crucial for health.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://r0bk.github.io/killedbyllm/">Killed by LLM</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>&quot;Killed by LLM&quot; is a project documenting AI benchmarks that have been surpassed by AI advancements, showcasing progress in areas like reasoning, mathematics, and coding. - The site, inspired by &quot;Killed by Google,&quot; provides details on original and final scores of benchmarks and the AI models that surpassed them, highlighting the rapid evolution of AI capabilities. - The term &quot;Saturation&quot; is used to describe benchmarks that can no longer effectively measure the cutting-edge capabilities of AI, and the project invites contributions to ensure data accuracy.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42606231">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion focuses on the Turing Test and its modern interpretations, especially concerning AI and Large Language Models (LLMs).</li>
<li>Modern versions of the Turing Test often simplify the challenge to identifying if a conversation partner is human, which LLMs can sometimes pass by mimicking non-native speakers.</li>
<li>The conversation highlights the limitations of current AI benchmarks and the potential for AI to be misused or misunderstood, questioning the true measure of intelligence in AI systems.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/live/clyjmy7vl64t">Justin Trudeau resigns</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Liberal Party of Canada is initiating the process to select a new leader, as announced by party president Sachit Mehra.</li>
<li>Justin Trudeau, praised for his decade-long leadership and efforts in rebuilding and making the party more inclusive, will remain in his role until a successor is chosen.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42611730">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Justin Trudeau has announced his plan to resign as Canada&#39;s Prime Minister, remaining in office until the Liberal Party selects a new leader.</li>
<li>His decision follows low approval ratings and internal party pressure, with controversies surrounding his handling of the trucker protest and other issues.</li>
<li>Trudeau&#39;s resignation is viewed as a strategic effort to allow the Liberal Party to regroup ahead of a potentially challenging election, with the possibility of a Conservative victory.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42604529">Favorite blog in 2024?</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42604529">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Simon Willison&#39;s blog is highlighted for its insightful content on artificial intelligence (AI) in 2024.</li>
<li>Other recommended blogs include Julia Evans, Fabien Sanglard, and Ethan Mollick&#39;s &quot;One Useful Thing,&quot; offering unique perspectives and diverse topics.</li>
<li>For those interested in economics, Noah Smith and Paul Krugman are suggested, while Dynomight and Not Boring provide a blend of tech and lifestyle content.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.bingeclock.com/blog/post/republishing-my-simpsons-fan-site-twenty-years-later">Republishing my Simpsons fan site, twenty years later</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42605707">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The relaunch of a Simpsons fan site after 20 years has evoked nostalgia for the early internet era, characterized by personal fan sites and creative freedom. - Many people recall the 90s and 2000s as a time of unregulated and non-commercialized internet, contrasting with today&#39;s more regulated and commercial landscape. - Some original fan sites still exist, serving as a reminder of the joy and creativity of creating content for enjoyment rather than financial gain.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/srsran">SrsRAN: Open-Source 4G/5G</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The srsRAN software suite is an open-source collection of 4G and 5G radio applications developed by SRS, implemented in C++ with minimal dependencies, and runs on Linux with standard hardware.</li>
<li>It is licensed under AGPLv3, which is a free software license ensuring that the software remains open-source.</li>
<li>The suite includes a 5G RAN (Radio Access Network) CU+DU (Central Unit and Distributed Unit) with a complete ORAN-native stack, and a 4G suite providing full network implementation for User Equipment (UE), eNodeB (evolved Node B), and EPC (Evolved Packet Core).</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42605201">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>SrsRAN is an open-source initiative that enables users to create their own 4G/5G networks using software and hardware such as Software Defined Radios (SDRs) and blank SIM cards.</li>
<li>The project provides an alternative to proprietary Radio Access Network (RAN) solutions, targeting telecom companies and offering flexibility for testing, emergency connectivity, and educational purposes.</li>
<li>Users should be aware of potential legal and technical challenges, particularly concerning spectrum licensing, as the legality of setting up personal networks varies by region.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.wi-fi.org/regulations-enabling-6-ghz-wi-fi">Regulations Enabling 6 GHz Wi-Fi</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Several countries, including Argentina, Brazil, Canada, and the United States, have adopted the full 5925-7125 MHz spectrum range for use.</li>
<li>The European Union has adopted a portion of this range, specifically 5925-6425 MHz, with a focus on 5945-6425 MHz.</li>
<li>Other countries, such as Andorra, Austria, and Belgium, are considering adopting specific portions of the spectrum, while countries like Egypt, Oman, and Tunisia are still evaluating their options.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42606484">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The debate centers on whether the 6 GHz band should be licensed for 5G by telecom companies or remain unlicensed for Wi-Fi use, with significant implications for spectrum allocation. - The 6 GHz band is seen as a solution to congestion in existing Wi-Fi bands, but there is hesitance to allocate more ISM (Industrial, Scientific, and Medical) bandwidth. - Discussions also cover Wi-Fi 7&#39;s technical aspects, such as hardware availability and compatibility, highlighting the broader impact on future wireless technology development.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.usmint.gov/paper-currency/uncut-currency/">Uncut Currency</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42608155">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Uncut currency sheets were once misused by cutting them into off-center pieces and selling them as error notes, prompting the Treasury to make serial numbers recognizable to prevent this.</li>
<li>For $1 bills, serial numbers on uncut sheets start with 99, allowing collectors to verify authenticity when purchasing &quot;miscut dollar errors.&quot;</li>
<li>The US Mint sells uncut currency sheets at a premium, and they are popular among collectors for novelty, often being framed or given as gifts, despite being legal tender.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://crowdhailer.me/2025-01-02/the-evolution-of-a-structural-code-editor/">The evolution of a structural code editor</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The post outlines the development of a structural editor for the eyg programming language, which treats code as a structured tree to prevent syntax errors and improve code comprehension.</li>
<li>Initially built with Gleam and Svelte, the editor now uses Gleam and Lustre, with a terminal version in Go, and has evolved to simplify the Abstract Syntax Tree (AST) for better navigation.</li>
<li>The latest version features a menu and icon-based user interface, enhancing usability across devices, and encourages user feedback to improve the coding experience.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42608923">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion focuses on structural code editors, which view code as a structured tree, offering potential benefits like eliminating syntax errors and improving type information.</li>
<li>Challenges for structural editors include compatibility with existing tools like Git and managing invalid code states during editing.</li>
<li>There is interest in how structural editors could improve programming accessibility and efficiency, particularly in non-traditional environments like mobile devices, though concerns about practicality and integration remain.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Doom, the Gallery Experience" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Doom%2C%20the%20Gallery%20Experience&subheading=Monday%2C%20January%206%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/06</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-06T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-05]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/05&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-05</h1>
<h2><a href="https://uwaterloo.ca/news/media/no-more-needles-tracking-blood-sugar-your-wrist">Researchers design wearable tech that can sense glucose levels more accurately</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Researchers at the University of Waterloo have created a wearable device that uses radar technology to monitor glucose levels non-invasively, removing the need for needles.</li>
<li>The device, led by Dr. George Shaker, incorporates a radar chip, a meta-surface for enhanced signal accuracy, and AI algorithms for precise glucose readings.</li>
<li>Currently USB-powered, the device aims to become battery-operated for improved portability and may eventually monitor additional health metrics, with efforts underway to commercialize the technology.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42599189">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Researchers have created wearable technology for non-invasive glucose monitoring, offering an alternative to finger pricking and Continuous Glucose Monitors (CGMs).</li>
<li>The technology aims to provide accurate glucose readings without direct contact with the bloodstream, which could be significant for clinical applications.</li>
<li>While promising, there is skepticism about its accuracy compared to existing CGMs, and further data and clinical trials are needed to confirm its effectiveness.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://nmn.gl/blog/ai-senior-developer">The day I taught AI to read code like a Senior Developer</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The AI was initially challenged with analyzing React codebases, approaching them like a novice developer. - By emulating senior developers&#39; strategies, such as focusing on core files and grouping changes by feature, the AI&#39;s code analysis improved significantly. - The focus is on enhancing code understanding rather than generation, with future plans to identify technical debt and comprehend team conventions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42601847">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article explores the challenges of training AI to read and analyze code with the proficiency of a senior developer, noting the difficulty in achieving consistent and accurate results.</li>
<li>It stresses the importance of providing context and structuring inputs to enhance AI performance in code analysis, while acknowledging skepticism about AI&#39;s current capabilities.</li>
<li>The discussion highlights the need for further experimentation and evaluation to validate AI&#39;s performance and considers the broader implications and potential advancements of AI in software development.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="http://rachelbythebay.com/w/2025/01/04/cruft/">Web page annoyances that I don&#39;t inflict on you here</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42599102">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The author avoids using certain web features like sticky bars, forced SSL/TLS, pop-ups, and unnecessary tracking to enhance user experience.</li>
<li>There is an ongoing debate about the necessity of HTTPS for security versus its compatibility issues with older browsers.</li>
<li>The discussion highlights the challenge of balancing user experience with modern web practices.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://tailscale.com/blog/how-nat-traversal-works">How Nat Traversal Works (2020)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>NAT traversal enables direct device connections despite the presence of Network Address Translators (NATs) and firewalls, using UDP-based protocols and direct socket control.</li>
<li>Techniques such as STUN (Session Traversal Utilities for NAT) help in discovering public IP addresses, while relays like TURN (Traversal Using Relays around NAT) or Tailscale&#39;s DERP are used for more challenging NATs.</li>
<li>The ICE (Interactive Connectivity Establishment) protocol optimizes connection paths by evaluating all possible options and selecting the most efficient one, ensuring robust NAT traversal with end-to-end encryption and authentication.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42600846">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article explores NAT (Network Address Translation) traversal, emphasizing the differences between TCP (Transmission Control Protocol) and UDP (User Datagram Protocol) hole punching, noting TCP&#39;s slightly higher complexity.</li>
<li>It challenges the perception of NAT as a security feature and discusses Tailscale&#39;s method for NAT traversal, raising concerns about depending solely on software ACLs (Access Control Lists) for security.</li>
<li>The discussion highlights the importance of secure endpoints and critiques the limitations of conventional network security strategies in the context of NAT traversal.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://amanvir.com/guten">Guten: A Tiny Newspaper Printer</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42599599">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Guten is a small-scale newspaper printer project designed to minimize screen time by delivering news in printed form. - Discussions around the project include concerns about the BPA content in thermal paper and suggestions for using BPA-free alternatives or different printing technologies like impact or dot-matrix printers. - Comparisons are made to the discontinued Little Printer, with recommendations for enhancing Guten&#39;s developer-friendliness and customization options, alongside considerations of environmental and health impacts of thermal paper.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Researchers design wearable tech that can sense glucose levels more accurately" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Researchers%20design%20wearable%20tech%20that%20can%20sense%20glucose%20levels%20more%20accurately&subheading=Sunday%2C%20January%205%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/05</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-05T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2025-01-04]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2025/01/04&#39;</h2>
<h1>2025-01-04</h1>
<h2><a href="https://practicapp.com/carbagepilot-part1/">Self driving 1993 Volvo with open pilot</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A group of friends participated in the Carbage Run 2025 Winter edition, a 6-day rally through Sweden to the polar circle and back to Helsinki, requiring cars to be at least 20 years old and valued under €1000.</li>
<li>They transformed a 1993 Volvo 940 Estate into a self-driving vehicle using openpilot from comma.ai, incorporating modern components like electric power steering, a Bosch iBooster, and a Tesla radar sensor.</li>
<li>Future updates will include details on wiring, a custom Engine Control Unit (ECU), and plans to open-source the code, highlighting the project&#39;s innovative approach to retrofitting older vehicles with autonomous technology.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42592910">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A 1993 Volvo 940 was retrofitted with OpenPilot, a self-driving technology, highlighting the intersection of classic car design and modern tech.</li>
<li>The project faced challenges, including updating the brake and steering systems, raising legal and safety concerns, particularly with DIY modifications like welding the steering column.</li>
<li>The discussion extended to car regulations in Europe, the decline of hotrods in the US, and cultural differences in car modification freedoms, with the project viewed as an inspiring DIY effort despite safety concerns.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/s-macke/VoxelSpace">VoxelSpace: Terrain rendering algorithm in less than 20 lines of code (2020)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>NovaLogic&#39;s 1992 game Comanche utilized the Voxel Space engine, a 2.5D rendering technique based on ray casting, to create detailed terrains with shading and shadows.</li>
<li>The Voxel Space engine used height and color maps and a simple rendering algorithm, drawing vertical lines from back to front, which could be optimized for performance.</li>
<li>The engine&#39;s code is available under the MIT license, but the technology may still be patented in certain regions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42588956">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>VoxelSpace is a terrain rendering algorithm notable for its simplicity, requiring less than 20 lines of code, and evokes nostalgia for innovative game development during hardware-limited eras.</li>
<li>Modern AAA games focus on complex optimizations and market trends, often at the expense of originality, whereas indie games and platforms like PICO-8 provide more creative freedom.</li>
<li>Despite technological advancements, some developers and players feel that the &quot;magic&quot; of older games is missing, though innovative projects like voxel rendering continue to inspire creativity.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://ameye.dev/notes/rendering-outlines/">How to draw an outline in a video game</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses five techniques for rendering outlines in Unity, a popular game development platform, highlighting their use in games like Sable and The Last of Us. - Techniques include Rim Effects, Vertex Extrusion, Blurred Buffer, Jump Flood Algorithm, and Edge Detection, each with unique advantages and trade-offs in terms of performance and visual quality. - The article provides insights into balancing these methods for optimal game aesthetics and gameplay support, with additional resources and credits for 3D models included.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42593614">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article explores advanced techniques for drawing outlines in video games, emphasizing the efficiency of the Jump Flood Algorithm (JFA) and Signed Distance Fields (SDFs) over traditional methods. - It delves into stylized 3D graphics, discussing rendering techniques and the potential use of neural networks for lighting and styling. - Contributors provide insights into the historical development of cel shading in games, such as Jet Set Radio, highlighting the evolving intersection of technology and art in 3D graphics.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://anntelnaes.substack.com/p/why-im-quitting-the-washington-post">I&#39;m quitting the Washington Post</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42591221">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The author is leaving the Washington Post due to its failure to adapt to the evolving media landscape and its approach to presenting issues, which they believe is ineffective for critical topics like democracy.</li>
<li>Traditional media, particularly local newspapers, are struggling financially, leading to biased reporting and a decline in public trust, while social media cannot replace the rigorous work of journalism.</li>
<li>Concerns are raised about the influence of wealthy individuals, such as Jeff Bezos, on media outlets, and the impact of corporate interests on the media&#39;s role in holding power accountable.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://twitter.com/damengchen/status/1875296442417607072">Perplexity got ads</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42589863">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Perplexity has introduced advertisements, leading to discussions about the inevitability of ads in online services due to consumer reluctance to pay for ad-free experiences. - Some users find ads intrusive and prefer subscription-based services like Kagi, which offer ad-free search, while others continue to choose free, ad-supported options. - This situation underscores the ongoing debate between ad-supported and subscription-based models in digital services.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Self driving 1993 Volvo with open pilot" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Self%20driving%201993%20Volvo%20with%20open%20pilot&subheading=Saturday%2C%20January%204%2C%202025%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2025/01/04</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-04T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
