<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0"
>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 19:07:56 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/newsletter/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <copyright><![CDATA[2023 Sunghyun Cho]]></copyright>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-11-24]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/11/24&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-11-24</h1>
<h2><a href="https://www.tyleo.com/html-glass.html">Frosted Glass from Games to the Web: HTML glass UI inspired by AAA game dev</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The guide explores creating a frosted glass effect in HTML, inspired by AAA games like Forza Horizon 3 and Forza Motorsport 7, providing sample code and assets.</li>
<li>Key techniques include using CSS&#39;s <code>backdrop-filter</code> for blur effects, <code>box-shadow</code> for depth, and JavaScript for dynamic light reflections, with both JavaScript and non-JavaScript versions for cross-platform compatibility.</li>
<li>The tutorial includes a &quot;Final Recipe&quot; section for a quick start, allowing users to craft their own stunning glass UI.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42225481">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion focuses on the use of frosted glass UI effects in web development, inspired by high-end game design, highlighting both aesthetic appeal and computational cost concerns.</li>
<li>There is a debate on the trade-offs between server bandwidth and client-side processing, with varying opinions based on personal experiences and technological perspectives.</li>
<li>The conversation also considers the efficiency of modern GPUs and the environmental impact of different computational methods.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/p8952/bocker">Bocker: Docker implemented in around 100 lines of Bash (2015)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Bocker Docker is a minimal Docker implementation written in approximately 100 lines of bash, designed for lightweight container management.</li>
<li>It requires specific system packages and configurations, including a btrfs filesystem and network settings, and is best run in a virtual machine due to its need for root access.</li>
<li>Bocker supports basic Docker functionalities like building, pulling, running containers, and managing resources, but lacks features such as data volume containers and port forwarding.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42224670">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Bocker is a simplified Docker implementation written in Bash, demonstrating how Docker&#39;s core functionalities can be minimized.</li>
<li>The discussion includes comparisons with other lightweight environment tools like proot and chroot, and alternatives such as Podman.</li>
<li>Key topics include Docker&#39;s evolution, its ecosystem&#39;s value, and the challenges of running containers on non-Linux systems.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://newsletter.weskao.com/p/how-to-give-a-senior-leader-feedback-without-getting-fired">How to give a senior leader feedback without getting fired</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Wes Kao&#39;s Newsletter provides strategies for giving feedback to senior leaders safely, such as the &quot;even more&quot; technique and using diplomatic language.</li>
<li>The newsletter emphasizes supporting feedback with data and sharing personal experiences to enhance communication effectiveness.</li>
<li>It also promotes Wes&#39;s Executive Communication &amp; Influence course, aimed at improving workplace communication skills.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42223099">Reactions</a></h3>
<h2><a href="https://hub.jhu.edu/2024/11/21/ancient-alphabet-discovered-syria/">Evidence of oldest known alphabetic writing unearthed in ancient Syrian city</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Researchers from Johns Hopkins University have uncovered what could be the oldest known alphabetic writing, dating to approximately 2400 BCE, in a Syrian tomb.</li>
<li>This discovery suggests that alphabetic writing is 500 years older than previously believed, potentially altering the understanding of its origins.</li>
<li>The writing, found on clay cylinders at Tell Umm-el Marra in Syria, predates known scripts from Egypt and will be presented at the American Society of Overseas Research&#39;s Annual Meeting.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42224330">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Researchers have discovered the oldest known alphabetic writing in an ancient Syrian city, dating back to approximately 2400 BCE, indicating that alphabetic writing may have originated earlier than previously believed.- The writing was found on four clay cylinders, but without a translation method, the content remains speculative, prompting questions about the evolution and dissemination of alphabetic writing systems.- This finding is significant as it challenges existing theories about the timeline and influence of alphabetic writing in ancient societies.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="http://www.righto.com/2024/11/antenna-diodes-in-pentium-processor.html">Antenna Diodes in the Pentium Processor</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Ken Shirriff&#39;s blog delves into computer history, with a focus on vintage computers and integrated circuit (IC) reverse engineering, providing insights into the complexities of chip design and manufacturing.</li>
<li>In a post about the Pentium processor, he explains &quot;antenna diodes,&quot; which protect circuitry from plasma-induced charges during the etching process, a critical aspect of manufacturing.</li>
<li>Despite being released in 1993 with 3.1 million transistors, the Pentium&#39;s use of antenna diodes is limited due to space constraints, highlighting ongoing challenges in modern IC design to mitigate antenna effects.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42223690">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Antenna diodes in Pentium processors are utilized during manufacturing to prevent charge buildup on long wires, protecting circuits from damage.</li>
<li>These diodes are not functional in the chip&#39;s active design, emphasizing their role solely in the manufacturing phase.</li>
<li>The discussion sheds light on the intricate processes of chip manufacturing, including the use of multiple layers and materials such as tungsten for vias, appealing to those interested in chip design and manufacturing.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://bitfieldconsulting.com/posts/career">A Career Ending Mistake</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article emphasizes the importance of planning the end of your career, focusing on achieving career goals beyond just retirement.</li>
<li>It outlines three potential career paths: Seniority (becoming a senior individual contributor), Management (transitioning to a managerial role), and Independence (working for yourself).</li>
<li>The text stresses the need for self-reflection, skill development, and flexibility, encouraging readers to actively plan their career paths and remain open to change and unexpected opportunities.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42228538">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>In the tech industry, contributions can quickly become obsolete after departure, as code is rewritten and documentation is lost.</li>
<li>The post suggests prioritizing financial gain and personal well-being over a rigid career path, highlighting management roles as potentially offering more long-term value than individual contributor positions.</li>
<li>Emphasizes the importance of adaptability in career paths and suggests that relationships and personal satisfaction often outweigh career achievements.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.wral.com/news/local/nc-state-marshall-brain-dies-november-2024/">Howstuffworks.com creator, Marshall Brain, has died</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42228759">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Marshall Brain, the creator of Howstuffworks.com and author of the speculative fiction &quot;Manna,&quot; has passed away, leaving a significant impact on many through his work.</li>
<li>He was a professor at NC State University, where he influenced and shaped the futures of numerous students.</li>
<li>His passing, reportedly by suicide, underscores the critical importance of mental health awareness, while his legacy continues to inspire curiosity and understanding.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Frosted Glass from Games to the Web: HTML glass UI inspired by AAA game dev" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Frosted%20Glass%20from%20Games%20to%20the%20Web%3A%20HTML%20glass%20UI%20inspired%20by%20AAA%20game%20dev&subheading=Sunday%2C%20November%2024%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/11/24</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-11-24T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-11-23]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/11/23&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-11-23</h1>
<h2><a href="https://blog.avas.space/rto/">The &#39;Return to Office&#39; Lies</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The blog post criticizes the push for returning to the office, arguing that roles like data entry and digital communication do not necessitate physical presence.</li>
<li>The author highlights the benefits of remote work, such as increased productivity, reduced stress, and better accessibility for disabled and chronically ill employees.</li>
<li>Concerns are raised about the potential loss of young talent if remote work options are limited, especially given the lack of performance bonuses despite increased workloads.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42221623">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Many individuals prefer remote work over higher salaries, valuing the benefits of avoiding commutes and having more personal time.</li>
<li>Some workers accept pay cuts for the flexibility and mental well-being that remote work provides.</li>
<li>The debate on remote work versus return to office (RTO) involves issues of control, productivity, in-person collaboration, and broader impacts on work-life balance and future work environments.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/check-out-the-highest-resolution-images-ever-captured-of-the-suns-entire-surface-180985518/">Highest-resolution images ever captured of the sun’s entire surface</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The European Space Agency (ESA) has released the highest-resolution images of the sun&#39;s surface, captured by the Solar Orbiter in March 2023, from less than 46 million miles away.</li>
<li>The Solar Orbiter, a joint mission with NASA launched in 2020, has achieved milestones such as capturing the closest images of the sun and its polar regions.</li>
<li>The new images, taken by the Polarimetric and Helioseismic Imager (PHI) and the Extreme Ultraviolet Imager (EUI), provide unprecedented detail of the sun&#39;s magnetic fields and outer atmosphere, aiming to enhance understanding of the sun&#39;s dynamic nature.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42220155">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Solar Orbiter has captured the highest-resolution images of the sun&#39;s entire surface, available in various formats such as visible light, magnetogram, velocity map, and ultraviolet views.</li>
<li>These images are accessible online, sparking discussions about their quality, processing, and some noted artifacts and slow zooming issues.</li>
<li>The images were taken over several hours, highlighting the sun&#39;s immense energy and scale, and prompting discussions on its impact and the potential for advanced life forms within stars.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://fabiensanglard.net/quake3/network.php">Quake 3 Source Code Review: Network Model (2012)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Fabien Sanglard&#39;s review praises Quake 3&#39;s network model for its efficient use of UDP/IP, which is preferred over TCP/IP to minimize latency in fast-paced gaming environments.</li>
<li>The server manages UDP&#39;s unreliability by using snapshot histories to create delta packets, ensuring efficient communication between the client and server.</li>
<li>The NetChannel module pre-fragments messages to prevent router fragmentation, and handles guaranteed delivery for certain messages, enhancing the overall network performance.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42218532">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The review of Quake 3&#39;s network model initiated discussions on work-life balance, highlighting user experiences of burnout and the advantages of reducing work hours for hobbies.</li>
<li>Quake 3&#39;s net code was effective for local area network (LAN) play but struggled with latency issues during remote play, contrasting with modern game protocols that require advanced logic for synchronization and bandwidth management.</li>
<li>The discussion provided resources for understanding real-time game protocols and reflected on the evolution of internet speeds and gaming experiences over time.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/11/22/synapse-bankruptcy-thousands-of-americans-see-their-savings-vanish.html">Americans see their savings vanish in Synapse fintech crisis</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The collapse of fintech company Synapse has resulted in thousands of Americans losing their savings, with accounts initially believed to be government-backed.</li>
<li>A dispute between Synapse and Evolve Bank led to missing funds and unresolved issues, leaving customers locked out of their accounts for months.</li>
<li>The incident underscores the risks associated with fintech companies that lack direct relationships with traditional banks, as regulatory bodies have not stepped in to resolve the crisis.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42219407">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Synapse fintech crisis has resulted in Americans losing their savings, with $96 million currently unaccounted for, as Synapse, the financial processor, went bankrupt.</li>
<li>Yotta, a fintech app involved in the crisis, offered low interest rates and lottery incentives but is not a bank, meaning the FDIC (Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation) won&#39;t cover the losses since no bank has failed.</li>
<li>This situation underscores the inherent risks associated with fintech companies and emphasizes the necessity for improved regulatory measures in the industry.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/ColleagueRiley/RGFW">RGFW: Single-header C99 window abstraction library</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Riley&#39;s Graphics library FrameWork (RGFW) is a lightweight, single-header library for creating graphics applications, offering a flexible alternative to GLFW.- RGFW supports multiple platforms, including UNIX, MacOS, Windows, and webASM, with experimental support for Wayland, and works with various graphics backends like OpenGL and Vulkan.- It is designed for RSGL but can be used independently or with other libraries, featuring a flexible event system and compatibility with multiple compilers, under the Zlib/libPNG license.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42217535">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>RGFW is a single-header C99 window abstraction library, with discussions focusing on its compatibility with Windows, particularly with MSVC (Microsoft Visual C++) and MinGW (Minimalist GNU for Windows) compilers.</li>
<li>The library&#39;s Wayland support is experimental, and users express a need for better alternatives to X11, a windowing system for bitmap displays.</li>
<li>The conversation highlights the pros and cons of single-header libraries, comparing RGFW to other libraries like SDL (Simple DirectMedia Layer) and GLFW, and addressing the challenges of multi-platform support, including mobile.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://docs.maxxinteractive.com/">MaXX Interactive Desktop -- the little brother of the great SGI Desktop on IRIX</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>MaXX Interactive Desktop has released a new version focused on high performance, stability, and productivity with a minimalist design and low resource usage.- The desktop environment is designed to enhance creativity by prioritizing user applications and minimizing visual distractions, catering to IRIX users, graphic artists, and developers.- The project is transitioning to a community-driven model, encouraging user participation and collaboration.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42218184">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>MaXX Interactive Desktop, inspired by the SGI Desktop on IRIX, is being developed for Linux, with future plans for FreeBSD and Windows11 WSL2 support.</li>
<li>The project aims to recreate a classic desktop experience but is progressing slowly and is not open source, which may limit community contributions.</li>
<li>Users express nostalgia for unique features and UI elements from older desktop environments, highlighting challenges in achieving modern compatibility.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="The 'Return to Office' Lies" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=The%20'Return%20to%20Office'%20Lies&subheading=Saturday%2C%20November%2023%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/11/23</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-11-23T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 23 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-11-22]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/11/22&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-11-22</h1>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/PaulPauls/llama3_interpretability_sae">Llama 3.2 Interpretability with Sparse Autoencoders</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The post discusses a personal side project focused on replicating mechanistic interpretability research on proprietary Large Language Models (LLMs), inspired by recent work from companies like Anthropic, OpenAI, and DeepMind.</li>
<li>The author is seeking feedback and engagement from the HackerNews community, indicating a collaborative and open approach to their research.</li>
<li>The project is linked to recent academic publications, suggesting it is grounded in current scientific discourse and advancements in the field of AI interpretability.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42208383">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Llama 3.2 Interpretability with Sparse Autoencoders is a project by PaulPauls that aims to replicate mechanistic interpretability research on proprietary Large Language Models (LLMs).- The project utilizes Sparse Autoencoders (SAEs) to explore the causal sequence of &quot;thoughts&quot; in models, drawing parallels to human reasoning.- This open research, available on GitHub, has initiated discussions on interpretability, human reasoning, and the challenges associated with evaluating SAEs, with PaulPauls welcoming community feedback.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://5-million-devs.netlify.com/">A Marble Madness-inspired WebGL game we built for Netlify</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A creative studio developed an interactive game for Netlify to celebrate reaching 5 million developers, inspired by the classic game Marble Madness.- The game utilizes Three.js for 3D graphics and Rapier for physics, integrating 2D content with CSS 3D transforms to create a seamless experience.- The studio invites users to try the game and provide feedback, highlighting the blend of marketing content with a game-like experience.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42212644">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A WebGL game inspired by Marble Madness was developed for Netlify to commemorate reaching 5 million developers, combining gameplay with marketing content.- The game utilizes Three.js for 3D graphics and Rapier for physics, integrating 2D content through CSS 3D transforms.- Feedback is encouraged to enhance the user experience.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.opb.org/article/2024/11/17/salmon-return-to-lay-eggs-in-historic-habitat-after-largest-dam-removal-project-in-us-history/">Salmon return to lay eggs in historic habitat after dam removal project</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Following the demolition of four dams on the Klamath River, hundreds of salmon have returned to spawn in areas that were previously inaccessible, marking a rapid ecological recovery.</li>
<li>This event is a significant victory for local tribes who advocated for the dam removal to restore the river&#39;s ecosystem, highlighting the project&#39;s success in improving water quality and salmon health.</li>
<li>The project is noted as the largest dam removal in U.S. history, with the swift return of salmon exceeding expectations and providing optimism for the river&#39;s future.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42213663">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Salmon have returned to their historic spawning grounds on the Klamath River following the removal of four dams, prompting discussions on their navigation methods after decades of being cut off.- The dam removal was part of a broader ecological restoration effort, supported by local tribes and environmental groups, aimed at restoring natural habitats.- The dams were outdated and provided limited electricity, making their removal a feasible option for enhancing the river&#39;s ecological health.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/11/22/amazon-to-invest-another-4-billion-in-anthropic-openais-biggest-rival.html">Amazon to invest another $4B in Anthropic, OpenAI&#39;s biggest rival</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Amazon has announced a significant $4 billion investment in Anthropic, an AI startup founded by former OpenAI executives, increasing its total investment to $8 billion.- Amazon Web Services (AWS) will serve as Anthropic&#39;s primary cloud and training partner, offering AWS customers early access to customize Anthropic&#39;s Claude chatbot with their data.- This investment highlights the competitive nature of the generative AI market, with Anthropic recently unveiling AI agents for complex tasks and Google having previously invested $2 billion in the company.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42215126">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Amazon is investing $4 billion in Anthropic, a competitor to OpenAI, to address capacity issues and enhance performance for Anthropic&#39;s Pro service.</li>
<li>The investment is expected to involve AWS (Amazon Web Services) credits, potentially lowering Amazon&#39;s actual expenditure, and includes using Amazon&#39;s chips for AI model training.</li>
<li>This strategic move supports Amazon&#39;s goal to increase AWS revenue and expand its artificial intelligence capabilities.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/pingcap/autoflow">Autoflow, a Graph RAG based and conversational knowledge base tool</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Autoflow is an open-source Knowledge Graph called GraphRAG, utilizing TiDB Vector, LlamaIndex, and DSPy, featuring a perplexity-style conversational search and a website crawler for sitemap URL scraping.</li>
<li>It can be deployed using Docker Compose, requiring 4 CPU cores and 8GB RAM, and includes a tech stack of TiDB, LlamaIndex, DSPy, Next.js, and shadcn/ui.</li>
<li>Autoflow allows users to edit the Knowledge Graph for accuracy and offers an embeddable JavaScript snippet for integrating a conversational search window on websites.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42210689">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Autoflow, a tool based on Graph RAG (Recurrent Attention Graph), has a complex workflow that some users find slow and cumbersome, especially for basic queries.</li>
<li>While the user interface is well-designed, there are calls for a more streamlined version to cater to users who may not need all its intricate features.</li>
<li>Discussions highlight interest in self-hosting, personal data management, and the potential use of local LLMs (Large Language Models) to improve personal browsing history management, emphasizing privacy and user choice.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://aws.amazon.com/about-aws/whats-new/2024/11/amazon-s3-express-one-zone-append-data-object/">Amazon S3 now supports the ability to append data to an object</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Amazon S3 Express One Zone now supports appending data to existing objects, eliminating the need for local storage and benefiting applications like log-processing and media broadcasting.</li>
<li>This feature is available in all AWS Regions and can be accessed using the AWS SDK, CLI, or Mountpoint for Amazon S3 (version 1.12.0 or higher).</li>
<li>The update is particularly advantageous for applications that require continuous file updates, enhancing efficiency and reducing storage overhead.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42211280">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Amazon S3 introduces a new feature allowing data to be appended to objects, but it is limited to the &quot;S3 Express One Zone&quot; bucket class, which is costlier and less available than the standard tier.</li>
<li>The feature supports up to 10,000 append operations per object, making it less ideal for direct log file writing, especially when compared to Azure&#39;s similar functionality available since 2015.</li>
<li>This development has sparked discussions on the practicality of S3&#39;s new feature due to its limitations and higher costs compared to other cloud storage solutions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://cacm.acm.org/news/a-camera-the-size-of-a-grain-of-salt-could-change-imaging-as-we-know-it/">A “meta-optics” camera that is the size of a grain of salt</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Researchers at Princeton University and the University of Washington have created a &quot;meta-optics&quot; camera, remarkably small at the size of a grain of salt, and 500,000 times smaller than traditional cameras.</li>
<li>This camera utilizes a metasurface with 1.6 million cylindrical posts to capture high-quality, full-color images, potentially transforming fields like medical imaging, consumer electronics, and space telescopes.</li>
<li>The metasurfaces are manufactured using techniques akin to computer chip production, which could lower costs and broaden the range of applications for these ultra-compact cameras.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42212992">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A &quot;meta-optics&quot; camera, as small as a grain of salt, can capture full-color images, though some question its image quality compared to traditional cameras.</li>
<li>The technology employs subwavelength nano-antennas and AI-driven post-processing to improve image quality, but images may still lack sharpness and color.</li>
<li>The camera&#39;s tiny size and potential uses in fields like medicine and military raise privacy concerns and highlight its ongoing relevance and impact since its 2021 publication.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://podcast.play.date/episodes/s01e31/">Story of the two thousand stolen Playdate handhelds</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42211689">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Two thousand Playdate handheld gaming devices were stolen, and FedEx has refused to compensate the $400,000 loss, citing a signature from an unauthorized individual.- This incident underscores significant issues in logistics and delivery verification, highlighting a pattern of inadequate responses from companies in similar situations.- The case emphasizes the importance of device registration as a potential method for recovering stolen goods.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://developer.chrome.com/blog/next-for-webgpu">What&#39;s Next for WebGPU</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The WebGPU specification is under active development, with major tech companies like Google, Mozilla, Apple, Intel, and Microsoft collaborating weekly.- A recent meeting aimed at advancing WebGPU to candidate recommendation status for the World Wide Web Consortium (W3C) and discussed new features such as subgroups, texel buffers, and 64-bit atomics.- The meeting highlighted the importance of collaboration and feedback, focusing on enhancing WebGPU&#39;s capabilities for web graphics and artificial intelligence (AI).</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42209272">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>WebGPU is focusing on adding features like bindless to enhance performance by minimizing frequent state changes, although implementation may take time.- Current limitations, such as small default texture limits, restrict WebGPU&#39;s use in serious applications, posing challenges for Rust game developers.- Despite these constraints, WebGPU is considered promising for advanced graphics and compute capabilities in web applications, with potential uses in gaming and machine learning, though platform adoption remains a concern, particularly with Apple&#39;s unique implementations.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://tailwindcss.com/blog/tailwindcss-v4-beta">Tailwind CSS v4.0 Beta 1</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Tailwind CSS v4.0 Beta 1 was released on November 21, 2024, introducing a faster engine and a unified toolchain.- This version emphasizes a CSS-first configuration, catering to modern web development needs with features like native cascade layers and wide-gamut colors.- Users are encouraged to explore the beta documentation to contribute to the preparation for the stable release expected early next year.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42210553">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Tailwind CSS v4.0 Beta 1 has been released, introducing features like the OKLCH color space and improved performance, which has sparked discussions in the web development community.</li>
<li>The release has prompted debates about the complexity of modern web development tools such as Vite and npm, with some users questioning their necessity and others defending their efficiency.</li>
<li>Tailwind CSS is praised for its utility classes that simplify CSS within HTML, offering benefits for responsive design and reducing CSS file sizes, similar to but more optimized than Bootstrap.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Llama 3.2 Interpretability with Sparse Autoencoders" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Llama%203.2%20Interpretability%20with%20Sparse%20Autoencoders&subheading=Friday%2C%20November%2022%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/11/22</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-11-22T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-11-21]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/11/21&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-11-21</h1>
<h2><a href="https://www.icc-cpi.int/news/situation-state-palestine-icc-pre-trial-chamber-i-rejects-state-israels-challenges">ICC issues warrants for Netanyahu, Gallant, and Hamas officials</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42203543">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The International Criminal Court (ICC) has issued arrest warrants for Israeli leaders Netanyahu and Gallant, along with Hamas officials, for alleged war crimes.</li>
<li>The warrants underscore the ICC&#39;s jurisdiction over crimes in Palestinian territories, even though Israel does not recognize the court&#39;s authority.</li>
<li>This situation highlights challenges in international law enforcement, as major powers like the US do not recognize the ICC, potentially limiting its effectiveness and making actual arrests unlikely.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/mathematical-thinking-isnt-what-you-think-it-is-20241118/">Everyone is capable of, and can benefit from, mathematical thinking</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>David Bessis, a mathematician, posits that mathematical thinking, which balances intuition and logic, is beneficial for everyone, enhancing creativity and understanding.- In his book &quot;Mathematica: A Secret World of Intuition and Curiosity,&quot; Bessis likens mathematical thinking to a dialogue between reason and instinct, akin to yoga, and emphasizes it as a skill developed through practice.- Bessis views math as a universal life lesson that can bring joy, clarity, and self-confidence, suggesting it is not just problem-solving but a form of self-help.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42200209">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Mathematical thinking is beneficial for everyone, but many face challenges due to ineffective teaching methods and lack of motivation.- Math is often mistakenly viewed as an innate talent rather than a skill that can be developed with the right approach and mindset, similar to sports.- Emphasizing that math is accessible to all, teaching should focus on developing mathematical thinking skills, making learning enjoyable and inclusive.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://torrentfreak.com/z-library-helps-students-to-overcome-academic-poverty-study-finds-241120/">Z-Library Helps Students to Overcome Academic Poverty, Study Finds</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A study in the Journal of University Teaching &amp; Learning Practice examines the use of Z-Library, a shadow library providing free books and academic articles, highlighting high costs and limited access as primary motivators.</li>
<li>Chinese postgraduate students, among others, use Z-Library to combat academic poverty, viewing it as crucial for academic success despite legal issues faced by the platform.</li>
<li>The study recommends that universities and publishers increase free access to content to bridge digital divides and address the needs of students relying on such resources.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42199301">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A study emphasizes Z-Library&#39;s role in alleviating academic poverty by offering free access to textbooks, aiding students in previewing books before buying physical copies.</li>
<li>The discussion explores the dual nature of piracy, with arguments that it can both negatively impact sales and potentially lead to legitimate purchases, maintaining resource relevance.</li>
<li>The conversation also references other platforms like Sci-Hub and Libgen, debating the ethical and educational implications of piracy in accessing educational and software resources.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.ualberta.ca/en/folio/2024/11/weight-loss-drug-found-to-shrink-heart-muscle.html">Weight-loss drug found to shrink muscle in mice, human cells</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A University of Alberta study indicates that weight-loss drugs such as Ozempic may lead to heart and muscle shrinkage, raising concerns about potential long-term health effects.</li>
<li>The study observed heart muscle loss in both mice and human cells, prompting researchers to recommend monitoring heart health in users of these drugs.</li>
<li>Experts suggest that up to 40% of weight loss from these drugs is muscle, advising users to maintain muscle mass through proper nutrition and resistance training during treatment.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42199447">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A study indicates that semaglutide, a weight-loss drug, may lead to more muscle loss than traditional dieting, raising concerns about its long-term health effects.</li>
<li>The research found that semaglutide reduces heart muscle in both mice and human cells, prompting a debate on whether the benefits of weight loss outweigh the potential risks.</li>
<li>Experts recommend proper nutrition and exercise to counteract muscle loss, emphasizing the need for further research on semaglutide&#39;s impact on muscle and overall health.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://bicycledutch.wordpress.com/2018/02/20/a-common-urban-intersection-in-the-netherlands/">A common urban intersection in the Netherlands (2018)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Urban intersections in the Netherlands, such as those in &#39;s-Hertogenbosch, are designed to prioritize safety and efficiency for all road users, including motor traffic, cyclists, and pedestrians.</li>
<li>Key features include protected cycleways, raised intersections, clear road markings, and priority rules that favor non-motorized traffic, reducing the need for traffic signals.</li>
<li>This design approach emphasizes the Dutch commitment to accommodating diverse traffic types through innovative and thoughtful infrastructure planning.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42202397">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Netherlands prioritizes cyclists and pedestrians at urban intersections, contrasting with countries like the UK and Italy, where cycling infrastructure often lacks priority and can be awkward or poorly designed.- The success of the Dutch model is due to a cultural shift and legal frameworks that favor cyclists, leading to safer and more efficient cycling environments.- There are calls for other countries to adopt the Dutch model to improve cycling safety and infrastructure, highlighting its effectiveness and appeal.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/11/google-cracks-down-on-parasite-seo-punishing-established-publishers/">Google stops letting sites like Forbes rule search for &quot;Best CBD Gummies&quot;</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Google has revised its site reputation abuse policy to address &quot;Parasite SEO,&quot; where established websites use their domain authority to promote unrelated third-party product recommendations.</li>
<li>This update has led to a decline in search rankings for sites like Forbes and Time, which have been using this tactic for affiliate content.</li>
<li>The policy change aims to improve the search experience by reducing the influence of exploitative SEO practices on search results.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42198115">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Google has implemented changes to prevent sites like Forbes from dominating search results for terms such as &quot;Best CBD Gummies,&quot; addressing issues with SEO spam and affiliate marketing.</li>
<li>This change aims to improve search result quality, which has been affected by AI-generated content and aggressive SEO tactics.</li>
<li>The move is also seen as a response to competition from AI tools like ChatGPT, as Google seeks to enhance search results and diminish the impact of low-quality content.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://electrobun.dev/">Electrobun: Cross-platform desktop applications written in TypeScript</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Electrobun is a tool for developing fast, small, cross-platform desktop applications using Typescript, leveraging bun for execution and zig for native bindings.</li>
<li>The latest version, Electrobun v0.0.13, can be installed with <code>$ bun install electrobun</code>, offering compact app bundles (~12MB) and minimal updates (as small as 4KB).</li>
<li>It provides an integrated workflow that allows developers to start coding in 5 minutes and distribute applications in 10, ensuring efficient performance with isolated processes and easy Remote Procedure Call (RPC) capabilities.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42199486">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Electrobun is a new framework designed for creating cross-platform desktop applications using TypeScript, similar to Electron but utilizing Bun and the system webview instead of Node.js and Chromium.</li>
<li>Currently, Electrobun is only available for macOS, with future plans to support Windows and Linux, and is in its early development stages focusing on stability.</li>
<li>The framework promises small update sizes and a custom Remote Procedure Call (RPC) mechanism for efficient inter-process communication, though it currently lacks comprehensive documentation and visual examples.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.php.net/releases/8.4/en.php">PHP 8.4</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>PHP 8.4.1 introduces significant updates, including property hooks for computed properties and asymmetric visibility for property access control.- Enhancements include an updated DOM API with HTML5 support, new array functions, and a new JIT (Just-In-Time) implementation for improved performance.- Deprecated features involve unbundled extensions and changes to certain constants and functions, encouraging users to upgrade for better performance and syntax.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42202670">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>PHP 8.4 introduces property hooks, a feature aimed at simplifying getters and setters, drawing comparisons to similar functionality in C#.</li>
<li>The update includes performance enhancements, improved stack traces, and new array functions, contributing to PHP&#39;s ongoing evolution.</li>
<li>Developers are divided on the changes, with some concerned about added complexity, while others appreciate the reduction in boilerplate code and a shift from Java-like verbosity.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://abenezer.org/blog/hyrum-law-in-golang">Hyrum&#39;s Law in Golang</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Hyrum&#39;s Law, named after Google engineer Hyrum Wright, suggests that with enough API users, all observable behaviors will be relied upon by someone, making changes risky.</li>
<li>In the Go programming language, altering error messages like &quot;http: request body too large&quot; can disrupt existing code that depends on these messages, illustrating Hyrum&#39;s Law.</li>
<li>This concept is not exclusive to Go; it is also evident in other languages like JavaScript, emphasizing the importance of designing systems to minimize unintended dependencies.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42201892">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Hyrum&#39;s Law suggests that any observable behavior in a system, even if unintended, can become a dependency for users, making changes potentially disruptive.</li>
<li>Library authors should document stable API parts and consider user dependencies, while consumers should be cautious of relying on undocumented features.</li>
<li>The discussion emphasizes balancing technical improvements with user expectations, noting differences in handling changes between open-source and enterprise software.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/gtls64/MontyHome-Hackers-Guide">We open-sourced our compost monitoring tech</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Monty Compost Co. is a startup focused on enhancing composting efficiency for both residential and industrial use through open-source technology.- The technology integrates with platforms like Raspberry Pi and Arduino, using sensors to monitor gas, temperature, moisture, and air pressure, with data exportable as CSV files.- While initially designed for compost monitoring, the technology is adaptable for Internet of Things (IoT) and environmental monitoring applications.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42200099">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Monty Compost Co. has released its compost monitoring technology as open-source, allowing for adaptation in various applications beyond composting.</li>
<li>The system is compatible with Raspberry Pi and Arduino, featuring sensors for gas composition, temperature, moisture, and air pressure, with data exportable as CSV files.</li>
<li>This technology is designed to optimize composting but is also applicable for Internet of Things (IoT) and environmental monitoring, encouraging user experimentation and project sharing.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://doomsdaymachines.net/p/the-meme-ification-of-the-demon-core">The meme-ification of the &quot;Demon Core&quot;</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The &quot;Demon Core,&quot; associated with two fatal nuclear accidents, has become a dark internet meme, often featuring unexpected juxtapositions with cute anime characters.- The meme&#39;s popularity since 2019 highlights a niche interest that has gained wider recognition, despite being considered in poor taste.- The &quot;Demon Core&quot; was the third plutonium core intended for WWII, adding complexity to its meme-ification, particularly due to its Japanese origins.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42200699">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The &quot;Demon Core&quot; memes originate from a blend of dark humor and historical nuclear incidents involving a plutonium sphere.</li>
<li>The memes juxtapose the core&#39;s dangerous nature with humorous or absurd contexts, sparking debate on whether the humor stems from the reckless experiments or as a coping mechanism for nuclear history.</li>
<li>This phenomenon illustrates how humor can emerge from serious topics, offering insights into human behavior and unexpected reactions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://thematrix1999.github.io/">The Matrix: Infinite-Horizon World Generation with Real-Time Interaction</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Matrix project is developing a real-time, immersive digital universe with high-quality visuals and frame-level precision, inspired by the film&#39;s concept.</li>
<li>It utilizes advanced models like Swin-DPM for generating infinitely long videos, allowing real-time control and exploration of dynamic environments.</li>
<li>The project plans to open-source its data to encourage research and innovation, showcasing diverse scenes that blend virtual and real-world settings.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42201117">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion focuses on the potential for generating infinite virtual worlds, inspired by &quot;The Matrix: Infinite-Horizon World Generation with Real-Time Interaction.&quot;</li>
<li>Comparisons are made to games like Minecraft, which utilize procedural generation to maintain spatial consistency, and suggestions include using low-resolution 3D worlds for effectiveness.</li>
<li>The role of AI in enhancing virtual reality (VR) and mixed reality experiences is highlighted, alongside concerns about the current technology&#39;s usability and marketability.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://trailimap.com/">Bike route planner that follows almost only official bike trails</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A new bike touring route planner app has been developed, focusing on utilizing existing bike infrastructure and allowing users to explore routes via maps or official trails.- The app currently covers Europe and uses OpenStreetMap data for optimal route planning, with future expansion plans to North America and globally.- Technically, the app employs Graphhopper for route finding, is built with Next.js 14 and Typescript, and uses a .NET backend, with map tiles sourced from MapTiler, though self-hosting is planned.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42197754">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A new bike route planner app has been developed, focusing on official bike trails for bike touring, and is currently available in Europe.- The app utilizes OpenStreetMap data and employs Graphhopper for route finding, with a web app built using Next.js and .NET.- Future expansion plans include extending the app&#39;s availability to North America and other regions, with an open invitation for feedback and collaboration from developers.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.reuters.com/business/aerospace-defense/boeing-overcharged-air-force-nearly-8000-soap-dispensers-watchdog-alleges-2024-10-29/">Boeing overcharged the U.S. Air Force 8,000% above market for soap dispensers</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42201068">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Boeing charged the U.S. Air Force $149,072 for soap dispensers, significantly above market price, equating to $671 per plane for 222 C-17 aircraft.</li>
<li>The inflated cost is attributed to compliance with military specifications and documentation requirements, sparking debate over the procurement process&#39;s efficiency.</li>
<li>The situation underscores potential inefficiencies in military contracting, with suggestions that the system may favor contractors like Boeing.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.cloudflare.com/resilient-internet-connectivity-baltic-cable-cuts/">Europe&#39;s Internet resilience mitigates impact of submarine cable cuts</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Recent cable cuts in the Baltic Sea, specifically the BCS East-West Interlink and C-Lion1 cables, did not significantly disrupt Internet connectivity in Europe due to resilient infrastructure.</li>
<li>Europe&#39;s robust Internet infrastructure, featuring multiple submarine and terrestrial connections, ensures minimal impact from such incidents by providing alternative routes.</li>
<li>Cloudflare Radar actively monitors global Internet connectivity, offering updates through social media and blog posts, highlighting the importance of redundant network architecture to prevent disruptions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42198635">Reactions</a></h3>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="ICC issues warrants for Netanyahu, Gallant, and Hamas officials" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=ICC%20issues%20warrants%20for%20Netanyahu%2C%20Gallant%2C%20and%20Hamas%20officials&subheading=Thursday%2C%20November%2021%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/11/21</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-11-21T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-11-20]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/11/20&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-11-20</h1>
<h2><a href="https://letsencrypt.org/2014/11/18/announcing-lets-encrypt/">Let&#39;s Encrypt is 10 years old now</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Let’s Encrypt is a free certificate authority that simplifies obtaining and managing server certificates, addressing the challenges of cost and complexity.</li>
<li>Supported by major organizations like Mozilla, Cisco, and the Electronic Frontier Foundation (EFF), it aims to make Internet security accessible and open to all.</li>
<li>Key principles of Let’s Encrypt include being free, automatic, secure, transparent, open, and cooperative, with opportunities for sponsorship or contribution to support the initiative.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42191228">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Let&#39;s Encrypt, celebrating its 10th anniversary, has transformed internet security by offering free HTTPS certificates, democratizing secure connections.</li>
<li>Despite its widespread adoption, some sectors, such as banking, require longer certificate validity, posing challenges for Let&#39;s Encrypt&#39;s use.</li>
<li>The service has improved web security through its open protocol and automation, though it remains reliant on donations, underscoring its non-profit mission.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.techdirt.com/2024/11/18/epic-allows-internet-archive-to-distribute-for-free-unreal-unreal-tournament-forever/">Epic Allows Internet Archive to Distribute Unreal and Unreal Tournament Forever</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>There is a suggestion that if HR 9495, a proposed bill, passes, it could potentially classify the Internet Archive as a terrorist organization without clear justification.</li>
<li>The concern is raised by an anonymous source, indicating that this classification might not be a primary focus or priority of the bill.</li>
<li>The implication of such a classification could have significant consequences for the Internet Archive, a digital library offering free access to a vast collection of digital content.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42190541">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Epic Games has permitted the Internet Archive to distribute Unreal and Unreal Tournament indefinitely, sparking hopes for potential open-source releases similar to Quake.</li>
<li>The Unreal Tournament community remains vibrant, with discussions about preserving and updating classic games, especially after Epic&#39;s decision to delist older titles from stores.</li>
<li>Open-sourcing Unreal Engine 1 could eventually occur, but it requires significant cleanup, and this move could benefit learning, development, and the preservation of gaming history.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://newsletter.gamediscover.co/p/how-tiny-glade-built-its-way-to-600k">Tiny Glade &#39;built&#39; its way to &gt;600k sold in a month</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Tiny Glade, a relaxing building game by Pounce Light, sold over 600,000 copies within a month of its release on Steam, indicating significant commercial success.</li>
<li>The game gained popularity through viral videos and participation in Steam&#39;s Next Fest, resulting in over 1.3 million wishlists, showcasing effective marketing strategies.</li>
<li>Its success is attributed to its serene, goal-free sandbox experience and engaging procedural generation technology, appealing to fans of cozy and city-building games.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42190065">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Tiny Glade sold over 600,000 copies in a month, attributed to its advanced custom lighting engine and the expertise of developers Tomasz Stachowiak and Anastasia Opara.</li>
<li>The game, developed using Rust and Vulkan, became popular through effective marketing and community engagement, showcasing Rust&#39;s potential in game development.</li>
<li>Despite some criticism for lacking depth, Tiny Glade offers a zen-like building experience, emphasizing the importance of community building before a game&#39;s launch.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.frost.kiwi/analytical-anti-aliasing/">AAA – Analytical Anti-Aliasing</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Analytical Anti-Aliasing is a technique designed to remove jagged edges (jaggies) in rasterized images by pre-calculating the fade of shape borders, ensuring smooth edges without artifacts.- This method is efficient as it does not require additional buffers or hardware and is compatible with basic WebGL 1.0, making it accessible for various applications.- It is highlighted for its professional use in platforms like Unity and Valve Software, offering clarity and sharpness without the blurriness common in other anti-aliasing methods, such as SSAA (Super-Sample Anti-Aliasing), SMAA (Subpixel Morphological Anti-Aliasing), and DLAA (Deep Learning Anti-Aliasing).</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42191709">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article &quot;AAA – Analytical Anti-Aliasing&quot; delves into anti-aliasing techniques, emphasizing analytical methods and their application in graphics programming.</li>
<li>It discusses the debate between linear and sRGB color spaces, limitations of WebGL, and challenges with overlapping shapes, providing a comprehensive exploration of these topics.</li>
<li>The article is noted for its depth, interactive elements, and feedback on its presentation, highlighting the complexity of graphics settings in games.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://history.stackexchange.com/questions/57033/what-is-the-origin-of-the-lake-tank-image-that-has-become-a-meme">What is the origin of the lake tank image that has become a meme? (2021)</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42193771">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The &quot;lake tank&quot; meme features a submerged Panzer IV tank in the Meuse River, Belgium, from WWII, and is popular among military enthusiasts and gamers.</li>
<li>It draws humor from the concept of receiving wisdom from unexpected sources, akin to the &quot;Lady of the Lake&quot; from Arthurian legend and the &quot;senpai of the pool&quot; meme.</li>
<li>The meme&#39;s niche appeal is partly due to its connection to historical and gaming contexts, resonating with specific online communities.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/auonsson.bsky.social/post/3lbc5va7f722p">Yi Peng 3 crossed both cables C-Lion 1 and BSC at times matching when they broke</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42191394">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A Chinese cargo ship, Yi Peng 3, allegedly severed undersea cables in the Baltic Sea, leading to suspicions of deliberate sabotage.</li>
<li>The ship&#39;s movements, captained by a Russian national, coincided with the timing of the cable breakage, raising geopolitical concerns.</li>
<li>This incident, following a similar one in October 2023, has led to increased scrutiny and ongoing investigations by the Danish navy.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://domainanalysis.io/p/architecture-modernization-execution">When did estimates turn into deadlines?</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>In software modernization projects, estimates should be viewed as flexible guidelines rather than strict deadlines due to the unpredictable nature of such projects.</li>
<li>Indu Alagarsamy likens architecture modernization to car repair, highlighting the need for adaptability and additional approvals when unforeseen issues arise.</li>
<li>Effective leadership in these projects involves asking insightful questions, embracing experimentation, and utilizing suitable frameworks to navigate complexities and achieve success.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42187506">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The post discusses the common issue of management treating project estimates as strict deadlines, often ignoring factors like changing specifications that can cause delays.</li>
<li>This practice leads to inflated estimates as a defensive measure to avoid blame for missing so-called &quot;deadlines,&quot; which can stifle innovation and honest work.</li>
<li>The suggested solution is to cultivate a company culture that tolerates mistakes and focuses on continuous improvement rather than assigning blame, promoting a more innovative and productive environment.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://twitter.com/spacex/status/1858995009384837380">SpaceX Super Heavy splashes down in the gulf, canceling chopsticks landing</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42188687">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>SpaceX&#39;s Super Heavy booster performed a soft splashdown in the Gulf of Mexico as a safety measure after automated health checks aborted the landing attempt on the &quot;chopsticks&quot; at the launch site.- The test flight successfully demonstrated engine relighting in space, marking a significant milestone for future orbital flights and SpaceX&#39;s goal of rapid reusability with Starship.- While SpaceX aims for frequent launches and missions like Mars colonization, the timeline for achieving these goals is uncertain due to potential technical and regulatory challenges.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://underjord.io/how-i-use-erlang-hot-code-updates.html">Using Erlang hot code updates</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Underjord, an Elixir consulting team, investigates Erlang&#39;s hot code updates, a distinctive feature allowing code changes without stopping the system.</li>
<li>Although Elixir, based on Erlang, supports hot code updates, the standard mix release lacks the necessary files, prompting experts to recommend learning this skill.</li>
<li>Hot code updates are particularly useful in development with Nerves for embedded devices, and more tooling in Elixir could enhance this process.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42187761">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Erlang&#39;s hot code updates enable rapid deployment of fixes without disconnecting users, which is particularly advantageous for systems with long-lived connections, such as telephony.</li>
<li>Although these updates can be complex and risky, potentially leading to non-replicable states, they are essential for maintaining continuous connections in real-time systems.</li>
<li>While some advocate for simpler rolling deployments, hot code updates provide unique benefits in scenarios where uninterrupted service is critical, despite the challenges they present.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.securityweek.com/apple-confirms-zero-day-attacks-hitting-intel-based-macs/">Apple Confirms Zero-Day Attacks Hitting macOS Systems</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42189581">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Apple has acknowledged zero-day attacks on macOS systems and advised users to update to the latest versions: iOS 18.1.1, macOS Sequoia 15.1.1, and iOS 17.7.2.</li>
<li>The vulnerabilities involve malicious web content that could allow arbitrary code execution, highlighting the critical need for timely software updates.</li>
<li>This incident is part of a recurring issue with iPhones, which have previously experienced web-exploitable security vulnerabilities, including web-based jailbreaks.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://emschwartz.me/understanding-the-bm25-full-text-search-algorithm/">Understanding the BM25 full text search algorithm</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>BM25, or Best Match 25, is a widely used algorithm for full-text search, implemented in systems like Lucene/Elasticsearch and SQLite, and often paired with vector similarity search in hybrid search systems.</li>
<li>It ranks documents based on relevance to a query using factors such as query terms, Inverse Document Frequency (IDF), term frequency, and document length normalization, following the Probability Ranking Principle.</li>
<li>BM25 scores are context-specific, meaning they are comparable within the same document collection but not across different collections or over time, due to potential changes in the collection affecting scores.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42190650">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion focuses on the BM25 search algorithm and its integration with modern search technologies, such as hybrid systems like Typesense that combine BM25 with vector-based semantic search.- Participants debate the effectiveness of BM25 compared to newer learning models, with some advocating for its continued use and others suggesting more advanced statistical models.- The conversation also explores tools and methods like Reciprocal Rank Fusion (RRF) and the role of machine learning in enhancing search capabilities.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.blender.org/download/releases/4-3/">Blender 4.3</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Blender 4.3, released on November 19, 2024, brings significant updates, including EEVEE&#39;s Light and Shadow Linking, a new Metallic BSDF node, and Gabor Noise texture node.</li>
<li>Enhancements include interactive multi-pass compositing, improved UV editing, and significant updates to Geometry Nodes and Grease Pencil for better performance and new tools.</li>
<li>The release also features user interface improvements, Video Sequencer enhancements, Vulkan backend support, and remains free, supported by community donations.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42190863">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Blender 4.3, particularly with the Bonsai add-on, is recommended for home remodeling due to its detailed planning capabilities.</li>
<li>The software is praised for its open-source model, strong community support, and development fund, contributing to its success and continuous improvement.</li>
<li>Users highlight Blender&#39;s versatility in art and 3D printing, and suggest tutorials like the donut tutorial for beginners to overcome its learning curve.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/OpenRiak">Open Riak – open, modern Riak fork</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42187766">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>OpenRiak is a modern fork of the Riak database, maintained by engineers from its major customers, focusing on enhancing stability in complex failure scenarios.</li>
<li>Supported by the Erlang Ecosystem Foundation, OpenRiak remains a niche product but may attract users with specific non-functional requirements.</li>
<li>The OpenRiak community is currently concentrating on Riak KV, with other forks being maintained by TI Tokyo, and plans to share future developments soon.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/leaningtech/webvm">Webvm: Virtual Machine for the Web</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>WebVM is a Linux virtual machine that operates within a web browser using HTML5 and WebAssembly, utilizing the CheerpX virtualization engine to support x86 binaries.</li>
<li>It offers a server-less, client-side environment with networking capabilities enabled through Tailscale, a VPN network, making it accessible without traditional server infrastructure.</li>
<li>WebVM is open-source under the Apache License 2.0, with specific restrictions for organizational use, and can be deployed by forking the repository, enabling GitHub Pages, and customizing Dockerfiles.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42190395">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>WebVM, developed by Leaning Technologies, is a virtual machine designed for web use, with potential applications in virtualizing corporate apps and plans to support Docker containers.</li>
<li>CheerpX, a proprietary component, is crucial for WebVM&#39;s offerings, providing support for Flash and Java, although WebVM itself is open-source.</li>
<li>Despite its inability to run offline due to large data needs, WebVM supports Tailscale for networking, and there is user interest in the feasibility and performance of web-based virtual machines.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.newscientist.com/article/2456782-bluesky-is-ushering-in-a-pick-your-own-algorithm-era-of-social-media/">Bluesky is ushering in a pick-your-own algorithm era of social media</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Bluesky, a social network with over 20 million users, provides personalized control over social media algorithms, allowing users to choose their content.</li>
<li>Unlike platforms like X (formerly Twitter), where algorithms dictate content, Bluesky offers a &quot;marketplace of algorithms&quot; for users to select feeds based on interests.</li>
<li>This approach empowers users to shape their social media experience and could set a new industry standard, despite challenges in finding or creating the right feed.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42193549">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Bluesky is launching customizable algorithms for social media, enabling users to select how they view content, either chronologically or through algorithmic sorting.</li>
<li>The introduction of these features sparks a debate on whether algorithms improve or diminish user experience, with opinions divided between the need for user control and the advantages of curated content.</li>
<li>Bluesky aims to balance user preferences and engagement by offering a chronological default feed while allowing for personalized content viewing options.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Let's Encrypt is 10 years old now" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Let's%20Encrypt%20is%2010%20years%20old%20now&subheading=Wednesday%2C%20November%2020%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/11/20</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-11-20T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-11-19]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/11/19&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-11-19</h1>
<h2><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-11-18/doj-will-push-google-to-sell-off-chrome-to-break-search-monopoly">DOJ will push Google to sell off Chrome</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42177767">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Department of Justice (DOJ) is urging Google to divest Chrome due to concerns about its market dominance and integration with other Google services, which enhances its data collection and advertising capabilities.</li>
<li>Critics claim Google&#39;s control over Chrome allows it to prioritize features that benefit its advertising business and potentially degrade service quality on rival browsers.</li>
<li>The DOJ&#39;s move is intended to foster competition, but there is debate over whether separating Chrome from Google would truly benefit consumers or simply shift data access to other companies.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://cerebras.ai/blog/llama-405b-inference">Llama 3.1 405B now runs at 969 tokens/s on Cerebras Inference</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Frontier AI&#39;s Llama 3.1 405B model on Cerebras has set a new speed record, achieving 969 tokens per second, making it the fastest frontier model available.</li>
<li>The model supports a 128K context length and offers the shortest time-to-first-token latency at 240ms, enhancing user experience significantly.</li>
<li>Cerebras has made Llama 3.1 available for customer trials, with general availability expected in Q1 2025, and pricing set at $6 per million input tokens and $12 per million output tokens.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42178761">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Llama 3.1 405B achieves a processing speed of 969 tokens per second on Cerebras Inference, surpassing typical implementations.</li>
<li>Cerebras employs a distinctive architecture with CPUs containing approximately 1 million cores, differing from traditional GPU setups.</li>
<li>Despite the high cost and power consumption of Cerebras&#39; system, the discussion suggests potential future affordability and significant implications for AI applications.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://reason.com/2024/11/18/how-scientific-americans-departing-editor-helped-degrade-science/">Scientific American&#39;s departing editor and the politicization of science</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Laura Helmuth, former editor of Scientific American, resigned following controversial social media posts and criticism regarding her editorial direction.</li>
<li>During her tenure, the magazine faced accusations of promoting a political agenda, which critics argue compromised its scientific credibility, particularly on sensitive topics like youth gender medicine.</li>
<li>The situation has contributed to a broader crisis of trust in scientific authority, with calls for Scientific American to prioritize science over politics to regain its reputation.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42177619">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Scientific American&#39;s editor has been criticized for allegedly politicizing science, as discussed in Susan Greenhalgh&#39;s book on Coca-Cola&#39;s use of science to divert attention from obesity issues.</li>
<li>The debate raises concerns about the phrase &quot;trust the science,&quot; suggesting it may align science with faith rather than skepticism, and highlights the influence of politics on scientific reporting.</li>
<li>The discussion underscores the tension between preserving scientific integrity and managing political influences, with claims that both political sides exploit science to further their agendas.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://tech.marksblogg.com/osm-mvt-vector-tiles.html">OpenStreetMap&#39;s New Vector Tiles</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>OpenStreetMap (OSM) has launched vector tiles in Mapbox Vector Tiles (MVT) format, enabling users to customize map styles and switch label languages, enhancing map clarity and flexibility.</li>
<li>This update marks a shift from the previous use of static raster tiles, allowing for sharper imagery and more dynamic data interaction.</li>
<li>The post includes guidance on setting up a Python environment and utilizing DuckDB for data analysis, with visualization possible through tools like QGIS and Leafmap.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42182519">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>OpenStreetMap has introduced new vector tiles, which provide smooth zooming and easy style editing but lack the detail of raster tiles, such as Points of Interest (POIs) and street names.</li>
<li>The open-source community has advanced vector map capabilities, yet challenges like rendering issues with Arabic text persist.</li>
<li>Vector tiles could potentially lower hosting costs but demand more client-side resources; they are currently in technical preview with ongoing improvements anticipated.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.researchgate.net/publication/374700857_Fair_coins_tend_to_land_on_the_same_side_they_started_Evidence_from_350757_flips">Fair coins tend to land on the side they started: Evidence from 350,757 flips</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42181345">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A study involving 350,757 coin flips suggests that coins are more likely to land on the side they started on, but the sample size was limited to 48 testers.</li>
<li>Critics point out that the study&#39;s methodology, including low flip height and rotations, may have skewed the results, and potential tester biases could affect the findings.</li>
<li>The study emphasizes the role of human imperfections in coin flips, but its conclusions may not be applicable beyond the specific conditions tested.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/sharkdp/hyperfine">Hyperfine: A command-line benchmarking tool</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Hyperfine is a versatile command-line benchmarking tool that supports statistical analysis, arbitrary shell commands, and provides real-time progress feedback.- It offers features like warmup runs, cache-clearing commands, outlier detection, and supports exporting results in CSV, JSON, and Markdown formats.- The tool is compatible with multiple operating systems and package managers, and is dual-licensed under the MIT and Apache License 2.0, making it accessible and flexible for developers.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42177462">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Hyperfine is a command-line benchmarking tool developed by the creator of other Rust-based utilities such as fd, bat, and hexyl, known for its user-friendly interface.</li>
<li>While praised for ease of use, some users have noted limitations in precision for very short benchmarks, suggesting alternatives like &#39;perf&#39; and &#39;multitime&#39; for specific needs.</li>
<li>Hyperfine is open-source, inviting users to contribute to its ongoing development and improvement.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://theconversation.com/im-a-neuroscientist-who-taught-rats-to-drive-their-joy-suggests-how-anticipating-fun-can-enrich-human-life-239029">Rats learned to drive</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A neuroscientist trained rats to drive small cars, demonstrating that the anticipation of fun can enhance motivation and joy, affecting behavior and brain function.</li>
<li>The study found that positive anticipation can shift cognitive styles from pessimistic to optimistic, highlighting the role of enriched environments and waiting periods for rewards.</li>
<li>Observations of rat behavior, such as tail posture, provided insights into emotional expressions, emphasizing the importance of positive experiences in shaping the brain.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42179774">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Rats have been trained to drive, highlighting discussions on animal intelligence and behavior, similar to an orangutan that learned to drive a golf cart by observation.</li>
<li>The ability of various animals, such as dogs and turtles, to perform similar tasks suggests a natural inclination for movement and raises questions about animal cognition.</li>
<li>The topic has generated interest in how animals communicate emotions, particularly through tail movements, and the potential for animals to undertake more complex tasks.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.maslowcnc.com">Maslow 4: Large format CNC routing made accessible</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Maslow 4 is a large format CNC (Computer Numerical Control) router that makes it easier for users to transform digital designs into physical creations.</li>
<li>The Maslow community is active in sharing diverse projects, including furniture, art, boats, and signs, showcasing the platform&#39;s versatility and encouraging creativity.</li>
<li>Users have successfully created various items such as standing desks, engravings, and even a tiny house, highlighting the potential of CNC technology for innovative projects.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42179467">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Maslow 4 is a large format CNC (Computer Numerical Control) router that gained significant attention through a successful Kickstarter campaign, raising $249,000, far surpassing its $16,000 goal.</li>
<li>The router is open-source, with software under GPLv3 (General Public License version 3) and CAD (Computer-Aided Design) files under CC-BY-SA 4 (Creative Commons Attribution-ShareAlike 4.0), allowing for community-driven development and customization.</li>
<li>It is noted for its affordability and versatility in cutting large sheets of wood, though some users find the setup challenging; the kit is priced at $525, excluding the router and frame.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="DOJ will push Google to sell off Chrome" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=DOJ%20will%20push%20Google%20to%20sell%20off%20Chrome&subheading=Tuesday%2C%20November%2019%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/11/19</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-11-19T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-11-18]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/11/18&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-11-18</h1>
<h2><a href="https://naehrdine.blogspot.com/2024/11/reverse-engineering-ios-18-inactivity.html">Reverse Engineering iOS 18 Inactivity Reboot</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>iOS 18 has introduced an inactivity reboot feature that automatically reboots iPhones after 3 days of inactivity to enhance security.- This feature transitions devices from the more vulnerable After First Unlock (AFU) state to the more secure Before First Unlock (BFU) state, protecting user data.- The Secure Enclave Processor (SEP) monitors the last unlock time and triggers a reboot if the device is inactive for over 3 days, effectively reducing the risk of theft and unauthorized access, though it presents challenges for law enforcement in data extraction.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42167633">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>iOS 18 introduces a security feature that reboots devices after three days of inactivity, returning them to a &quot;Before First Unlock&quot; (BFU) state to enhance data protection.</li>
<li>This feature aims to prevent unauthorized data access, ensuring sensitive data is accessible only after active user unlocking, impacting law enforcement data extraction and potentially inconveniencing users.</li>
<li>The post explores the balance between security measures and user experience, highlighting the challenges and implications of this new feature.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://ondsel.com/blog/goodbye/">We are shutting down Ondsel</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Ondsel is closing on October 30, 2024, due to the inability to achieve commercial success or a sustainable business model, despite community support.</li>
<li>Significant contributions to FreeCAD include a new assembly workbench, a 3D constraints solver, and enhancements to Sketcher and TechDraw, all of which will remain open-source.</li>
<li>Although Ondsel ES won&#39;t release v2024.3, former team members will continue contributing to FreeCAD, and users will have time to download their data before the server shuts down.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42169998">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Ondsel, a contributor to FreeCAD, is shutting down but has left a positive impact on the software&#39;s development.</li>
<li>The discussion emphasizes the challenges open-source CAD tools face in competing with commercial software, highlighting the need for affordability and user-friendly interfaces.</li>
<li>Despite Ondsel&#39;s closure, the community values its contributions and remains hopeful for ongoing advancements in open-source CAD solutions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://devblogs.microsoft.com/oldnewthing/20241112-00/?p=110507">Why did Windows 95 setup use three operating systems?</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42166606">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Windows 95 setup utilized three operating systems: DOS, a minimal version of Windows 3.1, and Windows 95, to ensure compatibility and ease of installation.- The installation process started with DOS, which then initiated a basic Windows 3.1 environment to facilitate the installation of Windows 95, allowing upgrades from older systems.- This discussion underscores the evolution of Windows and the challenges of balancing compatibility with the introduction of new features.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://michaels.world/2023/11/i-was-banned-from-the-hcaptcha-accessibility-account-for-not-being-blind/">I was banned from the hCaptcha accessibility account for not being blind (2023)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A user was banned from the hCaptcha accessibility account despite being blind, highlighting potential flaws in hCaptcha&#39;s accessibility measures.- The incident underscores the risks of relying on companies that may intentionally make their products inaccessible, with unreliable workarounds.- The user advises caution for those dependent on such services and suggests sharing this warning, particularly with webmasters using hCaptcha.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42171164">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A blind user was banned from the hCaptcha accessibility account, highlighting issues with hCaptcha&#39;s accessibility claims and system.- Many users, regardless of visual ability, find hCaptcha&#39;s challenges difficult and discriminatory, raising concerns about its effectiveness and inclusivity.- The broader issue is the general inaccessibility and ineffectiveness of captchas, with a call for improved solutions that enhance user experience and privacy.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://maxbo.me/a-html-file-is-all-you-need.html">Reactive HTML Notebooks</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The article discusses using HTML as a unified platform for scientific publishing, eliminating the need for multiple tools like Jupyter or LaTeX.- It showcases the creation of reactive HTML notebooks with interactive elements using libraries such as Observable, Pyodide, and WebR.- The potential for HTML to simplify the publishing process is highlighted, with a mention of the library @celine/celine for further development.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42170740">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion centers on using HTML as a base for computational notebooks, with critiques on current implementations and suggestions for a more declarative system called Heximal.</li>
<li>Comparisons are made with existing tools like Jupyter, Pluto, and Raku, highlighting challenges in persistence and ergonomics.</li>
<li>There is excitement about the potential for exploratory data analysis and publishing, but concerns about the complexity introduced by web technologies are also raised.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/trynova/nova">Nova JavaScript Engine</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A new JavaScript engine is being developed using data-oriented design, which optimizes data storage and access.- Key features include storing data in type-specific vectors and using type-discriminated indexes for heap references, enhancing performance.- Objects are divided into kind-specific vectors and split to avoid reading unused parts, improving efficiency.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42168166">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Nova is an experimental JavaScript engine that uses a data-oriented design, organizing data into type-specific vectors to enhance efficiency and performance.</li>
<li>Unlike traditional engines such as V8, Nova focuses on compact data storage and avoids alignment gaps, although it currently lacks a Just-In-Time (JIT) compiler and uses a bytecode interpreter.</li>
<li>The project aims to implement the full ECMAScript specification, with ongoing development and future plans for benchmarks and performance comparisons.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://fleetwood.dev/posts/you-could-have-designed-SOTA-positional-encoding">You could have designed state of the art positional encoding</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The post examines the development of positional encoding in transformer models, emphasizing Rotary Positional Encoding (RoPE) used in advanced models like LLama 3.2.- It discusses the necessity of positional information in self-attention mechanisms to comprehend token relationships, comparing various encoding methods and their limitations.- RoPE is introduced as a method that encodes relative positions through rotations, improving performance without changing semantic information, with potential extensions to multi-dimensional data.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42166948">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion centers on positional encoding in transformers, highlighting its role in helping models understand token order, which is essential for computing attention scores in the Query, Key, Value (QKV) mechanism.- Various encoding schemes, such as RoPE, are mentioned for their ability to allow flexible token positioning without needing to retrain the model.- Participants share experiences and challenges with implementing these encodings and express appreciation for the clarifications provided, with additional resources and discussions on related topics like context encoding and encoding method efficiency included.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.wired.com/story/alan-filion-torswats-guilty-plea-federal-charges-swatting/">Teen behind hundreds of swatting attacks pleads guilty to federal charges</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Alan Filion, an 18-year-old from California, pleaded guilty to federal charges for conducting over 375 swatting attacks, targeting schools, religious institutions, and US politicians.- Operating under the alias &quot;Torswats,&quot; Filion was part of an international swatting group, causing widespread fear and chaos across the US.- He faces up to five years in prison for each of four counts of making interstate threats, with his sentencing date yet to be determined.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42168652">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A teenager has pleaded guilty to federal charges for orchestrating over 375 swatting incidents, which involve making false emergency calls to trigger armed police responses.</li>
<li>The teen used online aliases and charged for these services on Telegram, highlighting the ease of call spoofing and the dangers of swatting, which can lead to violent confrontations.</li>
<li>This case emphasizes the need for improved police response protocols and accountability, as well as the potential for a 20-year sentence, though the actual time may be reduced due to juvenile status.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/2210.00714">It&#39;s time to replace TCP in the datacenter (2023)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The paper critiques TCP (Transmission Control Protocol) as outdated for modern datacenters, citing issues like stream orientation and in-order packet delivery.- It proposes Homa as a replacement, which addresses these TCP limitations but is not API-compatible with TCP.- Homa&#39;s adoption could be facilitated through integration with RPC (Remote Procedure Call) frameworks, making it more accessible for widespread use.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42168997">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Replacing TCP (Transmission Control Protocol) in data centers is difficult due to the need for extensive hardware support and expertise.- Although alternatives like QUIC (Quick UDP Internet Connections) and InfiniBand exist, their adoption is limited due to integration complexity and compatibility issues with existing systems.- Despite its limitations, TCP&#39;s established presence and the high cost of transitioning to new protocols suggest it will continue to dominate data centers for the foreseeable future.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://apps.apple.com/gb/app/islet-diabetes/id6453168642">The App I Built to Help Manage My Diabetes</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Joshua, a student, has developed Islet, a diabetes management app powered by GPT-4o-mini, now available on the App Store.</li>
<li>The app was initially a summer project and offers features like insulin management, carb counting, blood sugar tracking, personalized meal suggestions, and activity tracking.</li>
<li>Islet demonstrates the potential of AI in addressing real-world health issues, particularly for individuals with Type 1 diabetes.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42168491">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Joshua, a student, developed Islet, a diabetes management app using GPT-4o-mini, now available on the App Store, to help manage insulin, carb counts, and blood sugars.- The app provides meal suggestions, tracks activity, and offers insights, but is still in its early stages, with feedback welcomed for improvement.- Concerns have been raised about its medical device status and data privacy, highlighting the importance of addressing these issues in health management apps.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.tofugu.com/japan/japanese-black-companies/">How Japanese black companies oppress workers (2014)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The term &quot;black company&quot; describes exploitative workplaces, particularly in white-collar industries, originating from Japan and gaining prominence in the early 2000s.- The &quot;Black Corporations Award&quot; was created in 2012 to spotlight the worst offenders, with Watami Foodservice Co. frequently recognized for poor employee treatment.- A checklist by lawyer Yoshiyuki Iwasa helps identify black companies, with criteria such as unpaid overtime and abusive work environments, while Japan&#39;s Ministry of Health, Labour and Welfare is working to address these issues.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42169615">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Japanese &quot;black companies&quot; exploit workers by threatening legal action if they attempt to quit, creating a challenging work environment.</li>
<li>Contract workers in Japan face legal restrictions on quitting before their contract ends, highlighting a broader issue of oppressive work culture.</li>
<li>The American &quot;at-will&quot; employment model is contrasted, allowing employees to leave without notice but lacking job security, and is further complicated by the link between employment and healthcare.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://metropolisjapan.com/resignation-agencies/">Japanese workers turn to resignation agencies</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A survey by Mynavi Corp. indicates an increase in the use of resignation agencies in Japan, with 20% of workers in their 20s utilizing these services to quit their jobs.</li>
<li>Resignation agencies, such as Momuri, assist young workers in leaving jobs that negatively impact their mental health, managing the resignation process for a fee.</li>
<li>This trend signifies a generational shift towards valuing mental well-being and challenging traditional Japanese work norms, potentially leading to a more balanced work culture.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42169027">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Japanese workers are turning to resignation agencies to help them quit jobs, as some companies create obstacles for employees wishing to resign.</li>
<li>This trend underscores cultural challenges in Japan&#39;s work environment, where employees often experience guilt and pressure when attempting to leave a job.</li>
<li>Resignation agencies facilitate the resignation process, enabling employees to avoid direct confrontation, and contribute to broader discussions on Japan&#39;s work culture and its effects on employees.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.cbsnews.com/news/bhutan-emigration-crisis-60-minutes/">Bhutan, after prioritizing happiness, now faces an existential crisis</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Bhutan is experiencing a significant emigration of young people, despite offering free healthcare, education, and a growing economy, as they seek better job opportunities abroad, particularly in Australia.</li>
<li>In response, Bhutan&#39;s king plans to develop Gelephu Mindfulness City, designed by Danish architect Bjarke Ingels, to create jobs and attract young people back, focusing on sustainable development and Bhutanese values.</li>
<li>The success of this project is considered vital for Bhutan&#39;s future, with some citizens, like journalist Namgay Zam, inspired to support the initiative and remain in the country.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42172281">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Bhutan is experiencing a trend of young people leaving the country for better opportunities abroad, driven by materialism and exposure to other cultures.</li>
<li>Despite its focus on Gross National Happiness, Bhutan faces challenges from economic growth and globalization, leading to a brain drain as educated individuals seek higher earnings elsewhere.</li>
<li>The country has potential for future development through its unique culture, energy resources, and plans for a new city, but it also faces significant issues like ethnic tensions and economic pressures.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://museumofbadart.org/">Museum of Bad Art</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Museum Of Bad Art (MOBA) is a unique museum in Boston dedicated to showcasing art that is humorously flawed and wouldn&#39;t typically be displayed in traditional museums.</li>
<li>Located inside Dorchester Brewing Co, MOBA offers free admission, allowing visitors to enjoy both the art and the brewery&#39;s offerings, such as craft beers and food from M&amp;M Barbecue.</li>
<li>MOBA is featured in a 7-minute video by WSBE RI PBS on YouTube, and as a non-profit, it accepts tax-deductible donations to support its mission.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42168503">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Museum of Bad Art (MOBA) in Boston is dedicated to displaying art that traditional museums might reject, celebrating both creativity and failure.- Opinions on MOBA are mixed; some appreciate its unique approach, while others criticize it for potentially mocking amateur artists.- MOBA&#39;s collection is noted for its humor and sincerity, and it offers free admission at its location within the Dorchester Brewing Co.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://lwn.net/Articles/997958/">Linux kernel 6.12 has been released</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The 6.12 kernel has been released by Linus Torvalds, adhering to the regular release schedule, and is significant as the 2024 Long-Term Support (LTS) version.- Key features include support for the Arm permission overlay extension, improved Spectre mitigations, and completion of realtime preemption support, enhancing system performance and security.- This release may influence distributions to enable Rust and is expected to be used in Debian 13 and its derivatives, with improvements in handling larger block sizes in the XFS filesystem and performance tools like perf.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42169418">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Linux kernel 6.12 has been released as a Long-Term Support (LTS) version, meaning it will receive extended maintenance and updates.</li>
<li>Key features of this release include real-time support, SCHED_EXT (a new scheduling class), and compatibility with Raspberry Pi 5, enhancing its utility for various hardware.</li>
<li>The release also supports the networking chip in X870E Taichi motherboards, beneficial for AM5-based workstations, and follows the Linux kernel&#39;s typical versioning scheme of major releases every 8 weeks.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Reverse Engineering iOS 18 Inactivity Reboot" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Reverse%20Engineering%20iOS%2018%20Inactivity%20Reboot&subheading=Monday%2C%20November%2018%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/11/18</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-11-18T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-11-17]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/11/17&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-11-17</h1>
<h2><a href="https://michaelcharl.es/aubrey/en/code/new-rebeccapurple-css-logo">CSS gets a new logo and it uses the color <code>rebeccapurple</code></a></h2>
<ul>
<li>CSS has introduced a new logo, selected through a community vote on GitHub, featuring the color rebeccapurple (#663399).- The color rebeccapurple was added to the CSS specification in 2014 to honor Eric Meyer&#39;s daughter, Rebecca, who died of brain cancer at age six.- The new logo&#39;s design is consistent with the visual style of other web technologies such as JavaScript and TypeScript.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42161919">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>CSS has introduced a new logo featuring the color <code>rebeccapurple</code>, a tribute to Eric Meyer&#39;s daughter, Rebecca, who passed away at a young age.</li>
<li>The color <code>rebeccapurple</code> was chosen because Rebecca preferred to be called by her full name, adding a personal and emotional significance to the tech community.</li>
<li>The logo&#39;s design aligns with other web technologies like JavaScript and WebAssembly, emphasizing simplicity and unity in web development.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://firehose3d.theo.io/">The Bluesky firehose viewed in the style of a Windows XP screensaver</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42159786">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion highlights nostalgia for the early internet&#39;s open data access, using the Bluesky firehose as a symbol of that era.</li>
<li>Users express a desire to return to the creativity and innovation of the past, contrasting it with today&#39;s more closed and corporate web environment.</li>
<li>There is a conversation about the potential of federated and peer-to-peer protocols to revive the open spirit of the early internet, with comparisons to Twitter&#39;s initial openness and concerns about Bluesky potentially restricting access.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/rudyrucker/chaos">James Gleick&#39;s Chaos: The Software</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>James Gleick&#39;s CHAOS: The Software&quot; is a free release of a 1991 Autodesk DOS program, now available under a GNU license, allowing users to modify and share the code.</li>
<li>The program, inspired by Gleick&#39;s book &quot;Chaos: Making a New Science,&quot; includes six modules focusing on fractals and chaotic systems, and can run on any platform using DOSBox.&quot;</li>
<li>Key updates include improved display resolution and the removal of the old DOS TSR program metashel.exe, with contributions shared via the Chaos GitHub repository.&quot;</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42160647">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>James Gleick&#39;s book &quot;Chaos&quot; has significantly inspired readers, sparking interest in mathematics, fractals, and complex systems.</li>
<li>Many readers shared personal stories of how the book influenced their career paths and experiments with early computers and fractal rendering.</li>
<li>Rudy Rucker&#39;s involvement adds interest, as his contributions to science fiction and mathematics have also inspired many, highlighting the book&#39;s lasting impact and nostalgia.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.atlasobscura.com/articles/how-to-echolocate">Teach yourself to echolocate (2018)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Daniel Kish, who is blind, developed a method of navigation using echolocation, similar to bats, by producing clicking sounds and interpreting the echoes.</li>
<li>Echolocation can enhance confidence and independence for blind individuals and is learnable by sighted people as well.</li>
<li>The guide outlines steps to learn echolocation, including practicing sound awareness, using a blindfold, and starting in a quiet environment with simple clicking sounds.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42160071">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Audio mixing engineers use echolocation techniques to determine the placement of sounds in a mix, considering factors like proximity and height.</li>
<li>Echolocation involves sending out a sound and listening for echoes, similar to how bats and submarines operate, and is distinct from merely locating sound sources.</li>
<li>Humans can learn echolocation to navigate spaces, a skill that can be enhanced with practice, and some blind individuals use it for navigation, supported by various tools and techniques.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://bsky.jazco.dev/stats">Bluesky is currently gaining more than 1M users a day</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Atlasstatsrepo Explorercleanup provides aggregated statistics for posts in Jaz&#39;s Bluesky index, with data collection starting on May 1st, 2023.</li>
<li>The statistics, excluding Total Users, are incomplete after November 15th, 2024, due to increased activity.</li>
<li>Total User Count is sourced from the Bluesky API, excluding large bot accounts, ensuring more accurate user representation.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42159713">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Bluesky is experiencing rapid growth, gaining over 1 million users daily, as users discuss its features and compare it to platforms like Mastodon and Twitter.</li>
<li>Key features under discussion include the public block feature, absence of ads, and lack of algorithmic control, with debates on its potential for meaningful conversation versus engagement-driven content.</li>
<li>The platform&#39;s growth is partly due to its familiar interface for Twitter users and recent changes in Twitter&#39;s policies, though some users remain skeptical about its long-term appeal and potential issues with data privacy and decentralization.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://myelectricsparks.com/four-dead-tesla-doors-fail-open-crash-fire/">Four dead in fire as Tesla doors fail to open after crash</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A Tesla Model Y crash in Toronto on October 24 resulted in four fatalities and raised concerns about Tesla&#39;s electronic door mechanisms, as they failed to open, trapping passengers inside.- The incident has prompted an investigation into the car&#39;s battery and door mechanisms, with criticism directed at Tesla&#39;s manual release levers for being poorly designed.- This tragic event has ignited a broader debate regarding the safety features of electric vehicles, particularly focusing on emergency egress systems.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42158391">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A fatal accident in Toronto involving a Tesla Model Y resulted in four deaths due to the car&#39;s electronic doors failing to open after a crash.</li>
<li>Criticism has been directed at Tesla&#39;s design, which requires a hidden manual release for doors, deemed unintuitive during emergencies.</li>
<li>The incident has intensified discussions on the safety features of electric vehicles, highlighting the necessity for more user-friendly emergency mechanisms.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.voyageai.com/2024/11/12/voyage-multimodal-3/">All-in-one embedding model for interleaved text, images, and screenshots</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Voyage-multimodal-3 is a new model designed for multimodal embeddings, enhancing retrieval-augmented generation (RAG) and semantic search by processing both text and images together.</li>
<li>It achieves a 19.63% improvement in retrieval accuracy over the next best model across 20 datasets, outperforming models like OpenAI CLIP and Cohere multimodal v3.</li>
<li>The model is available now, with the first 200 million tokens offered for free, and it excels in mixed-modality searches, even with high screenshot ratios.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42162622">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>VoyageAI&#39;s all-in-one embedding model faces challenges with mixed-modality searches due to the &quot;modality gap,&quot; where text vectors align more closely with irrelevant texts than relevant images.</li>
<li>Gemini, a natively multimodal model, is trained on various modalities from the beginning, but it is less effective for semantic search compared to dedicated embedding models.</li>
<li>VoyageAI&#39;s models are currently available only via API, but the company is considering open-source tools and other deployment options to enhance accessibility and usability.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://erikmcclure.com/blog/stop-making-me-memorize-borrow-checker/">Stop making me memorize the borrow checker</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author discusses challenges with Rust&#39;s borrow checker, which often necessitates major code refactoring when it cannot handle specific situations.</li>
<li>Rust&#39;s complexity, particularly with lifetimes and async, requires developers to memorize rules to avoid frequent refactoring, making it more challenging than some simpler languages.</li>
<li>While Rust improves safety over C++ by preventing undefined behavior, its complexity and the need for better IDE tooling drive some developers to seek more user-friendly alternatives.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42160501">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Rust&#39;s borrow checker and strict memory safety rules can be challenging for developers accustomed to languages like C++, potentially impacting productivity in fast-paced environments.</li>
<li>While some developers find Rust&#39;s features enhance coding practices by preventing bugs, others feel it makes code refactoring tedious.</li>
<li>There is a debate on whether to use Rust selectively for performance-critical sections or to fully embrace its idioms to leverage its benefits.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://logica.dev/">Logica – Declarative logic programming language for data</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Logica is an open-source logic programming language designed for intuitive data manipulation, extending logic programming syntax to compile into SQL for easy access to SQL engines.</li>
<li>It uses predicates, akin to functions in Python or Java, to simplify complex queries and efficiently handle data processing, making it suitable for engineers and data scientists.</li>
<li>Logica is compatible with BigQuery, SQLite, and PostgreSQL, and while it is easy to learn and install with available tutorials, it is not an officially supported Google product.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42158445">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Logica is a declarative logic programming language developed by Google, designed to overcome SQL&#39;s limitations, particularly in complex data queries.</li>
<li>It is open-source and part of the Datalog family, which allows for compositional query language and reusable components, but it has limited adoption and is maintained by a single developer.</li>
<li>While Logica shows potential for simplifying complex queries and improving modularity, its syntax and practical benefits compared to SQL are still subjects of debate among users.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://ezzeriesa.notion.site/1-week-with-David-Beazley-and-SICP-4c440389cf1e43f48fe67c969967f655#58ee6b0435b24e26bd624b33ffed94df">Everything Is Just Functions: Mind-Blowing Insights from SICP and David Beazley</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>David Beazley&#39;s SICP (Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs) course in late 2022 provided deep insights into computation, similar to understanding compilers.</li>
<li>The course involved building a simple computation model using Scheme, a Lisp dialect, and creating a Scheme interpreter in Python, enhancing understanding of language commonalities.</li>
<li>Racket, a Scheme variant, was used for its ease of setup, covering basics like integers, operations, and special forms such as &#39;define&#39; for variable assignment.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42164541">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article explores encoding state as pure functions, drawing insights from SICP (Structure and Interpretation of Computer Programs) and David Beazley, with a focus on functional programming.</li>
<li>It uses a JavaScript example of the Maybe monad to illustrate the elegance of functional encodings for various data types.</li>
<li>The discussion critiques the Notion platform for performance and navigation issues, while also reflecting on the educational value of SICP and the practicality of functional programming in real-world applications.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/oracle/bpftune">Bpftune uses BPF to auto-tune Linux systems</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>bpftune is a tool that uses BPF (Berkeley Packet Filter) to automatically adjust system settings, addressing the challenge of managing numerous Linux kernel tunables in cloud environments.- It operates with minimal overhead, logs policy changes, and respects administrator settings by disabling auto-tuning when necessary, using a push-pull approach to optimize resource allocation.- The tool is zero-configuration, includes various tuners for system components, and is licensed under GPL-2.0, supporting both service and foreground operation with logging to syslog.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42163597">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Bpftune is a tool that uses BPF (Berkeley Packet Filter) to automatically optimize Linux systems, aiming for zero configuration and appealing to users who prefer automation.</li>
<li>Some users are concerned about potential system issues due to deviations from standard configurations, highlighting the importance of understanding changes to diagnose problems effectively.</li>
<li>The tool offers an &quot;advice mode&quot; to review suggested tweaks before implementation, providing a balance between automation and user control.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://xogot.com/">Xogot – Godot for iPad</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Xogot Godot, a new application, is now available for iPad, with a preview sign-up option for interested users.</li>
<li>Miguel de Icaza will present at GodotCon 2024, providing insights into the application and its features.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42161223">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Xogot is a version of the Godot game engine tailored for iPad, enabling game development directly on the device, created by Miguel de Icaza, known for Mono and Xamarin.</li>
<li>The application can also operate on Meta Quest and potentially VisionOS, reflecting Apple&#39;s updated policies that now allow such development environments on iOS, albeit with certain restrictions.</li>
<li>Xogot is not open source, sparking discussions about its impact and comparisons to similar projects like Redot.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.chemistryworld.com/news/meteorite-200-times-larger-than-one-that-killed-dinosaurs-reset-early-life/4020391.article">Effect of a giant meteorite impact on Paleoarchean environment and life</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A colossal meteorite impact over 3 billion years ago significantly affected early microbial life, initially causing devastation but later providing essential nutrients for some microbes to thrive.</li>
<li>Evidence of this ancient impact was discovered in South Africa, where spherule layers indicate past meteorite events, highlighting the scale of the impact, which was larger than the one that caused the extinction of the dinosaurs.</li>
<li>The impact introduced bioavailable iron and phosphorus to the ocean surface, facilitating microbial recovery and suggesting that large impacts, despite their initial harm, could benefit early ecosystems.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42160716">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A recent paper discusses a giant meteorite impact during the Paleoarchean era, highlighting its significant environmental and biological effects, such as tsunamis and atmospheric changes.- Despite the disruptions, early life forms likely recovered swiftly, with increased nutrients and iron potentially fostering microbial growth.- The paper also addresses misconceptions about dinosaur extinction, noting that some dinosaurs survived and evolved into modern birds, while acknowledging the challenges in interpreting ancient events.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/veloplanner/map-matrix">Claude AI built me a React app to compare maps side by side</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Map Matrix is a tool that enables users to compare multiple maps simultaneously, initially developed for veloplanner.com using Claude AI.</li>
<li>The development process was streamlined by using Claude AI to quickly generate a prototype and later enhanced with Cursor AI and the claude-3.5-sonnet model.</li>
<li>Users can add custom map sources, with configurations saved locally, and developers can set up the tool using <code>npm install</code> and <code>npm run dev</code> commands.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42164141">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Claude AI was instrumental in creating a React app for map comparison, with most of the code generated by the AI.- Users reported both advantages, such as accelerated development and reduced need for deep technical knowledge, and challenges, including AI limitations like hallucinations and non-functional code.- AI tools like Claude and Cursor AI are valued for rapid prototyping and small project development, despite concerns about increased competition and potential plagiarism.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://bitfieldconsulting.com/posts/constraints">Constraints in Go</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>This article is the final installment in a series about generics in the Go programming language, specifically focusing on constraints, a new feature.- Constraints in Go generics limit the types that can be used in generic functions, allowing for more precise operations by using basic interfaces like <code>fmt.Stringer</code>.- The series highlights various constraint types, such as type set constraints, unions, intersections, and interface literals, and encourages further exploration through the book &quot;Know Go&quot; by John Arundel.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42162878">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Go&#39;s generic constraints introduce complexity, contrasting with the language&#39;s focus on simplicity, due to differences between &quot;implementing&quot; and &quot;satisfying&quot; a constraint and limitations on constraint contents.</li>
<li>The complexity is partly attributed to retrofitting generics into Go, which was not initially designed to support them, sparking debate on their necessity and impact on the community.</li>
<li>Despite the complexity, generics are considered beneficial for library code, though some developers question their necessity for specific use cases.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="CSS gets a new logo and it uses the color `rebeccapurple`" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=CSS%20gets%20a%20new%20logo%20and%20it%20uses%20the%20color%20%60rebeccapurple%60&subheading=Sunday%2C%20November%2017%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/11/17</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-11-17T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-11-16]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/11/16&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-11-16</h1>
<h2><a href="https://www.half-life.com/en/halflife2/20th">Half-Life 2: 20th Anniversary Update</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Valve has released the Half-Life 2 20th Anniversary Update on Steam, featuring new content and enhancements.- The update includes developer commentary, Steam Workshop support, improved graphics, and bug fixes, along with new gamepad and input settings.- It also incorporates Episode One and Two expansions, and offers additional content like wallpapers and soundtracks for download.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42151865">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Half-Life 2&#39;s 20th Anniversary Update is now available, providing the game and its sequel episodes for free on Steam until the 18th, including bug fixes and enhancements.</li>
<li>The update has reignited discussions about the game&#39;s legacy, the possibility of a Half-Life 3, and Valve&#39;s development philosophy.</li>
<li>Fans are encouraged to explore the anniversary page for Easter eggs, and the update has been well-received for its attention to detail and the chance to revisit a classic game.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://anderegg.ca/2024/11/15/maybe-bluesky-has-won">Maybe Bluesky has &quot;won&quot;</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Bluesky is gaining traction as an alternative to X, but it is not yet fully decentralized or federated, relying on its own servers.- The platform employs the AT Protocol, which includes Personal Data Servers, Relays, and App Views, allowing users to host their own data, though this requires technical expertise and can be costly.- While Bluesky is free and offers features like domain-based usernames and customizable moderation, its financial model depends on domain sales, raising questions about its long-term sustainability.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42150278">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Bluesky is gaining attention as a more pleasant alternative to Mastodon, offering a filtering system that reduces divisive political content.</li>
<li>Users appreciate Bluesky&#39;s simplicity and control over content visibility, drawing comparisons to early Twitter, though concerns about its openness and data use persist.</li>
<li>The platform is experiencing growth as users migrate from Twitter, which is perceived as increasingly politically charged, indicating Bluesky&#39;s potential to become a significant social media player.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.roadandtrack.com/news/a62919131/tesla-has-highest-fatal-accident-rate-of-all-auto-brands-study/">Tesla has the highest fatal accident rate of all auto brands, study finds</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42150443">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A study indicates that Tesla has the highest fatal accident rate among auto brands, despite its advanced safety features.</li>
<li>The study suggests that driver behavior and conditions significantly contribute to the high accident rate, sparking debates on politics, media influence, and car design.</li>
<li>The study&#39;s methodology and the impact of driver demographics, as well as car features like touchscreens and vehicle weight, are subjects of scrutiny and discussion.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.sportingnews.com/us/boxing/news/netflix-buffering-livestream-issues-boxing-jake-paul-mike-tyson/327ee972d4b14d90cc370461">Netflix buffering issues: Boxing fans complain about Jake Paul vs. Mike Tyson</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Boxing fans encountered buffering issues on Netflix during the Jake Paul vs. Mike Tyson fight, leading to lag, choppy analysis, and black screens.</li>
<li>The streaming issues have raised concerns about Netflix&#39;s ability to handle live sports events, especially with upcoming NFL games scheduled for Christmas Day.</li>
<li>Some viewers opted for Antonio Brown&#39;s livestream on X, which garnered significant attention with 6.4 million viewers.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42153953">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Netflix experienced major buffering issues during the Jake Paul vs. Mike Tyson fight, resulting in numerous complaints about the live streaming quality.</li>
<li>Critics point out that Netflix&#39;s infrastructure, primarily designed for pre-recorded content, may not be well-suited for live streaming, unlike platforms such as YouTube and Amazon.</li>
<li>The incident underscores Netflix&#39;s challenges in the live sports streaming market, especially with future events like NFL games on the horizon.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://llamaocr.com/">Llama-OCR: Document to Markdown</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The post introduces a method to convert images into markdown format using llama-ocr and Together AI OCR, which are optical character recognition tools.</li>
<li>Users can upload an image to receive structured markdown, facilitating easier text extraction and formatting from images.</li>
<li>Example code in JavaScript is provided, demonstrating how to use the llama-ocr library to process an image file and obtain markdown output.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42154410">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Llama-OCR is a tool that converts documents into Markdown format using Llama 3.2 vision and is available as an npm package.</li>
<li>Future updates are planned to include features like PDF parsing and JSON output, although current users report mixed experiences with image handling and output consistency.</li>
<li>The tool is hosted on together.ai, with ongoing discussions about its performance and potential improvements, including suggestions for using local models or alternative OCR tools for better accuracy.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://bsky.bad-example.com/consuming-the-firehose-cheaply/">Consuming the Bluesky firehose for less than $2.50/mo</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Bluesky&#39;s public data, comprising 15 million users, is available through a websocket JSON feed named Jetstream, enabling real-time network monitoring.</li>
<li>A simple application was developed to listen for delete events from the Jetstream feed, displaying anonymized deleted text momentarily.</li>
<li>The app operates on Fly&#39;s smallest instance for $2.24/month, efficiently managing post events, content filtering, text caching, and broadcasting deleted posts, though more complex applications may face scalability challenges.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42152362">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Bluesky offers a cost-effective way to access its data stream, known as the &quot;firehose,&quot; for under $2.50/month, attracting user interest.</li>
<li>The platform is noted for features like using a website as a username and easy image sharing on iOS, drawing comparisons to early Twitter.</li>
<li>Bluesky&#39;s decentralized structure and community-driven development highlight its focus on open data access, contrasting with Twitter&#39;s current restrictions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://lists.freebsd.org/archives/freebsd-hackers/2024-November/004068.html">First Impressions: Lenovo T14s with Qualcomm Snapdragon ARM64 CPU</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Lenovo T14s with a Qualcomm Snapdragon ARM64 CPU is being evaluated, highlighting a shift from the traditional X86 architecture due to perceived inefficiencies.</li>
<li>Initial setup on FreeBSD-current required ARM64-specific patches, with some hardware components like the screen and NVME working, but others like the keyboard and USB-C ports not functioning.</li>
<li>Performance testing showed the device built the world in 3210 seconds using 24 Wh of energy, attributed to its 12 real CPUs, leading to a positive recommendation.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42150933">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Lenovo T14s with Qualcomm Snapdragon ARM64 CPU receives mixed reviews, with users noting issues such as non-functional keyboard, mouse, and USB-C ports.</li>
<li>Comparisons are drawn to Linux phones, highlighting similar limitations and compatibility challenges with ARM Linux desktops.</li>
<li>Despite current issues, there is optimism about future improvements and better driver support for ARM architecture in Lenovo laptops.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://yggdrasil-network.github.io/">Yggdrasil Network</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Yggdrasil is an experimental routing scheme aimed at providing a decentralized and future-proof alternative to current Internet routing protocols, particularly for large-scale mesh networks.- It offers features such as scalability, self-healing, encryption, and cross-platform support, functioning on various operating systems including Linux, macOS, Windows, iOS, and Android.- Despite being in the alpha stage, Yggdrasil is stable for daily use, offering end-to-end encrypted IPv6 routing and can be configured over both IPv4 and IPv6 networks.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42155780">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Yggdrasil Network is an experimental routing protocol focused on decentralization and scalability, inspired by cjdns but without a strict hierarchy.</li>
<li>Despite lacking a clear protocol specification, Yggdrasil has evolved with significant updates in versions 0.4 and 0.5, improving network latency.</li>
<li>The protocol uses IPv6 addresses derived from public keys, which could lead to address collisions, and is not primarily designed for anonymity.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/hengyoush/kyanos">Kyanos: eBPF-based network issue analysis tool</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Kyanos is an eBPF-based tool designed for network analysis, capable of capturing and analyzing various network requests such as HTTP, Redis, and MySQL.</li>
<li>It features advanced traffic filtering options by IP, port, process, container, and protocol, along with kernel-level latency insights and automatic SSL traffic decryption.</li>
<li>The tool is lightweight, requires minimal dependencies, and is compatible with Linux kernel versions 3.10 and 4.14 or higher, making it accessible for a wide range of users.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42154583">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Kyanos is a network analysis tool based on eBPF (extended Berkeley Packet Filter), offering real-time insights for troubleshooting and performance optimization.</li>
<li>It currently supports specific protocols, including HTTP, MySQL, and Redis, which some users see as a limitation.</li>
<li>Discussions highlight the relevance of technologies like RDMA (Remote Direct Memory Access) and OFED (OpenFabrics Enterprise Distribution) in high-performance computing, alongside a mention of a book for further learning about eBPF.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://twitter.com/DSCCRoss/status/1857208745014776215">M4 MacBook Pros use a quantum dot (QD) film rather than a red KSF phosphor film</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Apple&#39;s new MacBook Pro (M4) introduces the use of quantum dot (QD) film, replacing the previously used red KSF phosphor film.</li>
<li>The shift to QD film marks a significant change, as Apple had previously favored KSF for its efficiency and cadmium-free properties.</li>
<li>This update highlights Apple&#39;s ongoing efforts to enhance display technology in its devices.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42152928">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The new M4 MacBook Pros have switched from using a red KSF phosphor film to a quantum dot film, as identified through spectrum analysis rather than an official Apple announcement.</li>
<li>Quantum dots are expected to enhance the color gamut and motion performance of the displays, although response times are still a concern for MacBook displays.</li>
<li>Apple collaborates with display manufacturers such as Samsung, LG, and BOE for research and development to meet specific product requirements.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.zach.be/p/yc-is-wrong-about-llms-for-chip-design">YC is wrong about LLMs for chip design</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>YC&#39;s proposal to use Large Language Models (LLMs) for chip design is criticized for not matching the expertise of human engineers in creating innovative chip architectures.</li>
<li>While LLMs might lower design costs, they are unlikely to revolutionize chip design in high-value markets, similar to past attempts like high-level synthesis (HLS).</li>
<li>LLMs could be beneficial in verification processes, potentially addressing the talent shortage in this area, but they are not expected to produce superior chips or open new markets.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42156516">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion highlights skepticism about the effectiveness of Large Language Models (LLMs) in chip design, with comparisons to past tech hype cycles like blockchain.- Critics argue that LLMs are overhyped and not yet reliable for complex chip design tasks, which require deep expertise beyond current AI capabilities.- There is uncertainty about whether future advancements will overcome the limitations of LLMs in specialized fields with limited training data.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://arstechnica.com/tech-policy/2024/11/ftc-to-launch-investigation-into-microsofts-cloud-business/">FTC to launch investigation into Microsoft&#39;s cloud business</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The FTC is investigating Microsoft&#39;s cloud business for potential anti-competitive practices, particularly concerning Azure&#39;s licensing terms.</li>
<li>Allegations include increased fees and Office 365&#39;s incompatibility with rival cloud platforms, making it challenging for customers to switch.</li>
<li>This investigation is part of a broader regulatory effort by the FTC, with similar scrutiny from UK and EU regulators, as the cloud market continues to expand.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42152068">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The FTC is investigating Microsoft&#39;s cloud business for potential anti-competitive practices, including raising fees for customers who switch providers and making Office 365 incompatible with competing cloud services.</li>
<li>This investigation is part of a larger examination of big tech companies, reflecting ongoing concerns about their market power and business practices.</li>
<li>There is debate regarding the FTC&#39;s motivations, with opinions divided on whether the actions are a necessary regulation of tech giants or politically driven.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gadgets/2024/11/i-too-installed-an-open-source-garage-door-opener-and-am-loving-it/">Installed an open source garage door opener, and I&#39;m loving it</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>OpenGarage is an open-source garage door opener that integrates seamlessly with Home Assistant, offering enhanced control and customization for home automation.</li>
<li>It consists of a small ESP board with an ultrasonic sensor, controllable via a web browser or mobile app, making installation straightforward.</li>
<li>OpenGarage allows for automation of tasks, such as turning on lights when the garage door opens, highlighting its versatility and appeal for DIY home automation enthusiasts.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42150376">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The post discusses the use of open-source garage door openers, highlighting their flexibility and local control compared to subscription-based models like myQ.</li>
<li>Users express frustration with myQ&#39;s subscription model and lack of third-party support, leading them to explore alternatives such as RATGDO, Meross, and ESPHome.</li>
<li>Home automation enthusiasts are integrating these open-source solutions with systems like MQTT, Home Assistant, and Z-Wave for enhanced functionality and seamless control.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://labs.quansight.org/blog/dataframe-group-by">Non-elementary group-by aggregations in Polars vs pandas</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>At PyData Berlin 2024, Polars, a data processing library, was highlighted for its advanced features such as lazy execution, Rust integration, and multithreading.</li>
<li>A significant innovation of Polars is its support for non-elementary group-by aggregations, allowing users to perform complex operations more efficiently than pandas.</li>
<li>The blog suggests that new dataframe libraries should innovate beyond pandas&#39; API, with Polars serving as an example through its expressive syntax and enhanced data manipulation capabilities.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42152076">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Polars is becoming popular over Pandas for non-basic group-by operations due to its resemblance to Apache Spark and superior speed.- Users value Polars for its quick performance and simple setup, particularly with smaller datasets, despite Pandas&#39; established ecosystem.- The decision between using Pandas or Polars is influenced by specific use cases, performance requirements, and user preference, with some opting for SQL or DuckDB for complex data tasks.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://eclecticlight.co/2024/11/14/m4-macs-cant-virtualise-older-macos/">M4 Macs can&#39;t virtualise older macOS</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>M4 Macs are unable to virtualize macOS versions earlier than 13.4 Ventura, resulting in a black screen during boot attempts for older macOS virtual machines (VMs).</li>
<li>The issue likely arises early in the kernel boot phase, and resolving it would necessitate Apple updating older macOS kernels, which is improbable.</li>
<li>M1, M2, and M3 Macs can virtualize macOS Monterey 12.0.1 and later, but Big Sur cannot be virtualized on any Apple silicon.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42157086">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>M4 Macs are unable to virtualize macOS versions earlier than 13.4 Ventura, posing challenges for developers who need to test applications on older systems.</li>
<li>The absence of a built-in container solution for macOS complicates continuous integration (CI) processes, which are essential for automated testing and deployment.</li>
<li>Anka provides a partial solution by allowing macOS virtual machine (VM) images, but Apple&#39;s software license restricts this to two VMs, frustrating developers who require testing for backward compatibility.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Half-Life 2: 20th Anniversary Update" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Half-Life%202%3A%2020th%20Anniversary%20Update&subheading=Saturday%2C%20November%2016%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/11/16</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-11-16T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-11-15]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/11/15&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-11-15</h1>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/BAndysc/AvaloniaVisualBasic6">Visual Basic 6 IDE recreated in C#</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Avalonia Visual Basic 6 is a C# recreation of the classic Visual Basic 6 Integrated Development Environment (IDE) using Avalonia, intended as a fun, non-commercial project.- The project includes features like a visual designer, compatibility with VB6 project saving/loading, and limited support for the VB6 language.- Building the desktop version typically requires .NET 9.0, but .NET 8.0 can be used with modifications; compilation is done using <code>dotnet build</code>, and publishing with <code>dotnet publish</code> for both the IDE and runtime.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42141587">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A Visual Basic 6 Integrated Development Environment (IDE) has been recreated using C# and is accessible on GitHub, generating nostalgia among developers who started with VB6.</li>
<li>The project employs Avalonia, a cross-platform UI framework, and supports basic VB6 features, though it remains a work in progress.</li>
<li>The initiative has received positive feedback, sparking interest in further development and discussions on the evolution of graphical user interface (GUI) toolkits and the simplicity of VB6 compared to contemporary tools.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://legiscope.com/blog/hidden-productivity-drain-cookie-banners.html">Analysis of economic and productivity losses caused by cookie banners in Europe</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Europeans collectively spend 575 million hours each year interacting with cookie consent banners, a requirement of the EU Directive 2002/58, which aims to protect user privacy.- The economic impact of this time spent is substantial, costing €14.375 billion annually, equivalent to 0.10% of the EU&#39;s GDP, and represents a productivity loss akin to 287,500 full-time jobs.- There is a call for urgent revision of the directive to alleviate economic and productivity burdens, particularly affecting small and medium-sized enterprises.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42141843">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The European &quot;cookie law&quot; requires informed consent for tracking, but does not specifically mandate the use of cookie banners; companies opt for banners to comply.</li>
<li>A common issue is companies incorrectly implementing consent by setting tracking cookies by default and providing banners without a clear reject option, which is non-compliant.</li>
<li>The law&#39;s intent is to protect consumer rights, but companies often engage in &quot;malicious compliance&quot; to frustrate users, suggesting stricter enforcement and potential browser-based consent settings as solutions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.relativty.com/">Relativty: An open-source VR headset for $200</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Relativty is an open-source virtual reality (VR) headset developed by teenagers Maxim Perumal and Gabriel Combe, designed as a DIY project rather than a consumer product, costing approximately $200.- The headset supports SteamVR games and features experimental positional-scaling using any camera, with a motherboard based on the Atmel SAM3X8E ARM Cortex-M3 processor.- The creators are launching a new company, Unai, to develop a standalone VR headset, and they are currently hiring, with more information available on their website.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42143269">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Relativty is a $200 open-source VR headset with 3DoF (three degrees of freedom) tracking, similar to older models like Oculus Go, but lacks the more immersive 6DoF (six degrees of freedom) tracking.- HadesVR is a 6DoF open-source project developed from Relativty, offering enhanced immersion and reduced motion sickness compared to 3DoF systems.- Privacy concerns with Meta&#39;s Quest headsets are prompting some users to consider alternatives, and there is potential for educational projects using Relativty despite its limitations.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/11/14/new-apple-security-feature-reboots-iphones-after-3-days-researchers-confirm/">New Apple security feature reboots iPhones after 3 days, researchers confirm</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Apple&#39;s iOS 18 introduces an &quot;inactivity reboot&quot; feature that automatically restarts iPhones if they remain unlocked for 72 hours, enhancing security by securing encryption keys in the secure enclave chip.</li>
<li>This feature increases data protection against theft and outdated forensic tools but presents challenges for law enforcement in data extraction from devices.</li>
<li>Security researchers and companies like Magnet Forensics have confirmed the feature, highlighting the ongoing tension between Apple&#39;s security measures and law enforcement&#39;s data access needs.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42143265">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Apple&#39;s new security feature automatically reboots iPhones after 72 hours of inactivity, aiming to maintain security by clearing potential malware or errors.- This feature is akin to the security protocols of payment terminals, which reboot every 24 hours to ensure a secure state.- While some users express concerns about potential connectivity disruptions, the feature is generally viewed as a positive step towards enhanced security, with suggestions to make the reboot interval configurable.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://computerhistory.org/blog/in-memoriam-thomas-e-kurtz-1928-2024/">Thomas E. Kurtz has died</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Thomas E. Kurtz, co-inventor of the BASIC programming language, passed away on November 12, 2024, leaving a significant legacy in computing.</li>
<li>Kurtz played a crucial role in developing the Dartmouth Timesharing System, enabling widespread access to BASIC and influencing generations of computing and software development.</li>
<li>He held leadership roles at Dartmouth, contributed to BASIC standards, retired in 1993, and was honored as a Fellow of the Association for Computing Machinery (ACM) in 1994.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42141761">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Thomas E. Kurtz, co-creator of the BASIC programming language, has passed away, prompting many to share memories and gratitude for his contributions.- BASIC played a crucial role in democratizing computing, making programming accessible to non-experts and inspiring a generation of programmers.- Kurtz&#39;s work at Dartmouth, alongside John Kemeny, was significant in the development of time-sharing systems and educational computing, leaving a lasting impact on the tech industry.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/epasveer/seer">Seer: A GUI front end to GDB for Linux</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Seer is a graphical user interface (GUI) frontend for the GNU Debugger (gdb) on Linux, designed to enhance user experience with a simple interface.- Developed by Ernie Pasveer, Seer requires Linux, C++17, gdb with &quot;mi&quot; interpreter, CMake 3.1.0+, and QT6, and it no longer supports Qt5 beyond version 2.3.- Key features include source file management, variable tracking, and breakpoint management, with support and detailed instructions available on GitHub or via email.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42146338">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Seer is a graphical user interface (GUI) for the GNU Debugger (GDB) on Linux, but users report issues such as non-functional font changes and variable hover errors.</li>
<li>Despite its current flaws, Seer has potential if further developed, with users comparing it to other tools like Gede, which is noted for its simplicity and reliability.</li>
<li>Discussions highlight various debugging preferences, including GDB&#39;s built-in text user interface (TUI), Neovim, gdb-dashboard, and DDD, with some users favoring logging over debuggers for complex scenarios.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Visual Basic 6 IDE recreated in C#" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Visual%20Basic%206%20IDE%20recreated%20in%20C%23&subheading=Friday%2C%20November%2015%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/11/15</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-11-15T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
