<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0"
>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 19:07:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/newsletter/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <copyright><![CDATA[2023 Sunghyun Cho]]></copyright>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-12-14]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/12/14&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-12-14</h1>
<h2><a href="https://www.mercurynews.com/2024/12/13/openai-whistleblower-found-dead-in-san-francisco-apartment/">OpenAI whistleblower found dead in San Francisco apartment</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Former OpenAI employee and whistleblower Suchir Balaji was found dead in his San Francisco apartment, with authorities ruling it a suicide.</li>
<li>Balaji had accused OpenAI of copyright violations in training its ChatGPT program, leading to multiple lawsuits against the company.</li>
<li>OpenAI denies the allegations, asserting that its practices are legal under &quot;fair use&quot; laws, while Balaji was a key figure in the ongoing legal battles.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42412718">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Suchir Balaji, a former OpenAI employee known for his critical views on the company&#39;s use of copyrighted data, was found dead in his San Francisco apartment.</li>
<li>His death, ruled a suicide, has sparked public speculation and discussions, particularly due to his expected role in providing key information in lawsuits against OpenAI.</li>
<li>The circumstances surrounding his death have led to increased attention and debate within the tech community.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://openai.com/index/elon-musk-wanted-an-openai-for-profit/">Elon Musk wanted an OpenAI for-profit</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42411608">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Elon Musk initially envisioned OpenAI as a for-profit entity, but there is skepticism regarding its progress and impact.</li>
<li>Critics question OpenAI&#39;s ambitious claims, such as determining the world&#39;s fate and solving robotics by 2020, highlighting debates over its product-market fit and profitability.</li>
<li>The discussion includes the disruptive potential of AI tools like ChatGPT, the influence of tech leaders, and the challenges of balancing innovation with accountability.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.npr.org/2024/12/13/nx-s1-5155962/mckinsey-purdue-opioid-prosecution-doj">McKinsey and Company to pay $650M for role in opioid crisis</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>McKinsey &amp; Company has agreed to a $650 million settlement to resolve federal investigations into its involvement in promoting opioid sales for Purdue Pharma, covering both civil and criminal charges.</li>
<li>The settlement follows nearly $900 million previously settled with state and local governments, and McKinsey has committed to avoiding future work with controlled substances and will be subject to increased federal oversight.</li>
<li>Former McKinsey partner Martin Elling will plead guilty to obstruction of justice for document deletion, highlighting ongoing criticism that corporate leaders often evade jail time despite significant fines.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42413086">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>McKinsey &amp; Company will pay $650 million to settle federal civil and criminal charges related to its involvement in the opioid crisis, including a deferred prosecution agreement.</li>
<li>Critics argue that the settlement amount is inadequate considering the crisis&#39;s severity, which has led to hundreds of thousands of deaths, and call for harsher penalties, including criminal charges for executives.</li>
<li>The case underscores ongoing discussions about corporate accountability and whether financial penalties effectively deter unethical business practices.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.shirtpocket.com/blog/index.php/shadedgrey/youre_a_mean_one/">macOS 15.2 breaks the ability to copy the OS to another drive</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A significant issue with macOS 15.2 disrupts the replicator, causing a Resource Busy error during data replication, affecting third-party OS copying.</li>
<li>Users are advised to use &quot;Backup - all files&quot; with &quot;Smart Update&quot; to back up data, excluding the operating system, until Apple provides a fix.</li>
<li>The bug, identified as FB16090831, is unlikely to be resolved soon due to the holiday season, as reported by Dave Nanian from Shirt Pocket.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42413757">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>macOS 15.2 has disrupted the functionality of creating bootable backups using tools like SuperDuper and potentially Carbon Copy Cloner, causing user frustration.</li>
<li>The issue arises from Apple&#39;s restrictions on third-party tools, limiting their ability to manipulate the OS, and rendering the built-in utility ineffective.</li>
<li>Users are concerned about Apple&#39;s increasing control over their devices, likening it to a &quot;walled garden&quot; approach, and some are considering switching to alternatives like Linux.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://ai.meta.com/blog/meta-fair-updates-agents-robustness-safety-architecture/?_fb_noscript=1">Sharing new research, models, and datasets from Meta FAIR</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Meta FAIR has released new open-source research artifacts to advance machine intelligence, including Meta Motivo and Meta Video Seal.- Meta Motivo employs unsupervised reinforcement learning to enable human-like behaviors in virtual agents, while Meta Video Seal offers robust video watermarking capabilities.- Additional releases include Flow Matching for generative AI, Meta Explore Theory-of-Mind for social intelligence, and Meta Large Concept Models for hierarchical language reasoning, highlighting Meta&#39;s commitment to responsible AI development and collaboration with the research community.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42412360">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Meta FAIR is introducing new research, models, and datasets, highlighting innovations such as large concept models, dynamic byte latent transformers, and sparse memory layers to enhance AI quality and efficiency.</li>
<li>There is speculation about these advancements being integrated into future models like Llama 4, indicating Meta&#39;s strategic investment in AI to maintain competitiveness and reduce dependency on external providers.</li>
<li>The discussion emphasizes the significance of open-source contributions and the potential influence of AI on content generation and ad targeting.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://ai.meta.com/research/publications/byte-latent-transformer-patches-scale-better-than-tokens/?_fb_noscript=1">Byte Latent Transformer: Patches Scale Better Than Tokens</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Byte Latent Transformer (BLT) is a new byte-level large language model (LLM) architecture that achieves performance comparable to tokenization-based LLMs with enhanced efficiency and robustness.</li>
<li>BLT utilizes dynamically sized patches as computation units, which adjust based on the complexity of the data, leading to improved training and inference efficiency.</li>
<li>The study demonstrates that BLT can scale up to 8 billion parameters with 4 trillion training bytes, outperforming tokenization-based models by effectively scaling both patch and model size.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42415122">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Byte Latent Transformer (BLT) model by Meta introduces a novel approach by using patches instead of traditional tokens, addressing inefficiencies in handling out-of-dictionary words.- BLT consists of three components: an encoder for byte groupings, a transformer for processing, and a decoder for output, utilizing entropy thresholds for dynamic byte grouping.- This model aims to enhance efficiency and performance across languages, overcoming limitations of previous models, and highlights the ongoing challenges and potential in AI language processing.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YD-9NG1Ke5Y">Ilya Sutskever NeurIPS talk [video]</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42413677">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Ilya Sutskever&#39;s NeurIPS talk highlighted the limitations of current internet data for training AI models, likening it to the finite nature of fossil fuels, suggesting a need for new training methods.- The talk initiated discussions on reasoning unpredictability, the use of synthetic datasets, and the development of domain-specific AI models.- Attendees noted the significance of acknowledging data limitations and discussed the potential evolution of AI with new architectures and ethical considerations for future AI leaders.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/rochus-keller/Luon/blob/master/Readme.md">Luon programming language</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Luon is a high-level programming language that merges elements of Oberon and Lua, designed specifically for the LuaJIT Virtual Machine (VM).</li>
<li>It introduces static typing to Lua, allowing seamless integration with Lua and C libraries, and includes features like reference semantics, a HASHMAP type, and immutable STRING data types.</li>
<li>The project offers a compiler, Integrated Development Environment (IDE), and precompiled versions for Linux and Windows, and is open-source under GPL 2 or 3 licenses.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42413343">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Luon is a new programming language inspired by Lua and Oberon, developed by Rochus Keller, focusing on type-safety and structured data types.</li>
<li>It features a statically typed system and compiles to LuaJIT bytecode, aiming for simplicity and efficiency, particularly on older hardware.</li>
<li>Luon is part of Keller&#39;s broader language design projects, including Oberon+ and Micron, offering a modern approach to programming simplicity.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/bigskysoftware/htmx/blob/v2.0.4/CHANGELOG.md">Htmx 2.0.4 Released</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The latest update, version 2.0.4, introduces significant changes such as setting the default target for htmx.ajax to the body, fixing nested shadow root issues, and improving event handling and tag behavior.</li>
<li>This update also includes compatibility updates and bug fixes for extensions, highlighting ongoing improvements in the htmx library, which is used for enhancing HTML with AJAX, CSS Transitions, WebSockets, and Server-Sent Events (SSE).</li>
<li>The changelog reflects a consistent effort to enhance features and fix issues, with notable updates like improved shadow DOM support and the addition of new functionalities over time.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42413845">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Htmx 2.0.4 has been released, prompting discussions about its application in enhancing web interactivity by replacing JavaScript for simpler tasks.</li>
<li>The update introduces a change in the default behavior of <code>htmx.ajax</code>, which some users consider a breaking change, affecting existing implementations.</li>
<li>Htmx is recognized for improving server-side rendering without the need for extensive frontend frameworks, though it may not be suitable for complex client-side interactions compared to frameworks like React or Alpine.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://docs.astral.sh/uv/">Uv, a fast Python package and project manager</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>&quot;uv&quot; is a fast Python package and project manager written in Rust, designed to replace multiple tools like pip, poetry, and virtualenv, offering a significant speed boost of 10-100x over pip.</li>
<li>It provides comprehensive project management with features like a universal lockfile, Python version management, and support for Cargo-style workspaces, and can be installed without Rust or Python.</li>
<li>&quot;uv&quot; is backed by Astral and supports multiple operating systems, including macOS, Linux, and Windows, offering advanced features and efficiency for managing dependencies and environments.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42415602">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Uv is a rapidly growing Python package and project manager, noted for its speed and comprehensive management of Python versions and dependencies.</li>
<li>The tool has gained attention following Anthropic&#39;s Model Context Protocol announcement, highlighting its potential impact on Python development.</li>
<li>While some users appreciate its advantages over existing tools like pip and poetry, concerns about its VC funding, use of Rust, and unofficial Python builds raise questions about its long-term sustainability and potential ecosystem fragmentation.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/what-is-entropy-a-measure-of-just-how-little-we-really-know-20241213/">What Is Entropy? A Measure of Just How Little We Know</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Entropy, initially introduced by Sadi Carnot, measures disorder and is crucial for understanding the second law of thermodynamics, which states that entropy always increases.- The concept of entropy has expanded beyond thermodynamics to include information theory, where it represents uncertainty and is seen as subjective, depending on an observer&#39;s knowledge.- Researchers are exploring the use of information as a resource, with experiments in information engines and quantum thermodynamics, offering new opportunities for scientific innovation and understanding.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42415386">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Entropy is a measure of uncertainty or disorder in a system, relevant in fields like physics and information theory, indicating how much is unknown about a system&#39;s detailed states.</li>
<li>The concept of entropy is sometimes considered subjective, as it can vary based on the observer&#39;s perspective and the measurements available to them.</li>
<li>Entropy is crucial in discussions about thermodynamics, information theory, and even consciousness, as it describes how systems evolve towards more probable, less ordered states.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://veryfront.com/figma-kit">I made a free Figma library packed with components for fast prototyping</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42415637">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A free Figma library with components for rapid prototyping has been released by Veryfront, co-founded by Koji, to aid in web app development.</li>
<li>The library includes open-source components and templates compatible with Figma and React, integrating with Veryfront Studio for efficient development and deployment.</li>
<li>Users can access tools like Veryfront Studio, Components, Templates, and a Figma Kit for free, with an option to upgrade later.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.npmjs.com/package/@smoores/epub">@smoores/epub, a JavaScript library for working with EPUB publications</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A new EPUB library for Node.js has been developed and released as an NPM package, aimed at providing a well-maintained solution for creating EPUB books.</li>
<li>The library was initially created during the development of a project called Storyteller and is now available for the broader Node.js community.</li>
<li>The release was motivated by a request for advice on EPUB book creation, highlighting the demand for such a tool in the community.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42411727">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>@smoores/epub is a JavaScript library designed for handling EPUB files, developed as part of the Storyteller project, and released as a standalone NPM package.</li>
<li>The library addresses the need for EPUB creation and modification tools in the Node.js community, complementing Readium, which is used for reading EPUBs.</li>
<li>The project supports features like hosting books and syncing reading progress across devices, with ongoing discussions about sharing media overlays to optimize processing.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="OpenAI whistleblower found dead in San Francisco apartment" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=OpenAI%20whistleblower%20found%20dead%20in%20San%20Francisco%20apartment&subheading=Saturday%2C%20December%2014%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/12/14</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-14T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-12-13]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/12/13&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-12-13</h1>
<h2><a href="https://velofuso.com">I designed an espresso machine and coffee grinder</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The solo project involves designing an innovative espresso machine with a unique pump and adjustable pressure, aiming to improve outdated technology like 1977 vibratory pumps.- The machine is minimalist, user-friendly, and can also brew filter coffee, addressing common issues such as the need for scales and drip trays.- The project includes a gear pump upgrade kit for other machines and features a grinder with cylindrical burrs, although it faces challenges with oily roasts. Both machines require a DC power source.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42405046">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A solo project led to the design of an espresso machine and coffee grinder, emphasizing advanced internals and minimalist aesthetics.- The espresso machine includes a unique pump for adjustable pressure, suitable for both espresso and filter coffee, while the grinder uses cylindrical burrs for improved grounds.- Both devices operate on DC power, necessitating a power brick, and a gear pump upgrade kit is available for other machines; feedback suggests adding practical images and videos for better product presentation.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://spectrum.ieee.org/ibm-demo">A new video captures a 1968 demo of IBM’s Executive Terminal</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>In 1968, IBM demonstrated its Executive Terminal, an early attempt to integrate computers, video, and digital information to improve executive decision-making.</li>
<li>The demonstration highlighted IBM&#39;s innovative approach to using technology for strategic business purposes, marking a significant moment in the history of technology.</li>
<li>This event is notable for showcasing the potential of digital tools in corporate environments, paving the way for future advancements in executive technology solutions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42405462">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A newly released video showcases a 1968 demo of IBM&#39;s Executive Terminal, featuring an IBM 3270 display and a phone handset for remote spreadsheet operations.- The system was inspired by NASA&#39;s Apollo Mission Control, highlighting early efforts to integrate computing into executive workflows, akin to today&#39;s remote collaboration tools.- The demo provides insights into historical computing practices and the evolution of technology in business environments.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.alexmurrell.co.uk/articles/the-age-of-average">The age of average (2023)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>In the early 1990s, Russian artists Komar and Melamid used market research to reveal that people across different countries preferred similar blue landscapes, indicating a lack of individuality in art preferences.</li>
<li>This trend of homogeneity is observed in various fields such as interior design, architecture, cars, personal appearance, media, and branding, suggesting a dominance of convention and cliché.</li>
<li>The article suggests that this &quot;age of average&quot; offers an opportunity for bold brands to differentiate themselves by embracing creativity and originality.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42405999">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article explores the uniformity in modern architecture, design, and culture, attributing it to economic factors, globalization, and efficiency-focused practices.- Critics argue that this sameness is driven by profit motives and the desire to appeal to a broad audience, resulting in a loss of regional diversity and creativity.- The discussion highlights that while trends are not new, the current level of homogenization is unprecedented, with some viewing it as a natural result of global communication and market forces, while others mourn the loss of uniqueness and cultural identity.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.science.org/content/article/amid-cuts-basic-research-new-zealand-scraps-all-support-social-sciences">Amid cuts to basic research, New Zealand scraps all support for social sciences</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42405956">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>New Zealand has reduced funding for social sciences, igniting a debate over the value and methodologies of these fields.</li>
<li>Critics claim that certain social sciences have strayed from scientific methods, while supporters emphasize their role in addressing societal issues.</li>
<li>This funding cut is viewed as part of a larger trend favoring research with immediate economic benefits, prompting worries about potential long-term effects on society and academia.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/12/carta-is-making-it-too-difficult-to-cancel-subscriptions-some-founders-say/">Carta is making it too difficult to cancel subscriptions, some founders say</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Startup founders have criticized Carta, a cap table management software, for making subscription cancellations difficult, often requiring meetings scheduled after renewal dates.</li>
<li>Carta attributes the cancellation issues to a &quot;one-time staffing challenge&quot; and aims to clarify the process for customers.</li>
<li>Competitors like AngelList and Pulley offer simpler cancellation methods, and despite the criticism, some users still praise Carta&#39;s product.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42404144">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Some founders allege that Carta complicates the cancellation of subscriptions by necessitating hard-to-schedule meetings before automatic renewals.- Critics label this practice as a &quot;dark pattern,&quot; a design choice that manipulates users into actions they might not otherwise take, while others consider it a simple oversight.- The situation has sparked discussions about potential regulations to mandate straightforward cancellation processes, with competitors emphasizing their more user-friendly approaches.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://kennyballou.com/blog/2016/12/elixir-hot-swapping/index.html">Elixir/Erlang Hot Swapping Code (2016)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The guide delves into hot code swapping in Elixir/Erlang, enabling code updates without halting the system, a significant feature for maintaining uptime.- It explains essential concepts, including Erlang applications, .app and .rel files, and tools like Relups and Distillery for managing upgrades and releases.- The guide highlights the complexity of release management in Elixir and the continuous evolution of tools to support this process.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42404411">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Erlang/Elixir&#39;s hot code swapping enables updates without downtime, beneficial for high-availability systems such as drones and telephony.</li>
<li>Despite its advantages, the complexity of managing state changes and ensuring stability makes hot code swapping less common in web applications, which often prefer blue-green deployments.</li>
<li>While some developers use hot swapping for specific needs, it remains a niche feature and is not essential for most applications.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.defense.gov/News/News-Stories/Article/Article/4000004/test/">Test</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42408202">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A government document template in Quebec contains the placeholder title &quot;sdf fdsfdsfg&quot; in its metadata, resulting in many official documents sharing this title.</li>
<li>A humorous discussion on Hacker News speculates about the implications, with jokes about sleeper agents, military acronyms, and accidental posts.</li>
<li>The post&#39;s numerical ID, 4000004, has also sparked interest and speculation among users.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.quantamagazine.org/mathematicians-uncover-a-new-way-to-count-prime-numbers-20241211/">Mathematicians uncover a new way to count prime numbers</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Mathematicians Ben Green and Mehtaab Sawhney have developed a new method to count a specific type of prime numbers, enhancing our comprehension of these essential mathematical elements.</li>
<li>Their work builds on a conjecture by Friedlander and Iwaniec, proving there are infinitely many primes of the form p² + 4q², where both p and q are prime.</li>
<li>This breakthrough highlights the potential for new applications of Gowers norms, a mathematical tool, in the field of number theory.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42405733">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Mathematicians have developed a novel method to count prime numbers, showing that infinitely many primes can be expressed as the sum of squares of two whole numbers.</li>
<li>This discovery is crucial for number theory and may impact fields such as cryptography and computing, demonstrating the value of interdisciplinary approaches in mathematics.</li>
<li>Although the immediate practical applications are debated, foundational research like this often leads to unforeseen technological and scientific advancements.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.souzatharsis.com/tamingLLMs/markdown/toc.html">Taming LLMs – A Practical Guide to LLM Pitfalls with Open Source Software</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>&quot;Taming LLMs&quot; is a practical guide that addresses the challenges and pitfalls of using Large Language Models (LLMs) in applications, providing solutions for handling unstructured output and managing context windows.</li>
<li>The book offers practical Python examples and open-source solutions, covering topics like structured output, token limits, evaluation gaps, hallucination, safety concerns, cost factors, and avoiding vendor lock-in.</li>
<li>It aims to equip engineers and product managers with the knowledge to effectively harness LLMs while avoiding common pitfalls, making it a valuable resource for those working with these models.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42404202">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The guide addresses managing pitfalls in Large Language Models (LLMs) using open-source software, with some users suspecting it might be AI-generated.</li>
<li>Concerns were expressed about the rapid development and potential instability of LangChain, leading some developers to prefer using Python directly for LLM tasks due to LangChain&#39;s high level of abstraction.</li>
<li>Alternatives such as magentic and pydantic-ai were suggested, emphasizing the need to understand LLM patterns and maintain control over inputs and outputs for effective utilization.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://assets.bitbashing.io/papers/concurrency-primer.pdf">What every systems programmer should know about concurrency (2020) [pdf]</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42403744">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A 2020 review emphasizes the complexity and potential for errors in programming language memory model changes from the early 2010s, which can result in costly bugs.- Russ Cox recommends using sequentially-consistent atomics in systems programming to mitigate these issues.- The discussion covers the C++ focus of the document, challenges in multithreading, and the evolving role of systems programmers, with various opinions on concurrency and memory models.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://nypost.com/2024/12/12/opinion/feds-help-health-insurers-hide-dirty-secret-rising-denials/">Feds help health insurers hide their dirty secret: denials on the rise</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Health insurers have significantly increased claim denial rates from 1-2% in 2013 to an average of 15% by 2022, with some companies denying nearly half of all claims.</li>
<li>The Affordable Care Act mandates transparency in denial rates, but lack of enforcement has allowed insurers to benefit from these denials, with patients seldom appealing despite high success rates.</li>
<li>Betsy McCaughey advocates for federal intervention to ensure transparency and accountability in insurance markets by revealing insurers&#39; denial rates.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42408925">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Health insurance claim denials have significantly increased over the past decade, raising concerns about fairness and transparency.</li>
<li>The Affordable Care Act mandates disclosure of denial rates to consumers, but this information is frequently inaccessible, highlighting a lack of transparency.</li>
<li>The article advocates for regular audits and accountability in the insurance industry, as 41% of appealed denials are overturned, suggesting many initial denials may be unjustified.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.abq1347">A room temperature Li2O-based lithium-air battery enabled by a solid electrolyte</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42402927">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A new room temperature lithium-air battery using Li2O has been developed, potentially offering energy density comparable to gasoline.</li>
<li>The battery features a solid electrolyte and a gas diffusion layer with trimolybdenum phosphide nanoparticles, achieving a current density of 0.1 mA/cm².</li>
<li>With a specific energy of 685 Wh/kg and a volumetric energy density of 614 Wh/L, this technology could enhance electric vehicle and aircraft efficiency, though challenges in oxygen reduction reaction remain.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="I designed an espresso machine and coffee grinder" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=I%20designed%20an%20espresso%20machine%20and%20coffee%20grinder&subheading=Friday%2C%20December%2013%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/12/13</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-13T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-12-12]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/12/12&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-12-12</h1>
<h2><a href="https://lichess.org/@/Lichess/blog/wcc-2024-round-14-gukesh-becomes-the-youngest-world-champion-in-history/cDggdNZw">Gukesh becomes the youngest chess world champion in history</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>GM Gukesh D became the youngest world champion in the 2024 World Chess Championship by defeating GM Ding Liren in Round 14.</li>
<li>The match was notable for Gukesh&#39;s strategic play and deep preparation, capitalizing on Ding&#39;s blunder in a king and pawn endgame.</li>
<li>Lichess provided live coverage with commentary from GM Felix Blohberger, IM Laura Unuk, and guest GM Ivan Cheparinov, highlighting the event&#39;s significance and emotional moments.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42398952">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Gukesh, at 18, became the youngest chess world champion by defeating Ding Liren, showcasing his determination and skill.</li>
<li>The match was intense, with Ding initially favored due to his rapid and blitz skills, but Gukesh&#39;s pressure led to Ding&#39;s critical blunder.</li>
<li>The chess community is speculating on future matches, particularly in light of Magnus Carlsen&#39;s absence from the championship circuit.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.oldmapsonline.org/en/history/regions">Timemap.org – Interactive Map of History</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42397550">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>TimeMap.org is a newly launched interactive historical map project featured on Product Hunt, developed by Klokan using Linked Data and OpenHistoricalMaps to visualize history.- The project collaborates with prestigious institutions such as Stanford University and the British Library, aiming to improve historical understanding through user feedback and community contributions.- Users can explore historical maps, suggest timeline adjustments, and request data accuracy improvements, enhancing the project&#39;s development and accuracy.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/dec/11/new-jersey-drone-sightings-state-of-emergency">Mysterious New Jersey drone sightings prompt call for &#39;state of emergency&#39;</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Over 3,000 drone sightings in New Jersey and the US northeast have led to calls for a &quot;limited state of emergency&quot; and a temporary drone ban by State Senator Jon Bramnick.</li>
<li>Concerns are heightened due to drones being spotted near sensitive locations, such as President-elect Trump&#39;s golf course and critical infrastructure.</li>
<li>Despite the large number of sightings, the FBI has not provided an explanation, and the Pentagon has dismissed claims of foreign involvement, including from an &quot;Iranian mothership.&quot;</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42391443">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Mysterious drone sightings in New Jersey have raised concerns, similar to the 2018 Gatwick airport incident, where drone reports caused a shutdown without any drones being captured on camera or radar.</li>
<li>Authorities, including the FBI, Pentagon, and White House, have denied any foreign or military involvement, leading to speculation about a secretive government operation or misidentified aircraft.</li>
<li>The lack of concrete evidence or resolution has resulted in public anxiety and ongoing debate.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://nicholas.carlini.com/writing/2023/chat-gpt-2-in-c.html">A ChatGPT clone, in 3000 bytes of C, backed by GPT-2 (2023)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Nicholas Carlini has developed a ChatGPT clone using a minimal C implementation of GPT-2, which is only about 3000 bytes in size.- The project is dependency-free and optimized to run GPT-2 Small on modern machines, though it produces low-quality output.- This initiative highlights the simplicity of neural networks and the ability to condense complex machine learning models into compact code, with the source code available on GitHub.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42396372">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A ChatGPT clone, implemented in just 3000 bytes of C and powered by GPT-2, illustrates the simplicity and minimal code required to run a language model.- Although not highly functional, this project sparks discussions on AI&#39;s nature, training data&#39;s role, and the potential for small, efficient implementations.- It serves as an educational tool, demonstrating core concepts of transformers and the feasibility of compact AI solutions.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Gukesh becomes the youngest chess world champion in history" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Gukesh%20becomes%20the%20youngest%20chess%20world%20champion%20in%20history&subheading=Thursday%2C%20December%2012%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/12/12</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-12T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-12-11]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/12/11&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-12-11</h1>
<h2><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/12/10/business/media/the-onion-infowars-alex-jones.html">Bankruptcy judge rejects sale of Infowars to The Onion</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A judge has halted the sale of Infowars to The Onion, which intended to transform it into a satirical platform.</li>
<li>The decision was made despite backing from Sandy Hook victims&#39; families, leaving Infowars&#39; future in limbo.</li>
<li>A court-appointed trustee is now responsible for determining a new course of action, while The Onion remains interested in the acquisition.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42384921">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A bankruptcy judge has rejected the sale of Infowars to The Onion, stating that the auction process did not maximize returns for creditors, including the Sandy Hook families.- The judge criticized the sealed bid process for not promoting competitive bidding, which is essential for fair auction practices.- The Onion&#39;s bid involved $1.75 million in cash, with additional funds from the Sandy Hook families&#39; potential defamation judgment earnings, raising questions about the auction&#39;s fairness and legality.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.google/technology/google-deepmind/google-gemini-ai-update-december-2024/">Gemini 2.0: our new AI model for the agentic era</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Google DeepMind has launched Gemini 2.0, an advanced AI model designed for the &quot;agentic era,&quot; featuring capabilities such as native image and audio output and tool use.- Gemini 2.0 Flash is currently accessible to developers and trusted testers, with a wider release expected early next year, indicating a phased rollout strategy.- Google is focusing on responsible AI development, emphasizing safety and security, with potential applications in search, games, and robotics, highlighting the model&#39;s versatility and commitment to ethical AI practices.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42388783">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Google&#39;s Gemini 2.0 AI model is designed for the &quot;agentic era,&quot; capable of writing and executing Python code, but it cannot make network calls.- The model is proficient in vision tasks and is accessible to developers and testers via AI Studio, though it still encounters issues such as hallucinations and verbosity.- The AI community is discussing the terminology used, such as &quot;agentic&quot; and &quot;reasoning,&quot; with some considering these terms as marketing jargon.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/12/10/gm-halts-funding-of-robotaxi-development-by-cruise.html">GM exits robotaxi market, will bring Cruise operations in house</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>General Motors (GM) is discontinuing its funding for the Cruise robotaxi division, opting to integrate it into its tech team to focus on autonomous systems for personal vehicles.</li>
<li>GM aims to acquire the remaining Cruise shares by 2025, significantly reducing its annual expenditure on the division by more than half.</li>
<li>Cruise has faced challenges, such as a $1.5 million fine for not reporting a crash, while competitors like Waymo and Tesla continue to progress in the robotaxi market.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42381637">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>General Motors (GM) is withdrawing from the robotaxi market and integrating Cruise operations internally due to heightened competition.</li>
<li>Despite possessing advanced autonomous technology, GM&#39;s strategy is questioned, with issues such as the unavailability of Super Cruise for test drives.</li>
<li>The market for autonomous vehicles is uncertain, with waning interest and companies like Ford cutting costs for similar features, while Tesla&#39;s Full Self-Driving (FSD) still faces challenges in certain scenarios.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://electric-sql.com/blog/2024/12/10/electric-beta-release">Electric (Postgres sync engine) beta release</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Electric&#39;s sync engine, now in BETA with version 1.0.0-beta.1, facilitates real-time partial replication of Postgres data into local apps, enabling instant local data access without altering existing technology stacks.- The engine includes PGlite, a lightweight WebAssembly (WASM) version of Postgres for browsers, and is production-ready after a six-month rewrite, already utilized by companies like Google and Supabase.- Electric supports high-throughput workloads with low latency, is easy to adopt with simple APIs, and can be integrated incrementally, with Electric Cloud, a managed hosting service, in development.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42383136">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>ElectricSQL has released a beta version of its Postgres sync engine, generating interest due to its engineering quality and business model considerations.- The engine syncs data from Postgres to local applications as read-only replicas, suitable for high-read, low-write services, but does not support write-path synchronization.- Users are discussing its potential compared to alternatives like PowerSync and Triplit, and the project aims to simplify local/offline-first app development, despite challenges in multi-table synchronization and schema changes.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.courtlistener.com/docket/69221176/64/wpengine-inc-v-automattic-inc/">WPEngine, Inc. vs. Automattic– Order on Motion for Preliminary Injunction</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42382829">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The court case between WPEngine, Inc. and Automattic involves a preliminary injunction due to actions by Matt Mullenweg that allegedly harmed WPEngine.- The court ruled in favor of WPEngine, mandating Automattic to restore account access, return the ACF plugin, and remove a controversial checkbox without requiring a bond.- This case underscores tensions in the WordPress community and prompts discussions on open-source governance and the influence of private equity in tech companies.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Bankruptcy judge rejects sale of Infowars to The Onion" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Bankruptcy%20judge%20rejects%20sale%20of%20Infowars%20to%20The%20Onion&subheading=Wednesday%2C%20December%2011%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/12/11</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-11T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-12-10]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/12/10&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-12-10</h1>
<h2><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cp9nxee2r0do">What we know about CEO shooting suspect</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Luigi Mangione, a 26-year-old from a notable Baltimore family, has been charged with the murder of UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson in New York City.</li>
<li>Mangione was arrested in Pennsylvania with a ghost gun and a document hinting at a motive related to anger towards corporate America.</li>
<li>Despite his academic achievements and career as a data engineer, Mangione&#39;s social media suggests recent isolation from family and friends.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42370622">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The CEO shooting suspect&#39;s case has generated numerous theories, ranging from a deliberate plan to spread a message to mere incompetence and luck.- The suspect&#39;s behavior, including carrying evidence and appearing in public during a manhunt, has intensified public speculation.- The incident has sparked discussions on societal issues, particularly public frustration with the healthcare system and disparities in crime treatment based on victim status.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://twitter.com/itchio/status/1866239798924763227">This is not a joke, Funko just called my mom</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42371481">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Funko issued a takedown request targeting a specific page on itch.io, but it resulted in the temporary removal of the entire site, leading to public backlash.</li>
<li>Funko clarified that their intention was to target only a specific page, not the entire itch.io platform.</li>
<li>The incident has sparked discussions about the responsibility of companies and their partners in managing takedown requests effectively.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://treecalcul.us/">Tree Calculus</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Tree Calculus is a Turing-complete computational model with a single operator, allowing for program analysis, type checking, compilation, and optimization directly within the code.- It supports arbitrary type systems and gradual typing, enabling powerful Read-Eval-Print Loops (REPLs) and program deployment without external tools.- Its minimal syntax and semantics make it portable and easy to implement interpreters on any platform, suitable for modeling, formal specifications, and educational purposes.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42373437">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Tree Calculus is a programming language developed by Prof. Barry Jay, focusing on unlabeled trees and allowing introspection and manipulation of functions.</li>
<li>It is Turing complete, meaning it can perform any computation given enough time and resources, and offers unique features like function inversion, setting it apart from languages like Lisp or Forth.</li>
<li>The community is actively discussing its implications and potential applications, although there is some confusion regarding its presentation and purpose on the website treecalcul.us.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://trellis3d.github.io/">Trellis – 3D mesh generative model</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The post introduces a new 3D generation method using a unified Structured LATent (SLAT) representation, enhancing the creation of versatile and high-quality 3D assets.</li>
<li>The model, named TRELLIS, utilizes rectified flow transformers and is trained on a large dataset, outperforming existing methods in 3D generation.</li>
<li>The approach supports flexible output formats and local 3D editing, with plans to release the code, model, and data to the public.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42369476">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Trellis, a 3D mesh generative model, has generated mixed reactions due to its ability to produce high-quality assets, potentially shifting game development focus from graphics to storytelling.</li>
<li>While some express concern over the diminishing role of handmade artistry, others see potential for artists to adapt and use AI to enhance their work.</li>
<li>Trellis is recognized for its potential in prototyping and democratizing 3D modeling, despite current limitations like poor wireframe quality and challenges with certain shapes.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.savethearchive.com/">Save Music, Save the Archive</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Over 500 musicians are advocating for major labels to withdraw a $621 million lawsuit against the Internet Archive, a nonprofit cultural institution.</li>
<li>The musicians emphasize the need for fair compensation, protection of music legacies, and investment in living artists rather than supporting monopolistic practices.</li>
<li>They argue that the music industry&#39;s survival depends on prioritizing artists&#39; futures and preserving their works, urging public support through an open letter.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42373098">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Open source projects, such as Relisten, utilize the Internet Archive to store legally recorded concerts, aiding music fans and preserving cultural history.</li>
<li>The Internet Archive is facing legal challenges from major labels, particularly concerning projects like the Great 78 Project, which seeks to preserve historical recordings.</li>
<li>There is ongoing debate in the music industry about fair artist compensation, with discussions on copyright, streaming revenues, and alternative revenue models like direct sales and platforms such as Patreon.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://antirez.com/news/144">From where I left</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42378488">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The controversy centers on Redis changing its open-source license, causing discontent among contributors who feel betrayed by the move.- The new license is seen by some as complicating legal use, while others view it as essential to prevent exploitation by large corporations.- The emergence of Valkey, a Redis fork supported by major tech companies, and the return of Redis founder Salvatore Sanfilippo, are significant developments in the ongoing debate about open-source licensing and corporate influence.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/neovim/comments/1h7vhmg/bro_been_developing_his_2k_star_plugin_on_a/">Developer wrote 25k lines of Neovim plugin code using phone and touchscreen</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42374823">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A developer in Bangladesh wrote 25,000 lines of Neovim plugin code using only a phone and touchscreen, showcasing remarkable dedication and adaptability.</li>
<li>A fundraiser is being organized to provide him with a laptop, as laptops are costly in Bangladesh, highlighting the financial barriers faced by developers in developing countries.</li>
<li>The developer utilizes tools like Termius, tmux, and Vim on his phone, and his efforts have sparked discussions about the challenges of coding on a phone.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.bitsaboutmoney.com/archive/debanking-and-debunking/">Debanking (and Debunking?)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Debanking, the involuntary closure of bank accounts, is a contentious issue, particularly affecting crypto businesses, with concerns it may be used as a political tool.</li>
<li>The debate involves complex interactions between private and state actors, with some viewing debanking as necessary for risk management, while others see it as unfair and lacking due process.</li>
<li>Historical regulatory actions like Operation Choke Point, which pressured banks to sever ties with certain industries, are cited by critics as similar to current actions against crypto businesses, termed &quot;Choke Point 2.0.&quot;</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42371476">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Debanking involves banks closing accounts or denying services, often due to regulatory pressures such as Anti-Money Laundering (AML) laws, which aim to prevent illegal financial activities.</li>
<li>Critics highlight the lack of transparency and due process in debanking, which can unjustly impact individuals and businesses, limiting their economic participation.</li>
<li>The debate centers on whether banks should be required to offer basic services to everyone, regardless of perceived risks, and how this issue intersects with broader political and social concerns.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42377018">Double (YC W24) – Index Investing with 0% Expense Ratios</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Double is a financial platform that allows investment in over 50 stock market indexes with no expense ratios, charging a flat fee of $1/month for management, rebalancing, and tax-loss harvesting.</li>
<li>The platform offers direct indexing by purchasing individual stocks from popular indexes, providing customization and daily portfolio optimization, distinguishing itself from other robo-advisors.</li>
<li>Double has achieved $10 million in assets under management (AUM) and aims to disrupt the $100 billion/year ETF and mutual fund market by offering low-fee investment strategies.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42377018">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Double is an investment platform offering index investing with a flat fee of $1/month and 0% expense ratios, aiming to disrupt traditional ETF and mutual fund markets.- Founded by JJ and Mark, the platform manages over 50 stock market indexes and handles tasks like rebalancing and tax-loss harvesting, with $10M in assets under management.- Despite its innovative fee structure, there are concerns about Double&#39;s sustainability, security, and how it compares to established financial institutions like Vanguard and Fidelity.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="What we know about CEO shooting suspect" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=What%20we%20know%20about%20CEO%20shooting%20suspect&subheading=Tuesday%2C%20December%2010%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/12/10</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-10T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-12-09]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/12/09&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-12-09</h1>
<h2><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/itch.io/post/3lcu6h465bs2n">Itch.io Taken Down by Funko</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42363727">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Itch.io&#39;s domain was disabled due to a false fraud and phishing report by BrandShield concerning a fan page for a Funko Pop game.- The incident underscores issues with automated trademark enforcement and the lack of human oversight, as well as the slow response from the registrar, iwantmyname.- The situation has sparked user support for itch.io and criticism of the parties involved in the takedown.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://flatt.tech/research/posts/compromising-openwrt-supply-chain-sha256-collision/">Compromising OpenWrt Supply Chain</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A security engineer identified vulnerabilities in OpenWrt&#39;s firmware upgrade process, including command injection and SHA-256 hash collision issues.- The vulnerabilities allowed potential attackers to inject commands and create hash collisions, leading to the installation of malicious firmware.- The OpenWrt team promptly addressed and fixed these vulnerabilities, emphasizing the need for strong security in software supply chains.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42363102">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A vulnerability in OpenWrt&#39;s supply chain enabled targeted code execution without validation, posing a risk of backdoored builds.- The incident underscores the importance of reproducibility and transparency in software builds, similar to practices in Gentoo&#39;s ebuild repository.- OpenWrt&#39;s swift response highlights the efficiency of open-source projects in addressing security issues compared to closed-source alternatives.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://bcantrill.dtrace.org/2024/12/08/why-gelsinger-was-wrong-for-intel/">Pat Gelsinger was wrong for Intel</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Pat Gelsinger, despite his technical expertise and managerial skills, was deemed unsuitable as Intel&#39;s CEO due to his inability to address the company&#39;s cultural and strategic challenges.</li>
<li>His leadership decisions, such as maintaining dividends and aggressive advertising, were criticized for reflecting a peacetime approach rather than the necessary wartime leadership.</li>
<li>Gelsinger&#39;s management of Intel&#39;s Foundry Services and the termination of the Tofino project, a promising programmable switch silicon, were seen as significant missteps, leaving Intel&#39;s cultural issues unresolved.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42361955">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Pat Gelsinger, CEO of Intel, faced challenges including 10nm production delays and competition from TSMC, leading to significant stock drops despite strategic investments in manufacturing facilities.</li>
<li>Critics suggest that Intel&#39;s board, composed mainly of non-technical members, may be a core issue, questioning whether Gelsinger&#39;s technical expertise or an outsider is needed to resolve Intel&#39;s problems.</li>
<li>The ongoing debate centers on whether Gelsinger&#39;s strategies were appropriate or if the board&#39;s composition and decisions are hindering Intel&#39;s progress.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://json5.org/">JSON5 – JSON for Humans</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>JSON5, an extension of JSON, is designed for easier manual editing, making it ideal for configuration files but not suitable for machine communication.</li>
<li>Since its launch in 2012, JSON5 has gained significant popularity, with over 65 million downloads weekly, and is utilized by major projects like Chromium and Next.js.</li>
<li>JSON5 is a superset of JSON, incorporating ECMAScript 5.1 features, allowing for flexible syntax, and is compatible with ES5, with a JavaScript library available for parsing and serialization.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42360681">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>JSON5 is an extension of JSON designed to be more human-friendly by allowing features such as comments and trailing commas.</li>
<li>There is a debate on whether JSON should remain simple or evolve with additional features, as seen with JSON5, which is not an official update but an alternative format.</li>
<li>Some suggest using other formats like TOML or HJSON for more human-readable configurations, highlighting the ongoing discussion about JSON&#39;s evolution.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.france24.com/en/live-news/20241204-uk-bans-daytime-tv-ads-for-cereals-muffins-and-burgers">UK bans daytime TV ads for cereals, muffins and burgers</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The UK government is implementing a ban on daytime TV advertisements for sugary and &quot;less healthy&quot; foods, such as cereals, muffins, and burgers, to address child obesity.</li>
<li>Starting next October, these ads will only be allowed to air after 9:00 pm, with the goal of preventing 20,000 cases of childhood obesity each year.</li>
<li>Health Secretary Wes Streeting highlighted the importance of stopping the targeting of children with junk food advertisements.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42359836">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The UK has implemented a ban on daytime TV advertisements for junk food, including cereals, muffins, and burgers, as a measure to combat childhood obesity.</li>
<li>Critics argue that the ban is insufficient, as children are more influenced by online ads on platforms like YouTube and TikTok, which are not included in the ban.</li>
<li>The debate persists on whether the government should enforce existing laws and regulate online ads targeting children or if parents should take more responsibility in protecting children from harmful advertising.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://mastodon.social/@kiwix/113622081750449356">Hetzner has decided to cancel our account and terminate all servers.</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42365295">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Hetzner&#39;s account cancellation and server termination have prompted discussions on the necessity of backups and disaster recovery plans.</li>
<li>Users shared experiences of Hetzner&#39;s strict Terms of Service (ToS) enforcement, including immediate server shutdowns for violations, raising concerns about cloud provider reliability.</li>
<li>The debate emphasized the risks of depending on a single provider and the importance of using multiple providers for backups to ensure data security.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.google/technology/research/google-willow-quantum-chip/">Willow, Our Quantum Chip</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Google has introduced Willow, a quantum chip that marks a significant advancement in quantum error correction and computation speed.- Willow demonstrated its capability by performing a computation in under five minutes, a task that would take a supercomputer 10 septillion years, indicating its potential to tackle complex problems beyond classical computers.- This development is pivotal for the future of commercially viable quantum computers, with implications for revolutionizing industries such as medicine, energy, and artificial intelligence (AI).</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42367649">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Google&#39;s announcement of the quantum chip, Willow, featuring over 100 qubits with stability, marks a significant milestone in quantum computing.- This development could influence AI and data security, as quantum computing poses challenges to traditional encryption methods.- Despite the achievement, practical applications like Shor&#39;s algorithm require a much higher number of qubits, leading to mixed reactions regarding the chip&#39;s immediate impact.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://sora.com/">OpenAI: Sora</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42368604">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>OpenAI&#39;s Sora video generation tool is receiving mixed reviews due to challenges in creating precise content, as current AI technology struggles with detailed prompts and motion accuracy.</li>
<li>The tool is not yet available in the EU, and its release has faced server issues, affecting user experience.</li>
<li>While some users appreciate the novelty and potential of AI-generated content, there are concerns about the quality and pricing structure, with some noting it lags behind competitors.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Itch.io Taken Down by Funko" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Itch.io%20Taken%20Down%20by%20Funko&subheading=Monday%2C%20December%209%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/12/09</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-09T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-12-08]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/12/08&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-12-08</h1>
<h2><a href="https://nyxt.atlas.engineer/">Nyxt: The Hacker&#39;s Browser</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Nyxt is a browser designed for advanced users, emphasizing keyboard navigation and efficiency in online information analysis and extraction.</li>
<li>It features powerful tools like link hinting, Jump Headings for document navigation, and fuzzy search for easy tab management and command execution.</li>
<li>Additional functionalities include a built-in REPL (Read-Eval-Print Loop) for programmability, smart bookmark search, customizable autofills, clipboard history, and a tree-based history for tracking visited pages.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42354691">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Nyxt is a browser that integrates AI and semantic tools, aiming to enhance user experience by functioning as a &quot;second brain,&quot; though some users are skeptical about its AI capabilities and performance impact.</li>
<li>Written in Common Lisp, Nyxt is designed to be highly extensible like Emacs but does not support WebExtensions, limiting compatibility with popular extensions such as uBlock Origin.</li>
<li>Despite unique features like a tree-based history and keyboard-driven workflows, its practicality is debated compared to browsers like qutebrowser and Firefox; it is available on Linux, with unofficial support for BSD, macOS, and Windows.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://apnews.com/article/syria-assad-sweida-daraa-homs-hts-qatar-7f65823bbf0a7bd331109e8dff419430">Syrian government falls in end to 50-year rule of Assad family</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42355364">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Assad family&#39;s 50-year rule in Syria has ended, indicating a weakened state of their main supporters, Russia and Iran, who are engaged in other conflicts.</li>
<li>The power vacuum in Syria has led to a complex situation with multiple factions competing for control, creating uncertainty about the country&#39;s future.</li>
<li>The fall of Assad may contribute to regional instability and have broader implications for global politics, including the conflict in Ukraine.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.infochunk.com/schannel/index.html">Reverse engineering the Sega Channel game image file format</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Sega Channel was a pioneering games-on-demand service for the Sega Genesis, active from 1994 to 1998, offering around 50 games monthly.- In 2024, a user discovered a Sega Channel game image CD from 1996, leading to efforts in reverse engineering to extract and preserve its data.- The project successfully decoded exclusive games, emphasizing the role of community efforts and reverse engineering in preserving gaming history.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42353907">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Sega Channel was an innovative 1990s service that allowed users to download games via cable TV, functioning similarly to Teletext with a continuous data loop.</li>
<li>It was a precursor to modern digital game distribution, offering a rotating selection of games for a subscription fee, despite technical challenges and limited reach.</li>
<li>The service required special hardware and used satellite transmission to cable headends, but was known for its unreliability in certain areas.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://apnews.com/article/notre-dame-paris-latest-e50813cf016f08607c20ab115bc4b153">Notre Dame Cathedral reopens</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42353215">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Notre Dame Cathedral has reopened, restored to its original medieval appearance with modern updates, such as a new spire.</li>
<li>The restoration focused on reflecting the cathedral&#39;s initial design rather than its state before the 2018 fire, earning praise for craftsmanship and traditional techniques.</li>
<li>The project has sparked discussions on balancing historical authenticity with modern elements, drawing significant attention to Notre Dame&#39;s cultural and historical importance.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.wsj.com/tech/cybersecurity/hacking-brian-krebs-snowflake-waifu-49b87fce">Brian Krebs Investigates Internet&#39;s Most Vicious Hackers–From a Secret Location</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42354602">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Brian Krebs, a well-known cybersecurity journalist, is noted for his investigations into hacking activities, including exposing a significant cellphone tracking flaw in 2018.</li>
<li>The article discusses the ease with which young hackers can learn skills through online communities, highlighting the accessibility of hacking knowledge.</li>
<li>It also addresses the risks hackers face, often for minimal financial reward, emphasizing the importance and challenges of the cybersecurity field.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.atlantanewsfirst.com/2024/12/03/airline-informant-received-thousands-passenger-cash-seizures/">Airline informant received thousands from passenger cash seizures</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42354580">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>An airline informant received financial incentives from cash seizures of passengers, raising concerns about potential civil rights violations.</li>
<li>The DEA&#39;s &quot;consensual&quot; searches at airports, often criticized for being based on weak criteria, have been suspended following a Justice Department Inspector General&#39;s report.</li>
<li>Critics argue that civil asset forfeiture is unconstitutional and advocate for systemic reforms to prevent law enforcement abuse.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://news.mit.edu/2024/study-browsing-negative-content-online-makes-mental-health-struggles-worse-1205">Browsing negative content online makes mental health struggles worse: Study</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>MIT researchers have created a web plug-in named &quot;Digital Diet&quot; to assist users in making informed choices about online content to safeguard their mental health.</li>
<li>The tool employs natural language processing (NLP) to evaluate web pages based on emotion, knowledge, and actionability, steering users towards more positive content.</li>
<li>The research underscores the two-way relationship between online behavior and mental health, with findings published in Nature Human Behavior.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42353944">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A study indicates that exposure to negative online content can exacerbate mental health issues, contributing to feelings of anxiety and helplessness.- Managing online consumption is crucial, as constant exposure to negative information can significantly impact thoughts and emotions.- While staying informed is important for societal change, many find that reducing exposure to negative news and focusing on personal well-being can provide relief.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Nyxt: The Hacker's Browser" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Nyxt%3A%20The%20Hacker's%20Browser&subheading=Sunday%2C%20December%208%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/12/08</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-08T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-12-07]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/12/07&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-12-07</h1>
<h2><a href="https://shilin.ca/my-second-year-without-job/">My second year without a job</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42344002">Reactions</a></h3>
<h2><a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML/Element/dialog">: The Dialog Element</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The HTML `` element is used to create dialog boxes, which can be modal (pausing page interaction) or non-modal (allowing interaction).</li>
<li>JavaScript methods <code>.showModal()</code> and <code>.show()</code> are used to display modal and non-modal dialogs, respectively, while <code>.close()</code> is used to close them.</li>
<li>Accessibility is crucial; ensure focus is set correctly and provide a closing mechanism, such as a button, while using CSS <code>::backdrop</code> for styling modal backdrops.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42343089">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The dialog element on developer.mozilla.org has initiated a debate about the use of interactive HTML elements, such as file pickers and media players, with differing opinions on their consistency and predictability across browsers.</li>
<li>While some developers criticize the dialog element for being unstyled and not functioning like native popups, others value its semantic and accessibility benefits.</li>
<li>The discussion highlights challenges in maintaining design consistency and concerns about potential misuse by advertisers, indicating that the dialog element is a progressive step but still requires enhancements.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/orgs/organicmaps/discussions/9837">Maps.me co-founder tries to close down Organic Maps open-source fork</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Organic Maps has released the source code for its &quot;metaserver,&quot; which optimizes map download speeds by directing users to the best Content Delivery Network (CDN) servers based on their location.</li>
<li>The code, initially closed to prevent unauthorized forks, is now open under the MIT license, promoting transparency and community involvement.</li>
<li>The team is reconsidering the use of Cloudflare Workers to prevent vendor lock-in and has reverted unauthorized changes made by a contributor, emphasizing their commitment to privacy and transparency.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42343121">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Alexander Borsuk, co-founder of Maps.me, tried to close Organic Maps&#39; open-source fork by altering its MIT license and adding logging to a private repository.- Roman Tsisyk, another project maintainer, reversed these changes and made the repository public, leading to a conflict and the revocation of his permissions.- The incident underscores internal disagreements about the project&#39;s open-source nature, yet Organic Maps continues to be a widely used offline map application.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/Olshansk/postgres_for_everything">How to use Postgres for everything</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>&quot;Postgres for Everything&quot; is a repository that promotes the use of PostgreSQL, a popular open-source relational database, for a wide range of applications beyond traditional database tasks.- The repository invites contributions and tracks various innovative uses of PostgreSQL, including cron jobs, message queues, analytics, and more, highlighting its versatility.- The initiative includes 11 items related to Supabase, a platform that provides backend services using PostgreSQL, showcasing its integration and utility in modern application development.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42347606">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion emphasizes Postgres&#39; versatility in various applications but also points out limitations, such as handling null characters in strings and requiring custom SQL for skip-index scans.- Opinions vary on using Postgres for all purposes, with some cautioning against over-reliance on a single database for large teams and others praising its simplicity and reduced complexity.- Alternatives like Redis are mentioned, along with challenges in scaling and the importance of avoiding over-engineering in the early stages of a project.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.moment.dev/blog/lies-i-was-told-pt-1">Lies I was told about collab editing, Part 1: Algorithms for offline editing</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>In early 2024, research into collaborative editing systems for Moment&#39;s text editor highlighted challenges with offline editing, where popular algorithms like CRDTs (Conflict-free Replicated Data Types) and OT (Operational Transformation) often fail.- Offline editing increases direct conflicts, with 20-30% of these conflicts resulting in unacceptable outcomes, suggesting the issue is more of a user interface/user experience (UI/UX) challenge than an algorithmic one.- Researchers are now focusing on improving the user experience in offline editing, drawing parallels to how git handles document merging, which is a promising development.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42343953">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article addresses the challenges of collaborative editing, especially offline, and critiques current algorithms like Conflict-free Replicated Data Types (CRDTs) and Operational Transformation (OT) for not always yielding semantically meaningful results.- There is a consensus on the need for improved conflict resolution, potentially through user input or advanced tools like Large Language Models (LLMs), to handle semantic conflicts effectively.- The discussion also considers the role of User Interface/User Experience (UI/UX) solutions in enhancing the collaborative editing experience, highlighting that the issue extends beyond algorithms to understanding user intent.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://ollama.com/blog/structured-outputs">Structured Outputs with Ollama</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Ollama has introduced support for structured outputs, enabling models to generate outputs in a specific format using a JSON schema.</li>
<li>This feature is now available in the updated Ollama Python and JavaScript libraries, useful for tasks like data parsing from documents and images.</li>
<li>Users should update to the latest Ollama version and use the format parameter in cURL requests or libraries, with future updates promising performance enhancements and more format options.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42346344">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Ollama provides a method to generate structured data, such as JSON, from language models, with discussions on using GBNF grammars for more versatile output formats like XML or SQL.- Users debate the reliability of JSON outputs versus natural language, with insights into how language models (LLMs) generate text and the role of structured prompts.- Ollama&#39;s integration with llama.cpp is noted for simplifying model usage, though some view it as merely a wrapper, and the feature supports various models with differing accuracy levels.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0JouTsMQsEA">RollerCoaster Tycoon was the last of its kind [video]</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42346463">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>RollerCoaster Tycoon, developed primarily in assembly language by a small team, became a best-seller in 1999, showcasing a rare development style.</li>
<li>Fans suggest OpenRCT2 for enhanced features and compatibility, and Roller Coaster Tycoon Classic for modern devices, while alternatives like Parkitect and Planet Coaster provide varied experiences.</li>
<li>The video highlights the evolution of game development and the challenges small teams encounter when competing with larger studios, with indie successes like Minecraft illustrating the potential for small team achievements.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://source.washu.edu/2024/12/research-reveals-how-fructose-in-diet-enhances-tumor-growth/">Fructose in diet enhances tumor growth: research</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Fructose consumption has increased significantly over the last 50 years, primarily due to high-fructose corn syrup in beverages and processed foods.</li>
<li>Research from Washington University in St. Louis indicates that while fructose doesn&#39;t directly fuel tumors, the liver converts it into nutrients that support tumor growth in cancers such as melanoma, breast, and cervical cancer.</li>
<li>The study suggests potential new cancer treatments by exploring methods to prevent fructose from aiding tumor growth, possibly through dietary changes or pharmaceuticals, with partial funding from the National Institutes of Health (NIH).</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42343544">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Research from Washington University indicates that high fructose consumption may promote tumor growth by increasing circulating lipids, which are utilized by cancer cells for growth.- While fructose in fruits is typically safe due to additional nutrients, excessive intake from sources like high fructose corn syrup could be risky.- The study underscores the complexity of cancer metabolism and the potential influence of diet on cancer progression, though further research is necessary to fully comprehend these mechanisms.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/oils-for-unix/oils/wiki/The-Biggest-Shell-Programs-in-the-World">Biggest shell programs</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The page highlights significant shell programs, focusing on substantial hand-written scripts rather than those generated by tools like autoconf.- Notable entries include akinomyoga/ble.sh, a Bash Line Editor with 61K lines of code (LoC), and kalua, an OpenWRT addon with 56K source lines of code (SLoC).- The list provides insights into the complexity and diversity of shell scripting, featuring programs that utilize data structures and algorithms, typically exceeding 5,000 lines of code.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42346274">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion focuses on the complexities and challenges of using large shell scripts, such as issues with readability, error handling, and portability.- Users suggest considering alternatives like Python or AWK for complex tasks due to better maintainability, while tools like ShellCheck can help improve shell script quality.- The conversation highlights the balance between using shell scripts for quick tasks and opting for more robust programming languages for larger projects.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://dspy.ai/">DSPy – Programming–not prompting–LMs</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>DSPy is a framework designed for building modular AI systems using compositional Python code, focusing on improving language model (LM) outputs without relying solely on prompts.- It supports multiple large language model (LLM) providers like OpenAI, Anthropic, and Databricks, allowing users to describe AI behavior as code, facilitating easier iteration and optimization.- Originating from Stanford NLP, DSPy has a strong community presence on GitHub and Discord, contributing to open-source AI research and advancing program architectures and optimizers.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42343692">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>DSPy is a framework designed to optimize prompts for language models (LMs) by automating the selection of training data subsets, thus enhancing performance and minimizing manual adjustments.</li>
<li>It supports end-to-end training of large language model (LLM) programs, preventing the use of outdated prompts in code, and is particularly useful for tasks such as data extraction and summarization.</li>
<li>While some users find DSPy&#39;s complexity challenging, it is valued for its structured approach and features like assertions and suggestions that enforce output constraints.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="My second year without a job" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=My%20second%20year%20without%20a%20job&subheading=Saturday%2C%20December%207%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/12/07</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-07T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-12-06]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/12/06&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-12-06</h1>
<h2><a href="https://manuelmoreale.com/the-correct-amount-of-ads-is-zero">The correct amount of ads is zero</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Verge has introduced a subscription model with a paywalled version, offering benefits like full-text RSS feeds to subscribers.</li>
<li>The subscription aims to reduce ad exposure, but there is criticism that paying subscribers should not see any ads at all.</li>
<li>Concerns are raised about potential data selling to advertisers, suggesting that subscribers should not be subject to both ads and data monetization.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42334327">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The debate on ads in media centers around their necessity, with some viewing them as crucial for revenue diversification and cost reduction, while others advocate for an ad-free experience for paying subscribers.</li>
<li>Critics highlight privacy issues and the intrusive nature of online ads compared to traditional print ads, raising concerns about consumer experience and media integrity.</li>
<li>The discussion includes the sustainability of ad-supported models and explores alternative funding methods such as subscriptions or direct support through platforms like Patreon.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://addyo.substack.com/p/the-70-problem-hard-truths-about">The 70% problem: Hard truths about AI-assisted coding</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42336553">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>AI-assisted coding tools can rapidly generate code, similar to junior developers, but often require thorough review by experienced developers due to frequent mistakes.</li>
<li>While AI tools excel at handling repetitive tasks and offering initial code drafts, they struggle with complex problem-solving and creativity, limiting their ability to replace human programmers entirely.</li>
<li>The integration of AI tools into development workflows presents a challenge: enhancing learning and productivity without hindering the development of essential problem-solving skills.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://design-milk.com/portland-airport-grows-with-expansive-mass-timber-roof-canopy/">Portland airport grows with expansive mass timber roof canopy</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Portland Airport (PDX) has expanded its main terminal with a sustainable mass timber roof canopy, designed by ZGF, using locally sourced glulam Douglas Fir.</li>
<li>The nine-acre canopy aims to enhance airport capacity and passenger experience while reducing the carbon footprint, incorporating biophilic elements for a welcoming atmosphere.</li>
<li>This project sets a new standard for sustainable airport design, with completion anticipated in 2026.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42334323">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Portland airport has introduced a new mass timber roof canopy, which enhances natural light and raises the ceiling, as part of a multi-phase renovation project.</li>
<li>The design is appreciated for its aesthetics and improved acoustics, but some users report confusion with wayfinding.</li>
<li>The use of wood is considered a sustainable construction choice, though there are discussions about its impact on carbon emissions, drawing comparisons to other modern airports with natural themes.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.fabricatedknowledge.com/p/the-death-of-intel-when-boards-fail">Intel’s board, and an example of when boards and short-termism fail</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Pat Gelsinger&#39;s exit from Intel is portrayed as a firing rather than a retirement, emphasizing the board&#39;s failures and short-term focus over long-term strategy.- The board&#39;s lack of semiconductor expertise and focus on immediate shareholder value have been criticized, potentially harming Intel&#39;s long-term prospects and the U.S. semiconductor industry.- The board&#39;s failure to support Gelsinger&#39;s IDM 2.0 strategy suggests a shift towards selling company parts, which may benefit shareholders short-term but could damage Intel&#39;s future.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42334697">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Intel&#39;s board has faced criticism for lacking technical expertise and prioritizing short-term gains, which some believe has contributed to the company&#39;s recent struggles.</li>
<li>Pat Gelsinger, the current CEO, is viewed as capable but reportedly lacks sufficient support from the board, which has historically focused more on dividends and shareholder interests than on innovation.</li>
<li>There are calls for a cultural shift within Intel, emphasizing the need for better alignment with long-term goals to secure the company&#39;s future.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/trailbaseio/trailbase">Trailbase: Fast, single-file, open-source app server built using Rust and SQLite</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>TrailBase is an open-source application server designed for fast, type-safe APIs, utilizing Rust, SQLite, and V8, and is suitable for mobile, web, or desktop applications.</li>
<li>It offers sub-millisecond latencies, removing the need for dedicated caches, and supports various platforms with pre-built binaries and client packages available for Linux, MacOS, and multiple programming languages.</li>
<li>TrailBase is licensed under OSL-3.0, allowing it to be used as a framework without additional licensing requirements, and contributions from the community are encouraged.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42336207">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Trailbase is a fast, single-file, open-source application server developed using Rust and SQLite, which has initiated discussions about its security, particularly concerning SQL injection risks.- Users have suggested improvements like using prepared statements or tagged template strings to enhance the safety of SQL queries, and have compared Trailbase to similar projects like Pocketbase and Supabase.- Despite some concerns about documentation clarity and licensing debates, Trailbase has been positively received for its potential and respectful comparisons to other projects.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20241205391064/en/GitLab-Names-Bill-Staples-as-New-CEO">Gitlab names Bill Staples as new CEO</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>GitLab has appointed Bill Staples as the new CEO, with co-founder Sid Sijbrandij moving to Executive Chair of the Board due to health reasons.</li>
<li>Staples, formerly CEO at New Relic, brings extensive experience in developer platforms to GitLab, a prominent AI-powered DevSecOps platform.</li>
<li>GitLab serves over 10,000 customers, generates over $750 million in revenue, and is trusted by more than 40 million users, including over half of the Fortune 100 companies.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42333052">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>GitLab has appointed Bill Staples as the new CEO, succeeding Sid Sijbrandij, who is stepping down to focus on his cancer treatment.</li>
<li>The leadership change indicates GitLab&#39;s strategic shift from a developer-centric approach to targeting enterprise sales, with Staples having experience in preparing companies for acquisition.</li>
<li>The appointment has sparked discussions about GitLab&#39;s future, potential sale, and competition with GitHub, alongside user concerns about pricing and product focus.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.iaea.org/newscenter/pressreleases/update-263-iaea-director-general-statement-on-situation-in-ukraine">Ukraine&#39;s three nuclear power plants have restored electricity production</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Ukraine&#39;s nuclear power plants have resumed electricity production following recent grid attacks, highlighting the importance of a stable power supply for nuclear safety.</li>
<li>The International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) is actively monitoring the situation in Ukraine, underscoring its commitment to nuclear safety and security.</li>
<li>Equipment valued at over 14 million euros has been provided to Ukraine to bolster nuclear safety and security measures.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42337980">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Ukraine&#39;s nuclear power plants have resumed electricity production, demonstrating resilience despite the ongoing conflict.</li>
<li>Power outages are typically resolved within 48 hours, showcasing the efficiency of Ukraine&#39;s power grid management and repair capabilities.</li>
<li>The use of alternative solutions, such as solar inverter batteries, by residents and businesses highlights adaptability in maintaining operations during power disruptions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.vulnu.com/p/inside-exxonmobils-alleged-hack-for-hire-campaign-targeting-climate-activists">ExxonMobil&#39;s Alleged Hack-for-Hire Campaign Targeting Climate Activists</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>ExxonMobil is accused of orchestrating a hack-for-hire campaign, &quot;Fox Hunt,&quot; targeting over 500 climate activists and journalists using advanced cyber capabilities.</li>
<li>The operation allegedly involved phishing attacks and leaked emails to undermine environmental advocates and support Exxon’s legal strategies, despite the company&#39;s denial of involvement.</li>
<li>This case underscores the growing trend of digital warfare in corporate disputes, prompting FBI investigations and calls for stronger legal measures to combat such cyber operations.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42340346">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>ExxonMobil is accused of orchestrating a hack-for-hire campaign targeting climate activists and the organization Fight for the Future, which advocates for net neutrality.</li>
<li>The attack, initially perceived as random, was later identified as an attempt to access internal communications, prompting the organization to adopt a 3-month email retention policy for protection.</li>
<li>The incident underscores the necessity for accountability and stricter regulations on corporate misconduct, with potential links to a major American Internet Service Provider (ISP) or its lobbying group.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.kagi.com/kagi-teams">Kagi Teams</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Kagi for Teams, set to launch on December 5, 2024, provides businesses with a privacy-focused search and AI tool, emphasizing no ads, tracking, or data harvesting.</li>
<li>The service includes a premium search engine and universal AI access, with flexible pricing based on active users, offering Professional and Ultimate plans.</li>
<li>Kagi promises quick setup, available support, and significant return on investment (ROI) through faster research times, ensuring data privacy for businesses.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42339048">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Kagi Teams is a search engine praised for its ad-free, high-quality search results, offering a cleaner experience compared to Google.</li>
<li>Some users are willing to pay $120/year for Kagi, appreciating its ability to filter out ads and scams, but concerns exist over its use of Yandex, a Russian search engine with Kremlin ties.</li>
<li>Kagi also provides AI integrations and a team plan for businesses, though the Yandex association remains a significant concern for some users.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://kopiascsaba.hu/blog/teaching-elderly-people-to-use-android/">I spent a year building an Android course for the elderly</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author developed a video course to teach elderly individuals how to use Android smartphones, addressing common challenges such as intimidation by interfaces and lack of basic skills like scrolling or swiping.</li>
<li>The course includes a 400-page script, video recordings, and an Android app with exercises, initially hosted on Udemy and later moved to a dedicated website, &quot;Smartphone How-To.&quot;</li>
<li>Marketing the course is challenging due to the target audience&#39;s difficulties with online registration and payment, and the author seeks feedback for improvement.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42331660">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>An Android course was developed specifically for the elderly to assist with basic smartphone usage, receiving positive reviews on Udemy despite some challenges.- Feedback indicated issues such as cookie warnings and subscription confusion, with suggestions to simplify content and include popular apps like WhatsApp.- Future improvements may involve translations and addressing accessibility concerns to better support seniors in navigating smartphones and online resources.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/12/05/mckinsey-bribery-settlement-south-africa.html">McKinsey unit will pay $123M to settle claims it bribed South African officials</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A McKinsey &amp; Company subsidiary has agreed to pay $123 million to settle allegations of bribing South African officials, as reported by the U.S. Department of Justice.</li>
<li>The bribery scheme, involving McKinsey Africa, resulted in $85 million in profits through contracts with state-controlled utility companies.</li>
<li>Former McKinsey partner Vikas Sagar admitted guilt to conspiracy charges under the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act, and McKinsey Africa has agreed to a three-year deferred prosecution agreement, pledging to enhance compliance measures.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42332352">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>McKinsey has agreed to pay $123 million to settle allegations of bribing South African officials, highlighting concerns about corruption within consulting firms.</li>
<li>The settlement prompts discussions on the effectiveness of financial penalties as a deterrent and the accountability of large corporations.</li>
<li>The case underscores broader issues of corruption in business and government, with potential implications for international trade and regulation.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://huggingface.co/meta-llama/Llama-3.3-70B-Instruct">Llama-3.3-70B-Instruct</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42341388">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Meta has open-sourced Llama-3.3-70B-Instruct, a move to make AI more accessible and enhance their social platforms.</li>
<li>The model is competitive with Llama 3.2 405B and more cost-effective than GPT-4o, offering developers powerful tools for customization.</li>
<li>While the Llama models are open, they have commercial restrictions, indicating a strategic effort to challenge OpenAI&#39;s dominance and benefit the AI community.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://crackoverflow.com/docs/system_administration/containerization/install-docker-natively-on-android-phone-and-use-it-as-a-home-server/">Install postmarketOS on Android phone and use Docker as a home server</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The guide details installing Docker on a OnePlus 6T using postmarketOS, effectively converting it into a home server, but it erases all phone data.</li>
<li>Key requirements include a OnePlus 6 or 6T, Fastboot on a PC, and postmarketOS files, with steps involving enabling Developer Mode, flashing postmarketOS, and setting up SSH.</li>
<li>While this setup offers an alternative to a Raspberry Pi with an integrated screen and battery, it lacks Ethernet support and is limited to internal storage.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42340065">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article explores using postmarketOS, a Linux-based operating system, on Android phones to repurpose them as home servers with Docker, offering a more stable environment than Android.- It emphasizes the advantages of postmarketOS or Mobian for enhanced kernel security and support for older devices, such as the OnePlus 6/6T, while addressing concerns about battery life and continuous operation.- The discussion includes the limitations of using musl (a lightweight C standard library) instead of glibc (GNU C Library) and the innovative idea of utilizing old phones as servers.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://hackerherald.com/">Hacker Herald – like HN but with crowdsourced pics and subtitles</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author, along with former instructor Arnav and student Archis, has launched a project called Hacker Herald, a front end for Hacker News.- The project was developed during an online JavaScript programming course and aims to provide a visually appealing layout similar to popular newspaper sites.- The inclusion of visuals, such as images, is intended to enhance the storytelling experience by providing immediate context without needing to click through articles.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42338327">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Hacker Herald is a new project inspired by Hacker News, offering a newspaper-like layout with crowdsourced images and subtitles for tech news.</li>
<li>The project has received mixed feedback, with some users appreciating the visual appeal, while others prefer the simplicity of the original Hacker News format.</li>
<li>Concerns have been raised about image authenticity and privacy issues from hotlinking, with suggestions for improvements such as adding search, categories, and permalinks.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.ctvnews.ca/health/congo-government-says-it-s-on-alert-over-mystery-flu-like-disease-that-killed-dozens-1.7134550">Congo gov. says it&#39;s &#39;on alert&#39; over mystery flu-like disease that killed dozens</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42332129">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Congo government is on high alert due to a mysterious flu-like disease that has resulted in dozens of deaths, raising concerns about its nature and origin.</li>
<li>Experts are considering various possibilities, including it being an endemic disease, an emerging infectious disease, or a novel pathogen, with testing underway to identify the cause.</li>
<li>The affected area is known for malnutrition, which could worsen the impact, but there is currently no evidence of rapid or widespread transmission.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="The correct amount of ads is zero" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=The%20correct%20amount%20of%20ads%20is%20zero&subheading=Friday%2C%20December%206%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/12/06</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-06T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-12-05]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/12/05&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-12-05</h1>
<h2><a href="https://diataxis.fr/">Diátaxis – A systematic approach to technical documentation authoring</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Diátaxis is a systematic approach to technical documentation that focuses on user needs by categorizing content into four types: tutorials, how-to guides, technical reference, and explanation.</li>
<li>This method addresses issues related to content, style, and organization, benefiting both users and creators by enhancing documentation quality and accessibility.</li>
<li>Diátaxis has been successfully implemented in projects like Gatsby and Cloudflare, demonstrating its practical effectiveness in improving clarity and user accessibility.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42325011">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Diátaxis is a framework designed to enhance technical documentation by categorizing content into tutorials, how-to guides, reference materials, and explanations, each serving distinct user needs.</li>
<li>This approach is gaining popularity in tech writing as it aims to improve documentation quality by avoiding the pitfall of creating one-size-fits-all documents.</li>
<li>While the framework is beneficial, some experts advise maintaining flexibility to adapt to varying documentation requirements.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://smcleod.net/2024/12/bringing-k/v-context-quantisation-to-ollama/">Bringing K/V context quantisation to Ollama</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42323953">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The integration of K/V (Key/Value) context quantization into Ollama was a collaborative effort between the Ollama team and the community, taking approximately five months to complete.</li>
<li>Challenges were faced in merging the feature into the project, highlighting the complexities of contributing to large-scale projects.</li>
<li>The project underscores the dedication of hobbyists in AI development and includes discussions on various usage methods, such as GUI (Graphical User Interface) options and mobile compatibility, with tools like OpenWebUI and LibreChat being recommended.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://waymo.com/blog/2024/12/next-stop-miami/">Next stop: Miami</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Waymo One is set to expand its autonomous, all-electric ride-hailing service to Miami in 2026, using Jaguar I-PACEs.</li>
<li>The expansion is in partnership with Moove and follows successful tests in Miami&#39;s challenging weather conditions.</li>
<li>This move aligns with Miami&#39;s emphasis on sustainable and clean energy transportation, and the service will be accessible through the Waymo One app.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42328971">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Waymo is expanding its driverless car service to Miami, a city with challenging driving conditions, as part of its strategy to scale operations in various cities.- The expansion raises questions about Waymo&#39;s ability to handle Miami&#39;s unique challenges, including frequent flooding and aggressive driving behaviors.- Waymo partners with local companies to manage operations, focusing on its self-driving technology to address high costs and safety issues of human-driven taxis, aiming for a more efficient urban transportation solution.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.techdirt.com/2024/12/04/federal-court-says-dismantling-a-phone-to-install-firmware-isnt-a-search-even-if-was-done-to-facilitate-a-search/">Federal Court Says Dismantling a Phone to Install Firmware Isn&#39;t a &#39;Search&#39;</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The iPhone 6 is susceptible to the checkm8 exploit, which is a known security vulnerability.</li>
<li>Devices such as the iPhone XS and newer models are currently not affected by this exploit, indicating improved security measures in later models.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42329005">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A federal court decided that dismantling a phone to install firmware does not qualify as a &quot;search&quot; if data access is conducted with a valid warrant.- The government faced challenges accessing a device, leading them to send it for repair and firmware update, with a new warrant obtained before the actual data search.- This case underscores the complexities in legal interpretations and the difficulties in crafting clear headlines for technical legal matters.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.pgvecto.rs/vectorchord-store-400k-vectors-for-1-in-postgresql">VectorChord: Store 400k Vectors for $1 in PostgreSQL</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>VectorChord is a new PostgreSQL extension designed for efficient vector search, capable of storing 400,000 vectors for just $1, making it more cost-effective than competitors.- It utilizes IVF (Inverted File) and RaBitQ (Random Bit Quantization) techniques to enhance search speed and memory efficiency, making it suitable for handling large datasets.- VectorChord outperforms alternatives like Pinecone and pgvector in terms of both price and performance, offering scalable vector search with improved speed and precision for applications needing quick and accurate responses.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42324059">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>VectorChord has introduced a PostgreSQL extension that allows storing 400,000 vectors for a cost of $1, highlighting a cost-effective solution for vector storage.</li>
<li>Comparisons with Datastax&#39;s AstraDB reveal differences in replication strategies and associated costs, sparking discussions on performance and update handling.</li>
<li>The project plans to integrate features from pgvecto.rs and eventually phase out support for it, with users exploring the potential and limitations of VectorChord in vector database management.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/BTCUSD/">Bitcoin is over $100k</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42324263">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Bitcoin&#39;s recent surge past $100k has reignited debates on its value, with discussions focusing on its role as a speculative asset versus a store of value.</li>
<li>The rise has prompted conversations about wealth inequality, the environmental impact of cryptocurrency, and its potential as a decentralized financial tool.</li>
<li>Despite mixed opinions, Bitcoin&#39;s growth continues to draw attention, with predictions of further increases and warnings about its inherent volatility.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Diátaxis – A systematic approach to technical documentation authoring" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Di%C3%A1taxis%20%E2%80%93%20A%20systematic%20approach%20to%20technical%20documentation%20authoring&subheading=Thursday%2C%20December%205%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/12/05</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-05T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
