<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0"
>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 19:07:47 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/newsletter/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <copyright><![CDATA[2023 Sunghyun Cho]]></copyright>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-12-10]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/12/10&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-12-10</h1>
<h2><a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cp9nxee2r0do">What we know about CEO shooting suspect</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Luigi Mangione, a 26-year-old from a notable Baltimore family, has been charged with the murder of UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson in New York City.</li>
<li>Mangione was arrested in Pennsylvania with a ghost gun and a document hinting at a motive related to anger towards corporate America.</li>
<li>Despite his academic achievements and career as a data engineer, Mangione&#39;s social media suggests recent isolation from family and friends.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42370622">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The CEO shooting suspect&#39;s case has generated numerous theories, ranging from a deliberate plan to spread a message to mere incompetence and luck.- The suspect&#39;s behavior, including carrying evidence and appearing in public during a manhunt, has intensified public speculation.- The incident has sparked discussions on societal issues, particularly public frustration with the healthcare system and disparities in crime treatment based on victim status.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://twitter.com/itchio/status/1866239798924763227">This is not a joke, Funko just called my mom</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42371481">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Funko issued a takedown request targeting a specific page on itch.io, but it resulted in the temporary removal of the entire site, leading to public backlash.</li>
<li>Funko clarified that their intention was to target only a specific page, not the entire itch.io platform.</li>
<li>The incident has sparked discussions about the responsibility of companies and their partners in managing takedown requests effectively.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://treecalcul.us/">Tree Calculus</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Tree Calculus is a Turing-complete computational model with a single operator, allowing for program analysis, type checking, compilation, and optimization directly within the code.- It supports arbitrary type systems and gradual typing, enabling powerful Read-Eval-Print Loops (REPLs) and program deployment without external tools.- Its minimal syntax and semantics make it portable and easy to implement interpreters on any platform, suitable for modeling, formal specifications, and educational purposes.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42373437">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Tree Calculus is a programming language developed by Prof. Barry Jay, focusing on unlabeled trees and allowing introspection and manipulation of functions.</li>
<li>It is Turing complete, meaning it can perform any computation given enough time and resources, and offers unique features like function inversion, setting it apart from languages like Lisp or Forth.</li>
<li>The community is actively discussing its implications and potential applications, although there is some confusion regarding its presentation and purpose on the website treecalcul.us.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://trellis3d.github.io/">Trellis – 3D mesh generative model</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The post introduces a new 3D generation method using a unified Structured LATent (SLAT) representation, enhancing the creation of versatile and high-quality 3D assets.</li>
<li>The model, named TRELLIS, utilizes rectified flow transformers and is trained on a large dataset, outperforming existing methods in 3D generation.</li>
<li>The approach supports flexible output formats and local 3D editing, with plans to release the code, model, and data to the public.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42369476">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Trellis, a 3D mesh generative model, has generated mixed reactions due to its ability to produce high-quality assets, potentially shifting game development focus from graphics to storytelling.</li>
<li>While some express concern over the diminishing role of handmade artistry, others see potential for artists to adapt and use AI to enhance their work.</li>
<li>Trellis is recognized for its potential in prototyping and democratizing 3D modeling, despite current limitations like poor wireframe quality and challenges with certain shapes.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.savethearchive.com/">Save Music, Save the Archive</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Over 500 musicians are advocating for major labels to withdraw a $621 million lawsuit against the Internet Archive, a nonprofit cultural institution.</li>
<li>The musicians emphasize the need for fair compensation, protection of music legacies, and investment in living artists rather than supporting monopolistic practices.</li>
<li>They argue that the music industry&#39;s survival depends on prioritizing artists&#39; futures and preserving their works, urging public support through an open letter.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42373098">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Open source projects, such as Relisten, utilize the Internet Archive to store legally recorded concerts, aiding music fans and preserving cultural history.</li>
<li>The Internet Archive is facing legal challenges from major labels, particularly concerning projects like the Great 78 Project, which seeks to preserve historical recordings.</li>
<li>There is ongoing debate in the music industry about fair artist compensation, with discussions on copyright, streaming revenues, and alternative revenue models like direct sales and platforms such as Patreon.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://antirez.com/news/144">From where I left</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42378488">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The controversy centers on Redis changing its open-source license, causing discontent among contributors who feel betrayed by the move.- The new license is seen by some as complicating legal use, while others view it as essential to prevent exploitation by large corporations.- The emergence of Valkey, a Redis fork supported by major tech companies, and the return of Redis founder Salvatore Sanfilippo, are significant developments in the ongoing debate about open-source licensing and corporate influence.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://old.reddit.com/r/neovim/comments/1h7vhmg/bro_been_developing_his_2k_star_plugin_on_a/">Developer wrote 25k lines of Neovim plugin code using phone and touchscreen</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42374823">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A developer in Bangladesh wrote 25,000 lines of Neovim plugin code using only a phone and touchscreen, showcasing remarkable dedication and adaptability.</li>
<li>A fundraiser is being organized to provide him with a laptop, as laptops are costly in Bangladesh, highlighting the financial barriers faced by developers in developing countries.</li>
<li>The developer utilizes tools like Termius, tmux, and Vim on his phone, and his efforts have sparked discussions about the challenges of coding on a phone.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.bitsaboutmoney.com/archive/debanking-and-debunking/">Debanking (and Debunking?)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Debanking, the involuntary closure of bank accounts, is a contentious issue, particularly affecting crypto businesses, with concerns it may be used as a political tool.</li>
<li>The debate involves complex interactions between private and state actors, with some viewing debanking as necessary for risk management, while others see it as unfair and lacking due process.</li>
<li>Historical regulatory actions like Operation Choke Point, which pressured banks to sever ties with certain industries, are cited by critics as similar to current actions against crypto businesses, termed &quot;Choke Point 2.0.&quot;</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42371476">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Debanking involves banks closing accounts or denying services, often due to regulatory pressures such as Anti-Money Laundering (AML) laws, which aim to prevent illegal financial activities.</li>
<li>Critics highlight the lack of transparency and due process in debanking, which can unjustly impact individuals and businesses, limiting their economic participation.</li>
<li>The debate centers on whether banks should be required to offer basic services to everyone, regardless of perceived risks, and how this issue intersects with broader political and social concerns.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42377018">Double (YC W24) – Index Investing with 0% Expense Ratios</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Double is a financial platform that allows investment in over 50 stock market indexes with no expense ratios, charging a flat fee of $1/month for management, rebalancing, and tax-loss harvesting.</li>
<li>The platform offers direct indexing by purchasing individual stocks from popular indexes, providing customization and daily portfolio optimization, distinguishing itself from other robo-advisors.</li>
<li>Double has achieved $10 million in assets under management (AUM) and aims to disrupt the $100 billion/year ETF and mutual fund market by offering low-fee investment strategies.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42377018">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Double is an investment platform offering index investing with a flat fee of $1/month and 0% expense ratios, aiming to disrupt traditional ETF and mutual fund markets.- Founded by JJ and Mark, the platform manages over 50 stock market indexes and handles tasks like rebalancing and tax-loss harvesting, with $10M in assets under management.- Despite its innovative fee structure, there are concerns about Double&#39;s sustainability, security, and how it compares to established financial institutions like Vanguard and Fidelity.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="What we know about CEO shooting suspect" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=What%20we%20know%20about%20CEO%20shooting%20suspect&subheading=Tuesday%2C%20December%2010%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/12/10</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-10T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-12-09]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/12/09&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-12-09</h1>
<h2><a href="https://bsky.app/profile/itch.io/post/3lcu6h465bs2n">Itch.io Taken Down by Funko</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42363727">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Itch.io&#39;s domain was disabled due to a false fraud and phishing report by BrandShield concerning a fan page for a Funko Pop game.- The incident underscores issues with automated trademark enforcement and the lack of human oversight, as well as the slow response from the registrar, iwantmyname.- The situation has sparked user support for itch.io and criticism of the parties involved in the takedown.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://flatt.tech/research/posts/compromising-openwrt-supply-chain-sha256-collision/">Compromising OpenWrt Supply Chain</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A security engineer identified vulnerabilities in OpenWrt&#39;s firmware upgrade process, including command injection and SHA-256 hash collision issues.- The vulnerabilities allowed potential attackers to inject commands and create hash collisions, leading to the installation of malicious firmware.- The OpenWrt team promptly addressed and fixed these vulnerabilities, emphasizing the need for strong security in software supply chains.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42363102">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A vulnerability in OpenWrt&#39;s supply chain enabled targeted code execution without validation, posing a risk of backdoored builds.- The incident underscores the importance of reproducibility and transparency in software builds, similar to practices in Gentoo&#39;s ebuild repository.- OpenWrt&#39;s swift response highlights the efficiency of open-source projects in addressing security issues compared to closed-source alternatives.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://bcantrill.dtrace.org/2024/12/08/why-gelsinger-was-wrong-for-intel/">Pat Gelsinger was wrong for Intel</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Pat Gelsinger, despite his technical expertise and managerial skills, was deemed unsuitable as Intel&#39;s CEO due to his inability to address the company&#39;s cultural and strategic challenges.</li>
<li>His leadership decisions, such as maintaining dividends and aggressive advertising, were criticized for reflecting a peacetime approach rather than the necessary wartime leadership.</li>
<li>Gelsinger&#39;s management of Intel&#39;s Foundry Services and the termination of the Tofino project, a promising programmable switch silicon, were seen as significant missteps, leaving Intel&#39;s cultural issues unresolved.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42361955">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Pat Gelsinger, CEO of Intel, faced challenges including 10nm production delays and competition from TSMC, leading to significant stock drops despite strategic investments in manufacturing facilities.</li>
<li>Critics suggest that Intel&#39;s board, composed mainly of non-technical members, may be a core issue, questioning whether Gelsinger&#39;s technical expertise or an outsider is needed to resolve Intel&#39;s problems.</li>
<li>The ongoing debate centers on whether Gelsinger&#39;s strategies were appropriate or if the board&#39;s composition and decisions are hindering Intel&#39;s progress.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://json5.org/">JSON5 – JSON for Humans</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>JSON5, an extension of JSON, is designed for easier manual editing, making it ideal for configuration files but not suitable for machine communication.</li>
<li>Since its launch in 2012, JSON5 has gained significant popularity, with over 65 million downloads weekly, and is utilized by major projects like Chromium and Next.js.</li>
<li>JSON5 is a superset of JSON, incorporating ECMAScript 5.1 features, allowing for flexible syntax, and is compatible with ES5, with a JavaScript library available for parsing and serialization.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42360681">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>JSON5 is an extension of JSON designed to be more human-friendly by allowing features such as comments and trailing commas.</li>
<li>There is a debate on whether JSON should remain simple or evolve with additional features, as seen with JSON5, which is not an official update but an alternative format.</li>
<li>Some suggest using other formats like TOML or HJSON for more human-readable configurations, highlighting the ongoing discussion about JSON&#39;s evolution.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.france24.com/en/live-news/20241204-uk-bans-daytime-tv-ads-for-cereals-muffins-and-burgers">UK bans daytime TV ads for cereals, muffins and burgers</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The UK government is implementing a ban on daytime TV advertisements for sugary and &quot;less healthy&quot; foods, such as cereals, muffins, and burgers, to address child obesity.</li>
<li>Starting next October, these ads will only be allowed to air after 9:00 pm, with the goal of preventing 20,000 cases of childhood obesity each year.</li>
<li>Health Secretary Wes Streeting highlighted the importance of stopping the targeting of children with junk food advertisements.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42359836">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The UK has implemented a ban on daytime TV advertisements for junk food, including cereals, muffins, and burgers, as a measure to combat childhood obesity.</li>
<li>Critics argue that the ban is insufficient, as children are more influenced by online ads on platforms like YouTube and TikTok, which are not included in the ban.</li>
<li>The debate persists on whether the government should enforce existing laws and regulate online ads targeting children or if parents should take more responsibility in protecting children from harmful advertising.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://mastodon.social/@kiwix/113622081750449356">Hetzner has decided to cancel our account and terminate all servers.</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42365295">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Hetzner&#39;s account cancellation and server termination have prompted discussions on the necessity of backups and disaster recovery plans.</li>
<li>Users shared experiences of Hetzner&#39;s strict Terms of Service (ToS) enforcement, including immediate server shutdowns for violations, raising concerns about cloud provider reliability.</li>
<li>The debate emphasized the risks of depending on a single provider and the importance of using multiple providers for backups to ensure data security.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.google/technology/research/google-willow-quantum-chip/">Willow, Our Quantum Chip</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Google has introduced Willow, a quantum chip that marks a significant advancement in quantum error correction and computation speed.- Willow demonstrated its capability by performing a computation in under five minutes, a task that would take a supercomputer 10 septillion years, indicating its potential to tackle complex problems beyond classical computers.- This development is pivotal for the future of commercially viable quantum computers, with implications for revolutionizing industries such as medicine, energy, and artificial intelligence (AI).</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42367649">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Google&#39;s announcement of the quantum chip, Willow, featuring over 100 qubits with stability, marks a significant milestone in quantum computing.- This development could influence AI and data security, as quantum computing poses challenges to traditional encryption methods.- Despite the achievement, practical applications like Shor&#39;s algorithm require a much higher number of qubits, leading to mixed reactions regarding the chip&#39;s immediate impact.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://sora.com/">OpenAI: Sora</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42368604">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>OpenAI&#39;s Sora video generation tool is receiving mixed reviews due to challenges in creating precise content, as current AI technology struggles with detailed prompts and motion accuracy.</li>
<li>The tool is not yet available in the EU, and its release has faced server issues, affecting user experience.</li>
<li>While some users appreciate the novelty and potential of AI-generated content, there are concerns about the quality and pricing structure, with some noting it lags behind competitors.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Itch.io Taken Down by Funko" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Itch.io%20Taken%20Down%20by%20Funko&subheading=Monday%2C%20December%209%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/12/09</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-09T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-12-08]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/12/08&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-12-08</h1>
<h2><a href="https://nyxt.atlas.engineer/">Nyxt: The Hacker&#39;s Browser</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Nyxt is a browser designed for advanced users, emphasizing keyboard navigation and efficiency in online information analysis and extraction.</li>
<li>It features powerful tools like link hinting, Jump Headings for document navigation, and fuzzy search for easy tab management and command execution.</li>
<li>Additional functionalities include a built-in REPL (Read-Eval-Print Loop) for programmability, smart bookmark search, customizable autofills, clipboard history, and a tree-based history for tracking visited pages.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42354691">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Nyxt is a browser that integrates AI and semantic tools, aiming to enhance user experience by functioning as a &quot;second brain,&quot; though some users are skeptical about its AI capabilities and performance impact.</li>
<li>Written in Common Lisp, Nyxt is designed to be highly extensible like Emacs but does not support WebExtensions, limiting compatibility with popular extensions such as uBlock Origin.</li>
<li>Despite unique features like a tree-based history and keyboard-driven workflows, its practicality is debated compared to browsers like qutebrowser and Firefox; it is available on Linux, with unofficial support for BSD, macOS, and Windows.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://apnews.com/article/syria-assad-sweida-daraa-homs-hts-qatar-7f65823bbf0a7bd331109e8dff419430">Syrian government falls in end to 50-year rule of Assad family</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42355364">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Assad family&#39;s 50-year rule in Syria has ended, indicating a weakened state of their main supporters, Russia and Iran, who are engaged in other conflicts.</li>
<li>The power vacuum in Syria has led to a complex situation with multiple factions competing for control, creating uncertainty about the country&#39;s future.</li>
<li>The fall of Assad may contribute to regional instability and have broader implications for global politics, including the conflict in Ukraine.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.infochunk.com/schannel/index.html">Reverse engineering the Sega Channel game image file format</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Sega Channel was a pioneering games-on-demand service for the Sega Genesis, active from 1994 to 1998, offering around 50 games monthly.- In 2024, a user discovered a Sega Channel game image CD from 1996, leading to efforts in reverse engineering to extract and preserve its data.- The project successfully decoded exclusive games, emphasizing the role of community efforts and reverse engineering in preserving gaming history.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42353907">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Sega Channel was an innovative 1990s service that allowed users to download games via cable TV, functioning similarly to Teletext with a continuous data loop.</li>
<li>It was a precursor to modern digital game distribution, offering a rotating selection of games for a subscription fee, despite technical challenges and limited reach.</li>
<li>The service required special hardware and used satellite transmission to cable headends, but was known for its unreliability in certain areas.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://apnews.com/article/notre-dame-paris-latest-e50813cf016f08607c20ab115bc4b153">Notre Dame Cathedral reopens</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42353215">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Notre Dame Cathedral has reopened, restored to its original medieval appearance with modern updates, such as a new spire.</li>
<li>The restoration focused on reflecting the cathedral&#39;s initial design rather than its state before the 2018 fire, earning praise for craftsmanship and traditional techniques.</li>
<li>The project has sparked discussions on balancing historical authenticity with modern elements, drawing significant attention to Notre Dame&#39;s cultural and historical importance.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.wsj.com/tech/cybersecurity/hacking-brian-krebs-snowflake-waifu-49b87fce">Brian Krebs Investigates Internet&#39;s Most Vicious Hackers–From a Secret Location</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42354602">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Brian Krebs, a well-known cybersecurity journalist, is noted for his investigations into hacking activities, including exposing a significant cellphone tracking flaw in 2018.</li>
<li>The article discusses the ease with which young hackers can learn skills through online communities, highlighting the accessibility of hacking knowledge.</li>
<li>It also addresses the risks hackers face, often for minimal financial reward, emphasizing the importance and challenges of the cybersecurity field.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.atlantanewsfirst.com/2024/12/03/airline-informant-received-thousands-passenger-cash-seizures/">Airline informant received thousands from passenger cash seizures</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42354580">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>An airline informant received financial incentives from cash seizures of passengers, raising concerns about potential civil rights violations.</li>
<li>The DEA&#39;s &quot;consensual&quot; searches at airports, often criticized for being based on weak criteria, have been suspended following a Justice Department Inspector General&#39;s report.</li>
<li>Critics argue that civil asset forfeiture is unconstitutional and advocate for systemic reforms to prevent law enforcement abuse.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://news.mit.edu/2024/study-browsing-negative-content-online-makes-mental-health-struggles-worse-1205">Browsing negative content online makes mental health struggles worse: Study</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>MIT researchers have created a web plug-in named &quot;Digital Diet&quot; to assist users in making informed choices about online content to safeguard their mental health.</li>
<li>The tool employs natural language processing (NLP) to evaluate web pages based on emotion, knowledge, and actionability, steering users towards more positive content.</li>
<li>The research underscores the two-way relationship between online behavior and mental health, with findings published in Nature Human Behavior.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42353944">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A study indicates that exposure to negative online content can exacerbate mental health issues, contributing to feelings of anxiety and helplessness.- Managing online consumption is crucial, as constant exposure to negative information can significantly impact thoughts and emotions.- While staying informed is important for societal change, many find that reducing exposure to negative news and focusing on personal well-being can provide relief.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Nyxt: The Hacker's Browser" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Nyxt%3A%20The%20Hacker's%20Browser&subheading=Sunday%2C%20December%208%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/12/08</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-08T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-12-07]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/12/07&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-12-07</h1>
<h2><a href="https://shilin.ca/my-second-year-without-job/">My second year without a job</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42344002">Reactions</a></h3>
<h2><a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML/Element/dialog">: The Dialog Element</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The HTML `` element is used to create dialog boxes, which can be modal (pausing page interaction) or non-modal (allowing interaction).</li>
<li>JavaScript methods <code>.showModal()</code> and <code>.show()</code> are used to display modal and non-modal dialogs, respectively, while <code>.close()</code> is used to close them.</li>
<li>Accessibility is crucial; ensure focus is set correctly and provide a closing mechanism, such as a button, while using CSS <code>::backdrop</code> for styling modal backdrops.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42343089">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The dialog element on developer.mozilla.org has initiated a debate about the use of interactive HTML elements, such as file pickers and media players, with differing opinions on their consistency and predictability across browsers.</li>
<li>While some developers criticize the dialog element for being unstyled and not functioning like native popups, others value its semantic and accessibility benefits.</li>
<li>The discussion highlights challenges in maintaining design consistency and concerns about potential misuse by advertisers, indicating that the dialog element is a progressive step but still requires enhancements.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/orgs/organicmaps/discussions/9837">Maps.me co-founder tries to close down Organic Maps open-source fork</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Organic Maps has released the source code for its &quot;metaserver,&quot; which optimizes map download speeds by directing users to the best Content Delivery Network (CDN) servers based on their location.</li>
<li>The code, initially closed to prevent unauthorized forks, is now open under the MIT license, promoting transparency and community involvement.</li>
<li>The team is reconsidering the use of Cloudflare Workers to prevent vendor lock-in and has reverted unauthorized changes made by a contributor, emphasizing their commitment to privacy and transparency.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42343121">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Alexander Borsuk, co-founder of Maps.me, tried to close Organic Maps&#39; open-source fork by altering its MIT license and adding logging to a private repository.- Roman Tsisyk, another project maintainer, reversed these changes and made the repository public, leading to a conflict and the revocation of his permissions.- The incident underscores internal disagreements about the project&#39;s open-source nature, yet Organic Maps continues to be a widely used offline map application.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/Olshansk/postgres_for_everything">How to use Postgres for everything</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>&quot;Postgres for Everything&quot; is a repository that promotes the use of PostgreSQL, a popular open-source relational database, for a wide range of applications beyond traditional database tasks.- The repository invites contributions and tracks various innovative uses of PostgreSQL, including cron jobs, message queues, analytics, and more, highlighting its versatility.- The initiative includes 11 items related to Supabase, a platform that provides backend services using PostgreSQL, showcasing its integration and utility in modern application development.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42347606">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion emphasizes Postgres&#39; versatility in various applications but also points out limitations, such as handling null characters in strings and requiring custom SQL for skip-index scans.- Opinions vary on using Postgres for all purposes, with some cautioning against over-reliance on a single database for large teams and others praising its simplicity and reduced complexity.- Alternatives like Redis are mentioned, along with challenges in scaling and the importance of avoiding over-engineering in the early stages of a project.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.moment.dev/blog/lies-i-was-told-pt-1">Lies I was told about collab editing, Part 1: Algorithms for offline editing</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>In early 2024, research into collaborative editing systems for Moment&#39;s text editor highlighted challenges with offline editing, where popular algorithms like CRDTs (Conflict-free Replicated Data Types) and OT (Operational Transformation) often fail.- Offline editing increases direct conflicts, with 20-30% of these conflicts resulting in unacceptable outcomes, suggesting the issue is more of a user interface/user experience (UI/UX) challenge than an algorithmic one.- Researchers are now focusing on improving the user experience in offline editing, drawing parallels to how git handles document merging, which is a promising development.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42343953">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article addresses the challenges of collaborative editing, especially offline, and critiques current algorithms like Conflict-free Replicated Data Types (CRDTs) and Operational Transformation (OT) for not always yielding semantically meaningful results.- There is a consensus on the need for improved conflict resolution, potentially through user input or advanced tools like Large Language Models (LLMs), to handle semantic conflicts effectively.- The discussion also considers the role of User Interface/User Experience (UI/UX) solutions in enhancing the collaborative editing experience, highlighting that the issue extends beyond algorithms to understanding user intent.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://ollama.com/blog/structured-outputs">Structured Outputs with Ollama</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Ollama has introduced support for structured outputs, enabling models to generate outputs in a specific format using a JSON schema.</li>
<li>This feature is now available in the updated Ollama Python and JavaScript libraries, useful for tasks like data parsing from documents and images.</li>
<li>Users should update to the latest Ollama version and use the format parameter in cURL requests or libraries, with future updates promising performance enhancements and more format options.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42346344">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Ollama provides a method to generate structured data, such as JSON, from language models, with discussions on using GBNF grammars for more versatile output formats like XML or SQL.- Users debate the reliability of JSON outputs versus natural language, with insights into how language models (LLMs) generate text and the role of structured prompts.- Ollama&#39;s integration with llama.cpp is noted for simplifying model usage, though some view it as merely a wrapper, and the feature supports various models with differing accuracy levels.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0JouTsMQsEA">RollerCoaster Tycoon was the last of its kind [video]</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42346463">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>RollerCoaster Tycoon, developed primarily in assembly language by a small team, became a best-seller in 1999, showcasing a rare development style.</li>
<li>Fans suggest OpenRCT2 for enhanced features and compatibility, and Roller Coaster Tycoon Classic for modern devices, while alternatives like Parkitect and Planet Coaster provide varied experiences.</li>
<li>The video highlights the evolution of game development and the challenges small teams encounter when competing with larger studios, with indie successes like Minecraft illustrating the potential for small team achievements.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://source.washu.edu/2024/12/research-reveals-how-fructose-in-diet-enhances-tumor-growth/">Fructose in diet enhances tumor growth: research</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Fructose consumption has increased significantly over the last 50 years, primarily due to high-fructose corn syrup in beverages and processed foods.</li>
<li>Research from Washington University in St. Louis indicates that while fructose doesn&#39;t directly fuel tumors, the liver converts it into nutrients that support tumor growth in cancers such as melanoma, breast, and cervical cancer.</li>
<li>The study suggests potential new cancer treatments by exploring methods to prevent fructose from aiding tumor growth, possibly through dietary changes or pharmaceuticals, with partial funding from the National Institutes of Health (NIH).</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42343544">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Research from Washington University indicates that high fructose consumption may promote tumor growth by increasing circulating lipids, which are utilized by cancer cells for growth.- While fructose in fruits is typically safe due to additional nutrients, excessive intake from sources like high fructose corn syrup could be risky.- The study underscores the complexity of cancer metabolism and the potential influence of diet on cancer progression, though further research is necessary to fully comprehend these mechanisms.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/oils-for-unix/oils/wiki/The-Biggest-Shell-Programs-in-the-World">Biggest shell programs</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The page highlights significant shell programs, focusing on substantial hand-written scripts rather than those generated by tools like autoconf.- Notable entries include akinomyoga/ble.sh, a Bash Line Editor with 61K lines of code (LoC), and kalua, an OpenWRT addon with 56K source lines of code (SLoC).- The list provides insights into the complexity and diversity of shell scripting, featuring programs that utilize data structures and algorithms, typically exceeding 5,000 lines of code.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42346274">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion focuses on the complexities and challenges of using large shell scripts, such as issues with readability, error handling, and portability.- Users suggest considering alternatives like Python or AWK for complex tasks due to better maintainability, while tools like ShellCheck can help improve shell script quality.- The conversation highlights the balance between using shell scripts for quick tasks and opting for more robust programming languages for larger projects.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://dspy.ai/">DSPy – Programming–not prompting–LMs</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>DSPy is a framework designed for building modular AI systems using compositional Python code, focusing on improving language model (LM) outputs without relying solely on prompts.- It supports multiple large language model (LLM) providers like OpenAI, Anthropic, and Databricks, allowing users to describe AI behavior as code, facilitating easier iteration and optimization.- Originating from Stanford NLP, DSPy has a strong community presence on GitHub and Discord, contributing to open-source AI research and advancing program architectures and optimizers.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42343692">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>DSPy is a framework designed to optimize prompts for language models (LMs) by automating the selection of training data subsets, thus enhancing performance and minimizing manual adjustments.</li>
<li>It supports end-to-end training of large language model (LLM) programs, preventing the use of outdated prompts in code, and is particularly useful for tasks such as data extraction and summarization.</li>
<li>While some users find DSPy&#39;s complexity challenging, it is valued for its structured approach and features like assertions and suggestions that enforce output constraints.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="My second year without a job" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=My%20second%20year%20without%20a%20job&subheading=Saturday%2C%20December%207%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/12/07</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-07T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-12-06]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/12/06&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-12-06</h1>
<h2><a href="https://manuelmoreale.com/the-correct-amount-of-ads-is-zero">The correct amount of ads is zero</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Verge has introduced a subscription model with a paywalled version, offering benefits like full-text RSS feeds to subscribers.</li>
<li>The subscription aims to reduce ad exposure, but there is criticism that paying subscribers should not see any ads at all.</li>
<li>Concerns are raised about potential data selling to advertisers, suggesting that subscribers should not be subject to both ads and data monetization.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42334327">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The debate on ads in media centers around their necessity, with some viewing them as crucial for revenue diversification and cost reduction, while others advocate for an ad-free experience for paying subscribers.</li>
<li>Critics highlight privacy issues and the intrusive nature of online ads compared to traditional print ads, raising concerns about consumer experience and media integrity.</li>
<li>The discussion includes the sustainability of ad-supported models and explores alternative funding methods such as subscriptions or direct support through platforms like Patreon.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://addyo.substack.com/p/the-70-problem-hard-truths-about">The 70% problem: Hard truths about AI-assisted coding</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42336553">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>AI-assisted coding tools can rapidly generate code, similar to junior developers, but often require thorough review by experienced developers due to frequent mistakes.</li>
<li>While AI tools excel at handling repetitive tasks and offering initial code drafts, they struggle with complex problem-solving and creativity, limiting their ability to replace human programmers entirely.</li>
<li>The integration of AI tools into development workflows presents a challenge: enhancing learning and productivity without hindering the development of essential problem-solving skills.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://design-milk.com/portland-airport-grows-with-expansive-mass-timber-roof-canopy/">Portland airport grows with expansive mass timber roof canopy</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Portland Airport (PDX) has expanded its main terminal with a sustainable mass timber roof canopy, designed by ZGF, using locally sourced glulam Douglas Fir.</li>
<li>The nine-acre canopy aims to enhance airport capacity and passenger experience while reducing the carbon footprint, incorporating biophilic elements for a welcoming atmosphere.</li>
<li>This project sets a new standard for sustainable airport design, with completion anticipated in 2026.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42334323">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Portland airport has introduced a new mass timber roof canopy, which enhances natural light and raises the ceiling, as part of a multi-phase renovation project.</li>
<li>The design is appreciated for its aesthetics and improved acoustics, but some users report confusion with wayfinding.</li>
<li>The use of wood is considered a sustainable construction choice, though there are discussions about its impact on carbon emissions, drawing comparisons to other modern airports with natural themes.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.fabricatedknowledge.com/p/the-death-of-intel-when-boards-fail">Intel’s board, and an example of when boards and short-termism fail</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Pat Gelsinger&#39;s exit from Intel is portrayed as a firing rather than a retirement, emphasizing the board&#39;s failures and short-term focus over long-term strategy.- The board&#39;s lack of semiconductor expertise and focus on immediate shareholder value have been criticized, potentially harming Intel&#39;s long-term prospects and the U.S. semiconductor industry.- The board&#39;s failure to support Gelsinger&#39;s IDM 2.0 strategy suggests a shift towards selling company parts, which may benefit shareholders short-term but could damage Intel&#39;s future.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42334697">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Intel&#39;s board has faced criticism for lacking technical expertise and prioritizing short-term gains, which some believe has contributed to the company&#39;s recent struggles.</li>
<li>Pat Gelsinger, the current CEO, is viewed as capable but reportedly lacks sufficient support from the board, which has historically focused more on dividends and shareholder interests than on innovation.</li>
<li>There are calls for a cultural shift within Intel, emphasizing the need for better alignment with long-term goals to secure the company&#39;s future.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/trailbaseio/trailbase">Trailbase: Fast, single-file, open-source app server built using Rust and SQLite</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>TrailBase is an open-source application server designed for fast, type-safe APIs, utilizing Rust, SQLite, and V8, and is suitable for mobile, web, or desktop applications.</li>
<li>It offers sub-millisecond latencies, removing the need for dedicated caches, and supports various platforms with pre-built binaries and client packages available for Linux, MacOS, and multiple programming languages.</li>
<li>TrailBase is licensed under OSL-3.0, allowing it to be used as a framework without additional licensing requirements, and contributions from the community are encouraged.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42336207">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Trailbase is a fast, single-file, open-source application server developed using Rust and SQLite, which has initiated discussions about its security, particularly concerning SQL injection risks.- Users have suggested improvements like using prepared statements or tagged template strings to enhance the safety of SQL queries, and have compared Trailbase to similar projects like Pocketbase and Supabase.- Despite some concerns about documentation clarity and licensing debates, Trailbase has been positively received for its potential and respectful comparisons to other projects.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20241205391064/en/GitLab-Names-Bill-Staples-as-New-CEO">Gitlab names Bill Staples as new CEO</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>GitLab has appointed Bill Staples as the new CEO, with co-founder Sid Sijbrandij moving to Executive Chair of the Board due to health reasons.</li>
<li>Staples, formerly CEO at New Relic, brings extensive experience in developer platforms to GitLab, a prominent AI-powered DevSecOps platform.</li>
<li>GitLab serves over 10,000 customers, generates over $750 million in revenue, and is trusted by more than 40 million users, including over half of the Fortune 100 companies.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42333052">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>GitLab has appointed Bill Staples as the new CEO, succeeding Sid Sijbrandij, who is stepping down to focus on his cancer treatment.</li>
<li>The leadership change indicates GitLab&#39;s strategic shift from a developer-centric approach to targeting enterprise sales, with Staples having experience in preparing companies for acquisition.</li>
<li>The appointment has sparked discussions about GitLab&#39;s future, potential sale, and competition with GitHub, alongside user concerns about pricing and product focus.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.iaea.org/newscenter/pressreleases/update-263-iaea-director-general-statement-on-situation-in-ukraine">Ukraine&#39;s three nuclear power plants have restored electricity production</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Ukraine&#39;s nuclear power plants have resumed electricity production following recent grid attacks, highlighting the importance of a stable power supply for nuclear safety.</li>
<li>The International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) is actively monitoring the situation in Ukraine, underscoring its commitment to nuclear safety and security.</li>
<li>Equipment valued at over 14 million euros has been provided to Ukraine to bolster nuclear safety and security measures.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42337980">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Ukraine&#39;s nuclear power plants have resumed electricity production, demonstrating resilience despite the ongoing conflict.</li>
<li>Power outages are typically resolved within 48 hours, showcasing the efficiency of Ukraine&#39;s power grid management and repair capabilities.</li>
<li>The use of alternative solutions, such as solar inverter batteries, by residents and businesses highlights adaptability in maintaining operations during power disruptions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.vulnu.com/p/inside-exxonmobils-alleged-hack-for-hire-campaign-targeting-climate-activists">ExxonMobil&#39;s Alleged Hack-for-Hire Campaign Targeting Climate Activists</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>ExxonMobil is accused of orchestrating a hack-for-hire campaign, &quot;Fox Hunt,&quot; targeting over 500 climate activists and journalists using advanced cyber capabilities.</li>
<li>The operation allegedly involved phishing attacks and leaked emails to undermine environmental advocates and support Exxon’s legal strategies, despite the company&#39;s denial of involvement.</li>
<li>This case underscores the growing trend of digital warfare in corporate disputes, prompting FBI investigations and calls for stronger legal measures to combat such cyber operations.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42340346">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>ExxonMobil is accused of orchestrating a hack-for-hire campaign targeting climate activists and the organization Fight for the Future, which advocates for net neutrality.</li>
<li>The attack, initially perceived as random, was later identified as an attempt to access internal communications, prompting the organization to adopt a 3-month email retention policy for protection.</li>
<li>The incident underscores the necessity for accountability and stricter regulations on corporate misconduct, with potential links to a major American Internet Service Provider (ISP) or its lobbying group.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.kagi.com/kagi-teams">Kagi Teams</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Kagi for Teams, set to launch on December 5, 2024, provides businesses with a privacy-focused search and AI tool, emphasizing no ads, tracking, or data harvesting.</li>
<li>The service includes a premium search engine and universal AI access, with flexible pricing based on active users, offering Professional and Ultimate plans.</li>
<li>Kagi promises quick setup, available support, and significant return on investment (ROI) through faster research times, ensuring data privacy for businesses.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42339048">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Kagi Teams is a search engine praised for its ad-free, high-quality search results, offering a cleaner experience compared to Google.</li>
<li>Some users are willing to pay $120/year for Kagi, appreciating its ability to filter out ads and scams, but concerns exist over its use of Yandex, a Russian search engine with Kremlin ties.</li>
<li>Kagi also provides AI integrations and a team plan for businesses, though the Yandex association remains a significant concern for some users.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://kopiascsaba.hu/blog/teaching-elderly-people-to-use-android/">I spent a year building an Android course for the elderly</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author developed a video course to teach elderly individuals how to use Android smartphones, addressing common challenges such as intimidation by interfaces and lack of basic skills like scrolling or swiping.</li>
<li>The course includes a 400-page script, video recordings, and an Android app with exercises, initially hosted on Udemy and later moved to a dedicated website, &quot;Smartphone How-To.&quot;</li>
<li>Marketing the course is challenging due to the target audience&#39;s difficulties with online registration and payment, and the author seeks feedback for improvement.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42331660">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>An Android course was developed specifically for the elderly to assist with basic smartphone usage, receiving positive reviews on Udemy despite some challenges.- Feedback indicated issues such as cookie warnings and subscription confusion, with suggestions to simplify content and include popular apps like WhatsApp.- Future improvements may involve translations and addressing accessibility concerns to better support seniors in navigating smartphones and online resources.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.cnbc.com/2024/12/05/mckinsey-bribery-settlement-south-africa.html">McKinsey unit will pay $123M to settle claims it bribed South African officials</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A McKinsey &amp; Company subsidiary has agreed to pay $123 million to settle allegations of bribing South African officials, as reported by the U.S. Department of Justice.</li>
<li>The bribery scheme, involving McKinsey Africa, resulted in $85 million in profits through contracts with state-controlled utility companies.</li>
<li>Former McKinsey partner Vikas Sagar admitted guilt to conspiracy charges under the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act, and McKinsey Africa has agreed to a three-year deferred prosecution agreement, pledging to enhance compliance measures.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42332352">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>McKinsey has agreed to pay $123 million to settle allegations of bribing South African officials, highlighting concerns about corruption within consulting firms.</li>
<li>The settlement prompts discussions on the effectiveness of financial penalties as a deterrent and the accountability of large corporations.</li>
<li>The case underscores broader issues of corruption in business and government, with potential implications for international trade and regulation.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://huggingface.co/meta-llama/Llama-3.3-70B-Instruct">Llama-3.3-70B-Instruct</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42341388">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Meta has open-sourced Llama-3.3-70B-Instruct, a move to make AI more accessible and enhance their social platforms.</li>
<li>The model is competitive with Llama 3.2 405B and more cost-effective than GPT-4o, offering developers powerful tools for customization.</li>
<li>While the Llama models are open, they have commercial restrictions, indicating a strategic effort to challenge OpenAI&#39;s dominance and benefit the AI community.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://crackoverflow.com/docs/system_administration/containerization/install-docker-natively-on-android-phone-and-use-it-as-a-home-server/">Install postmarketOS on Android phone and use Docker as a home server</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The guide details installing Docker on a OnePlus 6T using postmarketOS, effectively converting it into a home server, but it erases all phone data.</li>
<li>Key requirements include a OnePlus 6 or 6T, Fastboot on a PC, and postmarketOS files, with steps involving enabling Developer Mode, flashing postmarketOS, and setting up SSH.</li>
<li>While this setup offers an alternative to a Raspberry Pi with an integrated screen and battery, it lacks Ethernet support and is limited to internal storage.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42340065">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The article explores using postmarketOS, a Linux-based operating system, on Android phones to repurpose them as home servers with Docker, offering a more stable environment than Android.- It emphasizes the advantages of postmarketOS or Mobian for enhanced kernel security and support for older devices, such as the OnePlus 6/6T, while addressing concerns about battery life and continuous operation.- The discussion includes the limitations of using musl (a lightweight C standard library) instead of glibc (GNU C Library) and the innovative idea of utilizing old phones as servers.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://hackerherald.com/">Hacker Herald – like HN but with crowdsourced pics and subtitles</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author, along with former instructor Arnav and student Archis, has launched a project called Hacker Herald, a front end for Hacker News.- The project was developed during an online JavaScript programming course and aims to provide a visually appealing layout similar to popular newspaper sites.- The inclusion of visuals, such as images, is intended to enhance the storytelling experience by providing immediate context without needing to click through articles.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42338327">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Hacker Herald is a new project inspired by Hacker News, offering a newspaper-like layout with crowdsourced images and subtitles for tech news.</li>
<li>The project has received mixed feedback, with some users appreciating the visual appeal, while others prefer the simplicity of the original Hacker News format.</li>
<li>Concerns have been raised about image authenticity and privacy issues from hotlinking, with suggestions for improvements such as adding search, categories, and permalinks.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.ctvnews.ca/health/congo-government-says-it-s-on-alert-over-mystery-flu-like-disease-that-killed-dozens-1.7134550">Congo gov. says it&#39;s &#39;on alert&#39; over mystery flu-like disease that killed dozens</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42332129">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Congo government is on high alert due to a mysterious flu-like disease that has resulted in dozens of deaths, raising concerns about its nature and origin.</li>
<li>Experts are considering various possibilities, including it being an endemic disease, an emerging infectious disease, or a novel pathogen, with testing underway to identify the cause.</li>
<li>The affected area is known for malnutrition, which could worsen the impact, but there is currently no evidence of rapid or widespread transmission.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="The correct amount of ads is zero" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=The%20correct%20amount%20of%20ads%20is%20zero&subheading=Friday%2C%20December%206%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/12/06</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-06T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-12-05]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/12/05&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-12-05</h1>
<h2><a href="https://diataxis.fr/">Diátaxis – A systematic approach to technical documentation authoring</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Diátaxis is a systematic approach to technical documentation that focuses on user needs by categorizing content into four types: tutorials, how-to guides, technical reference, and explanation.</li>
<li>This method addresses issues related to content, style, and organization, benefiting both users and creators by enhancing documentation quality and accessibility.</li>
<li>Diátaxis has been successfully implemented in projects like Gatsby and Cloudflare, demonstrating its practical effectiveness in improving clarity and user accessibility.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42325011">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Diátaxis is a framework designed to enhance technical documentation by categorizing content into tutorials, how-to guides, reference materials, and explanations, each serving distinct user needs.</li>
<li>This approach is gaining popularity in tech writing as it aims to improve documentation quality by avoiding the pitfall of creating one-size-fits-all documents.</li>
<li>While the framework is beneficial, some experts advise maintaining flexibility to adapt to varying documentation requirements.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://smcleod.net/2024/12/bringing-k/v-context-quantisation-to-ollama/">Bringing K/V context quantisation to Ollama</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42323953">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The integration of K/V (Key/Value) context quantization into Ollama was a collaborative effort between the Ollama team and the community, taking approximately five months to complete.</li>
<li>Challenges were faced in merging the feature into the project, highlighting the complexities of contributing to large-scale projects.</li>
<li>The project underscores the dedication of hobbyists in AI development and includes discussions on various usage methods, such as GUI (Graphical User Interface) options and mobile compatibility, with tools like OpenWebUI and LibreChat being recommended.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://waymo.com/blog/2024/12/next-stop-miami/">Next stop: Miami</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Waymo One is set to expand its autonomous, all-electric ride-hailing service to Miami in 2026, using Jaguar I-PACEs.</li>
<li>The expansion is in partnership with Moove and follows successful tests in Miami&#39;s challenging weather conditions.</li>
<li>This move aligns with Miami&#39;s emphasis on sustainable and clean energy transportation, and the service will be accessible through the Waymo One app.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42328971">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Waymo is expanding its driverless car service to Miami, a city with challenging driving conditions, as part of its strategy to scale operations in various cities.- The expansion raises questions about Waymo&#39;s ability to handle Miami&#39;s unique challenges, including frequent flooding and aggressive driving behaviors.- Waymo partners with local companies to manage operations, focusing on its self-driving technology to address high costs and safety issues of human-driven taxis, aiming for a more efficient urban transportation solution.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.techdirt.com/2024/12/04/federal-court-says-dismantling-a-phone-to-install-firmware-isnt-a-search-even-if-was-done-to-facilitate-a-search/">Federal Court Says Dismantling a Phone to Install Firmware Isn&#39;t a &#39;Search&#39;</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The iPhone 6 is susceptible to the checkm8 exploit, which is a known security vulnerability.</li>
<li>Devices such as the iPhone XS and newer models are currently not affected by this exploit, indicating improved security measures in later models.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42329005">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A federal court decided that dismantling a phone to install firmware does not qualify as a &quot;search&quot; if data access is conducted with a valid warrant.- The government faced challenges accessing a device, leading them to send it for repair and firmware update, with a new warrant obtained before the actual data search.- This case underscores the complexities in legal interpretations and the difficulties in crafting clear headlines for technical legal matters.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.pgvecto.rs/vectorchord-store-400k-vectors-for-1-in-postgresql">VectorChord: Store 400k Vectors for $1 in PostgreSQL</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>VectorChord is a new PostgreSQL extension designed for efficient vector search, capable of storing 400,000 vectors for just $1, making it more cost-effective than competitors.- It utilizes IVF (Inverted File) and RaBitQ (Random Bit Quantization) techniques to enhance search speed and memory efficiency, making it suitable for handling large datasets.- VectorChord outperforms alternatives like Pinecone and pgvector in terms of both price and performance, offering scalable vector search with improved speed and precision for applications needing quick and accurate responses.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42324059">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>VectorChord has introduced a PostgreSQL extension that allows storing 400,000 vectors for a cost of $1, highlighting a cost-effective solution for vector storage.</li>
<li>Comparisons with Datastax&#39;s AstraDB reveal differences in replication strategies and associated costs, sparking discussions on performance and update handling.</li>
<li>The project plans to integrate features from pgvecto.rs and eventually phase out support for it, with users exploring the potential and limitations of VectorChord in vector database management.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/BTCUSD/">Bitcoin is over $100k</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42324263">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Bitcoin&#39;s recent surge past $100k has reignited debates on its value, with discussions focusing on its role as a speculative asset versus a store of value.</li>
<li>The rise has prompted conversations about wealth inequality, the environmental impact of cryptocurrency, and its potential as a decentralized financial tool.</li>
<li>Despite mixed opinions, Bitcoin&#39;s growth continues to draw attention, with predictions of further increases and warnings about its inherent volatility.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Diátaxis – A systematic approach to technical documentation authoring" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Di%C3%A1taxis%20%E2%80%93%20A%20systematic%20approach%20to%20technical%20documentation%20authoring&subheading=Thursday%2C%20December%205%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/12/05</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-05T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-12-04]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/12/04&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-12-04</h1>
<h2><a href="https://walzr.com/IMG_0001/">IMG_0001</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Between 2009 and 2012, iPhones featured a &quot;Send to YouTube&quot; button in the Photos app, resulting in numerous uploads with default IMG_XXXX filenames.- A bot was developed, inspired by Ben Wallace, to locate 5 million of these videos, showcasing raw and unedited moments.- The collection of videos is available for viewing, presented in a random order, offering a glimpse into unfiltered content from that era.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42314547">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion revolves around a minimalist user interface (UI) feature that displays view counts on videos, evoking nostalgia for the early internet&#39;s more personal and authentic content.- Users express mixed emotions, with some viewing personal videos as an invasion of privacy, despite their public availability, highlighting ongoing privacy concerns in internet culture.- The conversation reflects on the evolution of internet culture, contrasting the raw authenticity of past online experiences with the more sanitized and potentially privacy-invasive nature of today&#39;s web.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.armaansahni.com/game/">My son (9 yrs old) used plain JavaScript to make a game, and wants your feedback</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>A 9-year-old has been learning coding, mastering HTML and CSS, and recently used Google Gemini to enhance his skills.- He created a game by coding HTML, CSS, and JavaScript in VSCode and used Piskel for animated graphics, with guidance from his parents and Google Gemini.- The child documented his experience in a blog post, discussing the process and receiving feedback from his programmer parents to refine his writing.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42312121">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A 9-year-old created a game using JavaScript, showcasing skills in HTML, CSS, and game design with tools like VSCode and Piskel.- The young developer received guidance from his programmer parents and used Google Gemini to enhance his coding skills.- Community feedback has been positive, with suggestions for improvements, indicating a supportive environment for his coding journey.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://egoless.engineering">Egoless Engineering</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The talk emphasizes the importance of fostering better work environments by breaking down unnecessary role divisions and encouraging collaboration across roles.- It highlights inefficiencies caused by excessive role splitting and the misconception of &quot;devops&quot; practices that create barriers rather than promoting collaboration.- The speaker advocates for valuing cooperation, curiosity, and shared responsibility, suggesting that misery should not be equated with productivity.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42311069">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Egoless Engineering focuses on collaboration, ownership, and minimizing unnecessary processes to enhance team efficiency.</li>
<li>It highlights the importance of creating high-trust environments to boost productivity and warns against the inefficiencies caused by politics in modern team structures.</li>
<li>Balancing autonomy with necessary oversight is crucial, especially in large projects, to foster a culture of trust and collaboration while managing human traits like ego.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.phoenixframework.org/blog/phoenix-liveview-1.0-released?release=1.0">Phoenix LiveView 1.0.0 is here</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Phoenix LiveView 1.0.0 has been released, offering a major update that simplifies dynamic server-rendered applications by reducing the need for JavaScript and enhancing real-time capabilities.- Key features of this release include a diffing engine for efficient updates, HEEx components for improved HTML composability, and interactive uploads, all leveraging Elixir and the Erlang VM for superior latency and scalability.- The update also introduces new features like streams and async operations, with future plans to integrate JavaScript hooks and Web Components, encouraging developers to explore its easy setup.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42312301">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Phoenix LiveView 1.0.0 has been released, featuring a new installer for easier setup and enhanced functionalities.</li>
<li>The release is considered a major milestone for the Elixir and Phoenix projects, with users praising its productivity and ease of use compared to other frameworks.</li>
<li>Despite some challenges like managing unreliable connections, the community is actively seeking solutions, and the creator, Chris McCord, is open to feedback.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/genie-2-a-large-scale-foundation-world-model/">Genie 2: A large-scale foundation world model</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Research Genie 2, released on December 4, 2024, is a large-scale foundation world model designed to generate diverse 3D environments for AI agent training.- Developed by Jack Parker-Holder&#39;s team, Genie 2 can create action-controllable, playable worlds from a single image prompt, supporting rapid prototyping and interactive experiences.- Genie 2 advances AI research by modeling object interactions, character animations, and environmental physics, addressing the challenge of creating rich training environments for embodied agents.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42317903">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Genie 2, developed by DeepMind, is a new world model that demonstrates potential in navigating environments using photos and text but lacks technical details, code, and open access.</li>
<li>It is considered more of a prototype for research and development rather than a finished product, leading to criticism about its inaccessibility and limited practical application.</li>
<li>The discussion around Genie 2 underscores the challenges of AI-generated content, the potential for future applications, and the competitive nature of AI development, with its real-world utility and impact still uncertain.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.openttd.org/">OpenTTD is an open source simulation game based upon Transport Tycoon Deluxe</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>OpenTTD 14.1 was released on May 3, 2024, focusing on bug fixes since the initial release.- Key updates include resolving a multiplayer desynchronization bug and enhancements to the ship pathfinder and unbunching feature.- Players have shown significant engagement, logging 34,700 hours in 17,219 games in the past week.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42314700">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>OpenTTD is an open-source simulation game inspired by Transport Tycoon Deluxe, notable for being playable without needing additional assets, unlike many other open-source remakes.- Released in 2004, OpenTTD replaced the original game graphics by 2009, enabling its distribution on platforms like Steam while maintaining the original style without asset copying.- The game supports multiplayer and has educational applications, such as in AI development, and continues to be popular for its nostalgic appeal and engaging gameplay.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/keyvank/30cc">My C compiler compiled itself</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42311031">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A user detailed their journey in developing a self-compiling C compiler, highlighting the challenges and rewards of the process.</li>
<li>Feedback focused on adhering to DRY (Don&#39;t Repeat Yourself) principles and avoiding unnecessary type casting with malloc(), a memory allocation function in C.</li>
<li>The discussion expanded to include topics like compiler compatibility, coding style, bootstrapping, and the pros and cons of using Makefiles versus Python scripts for project builds.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://tej.as/blog/how-to-grow-professional-relationships-tjs-model">How to grow professional relationships</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The TJS (The Journey to Synergy) Collaboration Model outlines seven states of professional relationships, ranging from competitive to shared identity, to enhance collaboration.</li>
<li>The model emphasizes moving from a zero-sum mindset to high-quality synergy, encouraging an abundance mindset and alignment with personal goals and values.</li>
<li>Key stages include Competition, Coexist, Communicate, Cooperate, Coordinate, Collaborate, and &quot;We are the same,&quot; with the ultimate goal of achieving more collectively than individually.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42315946">Reactions</a></h3>
<h2><a href="https://ppc.web.cern.ch/">A particle physics course for high-school students</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>CERN&#39;s Physics Education Research team has developed a pilot particle physics course for high-school students, consisting of 16 chapters with videos and quizzes.- The course, lasting approximately 4 hours, covers fundamental topics such as &quot;What is a particle?&quot; and &quot;What is a particle accelerator?&quot; and includes DIY experiments.- Participants can complete chapters in any order and earn a digital certificate upon completing all quizzes, with feedback encouraged to enhance future iterations.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42314340">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A particle physics course for high-school students in the UK involved 54 teenagers from 36 schools, conducted online over eight weeks.- Despite challenges such as limited interaction and self-esteem issues, over 80% of students passed a test with questions from an Oxford postgraduate quantum physics exam, with half achieving distinctions.- The course&#39;s success without complex math led to discussions on enforcing camera use in online classes, engaging students, and language accessibility for non-English speakers.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://blog.infected.systems/posts/2024-12-01-no-nat-november/">No NAT November: My month without IPv4</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The &quot;No NAT November&quot; challenge involved disabling IPv4 and using only IPv6, highlighting the potential and challenges of transitioning to IPv6-only networks.- The author suggests an &quot;IPv6-mostly&quot; approach, which prioritizes IPv6 while maintaining dual-stack networks, reducing maintenance and preparing for an IPv4-free future.- Transitional technologies like NAT64 and DNS64 helped address compatibility issues, with Apple devices adapting well, while Windows and Linux showed mixed results.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42313507">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion highlights challenges in transitioning from IPv4 to IPv6, including ISP support issues, hardware limitations, and business and technical hurdles.</li>
<li>Users note benefits of IPv6, such as improved latency and simplified network management by avoiding NAT (Network Address Translation) complexities.</li>
<li>The conversation includes skepticism about IPv6 adoption and explores technical solutions, configurations, and its impact on security and network management.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.propublica.org/article/formaldehyde-epa-trump-public-health-danger">Formaldehyde Causes More Cancer Than Any Other Toxic Air Pollutant</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Formaldehyde, a prevalent air pollutant from sources like car exhaust and factories, poses significant cancer risks, particularly linked to myeloid leukemia.- Efforts to regulate formaldehyde have been obstructed by industry influence and political changes, with notable setbacks during the Trump administration.- ProPublica&#39;s investigation underscores the underestimated risks of formaldehyde exposure and the ongoing challenges in implementing effective regulations, despite some progress under the Biden administration.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42313910">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Formaldehyde is recognized as a major carcinogenic air pollutant, with ongoing debates about its regulation and associated health risks, particularly myeloid leukemia.</li>
<li>The Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) faces criticism from some scientists regarding its assessment of formaldehyde&#39;s risks, highlighting the tension between public safety and economic interests.</li>
<li>Formaldehyde is commonly found in products like building materials and hair treatments, raising exposure concerns, while broader discussions include pollution from vehicle tires and reducing car dependency.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://emacsconf.org/2024/">EmacsConf 2024</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>EmacsConf 2024 is scheduled to be held online on December 7-8, featuring talks, volunteer opportunities, and discussions centered around GNU Emacs and Emacs Lisp.</li>
<li>The event will utilize free software for streaming and includes a satellite event in Lucerne, Switzerland, offering a hybrid experience.</li>
<li>Participants can engage in discussions via the emacsconf-discuss mailing list, organize through emacsconf-org, and connect on IRC at #emacsconf on irc.libera.chat, with content licensed under CC BY-SA 4.0 and GPLv3+.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42314024">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>EmacsConf 2024 emphasizes the lasting dedication of the Emacs community, showcasing its unique features despite not being as popular as editors like VS Code.- Key discussions focus on Emacs&#39; niche appeal, the relationship between popularity and software sustainability, and innovative presentations at the conference.- Notable topics include Emacs&#39; integration with AI and unique modes such as gptel, highlighting its adaptability and continued relevance.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.cnn.com/2024/12/04/us/brian-thompson-united-healthcare-death/index.html">UnitedHealthcare CEO fatally shot in midtown Manhattan</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42317968">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The UnitedHealthcare CEO was tragically shot in Manhattan, leading to widespread speculation about the motive behind the incident.</li>
<li>Some suggest the motive may be linked to UnitedHealthcare&#39;s controversial practices, including denying claims for terminal illnesses.</li>
<li>The event has ignited conversations about the safety of high-profile individuals and the impact of corporate actions on public sentiment.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/12/03/arts/stephen-king-maine-radio-stations.html">Stephen King to shut down his 3 radio stations in Maine</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Stephen King is closing his three radio stations in Bangor, Maine, after over 40 years of ownership, due to financial losses and his age.</li>
<li>The stations, which reflect King&#39;s passion for rock music and local media, will cease operations on New Year&#39;s Eve.</li>
<li>This decision marks a significant change in King&#39;s business affairs, as he reorganizes his ventures.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42310683">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Stephen King is shutting down his three radio stations in Maine due to the challenges posed by the rise of corporate broadcasting, which makes it hard for small stations to compete.</li>
<li>The radio industry is facing difficulties as digital platforms like podcasts and YouTube become more popular, drawing audiences away from traditional radio.</li>
<li>The closure of King&#39;s stations underscores the broader struggles of independent radio businesses in adapting to a rapidly evolving media environment.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://insideevs.com/news/742893/porsche-macan-electric-ev-recall-headlights/">The Porsche Macan EV is being recalled because its headlights are too bright</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Porsche is recalling 2,941 Macan Electric models in the U.S. due to headlights that are too bright, requiring a service center visit for a software update.</li>
<li>The issue cannot be resolved through an over-the-air update, necessitating a physical visit to a service center for the free fix.</li>
<li>The recall affects vehicles manufactured between March 15 and November 4, 2024, with dealers and owners being notified in December 2024 and January 2025, respectively.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42311912">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Porsche Macan EV is being recalled due to headlights that are excessively bright, causing discomfort and safety concerns for drivers.</li>
<li>The recall underscores the differences in headlight regulations between the US and Europe, with the US having stricter brightness limits but less enforcement on proper adjustment.</li>
<li>The issue highlights a broader frustration among drivers regarding the increasing brightness of modern car headlights, particularly on larger vehicles like SUVs and trucks.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="IMG_0001" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=IMG_0001&subheading=Wednesday%2C%20December%204%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/12/04</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-04T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-12-03]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/12/03&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-12-03</h1>
<h2><a href="https://www.map.cv/blog/redbook">Facebook&#39;s Little Red Book</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>In 2012, Facebook created a &quot;Little Red Book&quot; to maintain its identity and focus as it expanded to a billion users, emphasizing principles like breaking things, thinking big, and moving fast.</li>
<li>The book, designed by Ben Barry, served as a manifesto to preserve Facebook&#39;s ethos during rapid growth, showcasing the importance of storytelling in scaling company culture.</li>
<li>A high-quality digital version of this rare book has been created to illustrate how successful companies maintain their identity and culture.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42299863">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Facebook&#39;s &quot;Little Red Book&quot; was an employee guide from 2012, designed to inspire a sense of mission and tech optimism.</li>
<li>The guide has faced criticism for its naivety and lack of self-awareness, especially in light of Facebook&#39;s later controversies involving data privacy and misinformation.</li>
<li>The book is viewed as a relic from a more hopeful era in tech, contrasting with the current complex realities of social media.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://apnews.com/article/south-korea-yoon-martial-law-997c22ac93f6a9bece68454597e577c1">South Korean president declares emergency martial law</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42306020">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>South Korean President Yoon Suk Yeol declared emergency martial law, but the National Assembly voted to demand its lifting, rendering the declaration void.</li>
<li>The military insists martial law will continue until the president officially ends it, leading to debates about constitutional obligations and potential impeachment.</li>
<li>The declaration is compared to a coup attempt, raising concerns about the military&#39;s role and the president&#39;s motives, including avoiding scandal investigations.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.henrikkarlsson.xyz/p/art-gallery">Lessons I learned working at an art gallery</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42302784">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The text emphasizes the subjective nature of art evaluation and the significance of networking in an artist&#39;s career success.- It discusses the challenges in predicting successful art exhibitions and the role of early professional connections.- The conversation extends to the complexities of defining &quot;great art,&quot; the influence of commercial success, and the importance of communication in professional settings.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://commoncog.com/c/cases/y-combinator-power/">Y Combinator and Power in Silicon Valley</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>In 2010, AdGrok, a small startup, faced a lawsuit from their former employer, Adchemy, which threatened their financial stability.- Y Combinator, a startup accelerator backing AdGrok, played a pivotal role in resolving the lawsuit by leveraging its influence with Adchemy&#39;s investors and potential business partners.- Despite winning the lawsuit, the ordeal led to AdGrok&#39;s sale to Twitter in 2011, while Adchemy was later sold to Walmart Labs in a fire-sale acquisition.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42303798">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Y Combinator (YC) is a major player in Silicon Valley, influencing which startups gain traction post-accelerator.- Critics suggest YC has adopted a &quot;spray and pray&quot; strategy, prioritizing the number of startups over selectivity and quality.- The debate centers on whether YC should scale its operations or concentrate on fewer, high-quality startups, reflecting broader complexities in startup culture and investment strategies.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://chshersh.com/blog/2023-12-16-8-months-of-ocaml-after-8-years-of-haskell.html">8 months of OCaml after 8 years of Haskell in production (2023)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author compares Haskell and OCaml based on their experience, highlighting that Haskell has more features and packages, but OCaml&#39;s simplicity enhances productivity.- Haskell&#39;s tooling is powerful yet inconsistent, while OCaml&#39;s tooling is straightforward and reliable, with succinct compiler messages.- Both languages are suitable for industrial use, but the author prefers OCaml for its focus on development rather than overthinking, despite Haskell&#39;s more comprehensive documentation.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42302426">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The author compares their experiences with Haskell and OCaml, highlighting Haskell&#39;s elegant but complex syntax and inconsistent tooling, particularly with specific GHC (Glasgow Haskell Compiler) versions.- OCaml is praised for its straightforwardness, simpler module system, faster compiler, and practicality in production, with fewer language extensions and a more manageable learning curve.- The author emphasizes the significance of a robust standard library for the success of a programming language.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://apnews.com/article/hiv-infections-aids-prevention-shot-02606f7d7892f0baf55bd0a0ff2ba3de">Twice-Yearly HIV Shot Shows 100% Effectiveness in Women</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42302963">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A new twice-yearly HIV shot has demonstrated 100% effectiveness in women, providing a promising alternative to daily pills or monthly shots.</li>
<li>This development is crucial for individuals who find it challenging to adhere to daily medication regimens, potentially simplifying HIV prevention efforts.</li>
<li>Despite its promise, the cost of the injectable form is a concern, though Gilead plans to offer more affordable, generic versions in 120 lower-income countries, potentially impacting public health in high HIV prevalence regions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/12/blizzards-pulling-of-warcraft-i-ii-tests-gogs-new-preservation-program/">Blizzard&#39;s pulling of Warcraft I and II tests GOG&#39;s new Preservation Program</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Blizzard has requested GOG to remove the DRM-free bundle of Warcraft I &amp; II from its store due to the release of remastered versions.</li>
<li>GOG is offering the bundle at a discount before removal, ensuring that buyers will still have access and receive updates for compatibility with modern systems.</li>
<li>This situation underscores the ongoing tension between remastered and original game versions, with GOG striving to preserve classic games despite publisher decisions.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42303274">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Blizzard&#39;s removal of Warcraft I and II from GOG has drawn criticism, particularly in light of the negative feedback on the Warcraft 3 remaster.</li>
<li>Fans express concern that Blizzard, post-Activision merger, is focusing more on short-term profits than on maintaining game quality.</li>
<li>This situation underscores the difficulties in preserving gaming history, as highlighted by GOG&#39;s Preservation Program, and reflects the industry&#39;s trend towards profit-driven models.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2024/raspberry-pi-boosts-pi-5-performance-sdram-tuning">Raspberry Pi boosts Pi 5 performance with SDRAM tuning</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Raspberry Pi engineers have optimized SDRAM (Synchronous Dynamic Random-Access Memory) timings, resulting in a 10-20% performance boost for Pi 5 and Pi 4 at 2.4 GHz.</li>
<li>Overclocking, which involves increasing the clock speed beyond the manufacturer&#39;s specifications, can achieve up to a 32% speedup, with most Pi 5s reaching 2.6-3.0 GHz.</li>
<li>These performance enhancements, including NUMA (Non-Uniform Memory Access) emulation for better multi-core workload handling, may soon be available through firmware updates, potentially becoming standard features.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42303111">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The Raspberry Pi 5 has improved performance due to SDRAM tuning, leading to discussions about using Intel N100s as an alternative.- Rising prices of Raspberry Pis make Intel N100s more attractive for those prioritizing performance per dollar, despite the Pi&#39;s advantages in GPIO (General Purpose Input/Output) and compact size.- The debate centers on the best use cases, with some favoring Raspberry Pis for simplicity and others choosing N100s for their superior power and versatility.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2024/12/03/no-need-to-email-me-about-cisco-anyconnect/">No need to email me about Cisco AnyConnect</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author&#39;s name and email are included in Cisco&#39;s AnyConnect VPN client due to the use of the curl library, leading to confusion among users seeking support.- The author clarifies they are the lead developer of curl, a component used in the app, but not affiliated with Cisco or AnyConnect.- Users needing support for AnyConnect should contact Cisco directly at <a href="mailto:ac-mobile-feedback@cisco.com">ac-mobile-feedback@cisco.com</a>.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42303903">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Daniel Stenberg, the creator of curl, frequently receives misdirected support requests for Cisco AnyConnect, illustrating issues with companies obscuring their support channels.- Users often bypass their IT departments, possibly due to previous negative interactions, leading them to seek help from unrelated parties.- The conversation also highlights the difficulties of directly contacting individuals online, primarily due to concerns about spam.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.perl.com/article/duckduckgo-donates-25-000-to-the-perl-and-raku-foundation/">DuckDuckGo Donates $25k to the Perl and Raku Foundation</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>DuckDuckGo has donated $25,000 to The Perl and Raku Foundation (TPRF) on &quot;Giving Tuesday,&quot; contributing to their mission of advancing Perl and Raku programming languages.</li>
<li>Since 2011, DuckDuckGo has donated over $6 million to organizations that support online trust, highlighting its commitment to fostering secure and trustworthy online environments.</li>
<li>The donation will aid in funding core Perl development and community projects, with TPRF expressing gratitude for DuckDuckGo&#39;s support and confidence in their mission.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42307223">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>DuckDuckGo&#39;s $25k donation to the Perl and Raku Foundation has ignited discussions on the sustainability of open-source projects.</li>
<li>The decline in Perl usage and the lack of contributions from companies that rely on it highlight concerns about its future funding and tech debt issues.</li>
<li>The debate on the open-source model&#39;s reliance on donations and volunteer work suggests exploring alternative funding methods.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2024/12/company-claims-1000-percent-price-hike-drove-it-from-vmware-to-open-source-rival/">Company claims 1k% price hike drove it from VMware to open source rival</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Beeks Group, a UK cloud operator, transitioned 20,000 virtual machines (VMs) from VMware to OpenNebula following a 1,000% price increase after Broadcom acquired VMware.</li>
<li>This migration enhanced VM efficiency by 200% and allowed Beeks to allocate more resources to client workloads.</li>
<li>Broadcom&#39;s acquisition of VMware has led to increased costs and reduced support, prompting many companies, including AT&amp;T, to seek alternatives due to customer dissatisfaction.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42304955">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A significant price increase has prompted a company to transition from VMware to an open-source alternative, reflecting a broader trend in the industry.</li>
<li>The acquisition of VMware by Broadcom and subsequent pricing changes are driving businesses to explore other options, with Red Hat gaining new customers as a result.</li>
<li>The industry&#39;s shift towards containerization and Kubernetes is reducing the appeal of traditional virtual machines, emphasizing the need to consider vendor lock-in and explore alternatives like Proxmox or OpenNebula.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Facebook's Little Red Book" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Facebook's%20Little%20Red%20Book&subheading=Tuesday%2C%20December%203%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/12/03</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-03T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-12-02]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/12/02&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-12-02</h1>
<h2><a href="https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/newsroom/news/intel-ceo-news-dec-2024.html">Intel announces retirement of Pat Gelsinger</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Intel&#39;s CEO Pat Gelsinger announced his retirement after over 40 years, effective December 1, 2024, with David Zinsner and Michelle Johnston Holthaus serving as interim co-CEOs.</li>
<li>The board is committed to maintaining product leadership and efficiency, with Frank Yeary as interim executive chair during the search for a new CEO.</li>
<li>Intel remains a leader in semiconductor technology, inspired by Moore’s Law, with a focus on innovation and leadership continuity.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42296067">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Intel CEO Pat Gelsinger&#39;s retirement has prompted speculation about the company&#39;s future, with opinions divided on whether his aggressive strategy was beneficial or indicative of underlying issues.</li>
<li>Discussions have emerged about potential mergers, including a controversial suggestion of merging with AMD, which raises concerns about creating a monopoly.</li>
<li>The announcement has elicited mixed reactions, with some viewing it as a mistake and others considering it a necessary change for Intel&#39;s progress.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://publicdomainreview.org/features/entering-the-public-domain/2025/">What Will Enter the Public Domain in 2025?</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>On January 1, 2025, new works will enter the public domain, including those by creators who died in 1954 and 1974, and U.S. films/books from 1929.</li>
<li>The Public Domain Review, a UK Community Interest Company, uses profits for community benefit and relies on reader donations.</li>
<li>Readers are encouraged to explore resources like John Mark Ockerbloom’s “Public Domain Day Countdown” and Communia’s Manifesto for more information on the public domain.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42290448">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>In 2025, the expiration of the last patents on the h.264 (AVC) video codec will make it freely available, potentially increasing accessibility and reducing costs for users.</li>
<li>The HEVC codec remains entangled in patent complexities, highlighting ongoing challenges in video codec accessibility.</li>
<li>Discussions on copyright reform are ongoing, with proposals for shorter terms and more compulsory licenses to balance creators&#39; rights with public access, addressing concerns that current long terms primarily benefit corporations.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.math.uh.edu/~dblecher/pf2.html">How to Study Mathematics (2017)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The essay by Lawrence Neff Stout provides strategies for studying college-level mathematics, emphasizing the need for a deeper understanding of theory, definitions, and proofs compared to high school math.- Key strategies include understanding precise definitions, memorizing and comprehending theorems and proofs, and using techniques like working backwards to see how concepts interconnect.- The essay highlights the importance of practicing problems to develop techniques and judgment, and stresses that understanding is more crucial than memorization in college mathematics.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42290996">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Enjoyment in studying mathematics can enhance understanding and lead to success, as many students struggle with the subject due to unengaging teaching methods.- Having a mentor to reveal the enjoyable aspects of math and building confidence early can prevent students from giving up prematurely.- Effective strategies include engaging deeply with material, solving problems, and understanding definitions and proofs, balancing intuition with rigorous study for mastery.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://www.science.org/content/article/gene-behind-orange-fur-cats-found-last">Gene behind orange fur in cats</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42291386">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Recent studies indicate that the Arhgap36 gene, which influences GTP levels and MC1R receptor activity, may be responsible for orange fur in cats, rather than the Mc1r gene linked to red hair in humans.</li>
<li>This discovery underscores the complexity of genetics, where a single gene can impact multiple traits, and is part of broader research efforts to understand genetic mechanisms.</li>
<li>Understanding these genetic factors has potential implications for breeding and health, contributing to the popularity of orange cats, often noted for their playful behavior.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://corp.oup.com/news/brain-rot-named-oxford-word-of-the-year-2024/">’Brain rot‘ named Oxford Word of the Year 2024</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Oxford Word of the Year for 2024 is &quot;brain rot,&quot; selected through a public vote with over 37,000 participants, highlighting its growing relevance.- &quot;Brain rot&quot; describes the mental decline from consuming trivial online content, with a 230% increase in usage from 2023 to 2024, reflecting concerns about digital consumption&#39;s impact on mental health.- Originally coined by Henry David Thoreau in 1854, the term has gained popularity on platforms like TikTok, sparking discussions about the effects of excessive online content, particularly among Gen Z and Gen Alpha.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42292294">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>&quot;Brain rot&quot; has been selected as Oxford Word of the Year 2024, referring to the decline in mental state from excessive consumption of trivial online content.- The term underscores worries about shrinking attention spans and the addictive qualities of digital media, such as social media, TV, and video games.- Conversations around &quot;brain rot&quot; emphasize the need for moderation to balance relaxation and avoid overstimulation.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://retrogamecoders.com/c64-visual-studio-code/">Programming the C64 with Visual Studio Code</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The VS64 extension allows programming the Commodore 64 using Visual Studio Code on Mac, Windows, and Linux, providing a modern, cross-platform alternative to the Windows-only CBM PRG Studio.</li>
<li>VS64 supports BASIC, Assembly, and C programming with syntax highlighting, tools, and features like auto-numbering and label usage, enhancing the development experience.</li>
<li>It integrates with ACME and Kick assemblers, CC65 and LLVM-MOS C/C++ compilers, and the VICE C64 emulator for debugging, making it a comprehensive tool for C64 development.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42290861">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>The discussion emphasizes the nostalgia and continued interest in retro computing, particularly programming the Commodore 64 (C64) using Visual Studio Code.</li>
<li>Participants share experiences with vintage systems, crediting them for inspiring their software development careers, and discuss tools like &quot;retro debugger&quot; and YouTube tutorials for learning about old games and demos.</li>
<li>The conversation highlights the challenges and joys of programming in assembly language and BASIC, and mentions modern tools and extensions that enhance the retro coding experience.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Intel announces retirement of Pat Gelsinger" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Intel%20announces%20retirement%20of%20Pat%20Gelsinger&subheading=Monday%2C%20December%202%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/12/02</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-02T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[2024-12-01]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<hr>
<h2>slug: &#39;/2024/12/01&#39;</h2>
<h1>2024-12-01</h1>
<h2><a href="https://adventofcode.com/2024/about">Advent of Code 2024</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Advent of Code, created by Eric Wastl, is an Advent calendar featuring programming puzzles suitable for all skill levels, which can be solved in any programming language.</li>
<li>The puzzles are designed to run efficiently on older hardware and are intended for practice, interviews, or entertainment, without requiring a computer science background.</li>
<li>Participants are encouraged to share their experiences, test solutions with examples, and seek help if needed, while adhering to guidelines such as not using AI for solving puzzles and respecting trademark rules.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42287231">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Advent of Code 2024 has begun, with participants engaging in creative problem-solving and sharing their experiences.- Some participants are experimenting with unique approaches, such as using C without standard libraries or exploring new programming languages like Swift or Ada.- While there are concerns about AI&#39;s impact on the leaderboard, the event primarily fosters personal enjoyment, learning, and community interaction.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://follow.agwa.name/notice/AoZSMI38xcA3TrN1sm">A Brazilian CA trusted only by Microsoft has issued a certificate for google.com</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42284202">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>A Brazilian Certificate Authority (CA), trusted solely by Microsoft, issued a certificate for google.com, breaching Google&#39;s Certificate Authority Authorization (CAA) rules.</li>
<li>This incident raises concerns about the CA&#39;s reliability and Microsoft&#39;s decision to trust it, as other major browsers do not.</li>
<li>The certificate could facilitate man-in-the-middle attacks, allowing attackers to impersonate Google and distribute malware, underscoring the need for stricter oversight and transparency in CA trust decisions.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/privastead/privastead">Open-source private home security camera system (end-to-end encryption)</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The author developed a home security camera system called Privastead, focusing on privacy by using end-to-end encryption with OpenMLS and implementing it mostly in Rust.- Privastead is open-sourced for those with privacy concerns, requiring a compatible IP camera, a local machine, a server, and an Android smartphone for setup.- Currently, the system supports only one IP camera and Android, but the author seeks community feedback and contributions to enhance its capabilities.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42284412">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Privastead is an open-source home security camera system developed to address privacy concerns with existing solutions, utilizing end-to-end encryption via OpenMLS.- The system is primarily implemented in Rust and requires a supported IP camera, a local machine, a server, and an Android smartphone for operation.- The project is available on GitHub, inviting feedback and contributions from the community to enhance its functionality.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://github.com/maharmstone/ntfs2btrfs">Ntfs2btrfs does in-place conversion of NTFS filesystem to the open-source Btrfs</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>Ntfs2btrfs is a tool designed to convert NTFS file systems to Btrfs in-place, preserving the original image as a reflink copy for potential space recovery.</li>
<li>The tool is available for both Windows and Linux, with specific installation instructions and dependencies for each platform, and it includes features like compression support and rollback to NTFS.</li>
<li>Limitations include the lack of support for older extended attributes, large alternate data streams (ADS), and encrypted files, with specific conditions required for booting Windows from a Btrfs file system.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42283950">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Ntfs2btrfs is a tool that enables in-place conversion from NTFS (New Technology File System) to Btrfs (B-tree File System), sparking discussions on its utility and timing for large data transfers.</li>
<li>Users share mixed experiences with Btrfs, appreciating features like snapshots but recalling past stability issues, while also discussing other filesystems like ZFS and bcachefs.</li>
<li>The conversation underscores the complexities and risks of filesystem management, with some users advocating for backups and fresh formats over conversion tools.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://chipsandcheese.com/p/amd-disables-zen-4s-loop-buffer">AMD Disables Zen 4&#39;s Loop Buffer</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>AMD has disabled the loop buffer in its Zen 4 CPUs, a feature intended for power optimization rather than performance enhancement.- Performance tests indicate negligible differences with the loop buffer disabled, as the op cache compensates with sufficient bandwidth.- The decision to disable the loop buffer, possibly due to a hardware bug, is unlikely to significantly impact performance or power consumption, and the feature was not widely documented by AMD.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42283933">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>AMD has disabled the loop buffer in its Zen 4 CPUs, likely due to undisclosed hardware vulnerabilities, resulting in a minor performance decrease in certain situations.- The loop buffer was designed to enhance power efficiency and performance, but its removal indicates it may not have offered substantial advantages.- The quiet decision to disable the loop buffer has led to concerns regarding transparency and the management of hardware vulnerabilities.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://sfconservancy.org/news/2024/nov/29/openwrt-one-wireless-router-now-ships-black-friday/">OpenWRT One Released: First Router Designed Specifically for OpenWrt</a></h2>
<ul>
<li>The Software Freedom Conservancy (SFC) and OpenWrt have released the OpenWrt One, a wireless router designed to promote software freedom and the right to repair, priced at $89 with a case or $68.42 for the board.</li>
<li>The router is unbrickable, fully copyleft-compliant, and features a MediaTek MT7981B SoC, MT7976C wifi, 1 GiB DDR4 RAM, supporting Power over Ethernet (PoE) and USB-C power, with a USB serial interface for advanced users.</li>
<li>The device is FCC compliant, demonstrating that software right to repair can align with regulatory requirements, and each purchase includes a $10 donation to OpenWrt at the Software Freedom Conservancy.</li>
</ul>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42285689">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>OpenWRT One, the first router specifically designed for the OpenWrt open-source firmware, has been released, priced at $89.- It aims to balance copyleft compliance with FCC regulations, though it still includes some proprietary binary blobs for Wi-Fi functionality.- The release has sparked discussions on the benefits of separating router and Wi-Fi functions for greater flexibility in networking hardware.</li>
</ul>
<h2><a href="https://twitter.com/JeffDean/status/1858540085794451906">Jeff Dean Responds to EDA Industry about AlphaChip</a></h2>
<h3><a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42285128">Reactions</a></h3>
<ul>
<li>Jeff Dean addressed criticisms regarding Google&#39;s AlphaChip, noting that critics did not adhere to essential replication steps, like pre-training.- The debate questions whether AlphaChip&#39;s performance is on par with existing tools, with some suggesting Google&#39;s claims may be exaggerated.- This discussion underscores tensions between Google and the Electronic Design Automation (EDA) industry, involving accusations of bias and concerns about the replicability of Google&#39;s research.</li>
</ul>
<head>
  <meta property="og:title" content="Advent of Code 2024" />
  <meta property="og:type" content="website" />
  <meta property="og:image" content="https://og.cho.sh/api/og/?title=Advent%20of%20Code%202024&subheading=Sunday%2C%20December%201%2C%202024%3A%20Hacker%20News%20Summary" />
</head>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh/2024/12/01</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-01T00:00:00.000Z</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
