<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0"
>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 19:30:19 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/story/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Researchers design wearable tech that can sense glucose levels more accurately]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Researchers at the University of Waterloo have created a wearable device that uses radar technology to monitor glucose levels non-invasively, removing the need for needles.</li>
<li>The device, led by Dr. George Shaker, incorporates a radar chip, a meta-surface for enhanced signal accuracy, and AI algorithms for precise glucose readings.</li>
<li>Currently USB-powered, the device aims to become battery-operated for improved portability and may eventually monitor additional health metrics, with efforts underway to commercialize the technology.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://uwaterloo.ca/news/media/no-more-needles-tracking-blood-sugar-your-wrist</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-05T00:00:00.000ZResearchers design wearable tech that can sense glucose levels more accurately</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The day I taught AI to read code like a Senior Developer]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The AI was initially challenged with analyzing React codebases, approaching them like a novice developer. - By emulating senior developers&#39; strategies, such as focusing on core files and grouping changes by feature, the AI&#39;s code analysis improved significantly. - The focus is on enhancing code understanding rather than generation, with future plans to identify technical debt and comprehend team conventions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://nmn.gl/blog/ai-senior-developer</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-05T00:00:00.000ZThe day I taught AI to read code like a Senior Developer</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Web page annoyances that I don't inflict on you here]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://rachelbythebay.com/w/2025/01/04/cruft/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-05T00:00:00.000ZWeb page annoyances that I don&apos;t inflict on you here</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Nat Traversal Works (2020)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>NAT traversal enables direct device connections despite the presence of Network Address Translators (NATs) and firewalls, using UDP-based protocols and direct socket control.</li>
<li>Techniques such as STUN (Session Traversal Utilities for NAT) help in discovering public IP addresses, while relays like TURN (Traversal Using Relays around NAT) or Tailscale&#39;s DERP are used for more challenging NATs.</li>
<li>The ICE (Interactive Connectivity Establishment) protocol optimizes connection paths by evaluating all possible options and selecting the most efficient one, ensuring robust NAT traversal with end-to-end encryption and authentication.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://tailscale.com/blog/how-nat-traversal-works</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-05T00:00:00.000ZHow Nat Traversal Works (2020)</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Guten: A Tiny Newspaper Printer]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://amanvir.com/guten</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-05T00:00:00.000ZGuten: A Tiny Newspaper Printer</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Self driving 1993 Volvo with open pilot]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A group of friends participated in the Carbage Run 2025 Winter edition, a 6-day rally through Sweden to the polar circle and back to Helsinki, requiring cars to be at least 20 years old and valued under €1000.</li>
<li>They transformed a 1993 Volvo 940 Estate into a self-driving vehicle using openpilot from comma.ai, incorporating modern components like electric power steering, a Bosch iBooster, and a Tesla radar sensor.</li>
<li>Future updates will include details on wiring, a custom Engine Control Unit (ECU), and plans to open-source the code, highlighting the project&#39;s innovative approach to retrofitting older vehicles with autonomous technology.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://practicapp.com/carbagepilot-part1/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-04T00:00:00.000ZSelf driving 1993 Volvo with open pilot</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[VoxelSpace: Terrain rendering algorithm in less than 20 lines of code (2020)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>NovaLogic&#39;s 1992 game Comanche utilized the Voxel Space engine, a 2.5D rendering technique based on ray casting, to create detailed terrains with shading and shadows.</li>
<li>The Voxel Space engine used height and color maps and a simple rendering algorithm, drawing vertical lines from back to front, which could be optimized for performance.</li>
<li>The engine&#39;s code is available under the MIT license, but the technology may still be patented in certain regions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/s-macke/VoxelSpace</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-04T00:00:00.000ZVoxelSpace: Terrain rendering algorithm in less than 20 lines of code (2020)</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to draw an outline in a video game]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article discusses five techniques for rendering outlines in Unity, a popular game development platform, highlighting their use in games like Sable and The Last of Us. - Techniques include Rim Effects, Vertex Extrusion, Blurred Buffer, Jump Flood Algorithm, and Edge Detection, each with unique advantages and trade-offs in terms of performance and visual quality. - The article provides insights into balancing these methods for optimal game aesthetics and gameplay support, with additional resources and credits for 3D models included.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ameye.dev/notes/rendering-outlines/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-04T00:00:00.000ZHow to draw an outline in a video game</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I'm quitting the Washington Post]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://anntelnaes.substack.com/p/why-im-quitting-the-washington-post</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-04T00:00:00.000ZI&apos;m quitting the Washington Post</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Perplexity got ads]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/damengchen/status/1875296442417607072</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-04T00:00:00.000ZPerplexity got ads</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I am rich and have no idea what to do]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://vinay.sh/i-am-rich-and-have-no-idea-what-to-do-with-my-life/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-03T00:00:00.000ZI am rich and have no idea what to do</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[iTerm2 critical security release]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>iTerm2 version 3.5.11, released on January 2, 2025, addresses a critical security vulnerability related to the SSH integration feature in previous versions. - The bug involved logging input/output to a file on the remote host, which could be accessed by others, affecting users of versions 3.5.6 to 3.5.10 and certain beta versions. - Users are advised to update to version 3.5.11 immediately, delete the /tmp/framer.txt file, and verify the update using the provided SHA-256 and PGP signature for security assurance.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://iterm2.com/downloads/stable/iTerm2-3_5_11.changelog</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-03T00:00:00.000ZiTerm2 critical security release</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can LLMs write better code if you keep asking them to “write better code”?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>In November 2023, a meme trend involved users asking ChatGPT to iteratively enhance images, which was then applied to code using Claude 3.5 Sonnet to improve a Python program. - Initial attempts with vague prompts like &quot;write better code&quot; showed some improvements, but structured prompt engineering with specific optimization goals led to significant performance enhancements. - The experiment underscored the importance of human oversight, as while Large Language Models (LLMs) can offer innovative ideas, they may also introduce subtle bugs during code optimization.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://minimaxir.com/2025/01/write-better-code/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-03T00:00:00.000ZCan LLMs write better code if you keep asking them to “write better code”?</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Advent of Code 2024 in pure SQL]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Thomas Neumann shared his experience of solving the Advent of Code 2024 challenges using pure SQL, highlighting it as an exercise in alternative problem-solving approaches. - Neumann successfully completed all challenges, though he noted SQL&#39;s limitations in handling complex algorithms and state updates, suggesting potential improvements for SQL&#39;s efficiency. - The blog post includes a detailed SQL solution for one challenge and discusses the possibility of enhancing SQL to better support complex algorithm execution directly within databases.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>http://databasearchitects.blogspot.com/2024/12/advent-of-code-2024-in-pure-sql.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-03T00:00:00.000ZAdvent of Code 2024 in pure SQL</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[U.S. appeals court strikes down FCC's net neutrality rules]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A U.S. Appeals Court has invalidated the FCC&#39;s net neutrality rules, which mandated equal treatment of internet traffic by broadband providers, citing the FCC&#39;s overreach of legal authority.</li>
<li>The decision references a Supreme Court ruling that restricts the powers of regulatory agencies, impacting the FCC&#39;s ability to enforce net neutrality.</li>
<li>FCC Chair Jessica Rosenworcel called for Congress to legislate net neutrality, while Commissioner Brendan Carr supported the court&#39;s decision as a check on regulatory overreach.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.tvtechnology.com/news/sixth-circuit-of-appeals-strikes-down-fccs-net-neutrality-rules</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-03T00:00:00.000ZU.S. appeals court strikes down FCC&apos;s net neutrality rules</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Be a property owner and not a renter on the internet]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article stresses the importance of owning your digital space instead of relying solely on major internet platforms, which often prioritize their growth over user interests. - Strategies for maintaining control over your online presence include owning a domain, diversifying content across multiple platforms, and building direct connections with audiences through email lists. - By creating your own web property, you ensure flexibility and resilience in your digital endeavors, reducing dependency on any single network.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://den.dev/blog/be-a-property-owner-not-a-renter-on-the-internet/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-03T00:00:00.000ZBe a property owner and not a renter on the internet</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BlogScroll – An open directory of personal sites and blogs]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>BlogScroll is an open directory of personal sites and blogs, emphasizing digital spaces outside major technology companies, and is maintained on GitHub by Den Delimarsky. - Users can contribute to BlogScroll through GitHub or by emailing the creator, and updates are available via an RSS feed. - The directory includes various categories such as design-and-ux, personal, photo-video-production, and technology, showcasing contributions from numerous individuals.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blogscroll.com/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-03T00:00:00.000ZBlogScroll – An open directory of personal sites and blogs</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Alder Lake SHLX Anomaly]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Harold Aptroot discovered that the SHLX instruction on Intel&#39;s Alder Lake processors exhibits a &quot;medium latency&quot; of 3 cycles, which is atypical for left-shift operations that usually take 1 cycle. - This latency issue is specific to Alder Lake&#39;s performance cores and does not affect the efficiency cores, contradicting Intel&#39;s claims of a 1-cycle latency. - The latency varies based on the initialization of the shift count register, with 32-bit instructions or 64-bit instructions without immediates achieving 1-cycle latency, while 64-bit instructions with immediates result in 3-cycle latency.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://tavianator.com/2025/shlx.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-03T00:00:00.000ZThe Alder Lake SHLX Anomaly</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[One of my papers got declined today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://mathstodon.xyz/@tao/113721192051328193</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZOne of my papers got declined today</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MitmProxy2Swagger: Automagically reverse-engineer REST APIs]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>mitmproxy2swagger is a tool that converts mitmproxy captures into OpenAPI 3.0 specifications, facilitating the reverse-engineering of REST APIs by capturing application traffic. - The tool now supports HTTP Archive (HAR) files from browser Developer Tools, expanding its usability for developers. - Installation can be done using Python3 and pip or Docker, and the project employs tools like poetry, pre-commit, and pytest for development, with an MIT license.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/alufers/mitmproxy2swagger</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZMitmProxy2Swagger: Automagically reverse-engineer REST APIs</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The GPU, not the TPM, is the root of hardware DRM]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://mjg59.dreamwidth.org/70954.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZThe GPU, not the TPM, is the root of hardware DRM</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zasper: A Modern and Efficient Alternative to JupyterLab, Built in Go]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Zasper is a high-performance Integrated Development Environment (IDE) inspired by Jupyter, optimized for massive concurrency and minimal memory usage. - It is built with the Go programming language for enhanced concurrency and performance, offering both Electron and Web App versions, and is open-source under the AGPL-3.0 license. - Zasper supports REPL-style (Read-Eval-Print Loop) data applications and aims to expand beyond Jupyter Notebooks to support custom data applications, with full support on Mac and limited support on Linux.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/zasper-io/zasper</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZZasper: A Modern and Efficient Alternative to JupyterLab, Built in Go</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rails for everything]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Rails 8 is optimized for small projects and single developers, offering a comprehensive &quot;Getting Started with Rails&quot; guide to build full-featured applications.</li>
<li>SQLite is now production-ready in Rails 8, reducing the dependency on PostgreSQL or Redis, and includes basic continuous integration (CI) configuration with 2000 free GitHub action minutes.</li>
<li>The new authentication generator and straightforward deployment with Kamal make user sign-in and live app setup with SSL easier, promoting best practices.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://literallythevoid.com/blog/rails_for_everything.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZRails for everything</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Where to Work After 40?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42573875</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZWhere to Work After 40?</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My favourite computer ergonomics hack]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Jacob Vosmaer introduces &quot;The Beeper,&quot; a DIY device designed to encourage movement by beeping if the computer screen remains unlocked for too long. - The Beeper is composed of hardware (Adafruit Feather Huzzah ESP8266, switch, piezo buzzer), firmware (Lua script), and software that manages activation. - Despite its simplicity, the device effectively promotes regular movement, and Jacob acknowledges his wife&#39;s support in the project.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.jacobvosmaer.nl/0036-beeper/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZMy favourite computer ergonomics hack</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UBlockOrigin GPL code being stolen by team behind Honey browser extension]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://old.reddit.com/r/uBlockOrigin/comments/1hr6xjc/ubo_quick_filters_list_being_stolen_by_team/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZUBlockOrigin GPL code being stolen by team behind Honey browser extension</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blogs rot. Wikis wait]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The post contrasts the enduring nature of wikis with the transient nature of blogs, suggesting that by 2025, wikis will become more personal and meaningful.</li>
<li>Wikis are described as dynamic and reflective of the writer&#39;s evolving thoughts, whereas blogs are likened to static, forgotten storefronts.</li>
<li>The author is transitioning from a traditional website to a wiki format, indicating a shift in how personal content is managed and shared.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://j3s.sh/thought/blogs-rot-wikis-wait.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZBlogs rot. Wikis wait</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meta Wants More AI Bots on Facebook and Instagram]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Meta is set to launch AI bots on Facebook and Instagram to engage younger users and leverage its investment in generative AI technology. - These AI bots will have profiles and create content, functioning similarly to regular social media accounts, following Meta&#39;s acquisition of SocialAI. - This initiative reflects Meta&#39;s broader strategy of automating social interactions and content curation, aligning with trends seen in apps like Character.ai.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://nymag.com/intelligencer/article/meta-wants-more-ai-bots-on-facebook-and-instagram.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZMeta Wants More AI Bots on Facebook and Instagram</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My 25-year adventure in AI and ML]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Austin Z. Henley, an Associate Teaching Professor at Carnegie Mellon University, shares his 25-year journey in AI (Artificial Intelligence) and ML (Machine Learning), highlighting his transition from initial disinterest to active involvement through various projects.</li>
<li>His career path includes developing simple games, studying AI and neural networks, and applying decision trees and clustering during his PhD to analyze code editor data.</li>
<li>Henley joined Microsoft&#39;s program synthesis team in 2022, working on AI projects, including tools based on LLMs (Large Language Models), and continues to explore AI tools independently while teaching.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://austinhenley.com/blog/25yearsofai.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZMy 25-year adventure in AI and ML</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Happy New Year 2025]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42562750</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZHappy New Year 2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DOOM CAPTCHA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://doom-captcha.vercel.app/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZDOOM CAPTCHA</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Static search trees: faster than binary search]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article discusses the implementation and optimization of static search trees (S+ trees) for significantly faster searching of sorted data, achieving speeds 40 times faster than traditional binary search. - Optimization techniques such as batching, prefetching, and manual SIMD (Single Instruction, Multiple Data) are employed to enhance query throughput. - The article also explores various tree layouts, node sizes, and memory management strategies, with a discussion on future work like branchy search and interpolation search to further improve search efficiency.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://curiouscoding.nl/posts/static-search-tree/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZStatic search trees: faster than binary search</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[30% Drop In o1-Preview Accuracy When Putnam Problems Are Slightly Variated]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Putnam-AXIOM is a benchmark designed to assess large language models (LLMs) on advanced mathematical reasoning using problems from the Putnam Mathematical Competition. - The benchmark includes 236 original problems and a variation with 52 altered problems to avoid data contamination. - OpenAI&#39;s top-performing model achieved 41.95% accuracy on the original problems but experienced a significant performance drop of approximately 30% on the altered problems, highlighting challenges in adapting to variations.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://openreview.net/forum?id=YXnwlZe0yf&amp;noteId=yrsGpHd0Sf</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-01T00:00:00.000Z30% Drop In o1-Preview Accuracy When Putnam Problems Are Slightly Variated</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Databases in 2024: A Year in Review]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The database landscape in 2024 experienced significant changes, including major acquisitions, license shifts, and ongoing rivalries among key players like Redis, Elasticsearch, Databricks, and Snowflake. - DuckDB gained popularity for analytical queries, with integrations into Postgres, while notable releases included Amazon Aurora DSQL and Microsoft Garnet. - Acquisitions such as Tabular by Databricks and OrioleDB by Supabase were significant, and despite setbacks like OtterTune&#39;s closure, the industry remains dynamic with new projects and funding.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cs.cmu.edu/~pavlo/blog/2025/01/2024-databases-retrospective.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZDatabases in 2024: A Year in Review</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Books I Loved Reading in 2024]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The list features a diverse range of books, including historical, philosophical, scientific, and personal narratives, each offering unique insights and enriching experiences.</li>
<li>Highlights include Cicero&#39;s letters for insights into Roman life, Ben-Ari&#39;s works on computer science logic and program verification, and Steve Martin&#39;s memoir on comedic success.</li>
<li>The collection also includes philosophical explorations by Pierre Hadot and Nietzsche, Greek tragedies by Aeschylus, and literary works by Ursula Le Guin and Rabindranath Tagore.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://thoughts.wyounas.com/p/books-i-enjoyed-most-in-2024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZBooks I Loved Reading in 2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Terence Tao: One of my papers got declined today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://mathstodon.xyz/@tao/113721192051328193</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZTerence Tao: One of my papers got declined today</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[API Parrot – Automatically Reverse Engineer HTTP APIs]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>API Parrot is a new tool designed to simplify the automation of business processes by automatically identifying data correlations between API requests and providing a graphical flow representation. - It allows users to record requests, define inputs and outputs, and export these flows as JavaScript code, making the process more efficient than manual reverse engineering or using less optimal technologies like Robotic Process Automation (RPA). - The tool is built on Electron and is available for both Windows and Linux platforms, with a tutorial available for reverse engineering the USPS API.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://apiparrot.com/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZAPI Parrot – Automatically Reverse Engineer HTTP APIs</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FBI: Largest homemade explosives cache in agency history found in Virginia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://thehill.com/national-security/5061535-virginia-man-arrested-explosives/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZFBI: Largest homemade explosives cache in agency history found in Virginia</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Déjà vu: Ghostly CVEs in my terminal title]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Ghostty, a new terminal emulator, had a security vulnerability similar to one from 2003, allowing ASCII escape characters to execute commands like opening applications. - The issue was notably problematic with Zsh and Bash in vi mode, but Ghostty 1.0.1 has resolved this by disabling the feature by default. - Despite the security flaw, Ghostty is commended for its features, and the developer promptly addressed the issue, providing fixes and workarounds for users.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://dgl.cx/2024/12/ghostty-terminal-title</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZDéjà vu: Ghostly CVEs in my terminal title</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Large Concept Models: Language modeling in a sentence representation space]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The repository offers implementations for Large Concept Models (LCM), which utilize &quot;concepts&quot; as a higher-level semantic representation for language modeling.</li>
<li>LCM supports 200 text languages and 57 speech languages using the SONAR embedding space, and is trained for auto-regressive sentence prediction with methods like MSE regression and diffusion-based generation.</li>
<li>The repository provides installation instructions, data preparation, training, finetuning, and evaluation guidelines, and is released under the MIT license, using fairseq2 with UV and pip installation options.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/facebookresearch/large_concept_model</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZLarge Concept Models: Language modeling in a sentence representation space</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
