<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0"
>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 19:10:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/story/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Don't use cosine similarity carelessly]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Cosine similarity, a method for comparing vectors, can be misleading if used without understanding the context, as it may not accurately capture semantic similarities. - Embeddings, such as those from word2vec or sentence embeddings from Large Language Models (LLMs), require careful and intentional use to ensure they reflect the desired relationships. - To improve vector similarity results, consider using LLMs directly, creating task-specific embeddings through fine-tuning, and ensuring text is clean and prompts are well-engineered before embedding.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://p.migdal.pl/blog/2025/01/dont-use-cosine-similarity/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-15T00:00:00.000ZDon&apos;t use cosine similarity carelessly</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nevada Court Shuts Down Police Use of Federal Loophole for Civil Forfeiture]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://ij.org/press-release/nevada-court-shuts-down-police-use-of-federal-loophole-for-civil-forfeiture/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-15T00:00:00.000ZNevada Court Shuts Down Police Use of Federal Loophole for Civil Forfeiture</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TikTok preparing for U.S. shut-off on Sunday]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.reuters.com/technology/tiktok-preparing-us-shut-off-sunday-information-reports-2025-01-15/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-15T00:00:00.000ZTikTok preparing for U.S. shut-off on Sunday</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Generate audiobooks from E-books with Kokoro-82M]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Kokoro v0.19 is a new text-to-speech model with 82 million parameters, providing high-quality audio output in multiple languages, including American and British English, French, Korean, Japanese, and Mandarin.</li>
<li>Claudio Santini developed Audiblez, a tool that converts e-books into audiobooks using Kokoro, processing .epub files and generating audio files, with a conversion time of about 2 hours for a 100,000-word book on an M2 MacBook Pro.</li>
<li>Audiblez requires installation via pip, supports various languages and voices, and needs ffmpeg for .m4b file creation, with the tool available on GitHub for further development and improvements.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://claudio.uk/posts/epub-to-audiobook.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-15T00:00:00.000ZGenerate audiobooks from E-books with Kokoro-82M</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Road signs to help people limit radiation exposure in contaminated areas]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Manual on Uniform Traffic Control Devices (MUTCD) contains Cold War-era signs, such as &quot;MAINTAIN TOP SAFE SPEED,&quot; intended for radiological contamination zones.</li>
<li>These signs were part of Civil Defense strategies to safeguard citizens during a potential nuclear apocalypse, though they were never utilized.</li>
<li>Some of these signs are still included in the MUTCD as Emergency Management signs, highlighting historical fears and preparedness efforts from that period.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theautopian.com/if-you-ever-see-this-speed-sign-youre-probably-going-to-die/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-15T00:00:00.000ZRoad signs to help people limit radiation exposure in contaminated areas</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WTF Happened in 1971? (2019)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://wtfhappenedin1971.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-15T00:00:00.000ZWTF Happened in 1971? (2019)</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How rqlite is tested]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>rqlite is a lightweight distributed database that combines SQLite and Raft, focusing on reliability and quality through a structured testing strategy. - The testing strategy follows the testing pyramid, emphasizing unit tests for isolated components, integration tests for system-level validation, and minimal end-to-end tests for basic operation checks. - Key lessons from rqlite&#39;s testing approach include starting testing early, simplifying test code, and ensuring determinism, which helps maintain high quality with minimal overhead.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://philipotoole.com/how-is-rqlite-tested/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-15T00:00:00.000ZHow rqlite is tested</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rewriting my website in plain HTML and CSS]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author rebuilt their website using plain HTML and CSS, moving away from SvelteKit, to simplify the site and host it on Cloudflare Pages. - They used Pandoc for converting Markdown to HTML and Python for scripting, resulting in a smaller website, reducing asset size from ~356kb to ~88kb. - The project highlighted challenges such as code duplication and lack of live reloading, with plans to explore web components and FastAPI to address these issues, potentially serving as a template for others seeking a framework-free website with Markdown posts.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.vijayp.dev/blog/rewrite-plain-html/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-15T00:00:00.000ZRewriting my website in plain HTML and CSS</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Snyk security researcher deploys malicious NPM packages targeting cursor.com]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A Snyk security researcher released malicious NPM packages targeting Cursor.com, an AI coding company, to collect system data and send it to an attacker-controlled service.</li>
<li>The packages, identified as &quot;cursor-retrieval,&quot; &quot;cursor-always-local,&quot; and &quot;cursor-shadow-workspace,&quot; were flagged by the OpenSSF package analysis scanner, resulting in advisories MAL-2025-27, MAL-2025-28, and MAL-2025-29.</li>
<li>This incident highlights the importance of scrutinizing NPM packages before installation to avoid potential security threats.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://sourcecodered.com/snyk-malicious-npm-package/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-14T00:00:00.000ZSnyk security researcher deploys malicious NPM packages targeting cursor.com</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I Switched to Firefox and Never Looked Back]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Firefox is praised for its superior tab management, built-in Pocket feature for saving links, and a privacy-focused email relay, making it a strong alternative to Chrome. - Additional features like a user-friendly screenshot tool, a ChatGPT button, Picture-in-Picture, customizable search options, and smooth scrolling enhance the browsing experience. - Although Firefox lacks Chrome&#39;s web app feature, its thoughtful design and reduced resource demands make it a preferred choice for some users.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.howtogeek.com/why-i-switched-to-firefox-and-never-looked-back/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-14T00:00:00.000ZI Switched to Firefox and Never Looked Back</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sonos CEO steps down after app update debacle]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.reuters.com/business/retail-consumer/sonos-ceo-patrick-spence-steps-down-after-app-update-debacle-2025-01-13/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-14T00:00:00.000ZSonos CEO steps down after app update debacle</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[In the belly of the MrBeast]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://kevinmunger.substack.com/p/in-the-belly-of-the-mrbeast</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-14T00:00:00.000ZIn the belly of the MrBeast</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GitHub Git Operations Are Down]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>GitHub faced a Git operations outage on January 13, 2025, due to a configuration change affecting the internal load balancer, lasting from 23:35 to 00:24 UTC. - The issue was resolved by reverting the configuration change, and GitHub is working on improving monitoring and deployment processes to prevent similar incidents. - The outage also affected GitHub&#39;s Actions and Pages services, highlighting the interconnected nature of their platform services.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.githubstatus.com/incidents/qd96yfgvmcf9</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-14T00:00:00.000ZGitHub Git Operations Are Down</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ZFS 2.3 released with ZFS raidz expansion]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>OpenZFS 2.3.0 has been released, introducing significant features such as RAIDZ Expansion, Fast Deduplication, Direct Input/Output, JSON output, and support for long file names. - The release includes essential bug fixes and performance enhancements, compatible with Linux kernels 4.18 - 6.12 and FreeBSD versions 13.3, 14.0 - 14.2. - The update is a collaborative effort from 134 contributors, with comprehensive documentation and a change log available for review.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/openzfs/zfs/releases/tag/zfs-2.3.0</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-14T00:00:00.000ZZFS 2.3 released with ZFS raidz expansion</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Webtop – Alpine,Ubuntu,Fedora,and Arch containers containing full desktop envs]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Linuxserver/webtop provides containers based on Alpine, Ubuntu, Fedora, and Arch with full desktop environments accessible through web browsers, supporting both x86-64 and arm64 architectures.</li>
<li>Users can select from various desktop environments such as XFCE, KDE, MATE, i3, Openbox, and IceWM by using specific image tags, and access the Webtop via designated URLs.</li>
<li>Security features include Docker&#39;s seccomp option and authentication setup, with customization options available through environment variables, and support for GPU acceleration with open-source drivers.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://docs.linuxserver.io/images/docker-webtop/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-14T00:00:00.000ZWebtop – Alpine,Ubuntu,Fedora,and Arch containers containing full desktop envs</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[1 in 5 online job postings are either fake or never filled, study finds]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A recent study indicates that 20% of online job postings are either fake or remain unfilled, adding to job seekers&#39; frustration. - This &quot;ghost job&quot; trend might be a tactic for companies to project an image of growth. - Job platforms such as Greenhouse and LinkedIn have introduced job verification services to assist users in identifying genuine job opportunities.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://gizmodo.com/1-in-5-online-job-postings-are-either-fake-or-never-filled-study-finds-2000549706</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-14T00:00:00.000Z1 in 5 online job postings are either fake or never filled, study finds</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Making an intersection unsafe for pedestrians to save seconds for drivers]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://collegetowns.substack.com/p/making-an-intersection-unsafe-for</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-14T00:00:00.000ZMaking an intersection unsafe for pedestrians to save seconds for drivers</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PostgreSQL is the Database Management System of the Year 2024]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>PostgreSQL has been awarded DBMS of the Year 2024 by DB-Engines, achieving this recognition for the fifth time, surpassing 423 other database management systems.</li>
<li>PostgreSQL, with a history spanning nearly 35 years, continues to innovate, as seen in the recent enhancements of PostgreSQL 17, released in September 2024.</li>
<li>Snowflake and Microsoft secured second and third places, respectively, with Snowflake noted for its cloud-based data warehousing and multi-cloud support, while Microsoft offers robust managed relational databases through Azure SQL Database and SQL Server.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://db-engines.com/en/blog_post/109</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-14T00:00:00.000ZPostgreSQL is the Database Management System of the Year 2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google’s OAuth login doesn’t protect against purchasing a failed startup domain]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://trufflesecurity.com/blog/millions-at-risk-due-to-google-s-oauth-flaw</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-14T00:00:00.000ZGoogle’s OAuth login doesn’t protect against purchasing a failed startup domain</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Using coding skills to make passive income]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author transitioned from a CTO role to a solopreneur, successfully earning more through a portfolio of software products.</li>
<li>Key strategies include focusing on deep work, starting with small projects, iterating quickly, and dedicating time to marketing efforts.</li>
<li>The journey emphasizes resilience due to uncertainties, but highlights the unmatched autonomy and freedom of this career path, encouraging those with coding skills to consider it for passive income.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.coryzue.com/writing/solopreneur/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-14T00:00:00.000ZUsing coding skills to make passive income</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Spain proposes 100% tax on homes bought by non-EU residents]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Spain is considering a 100% tax on real estate purchases by non-EU residents, aiming to address the housing crisis and curb speculative buying.</li>
<li>Prime Minister Pedro Sánchez&#39;s proposal includes expanding social housing and regulating tourist rentals to tackle the disparity between housing prices and incomes.</li>
<li>The proposal&#39;s future as law is uncertain, with some analysts viewing it as a deterrent to foreign investors rather than a guaranteed legislative change.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/jan/13/spain-proposes-100-tax-on-homes-bought-by-non-eu-residents</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-14T00:00:00.000ZSpain proposes 100% tax on homes bought by non-EU residents</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple will soon receive 'made in America' chips from TSMC's Arizona fab]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Apple is testing processors from TSMC&#39;s Arizona facility, with plans for mass production by the first quarter, potentially becoming TSMC&#39;s first U.S. customer for locally manufactured chips. - This initiative aims to bolster U.S. silicon independence, reducing dependency on Taiwan, which is vulnerable to geopolitical and natural risks. - TSMC&#39;s Arizona fab is set to produce advanced 3nm and 2nm chips, with ongoing efforts to enhance local recruitment and partnerships with U.S. universities, although packaging will initially occur in Taiwan until the Peoria facility is operational.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.tomshardware.com/tech-industry/apple-will-soon-receive-made-in-america-chips-from-tsmcs-arizona-fab-company-in-final-stages-of-quality-verification</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-14T00:00:00.000ZApple will soon receive &apos;made in America&apos; chips from TSMC&apos;s Arizona fab</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[43K fewer drivers on Manhattan roads after congestion pricing turned on]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>After congestion pricing was implemented, there was a 7.5% reduction in drivers entering Manhattan below 60th Street, equating to 43,000 fewer drivers each weekday.</li>
<li>The reduction in traffic has improved traffic flow and increased bus speeds, with some express buses experiencing higher ridership.</li>
<li>The Metropolitan Transportation Authority (MTA) uses the toll revenue, estimated at $500 million annually, for transit improvements, despite some political opposition.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://gothamist.com/news/43k-fewer-drivers-on-manhattan-roads-after-congestion-pricing-turned-on-mta-says</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-14T00:00:00.000Z43K fewer drivers on Manhattan roads after congestion pricing turned on</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Uv's killer feature is making ad-hoc environments easy]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Uv offers a unique feature that simplifies ad-hoc scripting in Python by streamlining dependency and environment management. - Users can execute a single command, <code>uv run --python 3.12 --with pandas python</code>, to run scripts without altering the global environment. - This ease of use and memorability makes uv an attractive option for Python package management.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://valatka.dev/2025/01/12/on-killer-uv-feature.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-13T00:00:00.000ZUv&apos;s killer feature is making ad-hoc environments easy</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I deleted my social media accounts]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author deleted their social media accounts due to concerns about platforms like Meta and Twitter prioritizing profit over ethical considerations.</li>
<li>Highlighted issues include Mark Zuckerberg&#39;s decision to drop fact-checkers and collaborate with Trump, and Elon Musk&#39;s controversial actions, contributing to a toxic environment.</li>
<li>The author emphasizes the negative impact of social media on mental health, particularly for teenagers, and is exploring alternatives like blogging and new platforms cautiously.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://asylumsquare.com/backstage/2025-01-12/why-i-deleted-my-social-media-accounts</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-13T00:00:00.000ZI deleted my social media accounts</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Right to root access]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Consumers should have the right to install any software on devices they own, but companies often lock bootloaders and restrict root access, limiting user control. - While security is a valid concern, these restrictions are seen as anti-consumer and anti-competitive, contributing to e-waste and limiting repair options. - Advocates suggest that a &quot;right to root access&quot; should be included in right to repair discussions, with exceptions for critical systems where risks are too high.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://medhir.com/blog/right-to-root-access</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-13T00:00:00.000ZRight to root access</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Doom (1993) in a PDF]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A developer has created a Doom source port that operates within a PDF file, inspired by a similar Tetris project. - The project uses an older version of Emscripten to compile C code to asm.js, allowing it to run in the PDF&#39;s JavaScript runtime. - The implementation includes a 6-color monochrome display and is compatible only with Chromium-based browsers using the PDFium engine.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://doompdf.pages.dev/doom.pdf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-13T00:00:00.000ZDoom (1993) in a PDF</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Debugging: Indispensable rules for finding even the most elusive problems (2004)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>David A. Wheeler reviews &quot;Debugging: The 9 Indispensable Rules for Finding Even the Most Elusive Software and Hardware Problems&quot; by David J. Agans, highlighting it as a classic resource for developers.</li>
<li>The book emphasizes fundamental debugging principles applicable to both novice and experienced developers, using practical examples and real-life &quot;war stories&quot; to illustrate its nine key rules.</li>
<li>Wheeler commends the book for its focus on data gathering and handling intermittent problems, though he notes a desire for more specific tool advice, ultimately recommending it for its timeless debugging insights.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://dwheeler.com/essays/debugging-agans.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-13T00:00:00.000ZDebugging: Indispensable rules for finding even the most elusive problems (2004)</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How did they make cars fall apart in old movies (2017)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://movies.stackexchange.com/questions/79161/how-did-they-make-cars-fall-apart-in-old-movies</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-13T00:00:00.000ZHow did they make cars fall apart in old movies (2017)</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Standard patterns in choice-based games (2015)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The blog post by Sam Kabo Ashwell explores recurring design patterns in choice-based games, including Time Cave, Gauntlet, Branch and Bottleneck, and others, which affect gameplay and narrative structure.</li>
<li>These patterns influence player experience and story progression, with examples from interactive fiction illustrating their application.</li>
<li>The post notes that these patterns are flexible and can overlap, rather than being strict categories in game design.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://heterogenoustasks.wordpress.com/2015/01/26/standard-patterns-in-choice-based-games/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-13T00:00:00.000ZStandard patterns in choice-based games (2015)</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Free Movie: Frame-by-frame, handrawn reproduction of "The Bee Movie" (2023)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>MSCHF Interactive has launched &quot;The FREE Movie,&quot; a collaborative project where users recreate the BEE Movie frame-by-frame, with 92% of frames already completed.</li>
<li>Participants can actively engage by drawing, erasing, and previewing their contributions to the project.</li>
<li>The next ambitious project planned by MSCHF Interactive is a frame-by-frame recreation of the movie DUNE.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://thefreemovie.buzz/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-13T00:00:00.000ZThe Free Movie: Frame-by-frame, handrawn reproduction of &quot;The Bee Movie&quot; (2023)</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Disco Elysium Explorer]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Disco Elysium Explorer Project allows users to visualize and listen to dialogues from the game Disco Elysium, with all rights reserved by the studio ZA/UM. - The project offers features such as searching dialogues, building conversations, and visualizing them, enhancing the interactive experience. - It supports multiple languages, including Chinese, German, and Korean, making it accessible to a broader audience.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>http://134.0.119.41</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-13T00:00:00.000ZDisco Elysium Explorer</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[If we had the best product engineering organization, what would it look like?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The keynote at the Regional Scrum Gathering Tokyo by the VP of Engineering focused on key elements of a successful product engineering organization: People, Internal Quality, Lovability, Visibility, Agility, and Profitability.</li>
<li>Emphasized the importance of attracting top talent, maintaining internal quality by reducing waste, and ensuring product lovability by understanding stakeholder needs.</li>
<li>Highlighted the use of Extreme Programming (XP) and Fluid Scaling Technology (FaST) to enhance agility and adaptability, while aligning products with business goals for profitability.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.jamesshore.com/v2/blog/2025/the-best-product-engineering-org-in-the-world</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-13T00:00:00.000ZIf we had the best product engineering organization, what would it look like?</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Live London Underground / bus maps taken down by TfL trademark complaint]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>In June 2010, a live London Underground map was created using Transport for London&#39;s (TfL) open data API, gaining popularity and media attention.</li>
<li>On January 7, 2025, TfL requested the removal of the map due to trademark concerns, leading to its discontinuation despite potential adjustments.</li>
<li>The creator&#39;s site, traintimes.org.uk, remains active, and live bus information is available on bustimes.org.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://traintimes.org.uk/map/tube/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-13T00:00:00.000ZLive London Underground / bus maps taken down by TfL trademark complaint</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Qubes OS: A reasonably secure operating system]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Qubes OS is a highly secure operating system endorsed by experts, including Edward Snowden, for its strong isolation capabilities, making it suitable for sensitive tasks. - It supports running multiple operating systems and integrates with Whonix to enhance user privacy, appealing to journalists and organizations like the Freedom of the Press Foundation. - The Qubes community is welcoming to newcomers, providing support, resources, and opportunities to contribute or donate.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.qubes-os.org/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-13T00:00:00.000ZQubes OS: A reasonably secure operating system</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Canva outage: another tale of saturation and resilience]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Canva outage was caused by a deployment of a new editor page version, leading to a &quot;thundering herd&quot; effect with 1.5 million requests per second overwhelming the API Gateway. - A stale traffic rule routed user traffic over the public internet, causing high latency and a backlog, while a known performance issue in the API Gateway worsened the situation. - Canva engineers manually intervened by increasing capacity and using Cloudflare&#39;s firewall to block traffic temporarily, highlighting the importance of human intervention in managing system performance issues during crises.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://surfingcomplexity.blog/2024/12/21/the-canva-outage-another-tale-of-saturation-and-resilience/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-13T00:00:00.000ZThe Canva outage: another tale of saturation and resilience</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stop Trying to Schedule a Call with Me]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>New service trials often result in persistent follow-ups and marketing emails, turning initial outreach into relentless sales pitches.</li>
<li>The sales process is often tedious and time-consuming, especially in large companies, with products frequently not meeting expectations and offering limited support.</li>
<li>Customers often switch to better open-source alternatives, leading to a quiet departure from the original service despite retention efforts.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://matduggan.com/stop-trying-to-schedule-a-call-with-me/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-12T00:00:00.000ZStop Trying to Schedule a Call with Me</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kenney.nl: Free Game Assets]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.kenney.nl/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-12T00:00:00.000ZKenney.nl: Free Game Assets</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Illustrated Guide to a PhD]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>An illustrated guide is used to explain to new Ph.D. students how a Ph.D. expands the boundary of human knowledge, symbolized as a small dent.</li>
<li>Proceeds from the printed guide support research on genetic disorders, motivated by the author&#39;s personal connection to his son&#39;s rare condition.</li>
<li>The guide is licensed under Creative Commons, permitting sharing with attribution, and is available in multiple languages.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://matt.might.net/articles/phd-school-in-pictures/?_nospa=true</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-12T00:00:00.000ZThe Illustrated Guide to a PhD</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why I Chose Common Lisp]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author transitioned from Clojure to Common Lisp due to frustrations with Clojure&#39;s slow startup times for command-line interface (CLI) applications and perceived lack of community concern.</li>
<li>Common Lisp was chosen for its ability to create fast-starting standalone executables, compatibility with the Vim text editor, support across Windows, Mac, and Linux, and its strong community and ecosystem.</li>
<li>The author shares their experience to assist newcomers in understanding the benefits of Common Lisp and how they adapted to using it effectively.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.djhaskin.com/blog/why-i-chose-common-lisp/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-12T00:00:00.000ZWhy I Chose Common Lisp</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AI founders will learn the bitter lesson]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Historically, general AI approaches have outperformed specialized ones, as seen in fields like speech recognition and computer vision. - Richard Sutton&#39;s &quot;The Bitter Lesson&quot; emphasizes that general methods using computation are more effective than those relying on human domain knowledge. - The post suggests that AI founders should focus on creating products that leverage model improvements rather than compensating for current model limitations, as this is a more sustainable strategy.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://lukaspetersson.com/blog/2025/bitter-vertical/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-12T00:00:00.000ZAI founders will learn the bitter lesson</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Aaron Swartz and Sam Altman]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://journa.host/@jeremiak/113811327999722586</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-12T00:00:00.000ZAaron Swartz and Sam Altman</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Obvious things C should do]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Dlang community has integrated a C compiler within the D compiler, known as ImportC, to address unresolved issues in Standard C, now at C23. - ImportC enables functions to be executed at compile time, facilitating compile-time unit testing without the need for separate builds. - It also supports forward referencing and importing declarations without .h files, simplifying the development process.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.digitalmars.com/articles/Cobvious.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-12T00:00:00.000ZObvious things C should do</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[World's darkest and clearest skies at risk from industrial megaproject]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The European Southern Observatory (ESO) is worried about a proposed industrial complex by AES Andes near its Paranal Observatory in Chile, which may cause light pollution affecting astronomical research. - The Paranal Observatory is vital for projects like the Extremely Large Telescope (ELT), emphasizing the importance of preserving the dark skies. - ESO is advocating for the relocation of the industrial project to safeguard the observatory&#39;s environment.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.eso.org/public/news/eso2501/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-12T00:00:00.000ZWorld&apos;s darkest and clearest skies at risk from industrial megaproject</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bad Apple but it's 6,500 regexes that I search for in Vim]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A &quot;Bad Apple&quot; video was recreated in the text editor Vim using search queries, with each of the 6,500 frames represented as a 120x90 grid of binary digits.</li>
<li>Python was utilized to process the frames, and various algorithms were tested to optimize the search strings for better performance in Vim.</li>
<li>The project was a creative experiment conducted at The Recurse Center, showcasing the use of Vim macros to play the video by cycling through search patterns.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://eieio.games/blog/bad-apple-with-regex-in-vim/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-12T00:00:00.000ZBad Apple but it&apos;s 6,500 regexes that I search for in Vim</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Adobe Lightroom's AI Remove feature added a Bitcoin to bird in flight photo]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://bsky.app/profile/matthewraifman.bsky.social/post/3lfaqbygva22j</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-12T00:00:00.000ZAdobe Lightroom&apos;s AI Remove feature added a Bitcoin to bird in flight photo</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mullenweg Shuts Down WordPress Sustainability Team, Igniting Backlash]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Matt Mullenweg, co-founder of WordPress, has disbanded the WordPress Sustainability Team, leading to significant backlash from the community.</li>
<li>The team was dissolved following the resignation of team representative Thijs Buijs, who cited leadership issues, and Mullenweg&#39;s claim that the team was not meeting its objectives.</li>
<li>Critics have accused Mullenweg of hypocrisy, as he initially supported the team&#39;s formation, and the disbandment has raised concerns about the future of sustainability initiatives within WordPress.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.therepository.email/mullenweg-shuts-down-wordpress-sustainability-team-igniting-backlash</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-12T00:00:00.000ZMullenweg Shuts Down WordPress Sustainability Team, Igniting Backlash</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IP addresses through 2024]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article by Geoff Huston provides an annual update on IP addresses, focusing on the slow transition from IPv4 to IPv6 despite the predicted need for a larger address space.</li>
<li>It discusses the exhaustion of IPv4 addresses, the role of address transfers, and challenges in adopting IPv6, highlighting the fragmentation and market dynamics of IPv4 addresses.</li>
<li>The piece examines IPv6 allocation trends, noting regional differences and the impact of large allocations, and reflects on broader implications for the Internet&#39;s future, including network neutrality and market consolidation.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.potaroo.net/ispcol/2025-01/addr2024.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-12T00:00:00.000ZIP addresses through 2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Be Aware of the Makefile Effect]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The &quot;Makefile effect&quot; describes the practice of engineers copying and modifying existing complex configurations, like Makefiles, instead of creating new ones from scratch. - This approach is prevalent in various systems, such as Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment (CI/CD) configurations and build systems, and can indicate overly complex or poorly designed tools. - While not inherently negative, the Makefile effect can impede learning, complicate security, and lead to inefficient debugging, highlighting the need for thoughtful tool design that considers configurability and ease of use.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.yossarian.net/2025/01/10/Be-aware-of-the-Makefile-effect</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-11T00:00:00.000ZBe Aware of the Makefile Effect</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Portals and Quake]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article is the first in the &quot;Demystifying the PVS&quot; series, focusing on Quake&#39;s precomputed visibility system to address overdraw, where pixels are rendered multiple times. - Quake uses portal culling and potentially visible sets (PVS) by dividing the world into cells and portals, precomputing visibility to optimize rendering. - The article introduces the Portal and Leaf classes in vis.py, a Python reimplementation of Quake&#39;s visibility algorithm, highlighting the use of a leaf-to-leaf visibility matrix.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://30fps.net/pages/pvs-portals-and-quake/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-11T00:00:00.000ZPortals and Quake</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Phi-4 Bug Fixes]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://unsloth.ai/blog/phi4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-11T00:00:00.000ZPhi-4 Bug Fixes</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Very Wrong Math]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A design and construction company made a math error on Facebook, incorrectly calculating the Earth&#39;s radius as 4,333 feet, leading to a vastly underestimated circumference of just over 5 miles.</li>
<li>The error stemmed from calculating arc lengths without using the Earth&#39;s actual radius, which is approximately 3,959 miles.</li>
<li>The post highlighted that the outer arc was less than 1% longer than the inner arc, suggesting a potential reduction in flight time due to decreased air resistance.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.charlespetzold.com/blog/2025/01/Very-Wrong-Math.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-11T00:00:00.000ZVery Wrong Math</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Building Bauble]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Bauble is a 3D modeling and rendering tool that utilizes signed distance functions (SDFs) to create complex shapes and animations. - Initially a basic system for generating GLSL shaders, Bauble has been rewritten to include features like 3D model export, interactive editing, and custom lighting. - The tool now supports web embedding, interactive vector editing, and offers comprehensive documentation, making it accessible for creative projects and users interested in 3D design.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ianthehenry.com/posts/bauble/building-bauble/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-11T00:00:00.000ZBuilding Bauble</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nearly all binary searches and mergesorts are broken (2006)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>In 2006, Joshua Bloch identified a bug in the binary search algorithm, initially noted in Jon Bentley&#39;s &quot;Programming Pearls,&quot; where an overflow occurs when &#39;low&#39; and &#39;high&#39; exceed the maximum int value.</li>
<li>This bug, affecting arrays with lengths of 2^30 or more, was rare in the 1980s but is more common today, also impacting mergesort and other divide-and-conquer algorithms.</li>
<li>Bloch recommends fixing the issue by calculating the midpoint as <code>int mid = low + ((high - low) / 2);</code>, highlighting the challenges of writing error-free code and the necessity of thorough testing.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://research.google/blog/extra-extra-read-all-about-it-nearly-all-binary-searches-and-mergesorts-are-broken/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-11T00:00:00.000ZNearly all binary searches and mergesorts are broken (2006)</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Track your devices via Apple FindMy network in Go/TinyGo]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Go Haystack enables tracking of personal Bluetooth devices via Apple&#39;s &quot;Find My&quot; network without requiring Apple hardware, utilizing OpenHaystack and Macless-Haystack with Go/TinyGo tools.</li>
<li>Users can create their own beacons using TinyGo firmware on hardware like Adafruit Bluefruit boards and BBC Microbit, with setup requiring an Apple ID with two-factor authentication (2FA).</li>
<li>The process involves installing the go-haystack tool, using commands like <code>haystack scan</code> to locate devices, generating keys, flashing the device, and uploading a JSON file to macless-haystack for device visibility in the web UI.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/hybridgroup/go-haystack</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-11T00:00:00.000ZTrack your devices via Apple FindMy network in Go/TinyGo</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The State of Vim]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Following the passing of Vim founder Bram Moolenaar in 2023, the Vim community has reorganized to ensure the project&#39;s continued development, with Christian Brabandt as the current maintainer. - At VimConf 2024, it was discussed that the team has expanded, focusing on updating the Vim website, managing security, and enhancing communication channels. - Vim remains in maintenance mode, prioritizing community needs and integrating new features carefully, while continuing to support ICCF Holland, a charity established by Moolenaar.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://lwn.net/SubscriberLink/1002342/a8d8a17f30968b93/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-11T00:00:00.000ZThe State of Vim</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Flattening ASTs and other compiler data structures (2023)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The post discusses data structure flattening, a technique for compilers that optimizes abstract syntax trees (ASTs) by using a single array with indices instead of pointers. - This method enhances performance by improving memory locality, reducing reference size, and simplifying memory management, resulting in a 2.4× speedup in a microbenchmark. - The technique is notably used in Rust projects and offers ergonomic benefits, such as easier memory management, and is compared to bytecode interpreters for further performance improvements.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cs.cornell.edu/~asampson/blog/flattening.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-11T00:00:00.000ZFlattening ASTs and other compiler data structures (2023)</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[De-smarting the Marshall Uxbridge Bluetooth speaker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://tomscii.sig7.se/2025/01/De-smarting-the-Marshall-Uxbridge</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-11T00:00:00.000ZDe-smarting the Marshall Uxbridge Bluetooth speaker</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenAI's bot crushed this seven-person company's web site 'like a DDoS attack']]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Triplegangers&#39; e-commerce site experienced a DDoS-like attack due to OpenAI&#39;s bot making tens of thousands of requests to scrape over 65,000 product pages. - The site lacked a properly configured robots.txt file to block such bots, leading to increased AWS costs and concerns about data security. - This incident underscores the importance of AI companies obtaining permission before data scraping and serves as a warning for small businesses to monitor for AI bot activity.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://techcrunch.com/2025/01/10/how-openais-bot-crushed-this-seven-person-companys-web-site-like-a-ddos-attack/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-11T00:00:00.000ZOpenAI&apos;s bot crushed this seven-person company&apos;s web site &apos;like a DDoS attack&apos;</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I've Acquired a New Superpower]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A Reddit user discovered a technique to easily spot differences in &quot;spot-the-difference&quot; puzzles by crossing their eyes to create a third, shimmering image.</li>
<li>This method allows differences to become more apparent, and the user felt it was like gaining a new skill or &quot;superpower&quot; after practicing.</li>
<li>The user shared this technique with others, encouraging them to try it by focusing on the middle image created when crossing their eyes.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://danielwirtz.com/blog/spot-the-difference-superpower</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-10T00:00:00.000ZI&apos;ve Acquired a New Superpower</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Visualizing All ISBNs]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Anna&#39;s Archive, the largest open library, has visualized all ISBNs to track the progress of book backups, revealing that only 16% of books are backed up so far.</li>
<li>A $10,000 bounty is offered for improving the visualization&#39;s zoomability, interactivity, and usability, with prizes for the top three submissions, and all code must be open source.</li>
<li>This initiative is crucial for preserving rare books, as Anna&#39;s Archive holds the largest open collection of book metadata.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://annas-archive.org/blog/all-isbns.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-10T00:00:00.000ZVisualizing All ISBNs</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Predictions Scorecard, 2025 January 01]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author provides an annual update on predictions made in 2018 about self-driving cars, robotics, AI, machine learning, and human space travel, with plans to make new predictions for 2026-2036.</li>
<li>Despite significant developments in AI and self-driving cars in 2024, full autonomy and the replacement of human jobs with AI remain distant, with remote human monitoring still necessary for self-driving cars.</li>
<li>Human spaceflight progress is slow, with SpaceX&#39;s Starship and NASA&#39;s Artemis facing delays, while Blue Origin&#39;s New Glenn is nearing launch, and suborbital tourism shows limited progress.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://rodneybrooks.com/predictions-scorecard-2025-january-01/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-10T00:00:00.000ZPredictions Scorecard, 2025 January 01</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I had to take down my course-swapping site or be expelled]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>JD Kaim, a computer science student, developed HuskySwap, an app designed to facilitate class spot trading among students at the University of Washington. - Despite its initial purpose as a class project, Kaim faced a &quot;Notice of Violation&quot; from the university when attempting to integrate the app with the official registration system. - The situation has generated mixed reactions, with some criticizing the university&#39;s actions and others providing support and advice to Kaim, who remains optimistic about future endeavors and job prospects.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.linkedin.com/posts/jdkaim_github-jdkaimhuskyswap-huskyswap-project-activity-7282609173316415488-1jdb</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-09T00:00:00.000ZI had to take down my course-swapping site or be expelled</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Luigi Mangione's account has been renamed on Stack Overflow]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Evan Carroll highlights the erasure of Luigi Mangione&#39;s identity on Stack Overflow, where his account was renamed to &quot;user4616250&quot; without clear justification, raising concerns about attribution under the Creative Commons license.</li>
<li>Carroll&#39;s inquiry into this issue resulted in a year-long ban from Stack Exchange, which he perceives as retaliatory, contrasting with other platforms like GitHub and LinkedIn that have not erased Mangione.</li>
<li>The situation underscores a unique stance by Stack Exchange and calls for fair treatment of Mangione, who has not been convicted of any crime.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://substack.evancarroll.com/p/the-erasure-of-luigi-mangione</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-09T00:00:00.000ZLuigi Mangione&apos;s account has been renamed on Stack Overflow</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[You don't have to pay the Microsoft 365 price increase]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Microsoft 365 has increased its subscription prices by approximately 40%, citing the integration of its AI tool, Copilot, though full access to Copilot requires an additional subscription. - Customers can avoid the price hike by selecting a hidden &quot;Microsoft 365 Classic&quot; plan, which retains the old pricing but is not openly advertised. - This situation highlights the use of &quot;dark patterns,&quot; where user interfaces are designed to manipulate consumer choices, raising ethical concerns about transparency and consumer rights.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.consumer.org.nz/articles/you-don-t-have-to-pay-the-microsoft-365-price-increase</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-09T00:00:00.000ZYou don&apos;t have to pay the Microsoft 365 price increase</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[LA wildfires force thousands to evacuate, NASA JPL closed]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Wildfires in Los Angeles County have led to the evacuation of 70,000 people and power outages affecting 400,000 residents, with over 1,000 structures destroyed and two fatalities reported. - California Governor Gavin Newsom declared a state of emergency, deploying the National Guard and firefighters, including prisoners, to address the crisis. - NASA&#39;s Jet Propulsion Laboratory (JPL) is under threat, with emergency measures in place, and contingency plans to transfer Mars mission control if necessary.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theregister.com/2025/01/08/los_angeles_fires_jpl/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-09T00:00:00.000ZLA wildfires force thousands to evacuate, NASA JPL closed</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A playable game of Tetris inside a PDF]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Modern desktop browsers&#39; PDF engines, such as PDFium and PDF.js, can support JavaScript with sufficient input/output capabilities to create simple games like Tetris.</li>
<li>The project demonstrates the versatility of PDF scripting by using annotation fields for monochrome pixels and a text input box for keyboard input, despite some limitations.</li>
<li>The PDF is available in ASCII format, allowing users to open it in a text editor or view the source code on GitHub.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://th0mas.nl/downloads/pdftris.pdf</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-09T00:00:00.000ZA playable game of Tetris inside a PDF</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Salesforce will hire no more software engineers in 2025, says Marc Benioff]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Salesforce plans to halt hiring more software engineers in 2025, attributing a 30% productivity increase to AI advancements, as stated by CEO Marc Benioff. - The company will focus on its AI product, Agentforce, and increase hiring of salespeople to communicate AI&#39;s value to clients. - Despite recent layoffs due to over-hiring during the pandemic, Benioff anticipates company growth over the next five years, with upcoming events like Japan Dreamin’ and Architect Dreamin’ on the horizon.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.salesforceben.com/salesforce-will-hire-no-more-software-engineers-in-2025-says-marc-benioff/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-09T00:00:00.000ZSalesforce will hire no more software engineers in 2025, says Marc Benioff</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steve Langasek, one of Ubuntu Linux's leading lights, has died]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Steve Langasek, a prominent contributor to the Linux community, particularly Debian and Ubuntu, passed away on January 1, 2025, at the age of 45. - Langasek was known for his significant contributions to system administration, software development, and package maintenance, impacting projects like Linux-PAM, Samba, and OpenLDAP. - His leadership, mentorship, and dedication to open-source principles were highly regarded, with notable figures like Mark Shuttleworth and Dustin Kirkland praising his technical insight and spirit.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://thenewstack.io/steve-langasek-one-of-ubuntu-linuxs-leading-lights-has-died/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-09T00:00:00.000ZSteve Langasek, one of Ubuntu Linux&apos;s leading lights, has died</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Factorio Blueprint Visualizer]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A new website has been developed to visualize Factorio blueprints using vector graphics (SVG), allowing users to import and modify blueprints artfully. - The tool supports Factorio 2.0 and Factorio: Space Age, with improved performance after being ported from Python to JavaScript. - Users can adjust drawing settings and utilize the tool for text-to-image generation or pen plotting, with contributions and feedback encouraged.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/piebro/factorio-blueprint-visualizer</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-09T00:00:00.000ZFactorio Blueprint Visualizer</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mistakes engineers make in large established codebases]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Working in large, established codebases, often with millions of lines of code and involving hundreds of engineers, presents significant challenges for software engineers. - A common mistake is inconsistency, where engineers ignore existing code patterns and implement features in isolation, which can lead to maintenance issues and hinder future improvements. - To effectively work within large codebases, engineers should research existing patterns, understand the codebase&#39;s production impact, be cautious with dependencies, and carefully remove unnecessary code to maintain quality and value.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/large-established-codebases/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-08T00:00:00.000ZMistakes engineers make in large established codebases</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Magic/tragic email links: don't make them the only option]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Magic Links provide a passwordless login method via email links, offering enhanced security but can be inconvenient due to email delays and multi-device use.</li>
<li>They may pose security risks by encouraging users to access personal emails on work devices, highlighting the need for alternatives like One-Time Passwords (OTPs).</li>
<li>For improved user experience, especially for tech-savvy users, passkeys are recommended as a more flexible and secure option.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://recyclebin.zip/posts/annoyinglinks/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-08T00:00:00.000ZMagic/tragic email links: don&apos;t make them the only option</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Operating System in 1,000 Lines – Intro]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The book guides readers through building a small operating system from scratch, covering essential functions like context switching, paging, and file operations in C, all within approximately 1,000 lines of code.</li>
<li>It emphasizes learning new debugging techniques, particularly for challenges like the boot process and paging, and provides downloadable examples on GitHub.</li>
<li>The book is licensed under CC BY 4.0, with code under the MIT license, and requires familiarity with C and a UNIX-like environment as prerequisites.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://operating-system-in-1000-lines.vercel.app/en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-08T00:00:00.000ZOperating System in 1,000 Lines – Intro</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cracking a 512-bit DKIM key for less than $8 in the cloud]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A study of the SPF (Sender Policy Framework), DKIM (DomainKeys Identified Mail), and DMARC (Domain-based Message Authentication, Reporting, and Conformance) records of the top 1 million websites revealed over 1,700 public DKIM keys shorter than 1,024 bits, which are deemed insecure. - Researchers successfully cracked a 512-bit DKIM key from redfin.com using Python and CADO-NFS for under $8 on a cloud server, demonstrating the vulnerability of short keys. - The study emphasizes the need for email providers to reject DKIM signatures with keys shorter than 1,024 bits, as some providers like Yahoo Mail, Mailfence, and Tuta accepted the compromised signature.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://dmarcchecker.app/articles/crack-512-bit-dkim-rsa-key</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-08T00:00:00.000ZCracking a 512-bit DKIM key for less than $8 in the cloud</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft disguises Bing as Google to fool inattentive searchers]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Microsoft is reportedly altering Bing&#39;s appearance to resemble Google&#39;s interface, potentially misleading users into using Bing unintentionally. - This strategy underscores Microsoft&#39;s challenges in competing with Google&#39;s substantial market share in the search engine industry. - Critics suggest that this tactic may prioritize Microsoft&#39;s business objectives over providing a genuine user experience.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.pcworld.com/article/2568916/microsoft-disguises-bing-as-google-to-fool-inattentive-searchers.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-08T00:00:00.000ZMicrosoft disguises Bing as Google to fool inattentive searchers</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Laid off for the first time in my career, and twice in one year]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author shares their experience of being laid off twice in one year, emphasizing the importance of maintaining good relationships with former employers and being prepared for job searches. - Key signs of potential layoffs include a lack of company vision, distractions, low product usage, and sudden company meetings, suggesting employees should stay vigilant. - Advice for those laid off includes updating resumes, filing for unemployment, leveraging LinkedIn and networking, understanding business models, and maintaining self-worth beyond employment.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://dillonshook.com/laid-off/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-08T00:00:00.000ZLaid off for the first time in my career, and twice in one year</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fidget]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Fidget is a Rust-based library designed for handling large-scale mathematical expressions, particularly for implicit surfaces, which are compact and support operations like union and intersection. - The library is structured into three layers: frontend (converts scripts to bytecode), backend (efficiently evaluates expressions), and demos, with support for SIMD (Single Instruction, Multiple Data) and automatic differentiation. - Fidget is now publicly available on GitHub under the MPL 2.0 license, with future plans for GPU integration and improved meshing, encouraging exploration and development by users.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.mattkeeter.com/projects/fidget/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-08T00:00:00.000ZFidget</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Servo Revival: 2023-2024]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Igalia revitalized the Servo project, an experimental browser engine initially created by Mozilla, by taking over its maintenance in January 2023. - Significant progress includes upgrading dependencies, enhancing continuous integration (CI) and tooling, expanding community support, and adding support for Android and OpenHarmony. - The project has raised over $24,500 in donations, with future goals of becoming a default web engine for Rust applications and developing a full-featured web browser, despite challenges like competition and funding.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blogs.igalia.com/mrego/servo-revival-2023-2024/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-08T00:00:00.000ZServo Revival: 2023-2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A day in the life of a prolific voice phishing crew]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Apple and Google have issued warnings about phone scams, yet a group called &quot;Crypto Chameleon&quot; exploits their services to conduct phishing attacks, resulting in significant financial losses for victims like cryptocurrency investor Tony, who lost $4.7 million.</li>
<li>The phishing gang uses sophisticated methods, including phishing kits that mimic authentication pages and fake Apple support calls, with roles such as Caller, Operator, Drainer, and Owner to execute their scams.</li>
<li>Despite internal betrayals, these cybercriminal groups continue to thrive on platforms like Telegram and Discord, with a focus on targeting wealthy individuals, particularly those with cryptocurrency assets.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/a-day-in-the-life-of-a-prolific-voice-phishing-crew/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-08T00:00:00.000ZA day in the life of a prolific voice phishing crew</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Streets GL – 3D OpenStreetMap]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://streets.gl/#47.35245,8.50958,21.25,42.00,459.10</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-08T00:00:00.000ZStreets GL – 3D OpenStreetMap</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bye-bye Windows gaming? SteamOS officially expands past the Steam Deck]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Lenovo&#39;s Legion Go S will be the first non-Valve device officially &quot;Powered by SteamOS,&quot; indicating a significant shift from Windows for gaming PCs.</li>
<li>The SteamOS version of the device will be more affordable, starting at $500, compared to the Windows version priced at $730.</li>
<li>Valve&#39;s plan to release a beta version of SteamOS for personal installs could challenge Windows&#39; dominance in PC gaming, promoting a broader shift towards Linux-based gaming.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/01/bye-bye-windows-gaming-steamos-officially-expands-past-the-steam-deck/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-08T00:00:00.000ZBye-bye Windows gaming? SteamOS officially expands past the Steam Deck</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How I program with LLMs]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author has integrated Large Language Models (LLMs) into their programming workflow, finding them beneficial for tasks like autocomplete, search, and chat-driven programming.</li>
<li>They are developing a tool called sketch.dev, a Go programming Integrated Development Environment (IDE) designed to enhance productivity by automating repetitive tasks and improving programming efficiency.</li>
<li>LLMs are effective in generating code drafts and handling exam-style questions, although they can occasionally make errors, and they shift tradeoffs in programming by enabling more specialized code and comprehensive tests.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://crawshaw.io/blog/programming-with-llms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-07T00:00:00.000ZHow I program with LLMs</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia's Project Digits is a 'personal AI supercomputer']]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Nvidia unveiled Project Digits at CES 2025, a compact &quot;personal AI supercomputer&quot; built on the Grace Blackwell hardware platform, featuring the GB10 Grace Blackwell Superchip.</li>
<li>The device offers up to a petaflop of performance, suitable for AI researchers, data scientists, and students, and can handle models with up to 200 billion parameters.</li>
<li>Priced at $3,000, Project Digits will be available in May and can connect to Windows or Mac PCs, running on Nvidia&#39;s Linux-based DGX OS.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/01/06/nvidias-project-digits-is-a-personal-ai-computer/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-07T00:00:00.000ZNvidia&apos;s Project Digits is a &apos;personal AI supercomputer&apos;</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A minimax chess engine in regular expressions]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Nicholas Carlini developed a chess engine named Regex Chess, utilizing 84,688 regular expressions to execute valid chess moves, showcasing regex&#39;s potential in unconventional applications. - The engine functions like a regular expression CPU, featuring a unique instruction set for stack operations, variable handling, and conditional execution, and supports parallel move generation. - Regex Chess employs a simplified minimax search to evaluate and score pseudo-legal moves, highlighting a creative exploration of regex capabilities, with the code accessible on GitHub for public viewing.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://nicholas.carlini.com/writing/2025/regex-chess.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-07T00:00:00.000ZA minimax chess engine in regular expressions</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zig's comptime is bonkers good]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Scott Redig explores Zig&#39;s &#39;comptime&#39; feature, which enhances productivity by enabling metaprogramming, allowing code execution during compile time. - He provides six perspectives on &#39;comptime&#39;, highlighting its ability to simplify code reading and debugging, and compares it to generics, partial evaluation, and code generation. - Redig concludes that Zig&#39;s &#39;comptime&#39; is both powerful and simple, recommending further exploration through Zig&#39;s official resources and standard library.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.scottredig.com/blog/bonkers_comptime/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-07T00:00:00.000ZZig&apos;s comptime is bonkers good</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia announces next-gen RTX 5090 and RTX 5080 GPUs]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Nvidia unveiled its next-generation RTX 50-series GPUs at CES, featuring the high-end RTX 5090 and RTX 5080, priced at $1,999 and $999, respectively. - The RTX 5090 includes 32GB of GDDR7 memory and 21,760 CUDA cores, offering double the speed of its predecessor, the RTX 4090, while the RTX 5080 provides 16GB of memory and is twice as fast as the RTX 4080. - The series introduces new DLSS 4 technology, improving performance and image quality, and will be available for laptops starting in March.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24337396/nvidia-rtx-5080-5090-5070-ti-5070-price-release-date</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-07T00:00:00.000ZNvidia announces next-gen RTX 5090 and RTX 5080 GPUs</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Used Meta AI, now Instagram is using my face on ads targeted at me]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://old.reddit.com/r/ABoringDystopia/comments/1ht7fft/used_meta_ai_to_edit_a_selfie_now_instagram_is/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-07T00:00:00.000ZUsed Meta AI, now Instagram is using my face on ads targeted at me</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NYC Congestion Pricing Tracker]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Congestion Pricing Tracker is a project by Benjamin and Joshua Moshes, under the supervision of Brown University Professor Emily Oster, focusing on congestion pricing in New York. - The project includes web scripts and stylesheets, indicating a comprehensive digital approach to presenting information. - The webpage is optimized for search engines (SEO) and includes a 404 error page for handling not found content.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.congestion-pricing-tracker.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-07T00:00:00.000ZNYC Congestion Pricing Tracker</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First time a Blender-made production has won the Golden Globe]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Latvian director Gints Zilbalodis&#39; indie animation &quot;Flow&quot; won the Golden Globe for best animated feature, highlighting a significant achievement for independent films. - &quot;Flow,&quot; created with a modest $3.7 million budget using Blender, a free software, competed against major studio productions, showcasing the democratization of animation. - The film&#39;s victory reflects the Golden Globes&#39; growing inclusivity towards international titles and could impact the animated feature Oscar race, challenging Disney&#39;s traditional dominance.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://variety.com/2025/film/columns/flow-golden-globe-win-independent-animation-1236266805/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-07T00:00:00.000ZFirst time a Blender-made production has won the Golden Globe</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I live my life a quarter century at a time]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>On January 5, 2000, Steve Jobs introduced the Aqua user interface of Mac OS X, including the Dock, at Macworld Expo, with significant contributions from an engineer based in Apple Cork, Ireland.</li>
<li>The engineer, who had previously worked on DragThing, was instrumental in transforming Bas Ording&#39;s prototypes into functional code for the Dock, but eventually resigned due to relocation pressures.</li>
<li>After leaving Apple, the engineer revived DragThing and PCalc, which continue to be popular, and discovered an unsigned Non-Disclosure Agreement (NDA) in their possession.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://tla.systems/blog/2025/01/04/i-live-my-life-a-quarter-century-at-a-time/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-07T00:00:00.000ZI live my life a quarter century at a time</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Triptych Proposals]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Triptych Proposals by Alexander Petros and Carson Gross aim to improve HTML&#39;s ability to handle network requests by supporting additional HTTP methods like PUT, PATCH, and DELETE in forms.</li>
<li>The proposals also include enabling buttons to make HTTP requests without forms and allowing partial page replacements, aligning HTML more closely with REST principles.</li>
<li>These proposals were introduced at Big Sky Dev Con and are detailed in the Triptych Polyfill on GitHub, with ongoing updates to the fetch and navigation specifications to support these enhancements.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://alexanderpetros.com/triptych/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-07T00:00:00.000ZTriptych Proposals</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tramway SDK – The Unholy Union Between Half-Life and Morrowind Engines]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A new free, open-source game engine is being developed, similar to popular engines like Unreal and Source, with support for open-world streaming. - The engine is optimized for modern hardware, offering high performance, but is not yet ready for production use. - The developer intends to complete several large projects using this engine, although the current name is likely temporary.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://racenis.github.io/tram-sdk/why.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-07T00:00:00.000ZTramway SDK – The Unholy Union Between Half-Life and Morrowind Engines</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roman Empire's use of lead lowered IQ levels across Europe, study finds]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A study indicates that the Roman Empire&#39;s use of lead in metalworking caused a 2- to 3-point drop in IQ across Europe during the Pax Romana.</li>
<li>Researchers used Arctic ice cores to track lead pollution from 500BC to AD600, showing a significant increase during the Roman Empire&#39;s peak.</li>
<li>The study suggests that widespread lead exposure may have contributed to the decline of the Roman Empire, with pollution levels decreasing post-Roman era but rising again during the Industrial Revolution.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.theguardian.com/science/2025/jan/06/roman-empires-use-of-lead-lowered-iq-levels-across-europe-study-finds</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-07T00:00:00.000ZRoman Empire&apos;s use of lead lowered IQ levels across Europe, study finds</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Federal Reserve Bank of NY "Doomsday Book" 2022 via FOIA [pdf]]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.crisesnotes.com/content/files/2023/12/NYFRB-2006.--Doomsday-Book--Searchable.pdf</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-07T00:00:00.000ZFederal Reserve Bank of NY &quot;Doomsday Book&quot; 2022 via FOIA [pdf]</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ending our third party fact-checking program and moving to Community Notes model]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Meta is prioritizing free expression by simplifying its content moderation systems, which have been criticized for being overly complex and restrictive. - The company is ending its third-party fact-checking program in the U.S. and introducing a Community Notes system, similar to X, to provide context to potentially misleading posts through user contributions. - Meta is reducing restrictions on political content, simplifying enforcement processes to focus on severe violations, and personalizing political content visibility based on user preferences, aligning with Mark Zuckerberg&#39;s vision of free expression.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://about.fb.com/news/2025/01/meta-more-speech-fewer-mistakes/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-07T00:00:00.000ZEnding our third party fact-checking program and moving to Community Notes model</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Doom, the Gallery Experience]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;DOOM: The Gallery Experience&quot; is an art parody game by bobatealee, set in a reimagined version of the classic DOOM (1993) level E1M1, where players explore a gallery setting. - The game is compatible with HTML5, Windows, mobile devices, and gamepads, and was created using the Construct game development platform. - It has received a 5-star rating and is praised for its cultural satire and design, with contributions from Filippo Meozzi and Liam Stone.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://bobatealee.itch.io/doom-the-gallery-experience</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-06T00:00:00.000ZDoom, the Gallery Experience</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[3blue1brown YouTube Bitcoin video taken down as copyright violation]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Grant Sanderson, known for his educational content, reported that his 2017 video on Bitcoin was removed, and his channel received a copyright strike.</li>
<li>The copyright claim was made by Chainpatrol on behalf of Arbitrum, despite the video being entirely Sanderson&#39;s original content.</li>
<li>This incident highlights ongoing issues with copyright enforcement on digital platforms, where creators can face strikes even for their own work.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/3blue1brown/status/1876291319955398799</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-06T00:00:00.000Z3blue1brown YouTube Bitcoin video taken down as copyright violation</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hitting OKRs vs. Doing Your Job]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>In Engineering, quarterly Objectives and Key Results (OKRs) often seem redundant as they tend to mirror product roadmaps, leading to potential conflicts if they differ.</li>
<li>Marketing finds OKRs beneficial for defining quarterly focus, aligning with project timelines, and highlighting new campaigns or audiences, while ongoing tasks are tracked by Key Performance Indicators (KPIs).</li>
<li>Effective OKRs should emphasize unique or changing priorities each quarter, rather than routine tasks, to avoid stagnation and ensure they provide value beyond the roadmap.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://jessitron.com/2025/01/05/hitting-okrs-vs-doing-your-job/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-06T00:00:00.000ZHitting OKRs vs. Doing Your Job</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Time-Series Anomaly Detection: A Decade Review]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The paper &quot;Dive into Time-Series Anomaly Detection: A Decade Review&quot; highlights the significance of anomaly detection in time-series data due to advancements in data collection and the rise of streaming data. - It introduces a process-centric taxonomy to categorize existing anomaly detection methods and offers a meta-analysis of research trends in this domain. - The research is pertinent to various fields, including cybersecurity, finance, law enforcement, and healthcare, and is accessible on arXiv under the Machine Learning category.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.20512</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-06T00:00:00.000ZTime-Series Anomaly Detection: A Decade Review</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stimulation Clicker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://neal.fun/stimulation-clicker/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-06T00:00:00.000ZStimulation Clicker</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple squandered the Holy Grail]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Apple Intelligence, intended to enhance smartphone capabilities, did not meet expectations, with some features like Math Notes praised, but others criticized for being underwhelming.</li>
<li>Despite promising privacy and security through on-device processing and Private Cloud Compute, the product felt more like a tech demo than a groundbreaking tool.</li>
<li>The open-source community often surpasses corporate efforts like Apple Intelligence, which left users with only marginal improvements instead of transformative advancements.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://xeiaso.net/blog/2025/squandered-holy-grail/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-06T00:00:00.000ZApple squandered the Holy Grail</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Engineer eats efficiently for $2.50 a day (2016)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>An engineer embarks on a 46-day challenge to spend under $2.50 daily on food, documenting meals, costs, and cooking experiments. - Inspired by cooking shows, he sets rules to ensure fun, nutrition, and sharing, exploring recipes like cabbage rolls and ramen while managing costs and minimizing waste. - The experiment involves creative cooking with limited ingredients, using techniques such as brining and sous vide, and experimenting with emulsifiers, ultimately sharing insights on cost-effective cooking.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://futureboy.us/blog/twofifty.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-06T00:00:00.000ZEngineer eats efficiently for $2.50 a day (2016)</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Killed by LLM]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;Killed by LLM&quot; is a project documenting AI benchmarks that have been surpassed by AI advancements, showcasing progress in areas like reasoning, mathematics, and coding. - The site, inspired by &quot;Killed by Google,&quot; provides details on original and final scores of benchmarks and the AI models that surpassed them, highlighting the rapid evolution of AI capabilities. - The term &quot;Saturation&quot; is used to describe benchmarks that can no longer effectively measure the cutting-edge capabilities of AI, and the project invites contributions to ensure data accuracy.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://r0bk.github.io/killedbyllm/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-06T00:00:00.000ZKilled by LLM</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Justin Trudeau resigns]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Liberal Party of Canada is initiating the process to select a new leader, as announced by party president Sachit Mehra.</li>
<li>Justin Trudeau, praised for his decade-long leadership and efforts in rebuilding and making the party more inclusive, will remain in his role until a successor is chosen.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/live/clyjmy7vl64t</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-06T00:00:00.000ZJustin Trudeau resigns</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Favorite blog in 2024?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42604529</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-06T00:00:00.000ZFavorite blog in 2024?</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Republishing my Simpsons fan site, twenty years later]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bingeclock.com/blog/post/republishing-my-simpsons-fan-site-twenty-years-later</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-06T00:00:00.000ZRepublishing my Simpsons fan site, twenty years later</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SrsRAN: Open-Source 4G/5G]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The srsRAN software suite is an open-source collection of 4G and 5G radio applications developed by SRS, implemented in C++ with minimal dependencies, and runs on Linux with standard hardware.</li>
<li>It is licensed under AGPLv3, which is a free software license ensuring that the software remains open-source.</li>
<li>The suite includes a 5G RAN (Radio Access Network) CU+DU (Central Unit and Distributed Unit) with a complete ORAN-native stack, and a 4G suite providing full network implementation for User Equipment (UE), eNodeB (evolved Node B), and EPC (Evolved Packet Core).</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/srsran</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-06T00:00:00.000ZSrsRAN: Open-Source 4G/5G</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Regulations Enabling 6 GHz Wi-Fi]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Several countries, including Argentina, Brazil, Canada, and the United States, have adopted the full 5925-7125 MHz spectrum range for use.</li>
<li>The European Union has adopted a portion of this range, specifically 5925-6425 MHz, with a focus on 5945-6425 MHz.</li>
<li>Other countries, such as Andorra, Austria, and Belgium, are considering adopting specific portions of the spectrum, while countries like Egypt, Oman, and Tunisia are still evaluating their options.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wi-fi.org/regulations-enabling-6-ghz-wi-fi</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-06T00:00:00.000ZRegulations Enabling 6 GHz Wi-Fi</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Uncut Currency]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.usmint.gov/paper-currency/uncut-currency/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-06T00:00:00.000ZUncut Currency</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The evolution of a structural code editor]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The post outlines the development of a structural editor for the eyg programming language, which treats code as a structured tree to prevent syntax errors and improve code comprehension.</li>
<li>Initially built with Gleam and Svelte, the editor now uses Gleam and Lustre, with a terminal version in Go, and has evolved to simplify the Abstract Syntax Tree (AST) for better navigation.</li>
<li>The latest version features a menu and icon-based user interface, enhancing usability across devices, and encourages user feedback to improve the coding experience.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://crowdhailer.me/2025-01-02/the-evolution-of-a-structural-code-editor/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-06T00:00:00.000ZThe evolution of a structural code editor</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
