<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0"
>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 19:09:18 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/story/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mistakes engineers make in large established codebases]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Working in large, established codebases, often with millions of lines of code and involving hundreds of engineers, presents significant challenges for software engineers. - A common mistake is inconsistency, where engineers ignore existing code patterns and implement features in isolation, which can lead to maintenance issues and hinder future improvements. - To effectively work within large codebases, engineers should research existing patterns, understand the codebase&#39;s production impact, be cautious with dependencies, and carefully remove unnecessary code to maintain quality and value.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.seangoedecke.com/large-established-codebases/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-08T00:00:00.000ZMistakes engineers make in large established codebases</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Magic/tragic email links: don't make them the only option]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Magic Links provide a passwordless login method via email links, offering enhanced security but can be inconvenient due to email delays and multi-device use.</li>
<li>They may pose security risks by encouraging users to access personal emails on work devices, highlighting the need for alternatives like One-Time Passwords (OTPs).</li>
<li>For improved user experience, especially for tech-savvy users, passkeys are recommended as a more flexible and secure option.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://recyclebin.zip/posts/annoyinglinks/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-08T00:00:00.000ZMagic/tragic email links: don&apos;t make them the only option</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Operating System in 1,000 Lines – Intro]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The book guides readers through building a small operating system from scratch, covering essential functions like context switching, paging, and file operations in C, all within approximately 1,000 lines of code.</li>
<li>It emphasizes learning new debugging techniques, particularly for challenges like the boot process and paging, and provides downloadable examples on GitHub.</li>
<li>The book is licensed under CC BY 4.0, with code under the MIT license, and requires familiarity with C and a UNIX-like environment as prerequisites.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://operating-system-in-1000-lines.vercel.app/en</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-08T00:00:00.000ZOperating System in 1,000 Lines – Intro</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Cracking a 512-bit DKIM key for less than $8 in the cloud]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A study of the SPF (Sender Policy Framework), DKIM (DomainKeys Identified Mail), and DMARC (Domain-based Message Authentication, Reporting, and Conformance) records of the top 1 million websites revealed over 1,700 public DKIM keys shorter than 1,024 bits, which are deemed insecure. - Researchers successfully cracked a 512-bit DKIM key from redfin.com using Python and CADO-NFS for under $8 on a cloud server, demonstrating the vulnerability of short keys. - The study emphasizes the need for email providers to reject DKIM signatures with keys shorter than 1,024 bits, as some providers like Yahoo Mail, Mailfence, and Tuta accepted the compromised signature.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://dmarcchecker.app/articles/crack-512-bit-dkim-rsa-key</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-08T00:00:00.000ZCracking a 512-bit DKIM key for less than $8 in the cloud</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Microsoft disguises Bing as Google to fool inattentive searchers]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Microsoft is reportedly altering Bing&#39;s appearance to resemble Google&#39;s interface, potentially misleading users into using Bing unintentionally. - This strategy underscores Microsoft&#39;s challenges in competing with Google&#39;s substantial market share in the search engine industry. - Critics suggest that this tactic may prioritize Microsoft&#39;s business objectives over providing a genuine user experience.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.pcworld.com/article/2568916/microsoft-disguises-bing-as-google-to-fool-inattentive-searchers.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-08T00:00:00.000ZMicrosoft disguises Bing as Google to fool inattentive searchers</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Laid off for the first time in my career, and twice in one year]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author shares their experience of being laid off twice in one year, emphasizing the importance of maintaining good relationships with former employers and being prepared for job searches. - Key signs of potential layoffs include a lack of company vision, distractions, low product usage, and sudden company meetings, suggesting employees should stay vigilant. - Advice for those laid off includes updating resumes, filing for unemployment, leveraging LinkedIn and networking, understanding business models, and maintaining self-worth beyond employment.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://dillonshook.com/laid-off/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-08T00:00:00.000ZLaid off for the first time in my career, and twice in one year</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fidget]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Fidget is a Rust-based library designed for handling large-scale mathematical expressions, particularly for implicit surfaces, which are compact and support operations like union and intersection. - The library is structured into three layers: frontend (converts scripts to bytecode), backend (efficiently evaluates expressions), and demos, with support for SIMD (Single Instruction, Multiple Data) and automatic differentiation. - Fidget is now publicly available on GitHub under the MPL 2.0 license, with future plans for GPU integration and improved meshing, encouraging exploration and development by users.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.mattkeeter.com/projects/fidget/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-08T00:00:00.000ZFidget</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Servo Revival: 2023-2024]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Igalia revitalized the Servo project, an experimental browser engine initially created by Mozilla, by taking over its maintenance in January 2023. - Significant progress includes upgrading dependencies, enhancing continuous integration (CI) and tooling, expanding community support, and adding support for Android and OpenHarmony. - The project has raised over $24,500 in donations, with future goals of becoming a default web engine for Rust applications and developing a full-featured web browser, despite challenges like competition and funding.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blogs.igalia.com/mrego/servo-revival-2023-2024/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-08T00:00:00.000ZServo Revival: 2023-2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A day in the life of a prolific voice phishing crew]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Apple and Google have issued warnings about phone scams, yet a group called &quot;Crypto Chameleon&quot; exploits their services to conduct phishing attacks, resulting in significant financial losses for victims like cryptocurrency investor Tony, who lost $4.7 million.</li>
<li>The phishing gang uses sophisticated methods, including phishing kits that mimic authentication pages and fake Apple support calls, with roles such as Caller, Operator, Drainer, and Owner to execute their scams.</li>
<li>Despite internal betrayals, these cybercriminal groups continue to thrive on platforms like Telegram and Discord, with a focus on targeting wealthy individuals, particularly those with cryptocurrency assets.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/a-day-in-the-life-of-a-prolific-voice-phishing-crew/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-08T00:00:00.000ZA day in the life of a prolific voice phishing crew</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Streets GL – 3D OpenStreetMap]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://streets.gl/#47.35245,8.50958,21.25,42.00,459.10</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-08T00:00:00.000ZStreets GL – 3D OpenStreetMap</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bye-bye Windows gaming? SteamOS officially expands past the Steam Deck]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Lenovo&#39;s Legion Go S will be the first non-Valve device officially &quot;Powered by SteamOS,&quot; indicating a significant shift from Windows for gaming PCs.</li>
<li>The SteamOS version of the device will be more affordable, starting at $500, compared to the Windows version priced at $730.</li>
<li>Valve&#39;s plan to release a beta version of SteamOS for personal installs could challenge Windows&#39; dominance in PC gaming, promoting a broader shift towards Linux-based gaming.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2025/01/bye-bye-windows-gaming-steamos-officially-expands-past-the-steam-deck/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-08T00:00:00.000ZBye-bye Windows gaming? SteamOS officially expands past the Steam Deck</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How I program with LLMs]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author has integrated Large Language Models (LLMs) into their programming workflow, finding them beneficial for tasks like autocomplete, search, and chat-driven programming.</li>
<li>They are developing a tool called sketch.dev, a Go programming Integrated Development Environment (IDE) designed to enhance productivity by automating repetitive tasks and improving programming efficiency.</li>
<li>LLMs are effective in generating code drafts and handling exam-style questions, although they can occasionally make errors, and they shift tradeoffs in programming by enabling more specialized code and comprehensive tests.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://crawshaw.io/blog/programming-with-llms</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-07T00:00:00.000ZHow I program with LLMs</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia's Project Digits is a 'personal AI supercomputer']]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Nvidia unveiled Project Digits at CES 2025, a compact &quot;personal AI supercomputer&quot; built on the Grace Blackwell hardware platform, featuring the GB10 Grace Blackwell Superchip.</li>
<li>The device offers up to a petaflop of performance, suitable for AI researchers, data scientists, and students, and can handle models with up to 200 billion parameters.</li>
<li>Priced at $3,000, Project Digits will be available in May and can connect to Windows or Mac PCs, running on Nvidia&#39;s Linux-based DGX OS.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/01/06/nvidias-project-digits-is-a-personal-ai-computer/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-07T00:00:00.000ZNvidia&apos;s Project Digits is a &apos;personal AI supercomputer&apos;</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A minimax chess engine in regular expressions]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Nicholas Carlini developed a chess engine named Regex Chess, utilizing 84,688 regular expressions to execute valid chess moves, showcasing regex&#39;s potential in unconventional applications. - The engine functions like a regular expression CPU, featuring a unique instruction set for stack operations, variable handling, and conditional execution, and supports parallel move generation. - Regex Chess employs a simplified minimax search to evaluate and score pseudo-legal moves, highlighting a creative exploration of regex capabilities, with the code accessible on GitHub for public viewing.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://nicholas.carlini.com/writing/2025/regex-chess.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-07T00:00:00.000ZA minimax chess engine in regular expressions</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zig's comptime is bonkers good]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Scott Redig explores Zig&#39;s &#39;comptime&#39; feature, which enhances productivity by enabling metaprogramming, allowing code execution during compile time. - He provides six perspectives on &#39;comptime&#39;, highlighting its ability to simplify code reading and debugging, and compares it to generics, partial evaluation, and code generation. - Redig concludes that Zig&#39;s &#39;comptime&#39; is both powerful and simple, recommending further exploration through Zig&#39;s official resources and standard library.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.scottredig.com/blog/bonkers_comptime/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-07T00:00:00.000ZZig&apos;s comptime is bonkers good</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia announces next-gen RTX 5090 and RTX 5080 GPUs]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Nvidia unveiled its next-generation RTX 50-series GPUs at CES, featuring the high-end RTX 5090 and RTX 5080, priced at $1,999 and $999, respectively. - The RTX 5090 includes 32GB of GDDR7 memory and 21,760 CUDA cores, offering double the speed of its predecessor, the RTX 4090, while the RTX 5080 provides 16GB of memory and is twice as fast as the RTX 4080. - The series introduces new DLSS 4 technology, improving performance and image quality, and will be available for laptops starting in March.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theverge.com/2025/1/6/24337396/nvidia-rtx-5080-5090-5070-ti-5070-price-release-date</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-07T00:00:00.000ZNvidia announces next-gen RTX 5090 and RTX 5080 GPUs</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Used Meta AI, now Instagram is using my face on ads targeted at me]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://old.reddit.com/r/ABoringDystopia/comments/1ht7fft/used_meta_ai_to_edit_a_selfie_now_instagram_is/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-07T00:00:00.000ZUsed Meta AI, now Instagram is using my face on ads targeted at me</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NYC Congestion Pricing Tracker]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Congestion Pricing Tracker is a project by Benjamin and Joshua Moshes, under the supervision of Brown University Professor Emily Oster, focusing on congestion pricing in New York. - The project includes web scripts and stylesheets, indicating a comprehensive digital approach to presenting information. - The webpage is optimized for search engines (SEO) and includes a 404 error page for handling not found content.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.congestion-pricing-tracker.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-07T00:00:00.000ZNYC Congestion Pricing Tracker</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First time a Blender-made production has won the Golden Globe]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Latvian director Gints Zilbalodis&#39; indie animation &quot;Flow&quot; won the Golden Globe for best animated feature, highlighting a significant achievement for independent films. - &quot;Flow,&quot; created with a modest $3.7 million budget using Blender, a free software, competed against major studio productions, showcasing the democratization of animation. - The film&#39;s victory reflects the Golden Globes&#39; growing inclusivity towards international titles and could impact the animated feature Oscar race, challenging Disney&#39;s traditional dominance.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://variety.com/2025/film/columns/flow-golden-globe-win-independent-animation-1236266805/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-07T00:00:00.000ZFirst time a Blender-made production has won the Golden Globe</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I live my life a quarter century at a time]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>On January 5, 2000, Steve Jobs introduced the Aqua user interface of Mac OS X, including the Dock, at Macworld Expo, with significant contributions from an engineer based in Apple Cork, Ireland.</li>
<li>The engineer, who had previously worked on DragThing, was instrumental in transforming Bas Ording&#39;s prototypes into functional code for the Dock, but eventually resigned due to relocation pressures.</li>
<li>After leaving Apple, the engineer revived DragThing and PCalc, which continue to be popular, and discovered an unsigned Non-Disclosure Agreement (NDA) in their possession.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://tla.systems/blog/2025/01/04/i-live-my-life-a-quarter-century-at-a-time/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-07T00:00:00.000ZI live my life a quarter century at a time</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Triptych Proposals]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Triptych Proposals by Alexander Petros and Carson Gross aim to improve HTML&#39;s ability to handle network requests by supporting additional HTTP methods like PUT, PATCH, and DELETE in forms.</li>
<li>The proposals also include enabling buttons to make HTTP requests without forms and allowing partial page replacements, aligning HTML more closely with REST principles.</li>
<li>These proposals were introduced at Big Sky Dev Con and are detailed in the Triptych Polyfill on GitHub, with ongoing updates to the fetch and navigation specifications to support these enhancements.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://alexanderpetros.com/triptych/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-07T00:00:00.000ZTriptych Proposals</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tramway SDK – The Unholy Union Between Half-Life and Morrowind Engines]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A new free, open-source game engine is being developed, similar to popular engines like Unreal and Source, with support for open-world streaming. - The engine is optimized for modern hardware, offering high performance, but is not yet ready for production use. - The developer intends to complete several large projects using this engine, although the current name is likely temporary.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://racenis.github.io/tram-sdk/why.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-07T00:00:00.000ZTramway SDK – The Unholy Union Between Half-Life and Morrowind Engines</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Roman Empire's use of lead lowered IQ levels across Europe, study finds]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A study indicates that the Roman Empire&#39;s use of lead in metalworking caused a 2- to 3-point drop in IQ across Europe during the Pax Romana.</li>
<li>Researchers used Arctic ice cores to track lead pollution from 500BC to AD600, showing a significant increase during the Roman Empire&#39;s peak.</li>
<li>The study suggests that widespread lead exposure may have contributed to the decline of the Roman Empire, with pollution levels decreasing post-Roman era but rising again during the Industrial Revolution.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.theguardian.com/science/2025/jan/06/roman-empires-use-of-lead-lowered-iq-levels-across-europe-study-finds</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-07T00:00:00.000ZRoman Empire&apos;s use of lead lowered IQ levels across Europe, study finds</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Federal Reserve Bank of NY "Doomsday Book" 2022 via FOIA [pdf]]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.crisesnotes.com/content/files/2023/12/NYFRB-2006.--Doomsday-Book--Searchable.pdf</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-07T00:00:00.000ZFederal Reserve Bank of NY &quot;Doomsday Book&quot; 2022 via FOIA [pdf]</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ending our third party fact-checking program and moving to Community Notes model]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Meta is prioritizing free expression by simplifying its content moderation systems, which have been criticized for being overly complex and restrictive. - The company is ending its third-party fact-checking program in the U.S. and introducing a Community Notes system, similar to X, to provide context to potentially misleading posts through user contributions. - Meta is reducing restrictions on political content, simplifying enforcement processes to focus on severe violations, and personalizing political content visibility based on user preferences, aligning with Mark Zuckerberg&#39;s vision of free expression.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://about.fb.com/news/2025/01/meta-more-speech-fewer-mistakes/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-07T00:00:00.000ZEnding our third party fact-checking program and moving to Community Notes model</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Doom, the Gallery Experience]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;DOOM: The Gallery Experience&quot; is an art parody game by bobatealee, set in a reimagined version of the classic DOOM (1993) level E1M1, where players explore a gallery setting. - The game is compatible with HTML5, Windows, mobile devices, and gamepads, and was created using the Construct game development platform. - It has received a 5-star rating and is praised for its cultural satire and design, with contributions from Filippo Meozzi and Liam Stone.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://bobatealee.itch.io/doom-the-gallery-experience</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-06T00:00:00.000ZDoom, the Gallery Experience</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[3blue1brown YouTube Bitcoin video taken down as copyright violation]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Grant Sanderson, known for his educational content, reported that his 2017 video on Bitcoin was removed, and his channel received a copyright strike.</li>
<li>The copyright claim was made by Chainpatrol on behalf of Arbitrum, despite the video being entirely Sanderson&#39;s original content.</li>
<li>This incident highlights ongoing issues with copyright enforcement on digital platforms, where creators can face strikes even for their own work.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/3blue1brown/status/1876291319955398799</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-06T00:00:00.000Z3blue1brown YouTube Bitcoin video taken down as copyright violation</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hitting OKRs vs. Doing Your Job]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>In Engineering, quarterly Objectives and Key Results (OKRs) often seem redundant as they tend to mirror product roadmaps, leading to potential conflicts if they differ.</li>
<li>Marketing finds OKRs beneficial for defining quarterly focus, aligning with project timelines, and highlighting new campaigns or audiences, while ongoing tasks are tracked by Key Performance Indicators (KPIs).</li>
<li>Effective OKRs should emphasize unique or changing priorities each quarter, rather than routine tasks, to avoid stagnation and ensure they provide value beyond the roadmap.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://jessitron.com/2025/01/05/hitting-okrs-vs-doing-your-job/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-06T00:00:00.000ZHitting OKRs vs. Doing Your Job</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Time-Series Anomaly Detection: A Decade Review]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The paper &quot;Dive into Time-Series Anomaly Detection: A Decade Review&quot; highlights the significance of anomaly detection in time-series data due to advancements in data collection and the rise of streaming data. - It introduces a process-centric taxonomy to categorize existing anomaly detection methods and offers a meta-analysis of research trends in this domain. - The research is pertinent to various fields, including cybersecurity, finance, law enforcement, and healthcare, and is accessible on arXiv under the Machine Learning category.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.20512</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-06T00:00:00.000ZTime-Series Anomaly Detection: A Decade Review</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stimulation Clicker]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://neal.fun/stimulation-clicker/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-06T00:00:00.000ZStimulation Clicker</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple squandered the Holy Grail]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Apple Intelligence, intended to enhance smartphone capabilities, did not meet expectations, with some features like Math Notes praised, but others criticized for being underwhelming.</li>
<li>Despite promising privacy and security through on-device processing and Private Cloud Compute, the product felt more like a tech demo than a groundbreaking tool.</li>
<li>The open-source community often surpasses corporate efforts like Apple Intelligence, which left users with only marginal improvements instead of transformative advancements.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://xeiaso.net/blog/2025/squandered-holy-grail/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-06T00:00:00.000ZApple squandered the Holy Grail</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Engineer eats efficiently for $2.50 a day (2016)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>An engineer embarks on a 46-day challenge to spend under $2.50 daily on food, documenting meals, costs, and cooking experiments. - Inspired by cooking shows, he sets rules to ensure fun, nutrition, and sharing, exploring recipes like cabbage rolls and ramen while managing costs and minimizing waste. - The experiment involves creative cooking with limited ingredients, using techniques such as brining and sous vide, and experimenting with emulsifiers, ultimately sharing insights on cost-effective cooking.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://futureboy.us/blog/twofifty.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-06T00:00:00.000ZEngineer eats efficiently for $2.50 a day (2016)</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Killed by LLM]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;Killed by LLM&quot; is a project documenting AI benchmarks that have been surpassed by AI advancements, showcasing progress in areas like reasoning, mathematics, and coding. - The site, inspired by &quot;Killed by Google,&quot; provides details on original and final scores of benchmarks and the AI models that surpassed them, highlighting the rapid evolution of AI capabilities. - The term &quot;Saturation&quot; is used to describe benchmarks that can no longer effectively measure the cutting-edge capabilities of AI, and the project invites contributions to ensure data accuracy.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://r0bk.github.io/killedbyllm/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-06T00:00:00.000ZKilled by LLM</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Justin Trudeau resigns]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Liberal Party of Canada is initiating the process to select a new leader, as announced by party president Sachit Mehra.</li>
<li>Justin Trudeau, praised for his decade-long leadership and efforts in rebuilding and making the party more inclusive, will remain in his role until a successor is chosen.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/live/clyjmy7vl64t</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-06T00:00:00.000ZJustin Trudeau resigns</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Favorite blog in 2024?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42604529</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-06T00:00:00.000ZFavorite blog in 2024?</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Republishing my Simpsons fan site, twenty years later]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bingeclock.com/blog/post/republishing-my-simpsons-fan-site-twenty-years-later</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-06T00:00:00.000ZRepublishing my Simpsons fan site, twenty years later</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[SrsRAN: Open-Source 4G/5G]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The srsRAN software suite is an open-source collection of 4G and 5G radio applications developed by SRS, implemented in C++ with minimal dependencies, and runs on Linux with standard hardware.</li>
<li>It is licensed under AGPLv3, which is a free software license ensuring that the software remains open-source.</li>
<li>The suite includes a 5G RAN (Radio Access Network) CU+DU (Central Unit and Distributed Unit) with a complete ORAN-native stack, and a 4G suite providing full network implementation for User Equipment (UE), eNodeB (evolved Node B), and EPC (Evolved Packet Core).</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/srsran</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-06T00:00:00.000ZSrsRAN: Open-Source 4G/5G</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Regulations Enabling 6 GHz Wi-Fi]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Several countries, including Argentina, Brazil, Canada, and the United States, have adopted the full 5925-7125 MHz spectrum range for use.</li>
<li>The European Union has adopted a portion of this range, specifically 5925-6425 MHz, with a focus on 5945-6425 MHz.</li>
<li>Other countries, such as Andorra, Austria, and Belgium, are considering adopting specific portions of the spectrum, while countries like Egypt, Oman, and Tunisia are still evaluating their options.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wi-fi.org/regulations-enabling-6-ghz-wi-fi</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-06T00:00:00.000ZRegulations Enabling 6 GHz Wi-Fi</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Uncut Currency]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.usmint.gov/paper-currency/uncut-currency/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-06T00:00:00.000ZUncut Currency</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The evolution of a structural code editor]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The post outlines the development of a structural editor for the eyg programming language, which treats code as a structured tree to prevent syntax errors and improve code comprehension.</li>
<li>Initially built with Gleam and Svelte, the editor now uses Gleam and Lustre, with a terminal version in Go, and has evolved to simplify the Abstract Syntax Tree (AST) for better navigation.</li>
<li>The latest version features a menu and icon-based user interface, enhancing usability across devices, and encourages user feedback to improve the coding experience.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://crowdhailer.me/2025-01-02/the-evolution-of-a-structural-code-editor/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-06T00:00:00.000ZThe evolution of a structural code editor</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Researchers design wearable tech that can sense glucose levels more accurately]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Researchers at the University of Waterloo have created a wearable device that uses radar technology to monitor glucose levels non-invasively, removing the need for needles.</li>
<li>The device, led by Dr. George Shaker, incorporates a radar chip, a meta-surface for enhanced signal accuracy, and AI algorithms for precise glucose readings.</li>
<li>Currently USB-powered, the device aims to become battery-operated for improved portability and may eventually monitor additional health metrics, with efforts underway to commercialize the technology.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://uwaterloo.ca/news/media/no-more-needles-tracking-blood-sugar-your-wrist</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-05T00:00:00.000ZResearchers design wearable tech that can sense glucose levels more accurately</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The day I taught AI to read code like a Senior Developer]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The AI was initially challenged with analyzing React codebases, approaching them like a novice developer. - By emulating senior developers&#39; strategies, such as focusing on core files and grouping changes by feature, the AI&#39;s code analysis improved significantly. - The focus is on enhancing code understanding rather than generation, with future plans to identify technical debt and comprehend team conventions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://nmn.gl/blog/ai-senior-developer</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-05T00:00:00.000ZThe day I taught AI to read code like a Senior Developer</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Web page annoyances that I don't inflict on you here]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://rachelbythebay.com/w/2025/01/04/cruft/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-05T00:00:00.000ZWeb page annoyances that I don&apos;t inflict on you here</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How Nat Traversal Works (2020)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>NAT traversal enables direct device connections despite the presence of Network Address Translators (NATs) and firewalls, using UDP-based protocols and direct socket control.</li>
<li>Techniques such as STUN (Session Traversal Utilities for NAT) help in discovering public IP addresses, while relays like TURN (Traversal Using Relays around NAT) or Tailscale&#39;s DERP are used for more challenging NATs.</li>
<li>The ICE (Interactive Connectivity Establishment) protocol optimizes connection paths by evaluating all possible options and selecting the most efficient one, ensuring robust NAT traversal with end-to-end encryption and authentication.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://tailscale.com/blog/how-nat-traversal-works</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-05T00:00:00.000ZHow Nat Traversal Works (2020)</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Guten: A Tiny Newspaper Printer]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://amanvir.com/guten</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-05T00:00:00.000ZGuten: A Tiny Newspaper Printer</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Self driving 1993 Volvo with open pilot]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A group of friends participated in the Carbage Run 2025 Winter edition, a 6-day rally through Sweden to the polar circle and back to Helsinki, requiring cars to be at least 20 years old and valued under €1000.</li>
<li>They transformed a 1993 Volvo 940 Estate into a self-driving vehicle using openpilot from comma.ai, incorporating modern components like electric power steering, a Bosch iBooster, and a Tesla radar sensor.</li>
<li>Future updates will include details on wiring, a custom Engine Control Unit (ECU), and plans to open-source the code, highlighting the project&#39;s innovative approach to retrofitting older vehicles with autonomous technology.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://practicapp.com/carbagepilot-part1/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-04T00:00:00.000ZSelf driving 1993 Volvo with open pilot</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[VoxelSpace: Terrain rendering algorithm in less than 20 lines of code (2020)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>NovaLogic&#39;s 1992 game Comanche utilized the Voxel Space engine, a 2.5D rendering technique based on ray casting, to create detailed terrains with shading and shadows.</li>
<li>The Voxel Space engine used height and color maps and a simple rendering algorithm, drawing vertical lines from back to front, which could be optimized for performance.</li>
<li>The engine&#39;s code is available under the MIT license, but the technology may still be patented in certain regions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/s-macke/VoxelSpace</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-04T00:00:00.000ZVoxelSpace: Terrain rendering algorithm in less than 20 lines of code (2020)</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to draw an outline in a video game]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article discusses five techniques for rendering outlines in Unity, a popular game development platform, highlighting their use in games like Sable and The Last of Us. - Techniques include Rim Effects, Vertex Extrusion, Blurred Buffer, Jump Flood Algorithm, and Edge Detection, each with unique advantages and trade-offs in terms of performance and visual quality. - The article provides insights into balancing these methods for optimal game aesthetics and gameplay support, with additional resources and credits for 3D models included.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ameye.dev/notes/rendering-outlines/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-04T00:00:00.000ZHow to draw an outline in a video game</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I'm quitting the Washington Post]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://anntelnaes.substack.com/p/why-im-quitting-the-washington-post</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-04T00:00:00.000ZI&apos;m quitting the Washington Post</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Perplexity got ads]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/damengchen/status/1875296442417607072</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-04T00:00:00.000ZPerplexity got ads</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I am rich and have no idea what to do]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://vinay.sh/i-am-rich-and-have-no-idea-what-to-do-with-my-life/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-03T00:00:00.000ZI am rich and have no idea what to do</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[iTerm2 critical security release]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>iTerm2 version 3.5.11, released on January 2, 2025, addresses a critical security vulnerability related to the SSH integration feature in previous versions. - The bug involved logging input/output to a file on the remote host, which could be accessed by others, affecting users of versions 3.5.6 to 3.5.10 and certain beta versions. - Users are advised to update to version 3.5.11 immediately, delete the /tmp/framer.txt file, and verify the update using the provided SHA-256 and PGP signature for security assurance.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://iterm2.com/downloads/stable/iTerm2-3_5_11.changelog</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-03T00:00:00.000ZiTerm2 critical security release</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can LLMs write better code if you keep asking them to “write better code”?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>In November 2023, a meme trend involved users asking ChatGPT to iteratively enhance images, which was then applied to code using Claude 3.5 Sonnet to improve a Python program. - Initial attempts with vague prompts like &quot;write better code&quot; showed some improvements, but structured prompt engineering with specific optimization goals led to significant performance enhancements. - The experiment underscored the importance of human oversight, as while Large Language Models (LLMs) can offer innovative ideas, they may also introduce subtle bugs during code optimization.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://minimaxir.com/2025/01/write-better-code/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-03T00:00:00.000ZCan LLMs write better code if you keep asking them to “write better code”?</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Advent of Code 2024 in pure SQL]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Thomas Neumann shared his experience of solving the Advent of Code 2024 challenges using pure SQL, highlighting it as an exercise in alternative problem-solving approaches. - Neumann successfully completed all challenges, though he noted SQL&#39;s limitations in handling complex algorithms and state updates, suggesting potential improvements for SQL&#39;s efficiency. - The blog post includes a detailed SQL solution for one challenge and discusses the possibility of enhancing SQL to better support complex algorithm execution directly within databases.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>http://databasearchitects.blogspot.com/2024/12/advent-of-code-2024-in-pure-sql.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-03T00:00:00.000ZAdvent of Code 2024 in pure SQL</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[U.S. appeals court strikes down FCC's net neutrality rules]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A U.S. Appeals Court has invalidated the FCC&#39;s net neutrality rules, which mandated equal treatment of internet traffic by broadband providers, citing the FCC&#39;s overreach of legal authority.</li>
<li>The decision references a Supreme Court ruling that restricts the powers of regulatory agencies, impacting the FCC&#39;s ability to enforce net neutrality.</li>
<li>FCC Chair Jessica Rosenworcel called for Congress to legislate net neutrality, while Commissioner Brendan Carr supported the court&#39;s decision as a check on regulatory overreach.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.tvtechnology.com/news/sixth-circuit-of-appeals-strikes-down-fccs-net-neutrality-rules</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-03T00:00:00.000ZU.S. appeals court strikes down FCC&apos;s net neutrality rules</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Be a property owner and not a renter on the internet]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article stresses the importance of owning your digital space instead of relying solely on major internet platforms, which often prioritize their growth over user interests. - Strategies for maintaining control over your online presence include owning a domain, diversifying content across multiple platforms, and building direct connections with audiences through email lists. - By creating your own web property, you ensure flexibility and resilience in your digital endeavors, reducing dependency on any single network.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://den.dev/blog/be-a-property-owner-not-a-renter-on-the-internet/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-03T00:00:00.000ZBe a property owner and not a renter on the internet</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[BlogScroll – An open directory of personal sites and blogs]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>BlogScroll is an open directory of personal sites and blogs, emphasizing digital spaces outside major technology companies, and is maintained on GitHub by Den Delimarsky. - Users can contribute to BlogScroll through GitHub or by emailing the creator, and updates are available via an RSS feed. - The directory includes various categories such as design-and-ux, personal, photo-video-production, and technology, showcasing contributions from numerous individuals.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blogscroll.com/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-03T00:00:00.000ZBlogScroll – An open directory of personal sites and blogs</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Alder Lake SHLX Anomaly]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Harold Aptroot discovered that the SHLX instruction on Intel&#39;s Alder Lake processors exhibits a &quot;medium latency&quot; of 3 cycles, which is atypical for left-shift operations that usually take 1 cycle. - This latency issue is specific to Alder Lake&#39;s performance cores and does not affect the efficiency cores, contradicting Intel&#39;s claims of a 1-cycle latency. - The latency varies based on the initialization of the shift count register, with 32-bit instructions or 64-bit instructions without immediates achieving 1-cycle latency, while 64-bit instructions with immediates result in 3-cycle latency.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://tavianator.com/2025/shlx.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-03T00:00:00.000ZThe Alder Lake SHLX Anomaly</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[One of my papers got declined today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://mathstodon.xyz/@tao/113721192051328193</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZOne of my papers got declined today</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MitmProxy2Swagger: Automagically reverse-engineer REST APIs]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>mitmproxy2swagger is a tool that converts mitmproxy captures into OpenAPI 3.0 specifications, facilitating the reverse-engineering of REST APIs by capturing application traffic. - The tool now supports HTTP Archive (HAR) files from browser Developer Tools, expanding its usability for developers. - Installation can be done using Python3 and pip or Docker, and the project employs tools like poetry, pre-commit, and pytest for development, with an MIT license.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/alufers/mitmproxy2swagger</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZMitmProxy2Swagger: Automagically reverse-engineer REST APIs</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The GPU, not the TPM, is the root of hardware DRM]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://mjg59.dreamwidth.org/70954.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZThe GPU, not the TPM, is the root of hardware DRM</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zasper: A Modern and Efficient Alternative to JupyterLab, Built in Go]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Zasper is a high-performance Integrated Development Environment (IDE) inspired by Jupyter, optimized for massive concurrency and minimal memory usage. - It is built with the Go programming language for enhanced concurrency and performance, offering both Electron and Web App versions, and is open-source under the AGPL-3.0 license. - Zasper supports REPL-style (Read-Eval-Print Loop) data applications and aims to expand beyond Jupyter Notebooks to support custom data applications, with full support on Mac and limited support on Linux.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/zasper-io/zasper</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZZasper: A Modern and Efficient Alternative to JupyterLab, Built in Go</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rails for everything]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Rails 8 is optimized for small projects and single developers, offering a comprehensive &quot;Getting Started with Rails&quot; guide to build full-featured applications.</li>
<li>SQLite is now production-ready in Rails 8, reducing the dependency on PostgreSQL or Redis, and includes basic continuous integration (CI) configuration with 2000 free GitHub action minutes.</li>
<li>The new authentication generator and straightforward deployment with Kamal make user sign-in and live app setup with SSL easier, promoting best practices.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://literallythevoid.com/blog/rails_for_everything.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZRails for everything</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Where to Work After 40?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42573875</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZWhere to Work After 40?</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My favourite computer ergonomics hack]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Jacob Vosmaer introduces &quot;The Beeper,&quot; a DIY device designed to encourage movement by beeping if the computer screen remains unlocked for too long. - The Beeper is composed of hardware (Adafruit Feather Huzzah ESP8266, switch, piezo buzzer), firmware (Lua script), and software that manages activation. - Despite its simplicity, the device effectively promotes regular movement, and Jacob acknowledges his wife&#39;s support in the project.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.jacobvosmaer.nl/0036-beeper/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZMy favourite computer ergonomics hack</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UBlockOrigin GPL code being stolen by team behind Honey browser extension]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://old.reddit.com/r/uBlockOrigin/comments/1hr6xjc/ubo_quick_filters_list_being_stolen_by_team/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZUBlockOrigin GPL code being stolen by team behind Honey browser extension</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blogs rot. Wikis wait]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The post contrasts the enduring nature of wikis with the transient nature of blogs, suggesting that by 2025, wikis will become more personal and meaningful.</li>
<li>Wikis are described as dynamic and reflective of the writer&#39;s evolving thoughts, whereas blogs are likened to static, forgotten storefronts.</li>
<li>The author is transitioning from a traditional website to a wiki format, indicating a shift in how personal content is managed and shared.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://j3s.sh/thought/blogs-rot-wikis-wait.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZBlogs rot. Wikis wait</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meta Wants More AI Bots on Facebook and Instagram]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Meta is set to launch AI bots on Facebook and Instagram to engage younger users and leverage its investment in generative AI technology. - These AI bots will have profiles and create content, functioning similarly to regular social media accounts, following Meta&#39;s acquisition of SocialAI. - This initiative reflects Meta&#39;s broader strategy of automating social interactions and content curation, aligning with trends seen in apps like Character.ai.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://nymag.com/intelligencer/article/meta-wants-more-ai-bots-on-facebook-and-instagram.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZMeta Wants More AI Bots on Facebook and Instagram</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My 25-year adventure in AI and ML]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Austin Z. Henley, an Associate Teaching Professor at Carnegie Mellon University, shares his 25-year journey in AI (Artificial Intelligence) and ML (Machine Learning), highlighting his transition from initial disinterest to active involvement through various projects.</li>
<li>His career path includes developing simple games, studying AI and neural networks, and applying decision trees and clustering during his PhD to analyze code editor data.</li>
<li>Henley joined Microsoft&#39;s program synthesis team in 2022, working on AI projects, including tools based on LLMs (Large Language Models), and continues to explore AI tools independently while teaching.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://austinhenley.com/blog/25yearsofai.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZMy 25-year adventure in AI and ML</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Happy New Year 2025]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42562750</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZHappy New Year 2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DOOM CAPTCHA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://doom-captcha.vercel.app/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZDOOM CAPTCHA</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Static search trees: faster than binary search]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article discusses the implementation and optimization of static search trees (S+ trees) for significantly faster searching of sorted data, achieving speeds 40 times faster than traditional binary search. - Optimization techniques such as batching, prefetching, and manual SIMD (Single Instruction, Multiple Data) are employed to enhance query throughput. - The article also explores various tree layouts, node sizes, and memory management strategies, with a discussion on future work like branchy search and interpolation search to further improve search efficiency.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://curiouscoding.nl/posts/static-search-tree/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZStatic search trees: faster than binary search</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[30% Drop In o1-Preview Accuracy When Putnam Problems Are Slightly Variated]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Putnam-AXIOM is a benchmark designed to assess large language models (LLMs) on advanced mathematical reasoning using problems from the Putnam Mathematical Competition. - The benchmark includes 236 original problems and a variation with 52 altered problems to avoid data contamination. - OpenAI&#39;s top-performing model achieved 41.95% accuracy on the original problems but experienced a significant performance drop of approximately 30% on the altered problems, highlighting challenges in adapting to variations.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://openreview.net/forum?id=YXnwlZe0yf&amp;noteId=yrsGpHd0Sf</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-01T00:00:00.000Z30% Drop In o1-Preview Accuracy When Putnam Problems Are Slightly Variated</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Databases in 2024: A Year in Review]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The database landscape in 2024 experienced significant changes, including major acquisitions, license shifts, and ongoing rivalries among key players like Redis, Elasticsearch, Databricks, and Snowflake. - DuckDB gained popularity for analytical queries, with integrations into Postgres, while notable releases included Amazon Aurora DSQL and Microsoft Garnet. - Acquisitions such as Tabular by Databricks and OrioleDB by Supabase were significant, and despite setbacks like OtterTune&#39;s closure, the industry remains dynamic with new projects and funding.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cs.cmu.edu/~pavlo/blog/2025/01/2024-databases-retrospective.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZDatabases in 2024: A Year in Review</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Books I Loved Reading in 2024]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The list features a diverse range of books, including historical, philosophical, scientific, and personal narratives, each offering unique insights and enriching experiences.</li>
<li>Highlights include Cicero&#39;s letters for insights into Roman life, Ben-Ari&#39;s works on computer science logic and program verification, and Steve Martin&#39;s memoir on comedic success.</li>
<li>The collection also includes philosophical explorations by Pierre Hadot and Nietzsche, Greek tragedies by Aeschylus, and literary works by Ursula Le Guin and Rabindranath Tagore.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://thoughts.wyounas.com/p/books-i-enjoyed-most-in-2024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZBooks I Loved Reading in 2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Terence Tao: One of my papers got declined today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://mathstodon.xyz/@tao/113721192051328193</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZTerence Tao: One of my papers got declined today</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[API Parrot – Automatically Reverse Engineer HTTP APIs]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>API Parrot is a new tool designed to simplify the automation of business processes by automatically identifying data correlations between API requests and providing a graphical flow representation. - It allows users to record requests, define inputs and outputs, and export these flows as JavaScript code, making the process more efficient than manual reverse engineering or using less optimal technologies like Robotic Process Automation (RPA). - The tool is built on Electron and is available for both Windows and Linux platforms, with a tutorial available for reverse engineering the USPS API.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://apiparrot.com/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZAPI Parrot – Automatically Reverse Engineer HTTP APIs</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FBI: Largest homemade explosives cache in agency history found in Virginia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://thehill.com/national-security/5061535-virginia-man-arrested-explosives/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZFBI: Largest homemade explosives cache in agency history found in Virginia</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Déjà vu: Ghostly CVEs in my terminal title]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Ghostty, a new terminal emulator, had a security vulnerability similar to one from 2003, allowing ASCII escape characters to execute commands like opening applications. - The issue was notably problematic with Zsh and Bash in vi mode, but Ghostty 1.0.1 has resolved this by disabling the feature by default. - Despite the security flaw, Ghostty is commended for its features, and the developer promptly addressed the issue, providing fixes and workarounds for users.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://dgl.cx/2024/12/ghostty-terminal-title</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZDéjà vu: Ghostly CVEs in my terminal title</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Large Concept Models: Language modeling in a sentence representation space]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The repository offers implementations for Large Concept Models (LCM), which utilize &quot;concepts&quot; as a higher-level semantic representation for language modeling.</li>
<li>LCM supports 200 text languages and 57 speech languages using the SONAR embedding space, and is trained for auto-regressive sentence prediction with methods like MSE regression and diffusion-based generation.</li>
<li>The repository provides installation instructions, data preparation, training, finetuning, and evaluation guidelines, and is released under the MIT license, using fairseq2 with UV and pip installation options.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/facebookresearch/large_concept_model</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZLarge Concept Models: Language modeling in a sentence representation space</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
