<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0"
>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 19:07:15 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/story/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A QR code that sends you to a different destination – lenticular and adversarial]]></title>
            <link>https://mstdn.social/@isziaui/113874436953157913</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-24T00:00:00.000ZA QR code that sends you to a different destination – lenticular and adversarial</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The State of Vim]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Following the death of Bram Moolenaar, Vim&#39;s founder, in 2023, the community has reorganized to ensure the continuation of Vim&#39;s development, with Christian Brabandt taking a more active role. The project is addressing challenges such as managing the Vim GitHub organization, updating the website, and considering changes like XDG support, while remaining in maintenance mode. VimConf 2024 in Tokyo highlighted international collaboration, with presentations in English and Japanese, and emphasized community input and careful testing over a single leader approach.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1002342/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-24T00:00:00.000ZThe State of Vim</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UI is hell: four-function calculators]]></title>
            <link>https://lcamtuf.substack.com/p/ui-is-hell-four-function-calculators</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-24T00:00:00.000ZUI is hell: four-function calculators</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Build It Yourself]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Armin Ronacher addresses the problem of dependency churn in software development, especially in JavaScript and Rust ecosystems, where frequent updates and numerous dependencies can lead to security vulnerabilities and complexity.
 He suggests a shift towards writing code with minimal dependencies, emphasizing the advantages of stable, self-written functions over extensive dependency graphs.
 Ronacher calls for a cultural change in both corporate and open-source communities to prioritize simplicity and stability in coding practices, which can lead to reduced maintenance and faster implementation.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://lucumr.pocoo.org/2025/1/24/build-it-yourself/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-24T00:00:00.000ZBuild It Yourself</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I made an open-source laptop from scratch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.byran.ee/posts/creation/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZI made an open-source laptop from scratch</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to improve your WFH lighting to reduce eye strain]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>To minimize eye strain while working from home, create a balanced lighting environment using natural light, sheer curtains, and flicker-free artificial lights. Implement the 20/20/20 rule: every 20 minutes, look at something 20 feet away for 20 seconds to relax your eyes. Complement your workspace with light-filtering curtains and desk lighting that matches monitor brightness, while also taking regular breaks to maintain overall health.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://rustle.ca/posts/articles/work-from-home-lighting</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZHow to improve your WFH lighting to reduce eye strain</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tailwind CSS v4.0]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Tailwind CSS v4.0 introduces a high-performance engine, achieving builds up to 5x faster and incremental builds over 100x faster, enhancing performance and flexibility for developers. The update includes modern CSS features such as cascade layers, color-mix(), and built-in container queries, along with a first-party Vite plugin for improved integration and simplified installation. New features like 3D transform utilities, expanded gradient APIs, and CSS-first configuration with design tokens as CSS variables make it easier and faster to build modern web projects, with an upgrade guide available for existing projects.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://tailwindcss.com/blog/tailwindcss-v4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZTailwind CSS v4.0</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Federal Court (Finally) Rules Backdoor Searches of Data Unconstitutional]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>A federal district court has ruled that backdoor searches of databases containing Americans&#39; private communications under Section 702 require a warrant, marking a significant legal decision in United States v. Hasbajrami. Despite Congress reauthorizing Section 702, evidence shows misuse by the FBI and intelligence community, with 3.4 million warrantless searches conducted in 2021, prompting calls for reform to ensure constitutional protections. The court&#39;s decision highlights the unconstitutional nature of warrantless searches under Section 702, urging Congress to mandate warrants for searches involving U.S. persons&#39; data before its expiration in 2026.</p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2025/01/victory-federal-court-finally-rules-backdoor-searches-702-data-unconstitutional</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZFederal Court (Finally) Rules Backdoor Searches of Data Unconstitutional</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Most Influential Papers in Computer Science History]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The list highlights seven seminal papers in computer science history, each contributing foundational concepts that underpin modern technology, such as the Turing Machine, information theory, and the relational database model.
 These papers introduced groundbreaking ideas like NP-completeness, TCP/IP, the World Wide Web, and PageRank, which have significantly influenced computation, communication, and internet development.
 Bonus mentions include influential works on Lisp, distributed systems, and the &quot;Attention Is All You Need&quot; paper, showcasing the evolution and diversity of computer science research.</p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://terriblesoftware.org/2025/01/22/the-7-most-influential-papers-in-computer-science-history/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZMost Influential Papers in Computer Science History</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[F-Droid's Progress and What's Coming in 2025]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>In 2024, F-Droid made notable advancements in decentralizing app distribution, enhancing its infrastructure, and expanding its ecosystem, largely due to community support and funding. Significant achievements included infrastructure upgrades and the expansion of tools like Repomaker and Mobifree, with over 7205 app updates and 402 new apps added. Looking forward to 2025, F-Droid plans to utilize an Open Technology Fund grant to further improve infrastructure and continue focusing on decentralizing app distribution and promoting open-source alternatives.</p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://f-droid.org/2025/01/21/a-look-back-at-2024-f-droids-progress-and-whats-coming-in-2025.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZF-Droid&apos;s Progress and What&apos;s Coming in 2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Understanding gRPC, OpenAPI and REST and when to use them in API design (2020)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>API design primarily uses two models: gRPC (Remote Procedure Call) and REST (Representational State Transfer), both often mapped to HTTP, with gRPC using HTTP/2 for efficient communication.
 REST APIs are known for their simplicity and stability, while gRPC offers efficient client libraries and server implementations, making it suitable for internal APIs or when using specific tools like Cloud Endpoints.
 OpenAPI, similar to RPC, requires constructing URLs from templates, exposing HTTP details, and may involve complex custom HTTP mappings, offering broader HTTP tool compatibility compared to gRPC.</p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/api-management/understanding-grpc-openapi-and-rest-and-when-to-use-them</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZUnderstanding gRPC, OpenAPI and REST and when to use them in API design (2020)</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NIH hit with freezes on meetings, travel, communications, and hiring]]></title>
            <link
      >https://www.science.org/content/article/trump-hits-nih-devastating-freezes-meetings-travel-communications-and-hiring</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZNIH hit with freezes on meetings, travel, communications, and hiring</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bun 1.2 Is Released]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Bun 1.2 is a significant update for JavaScript and TypeScript development, enhancing Node.js compatibility and adding built-in support for S3 and Postgres. The update introduces Bun.sql for SQL databases, a faster package manager, and a built-in test runner, alongside improved performance and new JavaScript features. Bun 1.2 also enhances bundling with HTML imports, standalone executables, and a new CSS parser, while remaining free and open-source with ongoing community contributions.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://bun.sh/blog/bun-v1.2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZBun 1.2 Is Released</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tech takes the Pareto principle too far]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Bobby Lockhart critiques the tech industry&#39;s reliance on the Pareto Principle and MVPs, which often result in unfinished products due to insufficient incentives to complete them.
 He contrasts this with the gaming industry&#39;s &#39;vertical slice&#39; approach, which focuses on creating a polished product from the start.
 Lockhart advocates for a craftsmanlike approach to software development, emphasizing the importance of completing and refining products for a polished final outcome.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://bobbylox.com/blog/tech-takes-the-pareto-principle-too-far/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZTech takes the Pareto principle too far</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I made a multiplayer shooter game in Lisp, here is my journey]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The game &quot;Wizard Masters,&quot; a multiplayer third-person shooter, was developed using Clojure, a Lisp dialect, and is available on CrazyGames. Clojure was chosen for its full-stack capabilities and interactive REPL system, while Babylon.js was used for graphics due to its features and community support. Challenges included complex networking with Clojure async libraries, state management with Clojure&#39;s immutability, and the lack of a strong Clojure game development community, highlighting the potential benefits of transitioning to mainstream engines like Unity or Unreal for future projects.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ertu.dev/posts/i-made-an-online-shooter-game-in-lisp/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZI made a multiplayer shooter game in Lisp, here is my journey</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trae: An AI-powered IDE by ByteDance]]></title>
            <link>https://www.trae.ai/home</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZTrae: An AI-powered IDE by ByteDance</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Foundations of Large Language Models]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The book &quot;Foundations of Large Language Models&quot; by Tong Xiao and Jingbo Zhu explores key concepts such as pre-training, generative models, prompting techniques, and alignment methods in large language models. It targets college students, professionals, and practitioners in the field of natural language processing, making it a valuable resource for those interested in Computation and Language, Artificial Intelligence, and Machine Learning. The book is available for further reading on arXiv under the identifier 2501.09223 [cs.CL].</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.09223</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZFoundations of Large Language Models</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hacking Subaru: Tracking and Controlling Cars via the Starlink Admin Panel]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>A security vulnerability in Subaru&#39;s STARLINK service was discovered on November 20, 2024, allowing unauthorized access to vehicles and customer accounts in the US, Canada, and Japan. The flaw enabled attackers to remotely control vehicles and access personal information using minimal data, such as a last name and ZIP code, due to issues in the STARLINK admin panel. The vulnerability was reported and patched within 24 hours without any malicious exploitation, underscoring the challenges in securing connected car systems due to broad access permissions.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://samcurry.net/hacking-subaru</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZHacking Subaru: Tracking and Controlling Cars via the Starlink Admin Panel</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Where is London's most central sheep?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Vauxhall City Farm, established in 1976, is the closest city farm to central London, located just over a mile from Trafalgar Square.
 The farm houses several sheep, including a Shetland and a Herdwick named Daffodil, showcasing the rural charm within the urban environment.
 Spitalfields City Farm, the second closest to central London, hosts a Herdwick ewe named Beatrix and several Castlemilk Moorits, emphasizing the unique appeal of city farms in London.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://diamondgeezer.blogspot.com/2025/01/londons-most-central-sheep.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZWhere is London&apos;s most central sheep?</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ross Ulbricht granted a full pardon]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Ross has been granted a full pardon by former President Donald Trump, resulting in his release.
 The pardon has been met with significant gratitude, with Trump being commended for fulfilling his promise.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/Free_Ross/status/1881851923005165704</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-22T00:00:00.000ZRoss Ulbricht granted a full pardon</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stargate Project: SoftBank, OpenAI, Oracle, MGX to build data centers]]></title>
            <link
      >https://apnews.com/article/trump-ai-openai-oracle-softbank-son-altman-ellison-be261f8a8ee07a0623d4170397348c41</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-22T00:00:00.000ZStargate Project: SoftBank, OpenAI, Oracle, MGX to build data centers</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is anyone doing anything cool with tiny language models?]]></title>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42784365</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-22T00:00:00.000ZIs anyone doing anything cool with tiny language models?</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hunyuan3D 2.0 – High-Resolution 3D Assets Generation]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Hunyuan3D Studio has launched 3D generation capabilities on their website and released inference code and pretrained models for Hunyuan3D 2.0.
 Hunyuan3D 2.0 is an advanced system for creating high-resolution 3D assets, featuring a shape generation model (Hunyuan3D-DiT) and a texture synthesis model (Hunyuan3D-Paint), offering superior geometry details and texture quality.
 Users can access Hunyuan3D 2.0 through code or the Gradio App, with more information available on their official site and open-source plan.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/Tencent/Hunyuan3D-2</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-22T00:00:00.000ZHunyuan3D 2.0 – High-Resolution 3D Assets Generation</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mastercard DNS error went unnoticed for years]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>MasterCard resolved a DNS (Domain Name System) error that could have led to traffic interception by registering an unused domain, which had been a vulnerability for nearly five years. Security researcher Philippe Caturegli identified the issue, involving a typo in a DNS server name, and registered the domain for $300 to prevent potential misuse, despite MasterCard&#39;s claim of no security risk. Caturegli&#39;s actions and public disclosure highlighted potential vulnerabilities and criticized MasterCard&#39;s response, revealing a history of similar DNS typos with the domain.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/mastercard-dns-error-went-unnoticed-for-years/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-22T00:00:00.000ZMastercard DNS error went unnoticed for years</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What are these bumps on the top of a pull-tab can?]]></title>
            <link>https://old.reddit.com/r/whatisthisthing/comments/1i5ztq4/comment/m8a7m8m/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-22T00:00:00.000ZWhat are these bumps on the top of a pull-tab can?</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DHS removes all members of cyber security advisory boards, halts investigations]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The splash screen&#39;s minimal styles are defined, with additional styles located in a separate CSS file, ensuring a consistent and optimized user interface.
 The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) has ended all advisory committee memberships, impacting cybersecurity panels such as the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA).
 The Cyber Safety Review Board&#39;s investigation into the Salt Typhoon incident has been discontinued, indicating a halt in progress on this cybersecurity issue.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://bsky.app/profile/ericjgeller.com/post/3lgbpqmxeok2f</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-22T00:00:00.000ZDHS removes all members of cyber security advisory boards, halts investigations</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Isolating complexity is the essence of successful abstractions]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Complexity in software development should be managed and isolated rather than eliminated, as emphasized by Fred Hebert. In microservices, complexity is often hidden within individual services, while programming languages like Rust and TypeScript manage complexity through type systems and tools like Rust&#39;s borrow checker. Rust and TypeScript are favored by developers for their ability to reveal and manage complexity, allowing for successful abstractions by isolating complexity in well-defined areas.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://v5.chriskrycho.com/journal/essence-of-successful-abstractions/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-22T00:00:00.000ZIsolating complexity is the essence of successful abstractions</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My Struggle with Doom Scrolling]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The author addresses their doom scrolling habit by removing distracting apps like YouTube and Instagram and disabling the browser on their phone. They experienced some inconveniences, such as limited access to services, but found it beneficial for setting boundaries and reducing distractions. Reintroducing a restricted browser with a minimal user interface helped them regain control over media consumption, leading to more reading time and a calmer mindset.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://allthatjazz.me/posts/doom-scrolling-struggles</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-22T00:00:00.000ZMy Struggle with Doom Scrolling</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Tyranny of Structurelessness (1970)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Jo Freeman, also known as Joreen, critiques the concept of &quot;structurelessness&quot; in the women&#39;s liberation movement, arguing that all groups form structures, whether formal or informal. The article highlights issues with informal structures, such as elitism and lack of accountability, and suggests principles for democratic structuring. Emphasizes the necessity of formal structures to prevent power imbalances and to help the movement achieve its goals effectively and inclusively.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.jofreeman.com/joreen/tyranny.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-22T00:00:00.000ZThe Tyranny of Structurelessness (1970)</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[0-click deanonymization attack targeting Signal, Discord, other platforms]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>A 15-year-old high school student discovered a 0-click deanonymization attack using Cloudflare&#39;s caching system, which can locate users within a 250-mile radius. This vulnerability affects popular apps like Signal and Discord, enabling attackers to track users without their consent. Despite reporting the issue, only a related bug was patched by Cloudflare, leaving the core vulnerability unaddressed, highlighting the need for users, particularly journalists and activists, to be vigilant about their privacy.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://gist.github.com/hackermondev/45a3cdfa52246f1d1201c1e8cdef6117</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-21T00:00:00.000Z0-click deanonymization attack targeting Signal, Discord, other platforms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Startup Winter: Hacker News Lost Its Faith]]></title>
            <link>https://www.vincentschmalbach.com/startup-winter-hacker-news-lost-its-faith/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-21T00:00:00.000ZStartup Winter: Hacker News Lost Its Faith</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reverse engineering Call of Duty anti-cheat]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The Treyarch Anti-Cheat (TAC) in Black Ops Cold War is a user-mode anti-cheat system, lacking the kernel-mode component found in Modern Warfare&#39;s Ricochet. TAC employs Arxan for obfuscation, which complicates reverse engineering through techniques like runtime executable decryption, executable checksums, and pointer encryption. Key anti-cheat features include detection of API hooking, debug registers, network traffic monitoring, and external overlays, alongside various anti-debugging techniques and custom syscall stubs to bypass hooks.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ssno.cc/posts/reversing-tac-1-4-2025/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-21T00:00:00.000ZReverse engineering Call of Duty anti-cheat</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Did Elon Musk Appear to Sieg Heil at Trump Inauguration?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk was observed making a gesture at Trump&#39;s inauguration that some interpreted as a Nazi salute, leading to social media controversy. The Anti-Defamation League (ADL) suggested the gesture was likely an awkward moment rather than an intentional salute, with some attributing it to Musk&#39;s Asperger&#39;s syndrome. Musk responded to the controversy with a laughing emoji and expressed enthusiasm about Trump&#39;s mention of Mars, which aligns with his space exploration goals.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.jpost.com/international/article-838444</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-21T00:00:00.000ZDid Elon Musk Appear to Sieg Heil at Trump Inauguration?</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk appears to make back-to-back fascist salutes at inauguration rally]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk faced backlash for making a gesture resembling a fascist-style salute during Donald Trump&#39;s inauguration celebrations, which some interpreted as a Nazi salute.
 The Anti-Defamation League acknowledged the gesture&#39;s resemblance to a Nazi salute but later suggested it was an awkward moment of enthusiasm, drawing criticism from Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez.
 Musk&#39;s actions were celebrated by some far-right figures, fueling debates about his political affiliations and intentions.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2025/jan/20/trump-elon-musk-salute</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-21T00:00:00.000ZElon Musk appears to make back-to-back fascist salutes at inauguration rally</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meta Censoring '#Democrat' on Instagram]]></title>
            <link>https://mstdn.chrisalemany.ca/@chris/113864600222476627</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-21T00:00:00.000ZMeta Censoring &apos;#Democrat&apos; on Instagram</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Organize local communities without Facebook?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The individual is seeking to transition local community interactions from Facebook to a self-hosted, federated platform, which allows for decentralized control and management.
 They are looking for off-the-shelf solutions or collaborators to facilitate this move, indicating a need for accessible and customizable options.
 The context involves rural areas with multiple small towns, each with a population of around 50,000, highlighting the importance of connectivity and community engagement.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42779776</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-21T00:00:00.000ZOrganize local communities without Facebook?</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metacognitive laziness: Effects of generative AI on learning motivation]]></title>
            <link>https://bera-journals.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/bjet.13544</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-21T00:00:00.000ZMetacognitive laziness: Effects of generative AI on learning motivation</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Official DeepSeek R1 Now on Ollama]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>DeepSeek has introduced its first-generation reasoning models, which perform on par with OpenAI-o1 in tasks involving math, code, and reasoning. The models vary significantly in size, from 1.5 billion to 671 billion parameters, indicating diverse storage needs. These models are accessible under the MIT License, allowing for broad usage and modification.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ollama.com/library/deepseek-r1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-21T00:00:00.000ZOfficial DeepSeek R1 Now on Ollama</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[People are bad at reporting what they eat. That's a problem for dietary research]]></title>
            <link
      >https://www.science.org/content/article/people-are-bad-reporting-what-they-eat-s-problem-dietary-research</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-21T00:00:00.000ZPeople are bad at reporting what they eat. That&apos;s a problem for dietary research</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ROCm Device Support Wishlist]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>ROCm is gathering community feedback to determine which GPUs to support in future updates, with current compatibility details available on their website. Users are advocating for broader support, particularly for older and consumer-grade GPUs, and improved integration with Windows systems. There is a strong demand for consistent support across all architectures, emphasizing the significance of VRAM for AI applications, and calls for enhancements in AMD&#39;s APU support and a development process similar to NVIDIA&#39;s CUDA.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/ROCm/ROCm/discussions/4276</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-21T00:00:00.000ZROCm Device Support Wishlist</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ruff: Python linter and code formatter written in Rust]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Ruff DocsPlayground is a Python linter and code formatter written in Rust, offering speeds 10-100 times faster than traditional tools like Flake8 and Black. It supports Python 3.13, integrates with editors such as VS Code, and can replace multiple tools like Flake8, Black, and isort, while being monorepo-friendly. Ruff is widely adopted in major projects like Apache Airflow, FastAPI, and Pandas, and is available for installation via pip, pipx, and other package managers, with configuration support through pyproject.toml.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/astral-sh/ruff</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-21T00:00:00.000ZRuff: Python linter and code formatter written in Rust</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kimi K1.5: Scaling Reinforcement Learning with LLMs]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Kimi k1.5 is a cutting-edge multi-modal model that significantly outperforms GPT-4o and Claude Sonnet 3.5 in short-chain-of-thought (CoT) tasks, with improvements up to 550% on benchmarks such as AIME, MATH-500, and LiveCodeBench.
 It matches OpenAI&#39;s o1 in long-CoT performance across various modalities, utilizing reinforcement learning with long context scaling and enhanced policy optimization, while avoiding complex methods like Monte Carlo tree search.
 Kimi k1.5 is trained on both text and vision data, allowing for joint reasoning, and will soon be accessible via the Kimi OpenPlatform at <a href="https://kimi.ai">https://kimi.ai</a>.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/MoonshotAI/Kimi-k1.5</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-21T00:00:00.000ZKimi K1.5: Scaling Reinforcement Learning with LLMs</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Authors seek Meta's torrent client logs and seeding data in AI piracy probe]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Meta is facing a lawsuit for allegedly using pirated materials, specifically copyrighted books from LibGen, to train its AI models via BitTorrent.
 Authors, including Richard Kadrey and Sarah Silverman, accuse Meta of copyright infringement, while Meta claims its actions fall under fair use.
 The court has permitted new allegations about Meta&#39;s torrenting activities, with authors seeking access to Meta&#39;s torrent client logs and seeding data, underscoring the legal challenges surrounding AI training data and copyright issues.</p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://torrentfreak.com/authors-seek-metas-torrent-client-logs-and-seeding-data-in-ai-piracy-probe-250120/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-21T00:00:00.000ZAuthors seek Meta&apos;s torrent client logs and seeding data in AI piracy probe</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Gives Nazi Salute During Inauguration Speech]]></title>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e2bbb-6Clhs</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-21T00:00:00.000ZElon Gives Nazi Salute During Inauguration Speech</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It's time to make computing personal again]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The article highlights the decline of personal computing freedom due to surveillance capitalism and Digital Rights Management (DRM), which have transferred control from users to corporations.
 It contrasts the past era of personal computing, which offered more user freedom, with today&#39;s tech environment dominated by business models that erode privacy.
 The author advocates for reclaiming digital autonomy through supporting open-source projects, pushing for privacy legislation, and reforming DRM laws to restore personal computing values.</p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.vintagecomputing.com/index.php/archives/3292/the-pc-is-dead-its-time-to-make-computing-personal-again</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-20T00:00:00.000ZIt&apos;s time to make computing personal again</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DeepSeek-R1]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>DeepSeek-R1 and DeepSeek-R1-Zero are first-generation reasoning models, with DeepSeek-R1 addressing issues like repetition and language mixing seen in DeepSeek-R1-Zero.
 The models, including six distilled versions, are open-sourced, with DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Qwen-32B achieving state-of-the-art results in reasoning, code, and math tasks.
 These models are available for download on HuggingFace, and users can interact with them via a chat website or an OpenAI-Compatible API, with instructions for local deployment provided.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/deepseek-ai/DeepSeek-R1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-20T00:00:00.000ZDeepSeek-R1</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UK's hardware talent is being wasted]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The UK is experiencing a talent drain as top engineering graduates from prestigious universities face lower salaries compared to Silicon Valley, prompting many to switch to higher-paying fields like consulting or finance. This talent misallocation hinders innovation and economic growth, with issues such as geographical constraints, lack of venture capital for hardware, and stagnant traditional engineering firms contributing to the problem. The UK risks losing its best talent to overseas markets, missing the chance to create tech giants, and must act now to leverage its research institutions and engineering talent for a hardware revolution.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://josef.cn/blog/uk-talent</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-20T00:00:00.000ZUK&apos;s hardware talent is being wasted</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reverse Engineering Bambu Connect]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The guide discusses extracting a private key from the Bambu Connect app, an Electron application with known security vulnerabilities. Users are cautioned that the guide may be incomplete or outdated and should be followed at their own risk. The process involves using tools like Ghidra and asarfix to locate and decrypt the obfuscated private key and certificates, with a Python script provided for extraction.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://wiki.rossmanngroup.com/wiki/Reverse_Engineering_Bambu_Connect</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-20T00:00:00.000ZReverse Engineering Bambu Connect</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FrontierMath was funded by OpenAI]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The post highlights a lack of transparency in the collaboration between OpenAI and FrontierMath, with funding details only disclosed after a delay, causing confusion among contributors.
 Concerns are raised about OpenAI&#39;s potential access to and use of the dataset for training, despite verbal agreements suggesting otherwise, emphasizing the need for written agreements.
 The discussion underscores the importance of transparency and trust in collaborations, especially those involving AI capabilities, with commitments to improve transparency in future projects.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/cu2E8wgmbdZbqeWqb/meemi-s-shortform</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-20T00:00:00.000ZFrontierMath was funded by OpenAI</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why is Git Autocorrect too fast for Formula One drivers?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Git&#39;s autocorrect feature executes a mistyped command after a default delay of 0.1 seconds, which is often too quick for users to cancel. Introduced in 2008, the feature uses a modified Levenshtein distance algorithm to guess the intended command, but defaults to not running any command if mistyped. A proposed patch suggests interpreting a setting of &quot;1&quot; as &quot;immediately&quot; to enhance usability, allowing users to configure the delay or prompt for confirmation.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.gitbutler.com/why-is-git-autocorrect-too-fast-for-formula-one-drivers/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-20T00:00:00.000ZWhy is Git Autocorrect too fast for Formula One drivers?</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I Met Paul Graham Once]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The author attended Y Combinator in 2015, where they met Paul Graham and received advice on their startup, Appcanary, which was later acquired by GitHub.
 The author, now a transgender woman, expresses concern over Paul Graham&#39;s recent essay on &quot;Wokeness,&quot; feeling it reflects a rejection of inclusivity in the tech industry.
 The author is worried about increasing intolerance and potential discrimination in the tech industry but remains committed to living with respect and kindness.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://okayfail.com/2025/i-met-pg-once.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-20T00:00:00.000ZI Met Paul Graham Once</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Escape the walled garden and algorithm black boxes with RSS feeds]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>RSS (Really Simple Syndication) and Atom provide decentralized alternatives to centralized social media, allowing users to control their content consumption. Feed readers such as Miniflux, NetNewsWire, and Newsboat enable subscriptions to diverse content sources, including YouTube channels, podcasts, and blogs. Tools like PolitePol can create feeds for websites lacking them, promoting user autonomy in media consumption.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.johnwalker.nl/posts/escape-the-walled-garden-with-rss</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-20T00:00:00.000ZEscape the walled garden and algorithm black boxes with RSS feeds</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Please don't force dark mode]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Website designers are advised not to enforce dark mode on users, as it can cause eye strain, especially with high contrast settings like white text on a black background. The Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) currently suggest a minimum contrast ratio but do not address maximum contrast, which may lead to discomfort; this might be addressed in the upcoming WCAG 3.0. Dark mode is beneficial in specific scenarios, such as reading on OLED screens in dark environments or coding with Integrated Development Environments (IDEs) that offer comfortable contrast settings.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://iamvishnu.com/posts/please-dont-force-dark-mode</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-20T00:00:00.000ZPlease don&apos;t force dark mode</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TikTok goes dark in the US]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>TikTok experienced a temporary shutdown in the U.S. due to a federal ban, but service began to be restored by midday Sunday.
 The ban was driven by concerns over potential Chinese surveillance, with bipartisan support for requiring ByteDance, TikTok&#39;s owner, to sell the app.
 President-elect Donald Trump suggested delaying the ban and proposed a joint venture with U.S. ownership as a potential solution, while alternative apps gained popularity during the ban.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://techcrunch.com/2025/01/18/tiktok-goes-dark-in-the-u-s/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-19T00:00:00.000ZTikTok goes dark in the US</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kalman Filter Tutorial]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>KalmanFilter.NET provides a tutorial on the Kalman Filter, a mathematical tool for estimating and predicting system states in uncertain conditions, commonly used in tracking and navigation.
 The tutorial, initiated in 2017, includes numerical examples and intuitive explanations, covering both univariate and multivariate Kalman Filters, and has expanded to advanced topics like non-linear Kalman Filters.
 A book based on the tutorial offers a comprehensive guide from basics to advanced topics, with illustrative examples and practical applications, making the Kalman Filter accessible and understandable, with some parts available for free.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.kalmanfilter.net/default.aspx</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-19T00:00:00.000ZKalman Filter Tutorial</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Forgejo: A self-hosted lightweight software forge]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Forgejo is a self-hosted software forge that emphasizes security, scalability, federation, and privacy, developed by the community under Codeberg e.V.
 It serves as a Free Software alternative to GitHub, offering an easy installation process and low maintenance for efficient project management.
 Forgejo is designed to be resource-efficient, fostering collaboration and productivity, and supports innovation in decentralized software development.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://forgejo.org/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-19T00:00:00.000ZForgejo: A self-hosted lightweight software forge</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[So you want to build your own data center]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Railway transitioned from Google Cloud Platform to their own data centers due to issues with pricing, service limitations, and support, launching the Railway Metal project. - After nine months, they successfully went live with their first data center in California and are planning further regional expansions, focusing on efficient infrastructure management. - They developed tools such as Railyard and MetalCP to streamline operations and are currently hiring for Infrastructure Engineering roles.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.railway.com/p/data-center-build-part-one</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-18T00:00:00.000ZSo you want to build your own data center</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Investigating an “evil” RJ45 dongle]]></title>
            <link>https://lcamtuf.substack.com/p/investigating-an-evil-rj45-dongle</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-18T00:00:00.000ZInvestigating an “evil” RJ45 dongle</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I've been advocating for RSS support, and you should too]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The post advocates for the use of RSS (Really Simple Syndication) feeds, which allow users to receive updates from various platforms without ads or algorithms. - The author highlights successful requests for RSS support from platforms like GovTrack.us and encourages others to request RSS from organizations they are interested in. - Many platforms, such as NPR, YouTube, Substack, and Blogger, already support RSS, making it a valuable tool for staying informed.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://reedybear.bearblog.dev/ive-been-advocating-for-rss-support-and-you-should-too/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-18T00:00:00.000ZI&apos;ve been advocating for RSS support, and you should too</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Higher potassium intake at dinner linked to fewer sleep disturbances – study]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>A Japanese study using data from the Asken food-logging app investigated the relationship between potassium and sodium intake and insomnia in 4,568 adults. - Findings indicated that higher potassium intake, particularly at dinner, was associated with fewer sleep disturbances, as measured by the Athens Insomnia Scale (AIS). - While sodium intake has been previously linked to sleep issues, this study found no significant association with AIS scores, highlighting the need for further research on dietary impacts on sleep.</p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.nutraingredients-asia.com/Article/2025/01/07/higher-potassium-intake-at-dinner-linked-to-fewer-sleep-disturbances/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-18T00:00:00.000ZHigher potassium intake at dinner linked to fewer sleep disturbances – study</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Using ChatGPT is not bad for the environment]]></title>
            <link>https://andymasley.substack.com/p/individual-ai-use-is-not-bad-for</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-18T00:00:00.000ZUsing ChatGPT is not bad for the environment</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Canon wants us to pay for using our own camera as a webcam]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The author expresses frustration with Canon&#39;s software for using the Canon G5 X II camera as a webcam on macOS, highlighting issues with compatibility and server errors. - By macOS 15, the software issues were resolved, but many features required a subscription, raising concerns about additional charges for using owned hardware. - The post critiques the trend of hardware companies charging for software features, questioning the fairness of such practices.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://romanzipp.com/blog/no-you-cant-use-your-6299-canon-camera-as-a-webcam</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-17T00:00:00.000ZCanon wants us to pay for using our own camera as a webcam</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Starship Flight 7]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>SpaceX&#39;s Dragon spacecraft successfully completes a series of maneuvers to dock with the International Space Station (ISS), showcasing its advanced capabilities in space operations.
 The docking process involves multiple stages, including liftoff by Falcon 9, orbit activation, and a series of burns to align and approach the ISS.
 This event highlights SpaceX&#39;s continued role in supporting ISS missions and advancing commercial spaceflight technology.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.spacex.com/launches/mission/?missionId=starship-flight-7?submit</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-17T00:00:00.000ZStarship Flight 7</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Supreme Court rules to uphold TikTok ban, setting stage for shutdown]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The Supreme Court has upheld a law mandating ByteDance to divest TikTok by a specified deadline, or the app will face a ban in the U.S.
 There is uncertainty regarding whether service providers like Apple and Google will continue to support TikTok if the divestment does not occur.
 The future of TikTok in the U.S. remains uncertain, with users exploring alternative platforms and the Chinese government considering strategies to maintain its operations.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbc.com/2025/01/17/supreme-court-rules-to-uphold-tiktok-ban.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-17T00:00:00.000ZSupreme Court rules to uphold TikTok ban, setting stage for shutdown</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is the world becoming uninsurable?]]></title>
            <link>https://charleshughsmith.substack.com/p/is-the-world-becoming-uninsurable</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-17T00:00:00.000ZIs the world becoming uninsurable?</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Learn Yjs Interactively]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Learn Yjs is an interactive tutorial designed to teach users how to build real-time collaborative applications using the Yjs CRDT (Conflict-free Replicated Data Type) library. - The tutorial includes live examples, demos, and code exercises, covering Yjs basics, state handling in distributed apps, and challenges in collaborative app development. - Developed by Jamsocket, the tutorial utilizes Y-Sweet and is built with Astro, React, and Yjs, offering users a hands-on experience with automatic syncing and network interaction adjustments.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://learn.yjs.dev/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-17T00:00:00.000ZLearn Yjs Interactively</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Thoughts on a Month with Devin]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>In March 2024, a new AI company introduced Devin, an AI software engineer, with a substantial $21 million investment, aiming to automate tasks from learning new technologies to deploying applications. - Initial demonstrations of Devin were impressive, but testing by Answer.AI revealed mixed results, with Devin excelling in simple tasks like API integrations but struggling with complex projects. - Despite a user-friendly interface, Devin&#39;s autonomous nature led to inefficiencies, succeeding in only 3 out of 20 tasks, underscoring the disparity between AI expectations and practical performance.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.answer.ai/posts/2025-01-08-devin.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-17T00:00:00.000ZThoughts on a Month with Devin</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Some things to expect in 2025]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>LWN.net predicts the rise of the extensible scheduling class (sched-ext) in more distributions and an increase in Rust code within the Linux kernel by 2025. - Potential security threats, similar to the XZ backdoor, and challenges from AI-generated code are anticipated, alongside concerns about single-maintainer projects. - The year may witness more open hardware, a resurgence in mobile device distributions, and security issues in cloud-based products, with global conflicts potentially affecting the development community.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1003780/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-17T00:00:00.000ZSome things to expect in 2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I have made the decision to disband Hindenburg Research]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Hindenburg Research, known for challenging fraud and corruption, is disbanding as announced by founder Nate Anderson. - The decision to disband is driven by Anderson&#39;s desire for personal relief and to share their investigative methods with the public by open-sourcing their process. - Anderson expresses gratitude to his team, family, and readers, highlighting the impact and support received throughout their journey.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hindenburgresearch.com/gratitude/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-16T00:00:00.000ZI have made the decision to disband Hindenburg Research</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No Calls]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Zeke Gabrielse, founder of Keygen, initially avoided sales calls due to his introverted nature, implementing a &#39;no calls&#39; policy, which led to more direct interactions and his first enterprise sale.
 Gabrielse identified four key issues to address for a successful &#39;no calls&#39; approach: unclear offerings, poor onboarding, hidden pricing, and lack of trust, suggesting clear messaging, transparent pricing, self-serve onboarding, and trust-building documentation.
 While some enterprises still expect calls, Keygen uses brief &#39;discovery calls&#39; to transition to email discussions, and Gabrielse encourages others to consider a #nocalls approach if it aligns with their style.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://keygen.sh/blog/no-calls/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-16T00:00:00.000ZNo Calls</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nintendo announces the Switch 2 [video]]]></title>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=itpcsQQvgAQ</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-16T00:00:00.000ZNintendo announces the Switch 2 [video]</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Israel, Hamas reach ceasefire deal to end 15 months of war in Gaza]]></title>
            <link
      >https://www.reuters.com/world/middle-east/gaza-ceasefire-appears-close-us-egyptian-leaders-put-focus-coming-hours-2025-01-14/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-16T00:00:00.000ZIsrael, Hamas reach ceasefire deal to end 15 months of war in Gaza</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sweden brings more books and handwriting practice back to its schools (2023)]]></title>
            <link
      >https://apnews.com/article/sweden-digital-education-backlash-reading-writing-1dd964c628f76361c43dbf3964f7dbf4</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-16T00:00:00.000ZSweden brings more books and handwriting practice back to its schools (2023)</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nokia's internal presentation after iPhone was launched (2007) [pdf]]]></title>
            <link>https://nokia-apple-iphone-was-launched-presentation.tiiny.site/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-16T00:00:00.000ZNokia&apos;s internal presentation after iPhone was launched (2007) [pdf]</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UnitedHealth overcharged cancer patients for drugs by over 1,000%]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>UnitedHealth has been discovered to have overcharged certain cancer patients for medications by over 1,000%.
 FTC Chair Lina Khan is focusing on major pharmacy benefit managers, including UnitedHealth&#39;s OptumRx, Cigna&#39;s Express Scripts, and CVS Caremark Rx, as part of a broader investigation.</p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://fortune.com/2025/01/15/ftc-pbms-unitedhealth-brian-thompson-cvs-caremark-cigna-pharmacy-benefit-managers/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-16T00:00:00.000ZUnitedHealth overcharged cancer patients for drugs by over 1,000%</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blue Origin reaches orbit on first flight of its titanic New Glenn rocket]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Blue Origin&#39;s New Glenn rocket successfully reached orbit for the first time, marking a significant milestone for the company. - The launch faced initial challenges, including engine chill issues and a stray boat, but ultimately achieved an orbital velocity of 28,800 kph. - Although the first stage booster did not return to Earth, the successful launch demonstrates Blue Origin&#39;s progress and the impact of Jeff Bezos&#39;s investments.</p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://arstechnica.com/space/2025/01/blue-origin-reaches-orbit-on-first-flight-of-its-titanic-new-glenn-rocket/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-16T00:00:00.000ZBlue Origin reaches orbit on first flight of its titanic New Glenn rocket</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[100x defect tolerance: How we solved the yield problem]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Cerebras has developed a wafer-scale chip, significantly larger than standard chips, by reimagining the relationship between chip size and fault tolerance. - The Wafer Scale Engine (WSE) includes 970,000 small, fault-tolerant cores and a sophisticated routing architecture, achieving high yields and 93% silicon utilization. - This innovation demonstrates that wafer-scale computing is commercially viable, offering greater defect tolerance compared to traditional GPUs like Nvidia&#39;s H100.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://cerebras.ai/blog/100x-defect-tolerance-how-cerebras-solved-the-yield-problem</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-16T00:00:00.000Z100x defect tolerance: How we solved the yield problem</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nepenthes is a tarpit to catch AI web crawlers]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Nepenthes is a tarpit software designed to trap and deter web crawlers, particularly those collecting data for Large Language Models (LLMs), by generating endless, looping pages. - The software can create significant CPU load and is used to protect real content or to overwhelm AI models with irrelevant data, potentially affecting search engine visibility. - Installation options include Docker or manual setup, with configuration managed through a YAML file, but users should exercise caution due to its potential to be considered malicious.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://zadzmo.org/code/nepenthes/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-16T00:00:00.000ZNepenthes is a tarpit to catch AI web crawlers</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I Ditched the Algorithm for RSS–and You Should Too]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The article advocates for using RSS (Really Simple Syndication) as an alternative to social media algorithms, emphasizing its ability to deliver content without ads or unnecessary distractions.
 RSS allows users to subscribe directly to their favorite websites, including YouTube and Reddit, providing a streamlined and personalized content experience.
 The ease of setting up RSS feeds and the availability of feed generators for sites without native RSS support make it a practical tool for staying informed and saving time.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://joeyehand.com/blog/2025/01/15/i-ditched-the-algorithm-for-rssand-you-should-too/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-16T00:00:00.000ZI Ditched the Algorithm for RSS–and You Should Too</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenAI fails to deliver opt-out system for photographers]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>OpenAI missed its 2025 deadline for releasing Media Manager, a tool designed to help photographers opt out of having their work used in AI training data.
 The tool aimed to identify copyrighted content and address copyright disputes, but it appears to have been deprioritized, with no updates since August.
 Photographers currently face a cumbersome process of submitting each work they want excluded, leading to criticism that the system is unfair and unlikely to be widely adopted.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://petapixel.com/2025/01/06/openai-fails-to-deliver-opt-out-system-for-photographers/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-16T00:00:00.000ZOpenAI fails to deliver opt-out system for photographers</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[dnSpyEx: .NET debugger and assembly editor]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>dnSpyEx is an unofficial continuation of the dnSpy project, providing a debugger and .NET assembly editor for editing and debugging .NET and Unity assemblies without source code.
 The tool supports debugging .NET Framework, .NET, and Unity game assemblies, and includes features like setting breakpoints, evaluating expressions, and metadata editing.
 The latest stable release and beta builds are available on GitHub, and it uses open-source libraries like ILSpy and Roslyn, licensed under GPLv3.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/dnSpyEx/dnSpy</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-16T00:00:00.000ZdnSpyEx: .NET debugger and assembly editor</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No Billionares at FOSDEM]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Jack Dorsey, former CEO of Twitter, is scheduled to deliver a keynote at FOSDEM, a significant event for free software enthusiasts, due to his blockchain company&#39;s sponsorship. - Despite his substantial net worth and controversial history, including the sale of Twitter to Elon Musk, Dorsey&#39;s participation has sparked criticism and plans for a protest sit-in during his talk. - The protest is organized to occur at 11:45 AM outside the venue, with interested participants encouraged to contact the organizer via email.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://drewdevault.com/2025/01/16/2025-01-16-No-Billionares-at-FOSDEM-please.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-16T00:00:00.000ZNo Billionares at FOSDEM</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Intel's Tofino P4 Software Is Now Open Source]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Intel has open-sourced its Tofino P4 software, previously proprietary, to transform programmable networks and foster innovation within the P4 community. - This initiative democratizes access to advanced network programming tools, benefiting startups, academic institutions, and developers globally. - The source code is accessible in the p4lang structure, with components in the p4c and open-p4studio repositories, encouraging contributions and community engagement.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://p4.org/intels-tofino-p4-software-is-now-open-source/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-16T00:00:00.000ZIntel&apos;s Tofino P4 Software Is Now Open Source</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Don't use cosine similarity carelessly]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Cosine similarity, a method for comparing vectors, can be misleading if used without understanding the context, as it may not accurately capture semantic similarities. - Embeddings, such as those from word2vec or sentence embeddings from Large Language Models (LLMs), require careful and intentional use to ensure they reflect the desired relationships. - To improve vector similarity results, consider using LLMs directly, creating task-specific embeddings through fine-tuning, and ensuring text is clean and prompts are well-engineered before embedding.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://p.migdal.pl/blog/2025/01/dont-use-cosine-similarity/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-15T00:00:00.000ZDon&apos;t use cosine similarity carelessly</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nevada Court Shuts Down Police Use of Federal Loophole for Civil Forfeiture]]></title>
            <link
      >https://ij.org/press-release/nevada-court-shuts-down-police-use-of-federal-loophole-for-civil-forfeiture/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-15T00:00:00.000ZNevada Court Shuts Down Police Use of Federal Loophole for Civil Forfeiture</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TikTok preparing for U.S. shut-off on Sunday]]></title>
            <link
      >https://www.reuters.com/technology/tiktok-preparing-us-shut-off-sunday-information-reports-2025-01-15/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-15T00:00:00.000ZTikTok preparing for U.S. shut-off on Sunday</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Generate audiobooks from E-books with Kokoro-82M]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Kokoro v0.19 is a new text-to-speech model with 82 million parameters, providing high-quality audio output in multiple languages, including American and British English, French, Korean, Japanese, and Mandarin.
 Claudio Santini developed Audiblez, a tool that converts e-books into audiobooks using Kokoro, processing .epub files and generating audio files, with a conversion time of about 2 hours for a 100,000-word book on an M2 MacBook Pro.
 Audiblez requires installation via pip, supports various languages and voices, and needs ffmpeg for .m4b file creation, with the tool available on GitHub for further development and improvements.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://claudio.uk/posts/epub-to-audiobook.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-15T00:00:00.000ZGenerate audiobooks from E-books with Kokoro-82M</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Road signs to help people limit radiation exposure in contaminated areas]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The Manual on Uniform Traffic Control Devices (MUTCD) contains Cold War-era signs, such as &quot;MAINTAIN TOP SAFE SPEED,&quot; intended for radiological contamination zones.
 These signs were part of Civil Defense strategies to safeguard citizens during a potential nuclear apocalypse, though they were never utilized.
 Some of these signs are still included in the MUTCD as Emergency Management signs, highlighting historical fears and preparedness efforts from that period.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theautopian.com/if-you-ever-see-this-speed-sign-youre-probably-going-to-die/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-15T00:00:00.000ZRoad signs to help people limit radiation exposure in contaminated areas</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WTF Happened in 1971? (2019)]]></title>
            <link>https://wtfhappenedin1971.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-15T00:00:00.000ZWTF Happened in 1971? (2019)</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How rqlite is tested]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>rqlite is a lightweight distributed database that combines SQLite and Raft, focusing on reliability and quality through a structured testing strategy. - The testing strategy follows the testing pyramid, emphasizing unit tests for isolated components, integration tests for system-level validation, and minimal end-to-end tests for basic operation checks. - Key lessons from rqlite&#39;s testing approach include starting testing early, simplifying test code, and ensuring determinism, which helps maintain high quality with minimal overhead.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://philipotoole.com/how-is-rqlite-tested/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-15T00:00:00.000ZHow rqlite is tested</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rewriting my website in plain HTML and CSS]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The author rebuilt their website using plain HTML and CSS, moving away from SvelteKit, to simplify the site and host it on Cloudflare Pages. - They used Pandoc for converting Markdown to HTML and Python for scripting, resulting in a smaller website, reducing asset size from ~356kb to ~88kb. - The project highlighted challenges such as code duplication and lack of live reloading, with plans to explore web components and FastAPI to address these issues, potentially serving as a template for others seeking a framework-free website with Markdown posts.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.vijayp.dev/blog/rewrite-plain-html/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-15T00:00:00.000ZRewriting my website in plain HTML and CSS</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
