<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0"
>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 19:05:57 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/story/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[School smartphone ban results in better sleep and improved mood: study]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A study by psychologists at the University of York found that banning smartphones in schools improved sleep and mood among children.- Year 8 students at The Stanway School in Colchester participated in a 21-day smartphone ban, resulting in faster sleep onset and an extra hour of rest per night.- The study reported a 17% reduction in depression and an 18% reduction in anxiety, highlighting potential benefits of smartphone bans as governments evaluate their impact on youth.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.york.ac.uk/news-and-events/news/2024/research/school-smartphone-ban-better-sleep/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-15T00:00:00.000ZSchool smartphone ban results in better sleep and improved mood: study</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[They see your photos]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://theyseeyourphotos.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-15T00:00:00.000ZThey see your photos</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A visual proof that a^2 – b^2 = (a + b)(a – b)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A visual proof demonstrates the algebraic identity (a^2 - b^2 = (a + b)(a - b)), which is a fundamental concept in algebra.&quot;</li>
<li>The statement by Sophie Germain highlights the interconnectedness of algebra and geometry, suggesting that algebra can be represented visually through geometric diagrams.&quot;</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.futilitycloset.com/2024/12/15/tidy-2/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-15T00:00:00.000ZA visual proof that a^2 – b^2 = (a + b)(a – b)</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IRATA.ONLINE: A Community for Retro-Computing Enthusiasts]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>IRATA.ONLINE is a community platform for retro-computing enthusiasts, utilizing a PLATO-based system known for its multi-user, graphical, and interactive capabilities.- It supports a range of classic computing platforms such as Atari, Commodore, and Apple, allowing users to connect via web terminals or specific software like PLATOTERM.- The platform offers multi-player games, social features, and a development environment using the TUTOR programming language, catering to both gaming and development interests.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://irata.online/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-15T00:00:00.000ZIRATA.ONLINE: A Community for Retro-Computing Enthusiasts</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tenstorrent and the State of AI Hardware Startups]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://irrationalanalysis.substack.com/p/tenstorrent-and-the-state-of-ai-hardware</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-15T00:00:00.000ZTenstorrent and the State of AI Hardware Startups</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[When a Crystal Ball Isn't Enough to Make You Rich]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>In the 2023 &quot;The Crystal Ball Challenge,&quot; 118 finance-trained young adults were given $50 to trade the S&amp;P 500 and 30-year US Treasury bonds using news a day in advance, but without price data.</li>
<li>Despite having advance news, half of the participants lost money, and one in six went bankrupt, with an average gain of only 3.2%, due to incorrect market predictions and poor trade-sizing.</li>
<li>The experiment highlighted that even with foresight, successful trading requires skill and strategy, as demonstrated by five experienced traders who achieved better results.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://elmwealth.com/crystal-ball/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-15T00:00:00.000ZWhen a Crystal Ball Isn&apos;t Enough to Make You Rich</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenAI whistleblower found dead in San Francisco apartment]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Former OpenAI employee and whistleblower Suchir Balaji was found dead in his San Francisco apartment, with authorities ruling it a suicide.</li>
<li>Balaji had accused OpenAI of copyright violations in training its ChatGPT program, leading to multiple lawsuits against the company.</li>
<li>OpenAI denies the allegations, asserting that its practices are legal under &quot;fair use&quot; laws, while Balaji was a key figure in the ongoing legal battles.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.mercurynews.com/2024/12/13/openai-whistleblower-found-dead-in-san-francisco-apartment/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-14T00:00:00.000ZOpenAI whistleblower found dead in San Francisco apartment</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk wanted an OpenAI for-profit]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://openai.com/index/elon-musk-wanted-an-openai-for-profit/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-14T00:00:00.000ZElon Musk wanted an OpenAI for-profit</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[McKinsey and Company to pay $650M for role in opioid crisis]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>McKinsey &amp; Company has agreed to a $650 million settlement to resolve federal investigations into its involvement in promoting opioid sales for Purdue Pharma, covering both civil and criminal charges.</li>
<li>The settlement follows nearly $900 million previously settled with state and local governments, and McKinsey has committed to avoiding future work with controlled substances and will be subject to increased federal oversight.</li>
<li>Former McKinsey partner Martin Elling will plead guilty to obstruction of justice for document deletion, highlighting ongoing criticism that corporate leaders often evade jail time despite significant fines.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.npr.org/2024/12/13/nx-s1-5155962/mckinsey-purdue-opioid-prosecution-doj</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-14T00:00:00.000ZMcKinsey and Company to pay $650M for role in opioid crisis</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[macOS 15.2 breaks the ability to copy the OS to another drive]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A significant issue with macOS 15.2 disrupts the replicator, causing a Resource Busy error during data replication, affecting third-party OS copying.</li>
<li>Users are advised to use &quot;Backup - all files&quot; with &quot;Smart Update&quot; to back up data, excluding the operating system, until Apple provides a fix.</li>
<li>The bug, identified as FB16090831, is unlikely to be resolved soon due to the holiday season, as reported by Dave Nanian from Shirt Pocket.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.shirtpocket.com/blog/index.php/shadedgrey/youre_a_mean_one/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-14T00:00:00.000ZmacOS 15.2 breaks the ability to copy the OS to another drive</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sharing new research, models, and datasets from Meta FAIR]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Meta FAIR has released new open-source research artifacts to advance machine intelligence, including Meta Motivo and Meta Video Seal.- Meta Motivo employs unsupervised reinforcement learning to enable human-like behaviors in virtual agents, while Meta Video Seal offers robust video watermarking capabilities.- Additional releases include Flow Matching for generative AI, Meta Explore Theory-of-Mind for social intelligence, and Meta Large Concept Models for hierarchical language reasoning, highlighting Meta&#39;s commitment to responsible AI development and collaboration with the research community.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://ai.meta.com/blog/meta-fair-updates-agents-robustness-safety-architecture/?_fb_noscript=1</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-14T00:00:00.000ZSharing new research, models, and datasets from Meta FAIR</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Byte Latent Transformer: Patches Scale Better Than Tokens]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Byte Latent Transformer (BLT) is a new byte-level large language model (LLM) architecture that achieves performance comparable to tokenization-based LLMs with enhanced efficiency and robustness.</li>
<li>BLT utilizes dynamically sized patches as computation units, which adjust based on the complexity of the data, leading to improved training and inference efficiency.</li>
<li>The study demonstrates that BLT can scale up to 8 billion parameters with 4 trillion training bytes, outperforming tokenization-based models by effectively scaling both patch and model size.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://ai.meta.com/research/publications/byte-latent-transformer-patches-scale-better-than-tokens/?_fb_noscript=1</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-14T00:00:00.000ZByte Latent Transformer: Patches Scale Better Than Tokens</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ilya Sutskever NeurIPS talk [video]]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=YD-9NG1Ke5Y</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-14T00:00:00.000ZIlya Sutskever NeurIPS talk [video]</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Luon programming language]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Luon is a high-level programming language that merges elements of Oberon and Lua, designed specifically for the LuaJIT Virtual Machine (VM).</li>
<li>It introduces static typing to Lua, allowing seamless integration with Lua and C libraries, and includes features like reference semantics, a HASHMAP type, and immutable STRING data types.</li>
<li>The project offers a compiler, Integrated Development Environment (IDE), and precompiled versions for Linux and Windows, and is open-source under GPL 2 or 3 licenses.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/rochus-keller/Luon/blob/master/Readme.md</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-14T00:00:00.000ZLuon programming language</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Htmx 2.0.4 Released]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The latest update, version 2.0.4, introduces significant changes such as setting the default target for htmx.ajax to the body, fixing nested shadow root issues, and improving event handling and tag behavior.</li>
<li>This update also includes compatibility updates and bug fixes for extensions, highlighting ongoing improvements in the htmx library, which is used for enhancing HTML with AJAX, CSS Transitions, WebSockets, and Server-Sent Events (SSE).</li>
<li>The changelog reflects a consistent effort to enhance features and fix issues, with notable updates like improved shadow DOM support and the addition of new functionalities over time.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/bigskysoftware/htmx/blob/v2.0.4/CHANGELOG.md</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-14T00:00:00.000ZHtmx 2.0.4 Released</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Uv, a fast Python package and project manager]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;uv&quot; is a fast Python package and project manager written in Rust, designed to replace multiple tools like pip, poetry, and virtualenv, offering a significant speed boost of 10-100x over pip.</li>
<li>It provides comprehensive project management with features like a universal lockfile, Python version management, and support for Cargo-style workspaces, and can be installed without Rust or Python.</li>
<li>&quot;uv&quot; is backed by Astral and supports multiple operating systems, including macOS, Linux, and Windows, offering advanced features and efficiency for managing dependencies and environments.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://docs.astral.sh/uv/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-14T00:00:00.000ZUv, a fast Python package and project manager</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What Is Entropy? A Measure of Just How Little We Know]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Entropy, initially introduced by Sadi Carnot, measures disorder and is crucial for understanding the second law of thermodynamics, which states that entropy always increases.- The concept of entropy has expanded beyond thermodynamics to include information theory, where it represents uncertainty and is seen as subjective, depending on an observer&#39;s knowledge.- Researchers are exploring the use of information as a resource, with experiments in information engines and quantum thermodynamics, offering new opportunities for scientific innovation and understanding.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.quantamagazine.org/what-is-entropy-a-measure-of-just-how-little-we-really-know-20241213/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-14T00:00:00.000ZWhat Is Entropy? A Measure of Just How Little We Know</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I made a free Figma library packed with components for fast prototyping]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://veryfront.com/figma-kit</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-14T00:00:00.000ZI made a free Figma library packed with components for fast prototyping</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[@smoores/epub, a JavaScript library for working with EPUB publications]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A new EPUB library for Node.js has been developed and released as an NPM package, aimed at providing a well-maintained solution for creating EPUB books.</li>
<li>The library was initially created during the development of a project called Storyteller and is now available for the broader Node.js community.</li>
<li>The release was motivated by a request for advice on EPUB book creation, highlighting the demand for such a tool in the community.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.npmjs.com/package/@smoores/epub</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-14T00:00:00.000Z@smoores/epub, a JavaScript library for working with EPUB publications</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I designed an espresso machine and coffee grinder]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The solo project involves designing an innovative espresso machine with a unique pump and adjustable pressure, aiming to improve outdated technology like 1977 vibratory pumps.- The machine is minimalist, user-friendly, and can also brew filter coffee, addressing common issues such as the need for scales and drip trays.- The project includes a gear pump upgrade kit for other machines and features a grinder with cylindrical burrs, although it faces challenges with oily roasts. Both machines require a DC power source.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://velofuso.com</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-13T00:00:00.000ZI designed an espresso machine and coffee grinder</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A new video captures a 1968 demo of IBM’s Executive Terminal]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>In 1968, IBM demonstrated its Executive Terminal, an early attempt to integrate computers, video, and digital information to improve executive decision-making.</li>
<li>The demonstration highlighted IBM&#39;s innovative approach to using technology for strategic business purposes, marking a significant moment in the history of technology.</li>
<li>This event is notable for showcasing the potential of digital tools in corporate environments, paving the way for future advancements in executive technology solutions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://spectrum.ieee.org/ibm-demo</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-13T00:00:00.000ZA new video captures a 1968 demo of IBM’s Executive Terminal</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The age of average (2023)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>In the early 1990s, Russian artists Komar and Melamid used market research to reveal that people across different countries preferred similar blue landscapes, indicating a lack of individuality in art preferences.</li>
<li>This trend of homogeneity is observed in various fields such as interior design, architecture, cars, personal appearance, media, and branding, suggesting a dominance of convention and cliché.</li>
<li>The article suggests that this &quot;age of average&quot; offers an opportunity for bold brands to differentiate themselves by embracing creativity and originality.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.alexmurrell.co.uk/articles/the-age-of-average</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-13T00:00:00.000ZThe age of average (2023)</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amid cuts to basic research, New Zealand scraps all support for social sciences]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.science.org/content/article/amid-cuts-basic-research-new-zealand-scraps-all-support-social-sciences</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-13T00:00:00.000ZAmid cuts to basic research, New Zealand scraps all support for social sciences</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Carta is making it too difficult to cancel subscriptions, some founders say]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Startup founders have criticized Carta, a cap table management software, for making subscription cancellations difficult, often requiring meetings scheduled after renewal dates.</li>
<li>Carta attributes the cancellation issues to a &quot;one-time staffing challenge&quot; and aims to clarify the process for customers.</li>
<li>Competitors like AngelList and Pulley offer simpler cancellation methods, and despite the criticism, some users still praise Carta&#39;s product.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://techcrunch.com/2024/12/12/carta-is-making-it-too-difficult-to-cancel-subscriptions-some-founders-say/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-13T00:00:00.000ZCarta is making it too difficult to cancel subscriptions, some founders say</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elixir/Erlang Hot Swapping Code (2016)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The guide delves into hot code swapping in Elixir/Erlang, enabling code updates without halting the system, a significant feature for maintaining uptime.- It explains essential concepts, including Erlang applications, .app and .rel files, and tools like Relups and Distillery for managing upgrades and releases.- The guide highlights the complexity of release management in Elixir and the continuous evolution of tools to support this process.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://kennyballou.com/blog/2016/12/elixir-hot-swapping/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-13T00:00:00.000ZElixir/Erlang Hot Swapping Code (2016)</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Test]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.defense.gov/News/News-Stories/Article/Article/4000004/test/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-13T00:00:00.000ZTest</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mathematicians uncover a new way to count prime numbers]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Mathematicians Ben Green and Mehtaab Sawhney have developed a new method to count a specific type of prime numbers, enhancing our comprehension of these essential mathematical elements.</li>
<li>Their work builds on a conjecture by Friedlander and Iwaniec, proving there are infinitely many primes of the form p² + 4q², where both p and q are prime.</li>
<li>This breakthrough highlights the potential for new applications of Gowers norms, a mathematical tool, in the field of number theory.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.quantamagazine.org/mathematicians-uncover-a-new-way-to-count-prime-numbers-20241211/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-13T00:00:00.000ZMathematicians uncover a new way to count prime numbers</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Taming LLMs – A Practical Guide to LLM Pitfalls with Open Source Software]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;Taming LLMs&quot; is a practical guide that addresses the challenges and pitfalls of using Large Language Models (LLMs) in applications, providing solutions for handling unstructured output and managing context windows.</li>
<li>The book offers practical Python examples and open-source solutions, covering topics like structured output, token limits, evaluation gaps, hallucination, safety concerns, cost factors, and avoiding vendor lock-in.</li>
<li>It aims to equip engineers and product managers with the knowledge to effectively harness LLMs while avoiding common pitfalls, making it a valuable resource for those working with these models.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.souzatharsis.com/tamingLLMs/markdown/toc.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-13T00:00:00.000ZTaming LLMs – A Practical Guide to LLM Pitfalls with Open Source Software</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What every systems programmer should know about concurrency (2020) [pdf]]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://assets.bitbashing.io/papers/concurrency-primer.pdf</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-13T00:00:00.000ZWhat every systems programmer should know about concurrency (2020) [pdf]</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Feds help health insurers hide their dirty secret: denials on the rise]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Health insurers have significantly increased claim denial rates from 1-2% in 2013 to an average of 15% by 2022, with some companies denying nearly half of all claims.</li>
<li>The Affordable Care Act mandates transparency in denial rates, but lack of enforcement has allowed insurers to benefit from these denials, with patients seldom appealing despite high success rates.</li>
<li>Betsy McCaughey advocates for federal intervention to ensure transparency and accountability in insurance markets by revealing insurers&#39; denial rates.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://nypost.com/2024/12/12/opinion/feds-help-health-insurers-hide-dirty-secret-rising-denials/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-13T00:00:00.000ZFeds help health insurers hide their dirty secret: denials on the rise</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A room temperature Li2O-based lithium-air battery enabled by a solid electrolyte]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.science.org/doi/10.1126/science.abq1347</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-13T00:00:00.000ZA room temperature Li2O-based lithium-air battery enabled by a solid electrolyte</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gukesh becomes the youngest chess world champion in history]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>GM Gukesh D became the youngest world champion in the 2024 World Chess Championship by defeating GM Ding Liren in Round 14.</li>
<li>The match was notable for Gukesh&#39;s strategic play and deep preparation, capitalizing on Ding&#39;s blunder in a king and pawn endgame.</li>
<li>Lichess provided live coverage with commentary from GM Felix Blohberger, IM Laura Unuk, and guest GM Ivan Cheparinov, highlighting the event&#39;s significance and emotional moments.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://lichess.org/@/Lichess/blog/wcc-2024-round-14-gukesh-becomes-the-youngest-world-champion-in-history/cDggdNZw</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-12T00:00:00.000ZGukesh becomes the youngest chess world champion in history</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Timemap.org – Interactive Map of History]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.oldmapsonline.org/en/history/regions</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-12T00:00:00.000ZTimemap.org – Interactive Map of History</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mysterious New Jersey drone sightings prompt call for 'state of emergency']]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Over 3,000 drone sightings in New Jersey and the US northeast have led to calls for a &quot;limited state of emergency&quot; and a temporary drone ban by State Senator Jon Bramnick.</li>
<li>Concerns are heightened due to drones being spotted near sensitive locations, such as President-elect Trump&#39;s golf course and critical infrastructure.</li>
<li>Despite the large number of sightings, the FBI has not provided an explanation, and the Pentagon has dismissed claims of foreign involvement, including from an &quot;Iranian mothership.&quot;</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/dec/11/new-jersey-drone-sightings-state-of-emergency</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-12T00:00:00.000ZMysterious New Jersey drone sightings prompt call for &apos;state of emergency&apos;</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A ChatGPT clone, in 3000 bytes of C, backed by GPT-2 (2023)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Nicholas Carlini has developed a ChatGPT clone using a minimal C implementation of GPT-2, which is only about 3000 bytes in size.- The project is dependency-free and optimized to run GPT-2 Small on modern machines, though it produces low-quality output.- This initiative highlights the simplicity of neural networks and the ability to condense complex machine learning models into compact code, with the source code available on GitHub.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://nicholas.carlini.com/writing/2023/chat-gpt-2-in-c.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-12T00:00:00.000ZA ChatGPT clone, in 3000 bytes of C, backed by GPT-2 (2023)</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bankruptcy judge rejects sale of Infowars to The Onion]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A judge has halted the sale of Infowars to The Onion, which intended to transform it into a satirical platform.</li>
<li>The decision was made despite backing from Sandy Hook victims&#39; families, leaving Infowars&#39; future in limbo.</li>
<li>A court-appointed trustee is now responsible for determining a new course of action, while The Onion remains interested in the acquisition.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/12/10/business/media/the-onion-infowars-alex-jones.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-11T00:00:00.000ZBankruptcy judge rejects sale of Infowars to The Onion</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gemini 2.0: our new AI model for the agentic era]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Google DeepMind has launched Gemini 2.0, an advanced AI model designed for the &quot;agentic era,&quot; featuring capabilities such as native image and audio output and tool use.- Gemini 2.0 Flash is currently accessible to developers and trusted testers, with a wider release expected early next year, indicating a phased rollout strategy.- Google is focusing on responsible AI development, emphasizing safety and security, with potential applications in search, games, and robotics, highlighting the model&#39;s versatility and commitment to ethical AI practices.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.google/technology/google-deepmind/google-gemini-ai-update-december-2024/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-11T00:00:00.000ZGemini 2.0: our new AI model for the agentic era</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GM exits robotaxi market, will bring Cruise operations in house]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>General Motors (GM) is discontinuing its funding for the Cruise robotaxi division, opting to integrate it into its tech team to focus on autonomous systems for personal vehicles.</li>
<li>GM aims to acquire the remaining Cruise shares by 2025, significantly reducing its annual expenditure on the division by more than half.</li>
<li>Cruise has faced challenges, such as a $1.5 million fine for not reporting a crash, while competitors like Waymo and Tesla continue to progress in the robotaxi market.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbc.com/2024/12/10/gm-halts-funding-of-robotaxi-development-by-cruise.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-11T00:00:00.000ZGM exits robotaxi market, will bring Cruise operations in house</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Electric (Postgres sync engine) beta release]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Electric&#39;s sync engine, now in BETA with version 1.0.0-beta.1, facilitates real-time partial replication of Postgres data into local apps, enabling instant local data access without altering existing technology stacks.- The engine includes PGlite, a lightweight WebAssembly (WASM) version of Postgres for browsers, and is production-ready after a six-month rewrite, already utilized by companies like Google and Supabase.- Electric supports high-throughput workloads with low latency, is easy to adopt with simple APIs, and can be integrated incrementally, with Electric Cloud, a managed hosting service, in development.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://electric-sql.com/blog/2024/12/10/electric-beta-release</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-11T00:00:00.000ZElectric (Postgres sync engine) beta release</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WPEngine, Inc. vs. Automattic– Order on Motion for Preliminary Injunction]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.courtlistener.com/docket/69221176/64/wpengine-inc-v-automattic-inc/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-11T00:00:00.000ZWPEngine, Inc. vs. Automattic– Order on Motion for Preliminary Injunction</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What we know about CEO shooting suspect]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Luigi Mangione, a 26-year-old from a notable Baltimore family, has been charged with the murder of UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson in New York City.</li>
<li>Mangione was arrested in Pennsylvania with a ghost gun and a document hinting at a motive related to anger towards corporate America.</li>
<li>Despite his academic achievements and career as a data engineer, Mangione&#39;s social media suggests recent isolation from family and friends.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cp9nxee2r0do</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-10T00:00:00.000ZWhat we know about CEO shooting suspect</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This is not a joke, Funko just called my mom]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/itchio/status/1866239798924763227</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-10T00:00:00.000ZThis is not a joke, Funko just called my mom</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tree Calculus]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Tree Calculus is a Turing-complete computational model with a single operator, allowing for program analysis, type checking, compilation, and optimization directly within the code.- It supports arbitrary type systems and gradual typing, enabling powerful Read-Eval-Print Loops (REPLs) and program deployment without external tools.- Its minimal syntax and semantics make it portable and easy to implement interpreters on any platform, suitable for modeling, formal specifications, and educational purposes.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://treecalcul.us/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-10T00:00:00.000ZTree Calculus</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trellis – 3D mesh generative model]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The post introduces a new 3D generation method using a unified Structured LATent (SLAT) representation, enhancing the creation of versatile and high-quality 3D assets.</li>
<li>The model, named TRELLIS, utilizes rectified flow transformers and is trained on a large dataset, outperforming existing methods in 3D generation.</li>
<li>The approach supports flexible output formats and local 3D editing, with plans to release the code, model, and data to the public.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://trellis3d.github.io/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-10T00:00:00.000ZTrellis – 3D mesh generative model</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Save Music, Save the Archive]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Over 500 musicians are advocating for major labels to withdraw a $621 million lawsuit against the Internet Archive, a nonprofit cultural institution.</li>
<li>The musicians emphasize the need for fair compensation, protection of music legacies, and investment in living artists rather than supporting monopolistic practices.</li>
<li>They argue that the music industry&#39;s survival depends on prioritizing artists&#39; futures and preserving their works, urging public support through an open letter.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.savethearchive.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-10T00:00:00.000ZSave Music, Save the Archive</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[From where I left]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://antirez.com/news/144</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-10T00:00:00.000ZFrom where I left</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Developer wrote 25k lines of Neovim plugin code using phone and touchscreen]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://old.reddit.com/r/neovim/comments/1h7vhmg/bro_been_developing_his_2k_star_plugin_on_a/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-10T00:00:00.000ZDeveloper wrote 25k lines of Neovim plugin code using phone and touchscreen</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Debanking (and Debunking?)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Debanking, the involuntary closure of bank accounts, is a contentious issue, particularly affecting crypto businesses, with concerns it may be used as a political tool.</li>
<li>The debate involves complex interactions between private and state actors, with some viewing debanking as necessary for risk management, while others see it as unfair and lacking due process.</li>
<li>Historical regulatory actions like Operation Choke Point, which pressured banks to sever ties with certain industries, are cited by critics as similar to current actions against crypto businesses, termed &quot;Choke Point 2.0.&quot;</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bitsaboutmoney.com/archive/debanking-and-debunking/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-10T00:00:00.000ZDebanking (and Debunking?)</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Double (YC W24) – Index Investing with 0% Expense Ratios]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Double is a financial platform that allows investment in over 50 stock market indexes with no expense ratios, charging a flat fee of $1/month for management, rebalancing, and tax-loss harvesting.</li>
<li>The platform offers direct indexing by purchasing individual stocks from popular indexes, providing customization and daily portfolio optimization, distinguishing itself from other robo-advisors.</li>
<li>Double has achieved $10 million in assets under management (AUM) and aims to disrupt the $100 billion/year ETF and mutual fund market by offering low-fee investment strategies.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42377018</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-10T00:00:00.000ZDouble (YC W24) – Index Investing with 0% Expense Ratios</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Itch.io Taken Down by Funko]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://bsky.app/profile/itch.io/post/3lcu6h465bs2n</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-09T00:00:00.000ZItch.io Taken Down by Funko</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Compromising OpenWrt Supply Chain]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A security engineer identified vulnerabilities in OpenWrt&#39;s firmware upgrade process, including command injection and SHA-256 hash collision issues.- The vulnerabilities allowed potential attackers to inject commands and create hash collisions, leading to the installation of malicious firmware.- The OpenWrt team promptly addressed and fixed these vulnerabilities, emphasizing the need for strong security in software supply chains.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatt.tech/research/posts/compromising-openwrt-supply-chain-sha256-collision/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-09T00:00:00.000ZCompromising OpenWrt Supply Chain</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pat Gelsinger was wrong for Intel]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Pat Gelsinger, despite his technical expertise and managerial skills, was deemed unsuitable as Intel&#39;s CEO due to his inability to address the company&#39;s cultural and strategic challenges.</li>
<li>His leadership decisions, such as maintaining dividends and aggressive advertising, were criticized for reflecting a peacetime approach rather than the necessary wartime leadership.</li>
<li>Gelsinger&#39;s management of Intel&#39;s Foundry Services and the termination of the Tofino project, a promising programmable switch silicon, were seen as significant missteps, leaving Intel&#39;s cultural issues unresolved.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://bcantrill.dtrace.org/2024/12/08/why-gelsinger-was-wrong-for-intel/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-09T00:00:00.000ZPat Gelsinger was wrong for Intel</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[JSON5 – JSON for Humans]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>JSON5, an extension of JSON, is designed for easier manual editing, making it ideal for configuration files but not suitable for machine communication.</li>
<li>Since its launch in 2012, JSON5 has gained significant popularity, with over 65 million downloads weekly, and is utilized by major projects like Chromium and Next.js.</li>
<li>JSON5 is a superset of JSON, incorporating ECMAScript 5.1 features, allowing for flexible syntax, and is compatible with ES5, with a JavaScript library available for parsing and serialization.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://json5.org/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-09T00:00:00.000ZJSON5 – JSON for Humans</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UK bans daytime TV ads for cereals, muffins and burgers]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The UK government is implementing a ban on daytime TV advertisements for sugary and &quot;less healthy&quot; foods, such as cereals, muffins, and burgers, to address child obesity.</li>
<li>Starting next October, these ads will only be allowed to air after 9:00 pm, with the goal of preventing 20,000 cases of childhood obesity each year.</li>
<li>Health Secretary Wes Streeting highlighted the importance of stopping the targeting of children with junk food advertisements.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.france24.com/en/live-news/20241204-uk-bans-daytime-tv-ads-for-cereals-muffins-and-burgers</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-09T00:00:00.000ZUK bans daytime TV ads for cereals, muffins and burgers</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hetzner has decided to cancel our account and terminate all servers.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://mastodon.social/@kiwix/113622081750449356</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-09T00:00:00.000ZHetzner has decided to cancel our account and terminate all servers.</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Willow, Our Quantum Chip]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Google has introduced Willow, a quantum chip that marks a significant advancement in quantum error correction and computation speed.- Willow demonstrated its capability by performing a computation in under five minutes, a task that would take a supercomputer 10 septillion years, indicating its potential to tackle complex problems beyond classical computers.- This development is pivotal for the future of commercially viable quantum computers, with implications for revolutionizing industries such as medicine, energy, and artificial intelligence (AI).</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.google/technology/research/google-willow-quantum-chip/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-09T00:00:00.000ZWillow, Our Quantum Chip</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenAI: Sora]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://sora.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-09T00:00:00.000ZOpenAI: Sora</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nyxt: The Hacker's Browser]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Nyxt is a browser designed for advanced users, emphasizing keyboard navigation and efficiency in online information analysis and extraction.</li>
<li>It features powerful tools like link hinting, Jump Headings for document navigation, and fuzzy search for easy tab management and command execution.</li>
<li>Additional functionalities include a built-in REPL (Read-Eval-Print Loop) for programmability, smart bookmark search, customizable autofills, clipboard history, and a tree-based history for tracking visited pages.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://nyxt.atlas.engineer/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-08T00:00:00.000ZNyxt: The Hacker&apos;s Browser</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Syrian government falls in end to 50-year rule of Assad family]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://apnews.com/article/syria-assad-sweida-daraa-homs-hts-qatar-7f65823bbf0a7bd331109e8dff419430</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-08T00:00:00.000ZSyrian government falls in end to 50-year rule of Assad family</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reverse engineering the Sega Channel game image file format]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Sega Channel was a pioneering games-on-demand service for the Sega Genesis, active from 1994 to 1998, offering around 50 games monthly.- In 2024, a user discovered a Sega Channel game image CD from 1996, leading to efforts in reverse engineering to extract and preserve its data.- The project successfully decoded exclusive games, emphasizing the role of community efforts and reverse engineering in preserving gaming history.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.infochunk.com/schannel/index.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-08T00:00:00.000ZReverse engineering the Sega Channel game image file format</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Notre Dame Cathedral reopens]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://apnews.com/article/notre-dame-paris-latest-e50813cf016f08607c20ab115bc4b153</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-08T00:00:00.000ZNotre Dame Cathedral reopens</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brian Krebs Investigates Internet's Most Vicious Hackers–From a Secret Location]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wsj.com/tech/cybersecurity/hacking-brian-krebs-snowflake-waifu-49b87fce</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-08T00:00:00.000ZBrian Krebs Investigates Internet&apos;s Most Vicious Hackers–From a Secret Location</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Airline informant received thousands from passenger cash seizures]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.atlantanewsfirst.com/2024/12/03/airline-informant-received-thousands-passenger-cash-seizures/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-08T00:00:00.000ZAirline informant received thousands from passenger cash seizures</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Browsing negative content online makes mental health struggles worse: Study]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>MIT researchers have created a web plug-in named &quot;Digital Diet&quot; to assist users in making informed choices about online content to safeguard their mental health.</li>
<li>The tool employs natural language processing (NLP) to evaluate web pages based on emotion, knowledge, and actionability, steering users towards more positive content.</li>
<li>The research underscores the two-way relationship between online behavior and mental health, with findings published in Nature Human Behavior.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://news.mit.edu/2024/study-browsing-negative-content-online-makes-mental-health-struggles-worse-1205</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-08T00:00:00.000ZBrowsing negative content online makes mental health struggles worse: Study</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My second year without a job]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://shilin.ca/my-second-year-without-job/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-07T00:00:00.000ZMy second year without a job</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[: The Dialog Element]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The HTML `` element is used to create dialog boxes, which can be modal (pausing page interaction) or non-modal (allowing interaction).</li>
<li>JavaScript methods <code>.showModal()</code> and <code>.show()</code> are used to display modal and non-modal dialogs, respectively, while <code>.close()</code> is used to close them.</li>
<li>Accessibility is crucial; ensure focus is set correctly and provide a closing mechanism, such as a button, while using CSS <code>::backdrop</code> for styling modal backdrops.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML/Element/dialog</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-07T00:00:00.000Z: The Dialog Element</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maps.me co-founder tries to close down Organic Maps open-source fork]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Organic Maps has released the source code for its &quot;metaserver,&quot; which optimizes map download speeds by directing users to the best Content Delivery Network (CDN) servers based on their location.</li>
<li>The code, initially closed to prevent unauthorized forks, is now open under the MIT license, promoting transparency and community involvement.</li>
<li>The team is reconsidering the use of Cloudflare Workers to prevent vendor lock-in and has reverted unauthorized changes made by a contributor, emphasizing their commitment to privacy and transparency.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/orgs/organicmaps/discussions/9837</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-07T00:00:00.000ZMaps.me co-founder tries to close down Organic Maps open-source fork</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to use Postgres for everything]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;Postgres for Everything&quot; is a repository that promotes the use of PostgreSQL, a popular open-source relational database, for a wide range of applications beyond traditional database tasks.- The repository invites contributions and tracks various innovative uses of PostgreSQL, including cron jobs, message queues, analytics, and more, highlighting its versatility.- The initiative includes 11 items related to Supabase, a platform that provides backend services using PostgreSQL, showcasing its integration and utility in modern application development.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/Olshansk/postgres_for_everything</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-07T00:00:00.000ZHow to use Postgres for everything</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lies I was told about collab editing, Part 1: Algorithms for offline editing]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>In early 2024, research into collaborative editing systems for Moment&#39;s text editor highlighted challenges with offline editing, where popular algorithms like CRDTs (Conflict-free Replicated Data Types) and OT (Operational Transformation) often fail.- Offline editing increases direct conflicts, with 20-30% of these conflicts resulting in unacceptable outcomes, suggesting the issue is more of a user interface/user experience (UI/UX) challenge than an algorithmic one.- Researchers are now focusing on improving the user experience in offline editing, drawing parallels to how git handles document merging, which is a promising development.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moment.dev/blog/lies-i-was-told-pt-1</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-07T00:00:00.000ZLies I was told about collab editing, Part 1: Algorithms for offline editing</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Structured Outputs with Ollama]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Ollama has introduced support for structured outputs, enabling models to generate outputs in a specific format using a JSON schema.</li>
<li>This feature is now available in the updated Ollama Python and JavaScript libraries, useful for tasks like data parsing from documents and images.</li>
<li>Users should update to the latest Ollama version and use the format parameter in cURL requests or libraries, with future updates promising performance enhancements and more format options.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ollama.com/blog/structured-outputs</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-07T00:00:00.000ZStructured Outputs with Ollama</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RollerCoaster Tycoon was the last of its kind [video]]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0JouTsMQsEA</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-07T00:00:00.000ZRollerCoaster Tycoon was the last of its kind [video]</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fructose in diet enhances tumor growth: research]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Fructose consumption has increased significantly over the last 50 years, primarily due to high-fructose corn syrup in beverages and processed foods.</li>
<li>Research from Washington University in St. Louis indicates that while fructose doesn&#39;t directly fuel tumors, the liver converts it into nutrients that support tumor growth in cancers such as melanoma, breast, and cervical cancer.</li>
<li>The study suggests potential new cancer treatments by exploring methods to prevent fructose from aiding tumor growth, possibly through dietary changes or pharmaceuticals, with partial funding from the National Institutes of Health (NIH).</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://source.washu.edu/2024/12/research-reveals-how-fructose-in-diet-enhances-tumor-growth/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-07T00:00:00.000ZFructose in diet enhances tumor growth: research</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Biggest shell programs]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The page highlights significant shell programs, focusing on substantial hand-written scripts rather than those generated by tools like autoconf.- Notable entries include akinomyoga/ble.sh, a Bash Line Editor with 61K lines of code (LoC), and kalua, an OpenWRT addon with 56K source lines of code (SLoC).- The list provides insights into the complexity and diversity of shell scripting, featuring programs that utilize data structures and algorithms, typically exceeding 5,000 lines of code.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/oils-for-unix/oils/wiki/The-Biggest-Shell-Programs-in-the-World</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-07T00:00:00.000ZBiggest shell programs</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DSPy – Programming–not prompting–LMs]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>DSPy is a framework designed for building modular AI systems using compositional Python code, focusing on improving language model (LM) outputs without relying solely on prompts.- It supports multiple large language model (LLM) providers like OpenAI, Anthropic, and Databricks, allowing users to describe AI behavior as code, facilitating easier iteration and optimization.- Originating from Stanford NLP, DSPy has a strong community presence on GitHub and Discord, contributing to open-source AI research and advancing program architectures and optimizers.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://dspy.ai/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-07T00:00:00.000ZDSPy – Programming–not prompting–LMs</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The correct amount of ads is zero]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Verge has introduced a subscription model with a paywalled version, offering benefits like full-text RSS feeds to subscribers.</li>
<li>The subscription aims to reduce ad exposure, but there is criticism that paying subscribers should not see any ads at all.</li>
<li>Concerns are raised about potential data selling to advertisers, suggesting that subscribers should not be subject to both ads and data monetization.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://manuelmoreale.com/the-correct-amount-of-ads-is-zero</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZThe correct amount of ads is zero</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The 70% problem: Hard truths about AI-assisted coding]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://addyo.substack.com/p/the-70-problem-hard-truths-about</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZThe 70% problem: Hard truths about AI-assisted coding</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Portland airport grows with expansive mass timber roof canopy]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Portland Airport (PDX) has expanded its main terminal with a sustainable mass timber roof canopy, designed by ZGF, using locally sourced glulam Douglas Fir.</li>
<li>The nine-acre canopy aims to enhance airport capacity and passenger experience while reducing the carbon footprint, incorporating biophilic elements for a welcoming atmosphere.</li>
<li>This project sets a new standard for sustainable airport design, with completion anticipated in 2026.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://design-milk.com/portland-airport-grows-with-expansive-mass-timber-roof-canopy/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZPortland airport grows with expansive mass timber roof canopy</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Intel’s board, and an example of when boards and short-termism fail]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Pat Gelsinger&#39;s exit from Intel is portrayed as a firing rather than a retirement, emphasizing the board&#39;s failures and short-term focus over long-term strategy.- The board&#39;s lack of semiconductor expertise and focus on immediate shareholder value have been criticized, potentially harming Intel&#39;s long-term prospects and the U.S. semiconductor industry.- The board&#39;s failure to support Gelsinger&#39;s IDM 2.0 strategy suggests a shift towards selling company parts, which may benefit shareholders short-term but could damage Intel&#39;s future.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.fabricatedknowledge.com/p/the-death-of-intel-when-boards-fail</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZIntel’s board, and an example of when boards and short-termism fail</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trailbase: Fast, single-file, open-source app server built using Rust and SQLite]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>TrailBase is an open-source application server designed for fast, type-safe APIs, utilizing Rust, SQLite, and V8, and is suitable for mobile, web, or desktop applications.</li>
<li>It offers sub-millisecond latencies, removing the need for dedicated caches, and supports various platforms with pre-built binaries and client packages available for Linux, MacOS, and multiple programming languages.</li>
<li>TrailBase is licensed under OSL-3.0, allowing it to be used as a framework without additional licensing requirements, and contributions from the community are encouraged.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/trailbaseio/trailbase</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZTrailbase: Fast, single-file, open-source app server built using Rust and SQLite</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gitlab names Bill Staples as new CEO]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>GitLab has appointed Bill Staples as the new CEO, with co-founder Sid Sijbrandij moving to Executive Chair of the Board due to health reasons.</li>
<li>Staples, formerly CEO at New Relic, brings extensive experience in developer platforms to GitLab, a prominent AI-powered DevSecOps platform.</li>
<li>GitLab serves over 10,000 customers, generates over $750 million in revenue, and is trusted by more than 40 million users, including over half of the Fortune 100 companies.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20241205391064/en/GitLab-Names-Bill-Staples-as-New-CEO</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZGitlab names Bill Staples as new CEO</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ukraine's three nuclear power plants have restored electricity production]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Ukraine&#39;s nuclear power plants have resumed electricity production following recent grid attacks, highlighting the importance of a stable power supply for nuclear safety.</li>
<li>The International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) is actively monitoring the situation in Ukraine, underscoring its commitment to nuclear safety and security.</li>
<li>Equipment valued at over 14 million euros has been provided to Ukraine to bolster nuclear safety and security measures.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.iaea.org/newscenter/pressreleases/update-263-iaea-director-general-statement-on-situation-in-ukraine</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZUkraine&apos;s three nuclear power plants have restored electricity production</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ExxonMobil's Alleged Hack-for-Hire Campaign Targeting Climate Activists]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>ExxonMobil is accused of orchestrating a hack-for-hire campaign, &quot;Fox Hunt,&quot; targeting over 500 climate activists and journalists using advanced cyber capabilities.</li>
<li>The operation allegedly involved phishing attacks and leaked emails to undermine environmental advocates and support Exxon’s legal strategies, despite the company&#39;s denial of involvement.</li>
<li>This case underscores the growing trend of digital warfare in corporate disputes, prompting FBI investigations and calls for stronger legal measures to combat such cyber operations.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.vulnu.com/p/inside-exxonmobils-alleged-hack-for-hire-campaign-targeting-climate-activists</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZExxonMobil&apos;s Alleged Hack-for-Hire Campaign Targeting Climate Activists</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kagi Teams]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Kagi for Teams, set to launch on December 5, 2024, provides businesses with a privacy-focused search and AI tool, emphasizing no ads, tracking, or data harvesting.</li>
<li>The service includes a premium search engine and universal AI access, with flexible pricing based on active users, offering Professional and Ultimate plans.</li>
<li>Kagi promises quick setup, available support, and significant return on investment (ROI) through faster research times, ensuring data privacy for businesses.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.kagi.com/kagi-teams</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZKagi Teams</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I spent a year building an Android course for the elderly]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author developed a video course to teach elderly individuals how to use Android smartphones, addressing common challenges such as intimidation by interfaces and lack of basic skills like scrolling or swiping.</li>
<li>The course includes a 400-page script, video recordings, and an Android app with exercises, initially hosted on Udemy and later moved to a dedicated website, &quot;Smartphone How-To.&quot;</li>
<li>Marketing the course is challenging due to the target audience&#39;s difficulties with online registration and payment, and the author seeks feedback for improvement.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://kopiascsaba.hu/blog/teaching-elderly-people-to-use-android/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZI spent a year building an Android course for the elderly</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[McKinsey unit will pay $123M to settle claims it bribed South African officials]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A McKinsey &amp; Company subsidiary has agreed to pay $123 million to settle allegations of bribing South African officials, as reported by the U.S. Department of Justice.</li>
<li>The bribery scheme, involving McKinsey Africa, resulted in $85 million in profits through contracts with state-controlled utility companies.</li>
<li>Former McKinsey partner Vikas Sagar admitted guilt to conspiracy charges under the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act, and McKinsey Africa has agreed to a three-year deferred prosecution agreement, pledging to enhance compliance measures.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbc.com/2024/12/05/mckinsey-bribery-settlement-south-africa.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZMcKinsey unit will pay $123M to settle claims it bribed South African officials</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Llama-3.3-70B-Instruct]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://huggingface.co/meta-llama/Llama-3.3-70B-Instruct</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZLlama-3.3-70B-Instruct</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Install postmarketOS on Android phone and use Docker as a home server]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The guide details installing Docker on a OnePlus 6T using postmarketOS, effectively converting it into a home server, but it erases all phone data.</li>
<li>Key requirements include a OnePlus 6 or 6T, Fastboot on a PC, and postmarketOS files, with steps involving enabling Developer Mode, flashing postmarketOS, and setting up SSH.</li>
<li>While this setup offers an alternative to a Raspberry Pi with an integrated screen and battery, it lacks Ethernet support and is limited to internal storage.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://crackoverflow.com/docs/system_administration/containerization/install-docker-natively-on-android-phone-and-use-it-as-a-home-server/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZInstall postmarketOS on Android phone and use Docker as a home server</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hacker Herald – like HN but with crowdsourced pics and subtitles]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author, along with former instructor Arnav and student Archis, has launched a project called Hacker Herald, a front end for Hacker News.- The project was developed during an online JavaScript programming course and aims to provide a visually appealing layout similar to popular newspaper sites.- The inclusion of visuals, such as images, is intended to enhance the storytelling experience by providing immediate context without needing to click through articles.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hackerherald.com/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZHacker Herald – like HN but with crowdsourced pics and subtitles</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Congo gov. says it's 'on alert' over mystery flu-like disease that killed dozens]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.ctvnews.ca/health/congo-government-says-it-s-on-alert-over-mystery-flu-like-disease-that-killed-dozens-1.7134550</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZCongo gov. says it&apos;s &apos;on alert&apos; over mystery flu-like disease that killed dozens</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
