<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0"
>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 19:14:21 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/story/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenAI Furious DeepSeek Might Have Stolen All the Data OpenAI Stole from Us]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>OpenAI, Microsoft, and AI expert David Sacks allege that DeepSeek unfairly used OpenAI&#39;s data to develop a superior language model.
 Investigations by Bloomberg and Financial Times are examining if DeepSeek improperly trained its R1 model using OpenAI outputs, potentially through a technique called &quot;distillation,&quot; which extracts knowledge from existing models.
 The situation is notable as OpenAI, often criticized for using data without authorization, is now raising concerns about similar practices by others.</p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.404media.co/openai-furious-deepseek-might-have-stolen-all-the-data-openai-stole-from-us/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-29T00:00:00.000ZOpenAI Furious DeepSeek Might Have Stolen All the Data OpenAI Stole from Us</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I still like Sublime Text]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Sublime Text remains a preferred choice in 2025 due to its speed, cross-platform compatibility, and features like Language Server Protocol (LSP), snippets, and multiple cursors.
 The software is considered &quot;done,&quot; meaning it is stable and reliable, with the latest update released in January 2025, maintaining its relevance and efficiency.
 Sublime Text has significantly influenced modern editors, and its simplicity and distraction-free environment continue to attract users seeking a fast and efficient coding experience.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ohdoylerules.com/workflows/why-i-still-like-sublime-text-in-2025/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-29T00:00:00.000ZI still like Sublime Text</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Science YouTuber physicsgirl (Dianna Cowern) stands for the first time in 2 yrs]]></title>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/shorts/2ntx91cOYEc</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-29T00:00:00.000ZScience YouTuber physicsgirl (Dianna Cowern) stands for the first time in 2 yrs</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why DeepSeek had to be open source]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>DeepSeek, a Chinese AI lab, has open-sourced its reasoning model R1, which is comparable to OpenAI&#39;s o1, to build trust in Western markets and address skepticism about Chinese tech, particularly regarding data security. The open-sourcing of R1 is also a strategic move to innovate efficiently amid export controls on advanced chips, highlighting the cost advantage of open-source models over proprietary ones like OpenAI. Open-source models, such as DeepSeek&#39;s R1, offer customizability and lower costs, challenging proprietary models, although OpenAI maintains a leadership position due to its first-to-market advantage and resources.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.getlago.com/blog/deepseek-open-source</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-29T00:00:00.000ZWhy DeepSeek had to be open source</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I do not want AI to "polish" me]]></title>
            <link>https://thebloggess.com/2025/01/28/no-i-do-not-want-ai-to-polish-me/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-29T00:00:00.000ZI do not want AI to &quot;polish&quot; me</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Questions censored by DeepSeek]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>DeepSeek-R1, an open-source model from China, is under scrutiny for being subject to Chinese Communist Party (CCP) censorship, with concerns about its refusal rate on sensitive topics. A dataset of 1,360 prompts was used to test the model, revealing that approximately 85% of prompts on topics like Taiwanese independence were censored, yet jailbreaking attempts showed the censorship could be easily bypassed. Future evaluations will compare the handling of sensitive topics between Chinese and American models, highlighting differences in censorship and content moderation.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.promptfoo.dev/blog/deepseek-censorship/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-29T00:00:00.000ZQuestions censored by DeepSeek</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Goodbye, Slopify]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>A user expresses dissatisfaction with Spotify&#39;s Discover Weekly playlist, which now includes AI-generated music and covers. The user criticizes Spotify&#39;s app for being bloated and clunky, leading to their decision to unsubscribe. This situation highlights a growing concern about AI-generated content in music streaming services and its impact on user experience and support for real artists.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://alexeystar.com/blog/slopify/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-29T00:00:00.000ZGoodbye, Slopify</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bacteria (and Their Metabolites) and Depression]]></title>
            <link>https://www.science.org/content/blog-post/bacteria-and-their-metabolites-and-depression</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-29T00:00:00.000ZBacteria (and Their Metabolites) and Depression</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DeepSeek's multi-head latent attention and other KV cache tricks]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Key-Value (KV) caches enhance the speed of language models, such as ChatGPT, by reducing redundant computations, thus improving inference efficiency.
 KV caching decreases computational complexity from 𝑂(𝑛³) to 𝑂(𝑛²) by storing key and value information for each token, though it increases memory usage.
 Innovations in token selection, compression, and architectural redesigns, such as Multi-head Latent Attention, address the memory demands of KV caching, optimizing Transformer-based models.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pyspur.dev/blog/multi-head-latent-attention-kv-cache-paper-list</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-29T00:00:00.000ZDeepSeek&apos;s multi-head latent attention and other KV cache tricks</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parkinsons patient "feels cured" with new adaptive deep brain stimulation device]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Kevin Hill, a Parkinson&#39;s patient, reports feeling &quot;cured&quot; after receiving a groundbreaking brain implant that sends electrical signals to his brain, significantly alleviating his symptoms.
 The adaptive deep brain stimulation system, developed by Medtronic, automatically adjusts treatment based on brain activity, offering potential improvements in patients&#39; quality of life.
 With approximately 153,000 people in the UK affected by Parkinson&#39;s, this innovation could have a substantial impact as the number of cases is expected to increase.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/ckgn49r069wo</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-29T00:00:00.000ZParkinsons patient &quot;feels cured&quot; with new adaptive deep brain stimulation device</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Seagate: 'new' hard drives used for tens of thousands of hours]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>German customers have reported purchasing &quot;new&quot; Seagate hard drives that were actually used, with some showing extensive usage hours.
 The issue was identified by Heise.de after multiple reports concerning Seagate Exos HDDs, which were sold as new but lacked the standard five-year warranty.
 Seagate is investigating potential fraud, as the drives&#39; SMART (Self-Monitoring, Analysis, and Reporting Technology) stats were reset, and the issue involves several retailers, including Amazon and Mindfactory.</p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.tomshardware.com/pc-components/hdds/german-seagate-customers-say-their-new-hard-drives-were-actually-used-resold-hdds-reportedly-used-for-tens-of-thousands-of-hours</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-29T00:00:00.000ZSeagate: &apos;new&apos; hard drives used for tens of thousands of hours</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Discovery Coding]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Discovery Coding is a programming method where coders write code to understand a problem, similar to discovery writing in fiction, where the story develops during the writing process.
 This approach may seem less organized compared to structured planning but can still yield rigorous and effective end-products by focusing on understanding system constraints.
 The programming community is encouraged to recognize and accept diverse approaches to software design, acknowledging that there is no single correct method, as it is a human process that varies among individuals.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://jimmyhmiller.github.io/discovery-coding</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-29T00:00:00.000ZDiscovery Coding</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Apple and SpaceX link up to support Starlink satellite network on iPhones]]></title>
            <link
      >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2025-01-29/apple-and-spacex-link-up-to-support-starlink-satellite-network-on-iphones</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-29T00:00:00.000ZApple and SpaceX link up to support Starlink satellite network on iPhones</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Libraries and Well-Being: A Case Study from The New York Public Library]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>A study by the New York Public Library reveals that libraries greatly improve well-being and community connection, particularly in lower-income areas. Key findings show that 92% of users feel calm after visiting, 74% feel better equipped to handle life, and 90% enjoy learning more. Libraries are identified as places fostering optimism, empathy, and community, serving as a powerful antidote to modern stressors.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://lithub.com/its-official-research-has-found-that-libraries-make-everything-better/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-29T00:00:00.000ZLibraries and Well-Being: A Case Study from The New York Public Library</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Our phones are killing our ability to feel sexy (2024)]]></title>
            <link>https://catherineshannon.substack.com/p/your-phone-is-why-you-dont-feel-sexy</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-29T00:00:00.000ZOur phones are killing our ability to feel sexy (2024)</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We're bringing Pebble back]]></title>
            <link>https://repebble.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-28T00:00:00.000ZWe&apos;re bringing Pebble back</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Google open-sources the Pebble OS]]></title>
            <link>https://opensource.googleblog.com/2025/01/see-code-that-powered-pebble-smartwatches.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-28T00:00:00.000ZGoogle open-sources the Pebble OS</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Run DeepSeek R1 Dynamic 1.58-bit]]></title>
            <link>https://unsloth.ai/blog/deepseekr1-dynamic</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-28T00:00:00.000ZRun DeepSeek R1 Dynamic 1.58-bit</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Promising results from DeepSeek R1 for code]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>A pull request (PR) by Xuan-Son Nguyen for llama.cpp enhances WebAssembly (WASM) speed using Single Instruction, Multiple Data (SIMD) instructions, with significant contributions from DeekSeek-R1.
 The PR includes a dynamic model_map built from API responses, removing the necessity for hardcoded versions, showcasing innovation in plugin development.
 Simon Willison’s Weblog also covers recent topics such as open source projects, Anthropic&#39;s Citations API, and Large Language Model (LLM) projects, indicating a focus on cutting-edge technology discussions.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://simonwillison.net/2025/Jan/27/llamacpp-pr/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-28T00:00:00.000ZPromising results from DeepSeek R1 for code</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Illustrated DeepSeek-R1]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>DeepSeek-R1 is a newly released AI model emphasizing enhanced reasoning capabilities through a structured three-step training process: language modeling, supervised fine-tuning (SFT), and preference tuning. The model incorporates long chains of reasoning data, an interim reasoning model, and large-scale reinforcement learning (RL), excelling in reasoning tasks by generating thinking tokens. It utilizes a mixture-of-experts architecture, which allows it to efficiently handle complex reasoning tasks, marking a significant advancement in AI model design.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://newsletter.languagemodels.co/p/the-illustrated-deepseek-r1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-28T00:00:00.000ZThe Illustrated DeepSeek-R1</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Machine Learning in Production (CMU Course)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Carnegie Mellon University offers a course titled &quot;Machine Learning in Production/AI Engineering&quot; for Spring 2025, focusing on building, deploying, and maintaining machine learning-enabled software products. The course emphasizes responsible AI practices and MLOps (Machine Learning Operations), covering the entire lifecycle from prototype to production. It is designed for students with data science and basic programming skills, featuring lectures, labs, and a group project, with resources available on GitHub.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://mlip-cmu.github.io/s2025/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-28T00:00:00.000ZMachine Learning in Production (CMU Course)</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Open-R1: an open reproduction of DeepSeek-R1]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Open-R1 is an initiative to replicate DeepSeek-R1, a reasoning model comparable to OpenAI&#39;s o1, focusing on transparency and open-source collaboration.
 The project seeks to recreate DeepSeek-R1&#39;s datasets and training pipeline, which are currently undisclosed, using reinforcement learning (RL) without human supervision.
 Open-R1 encourages community contributions to expand the model&#39;s applications beyond mathematics, including fields like coding and medicine.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://huggingface.co/blog/open-r1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-28T00:00:00.000ZOpen-R1: an open reproduction of DeepSeek-R1</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The future of Rebble]]></title>
            <link>https://rebble.io/2025/01/27/the-future-of-rebble.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-28T00:00:00.000ZThe future of Rebble</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Alpha Myth: How captive wolves led us astray]]></title>
            <link>https://anthonydavidadams.substack.com/p/the-alpha-myth-how-captive-wolves</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-28T00:00:00.000ZThe Alpha Myth: How captive wolves led us astray</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Go 1.24's go tool is one of the best additions to the ecosystem in years]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Go 1.24 introduces a new <code>go tool</code> command and <code>tool</code> directive in <code>go.mod</code>, enhancing the management of project tools in the Go ecosystem.
 This update addresses issues with the <code>tools.go</code> pattern, such as performance impacts and dependency tree bloat, by allowing more efficient tool management and reducing unnecessary dependencies.
 While the <code>go tool</code> command improves performance by caching <code>go run</code> invocations, there are concerns about tool dependencies being treated as indirect, potentially leading to dependency clashes.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.jvt.me/posts/2025/01/27/go-tools-124/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-28T00:00:00.000ZGo 1.24&apos;s go tool is one of the best additions to the ecosystem in years</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I trusted an LLM, now I'm on day 4 of an afternoon project]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The author embarked on a project called Deskthang, intending to create a desk device using a Raspberry Pi Pico, LCD display, and RGB LEDs, while testing AI&#39;s capabilities.
 AI tools like ChatGPT and Claude initially assisted but ultimately led to a buggy implementation, causing issues like buffer conflicts and data corruption.
 Key lessons learned include recognizing AI as a tool rather than a co-pilot, understanding the value of friction and mistakes in learning, and the importance of patience over overconfidence.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://nemo.foo/blog/day-4-of-an-afternoon-project</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-28T00:00:00.000ZI trusted an LLM, now I&apos;m on day 4 of an afternoon project</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia sheds almost $600B in market cap]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Nvidia&#39;s market cap suffered a historic loss of nearly $600 billion, with shares dropping 17% due to competition concerns from Chinese AI lab DeepSeek.
 The sell-off impacted the broader U.S. tech sector, causing declines in companies like Dell and Oracle, and contributing to a 3.1% fall in the Nasdaq index.
 DeepSeek&#39;s new AI model, developed using Nvidia&#39;s H800 chips, has heightened competition fears, affecting Nvidia&#39;s stock despite its previous gains, and reducing CEO Jensen Huang&#39;s net worth by $21 billion.</p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.cnbc.com/2025/01/27/nvidia-sheds-almost-600-billion-in-market-cap-biggest-drop-ever.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-28T00:00:00.000ZNvidia sheds almost $600B in market cap</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Janus Pro 1B running 100% locally in-browser on WebGPU]]></title>
            <link
      >https://old.reddit.com/r/LocalLLaMA/comments/1ibnso0/janus_pro_1b_running_100_locally_inbrowser_on/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-28T00:00:00.000ZJanus Pro 1B running 100% locally in-browser on WebGPU</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Berkeley Researchers Replicate DeepSeek R1's Core Tech for Just $30: A Small Mod]]></title>
            <link>https://xyzlabs.substack.com/p/berkeley-researchers-replicate-deepseek</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-28T00:00:00.000ZBerkeley Researchers Replicate DeepSeek R1&apos;s Core Tech for Just $30: A Small Mod</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A layoff fundamentally changed how I perceive work]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The author received an unexpected layoff notice from their company&#39;s COO, despite previous assurances that layoffs wouldn&#39;t occur, indicating a disconnect between company communication and actions.
 The experience led to a loss of trust in modern work environments, where employees feel disposable even when companies are financially stable, prompting a shift towards minimal effort and job security skepticism.
 In Germany, labor laws prioritize protecting vulnerable employees during layoffs, but this does not guarantee job security for all, leading to advice for employees to adhere strictly to contract hours and seek other job opportunities.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://mertbulan.com/2025/01/26/once-you-are-laid-off-you-will-never-be-the-same-again/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-27T00:00:00.000ZA layoff fundamentally changed how I perceive work</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Marginalia – A search engine that prioritizes non-commercial content]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Marginalia Search has launched a new site focusing on non-commercial content and discovery tools, emphasizing user privacy and data protection.
 The search engine operates using open-source technology, without AI or cloud services, and complies with GDPR and the EU Cookie Directive.
 The source code is available under an AGPL license, promoting transparency and community collaboration.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://marginalia-search.com/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-27T00:00:00.000ZMarginalia – A search engine that prioritizes non-commercial content</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kansas tuberculosis outbreak is America's largest recorded since the 1950s]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Kansas is facing the largest tuberculosis outbreak in U.S. history, with 66 active cases and 79 latent infections reported in the Kansas City metro area since 2024, primarily in Wyandotte County. The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC) is aiding local health officials in managing the outbreak, which is ongoing but has seen a reduction in active cases to approximately 32. Tuberculosis is a bacterial infection affecting the lungs, spread through the air, and treatable with antibiotics, with the risk to the general public considered low.</p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.cjonline.com/story/news/politics/government/2025/01/24/kansas-tuberculosis-outbreak-is-largest-in-recorded-history-in-u-s/77881467007/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-27T00:00:00.000ZKansas tuberculosis outbreak is America&apos;s largest recorded since the 1950s</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Openhaystack: Build 'AirTags' – track Bluetooth devices via Apple's network]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>OpenHaystack is a framework that enables tracking of personal Bluetooth devices using Apple&#39;s Find My network, developed by the Secure Mobile Networking Lab at TU Darmstadt.
 It is based on reverse-engineering Apple&#39;s Find My network and requires macOS 11 and a Bluetooth device, such as a BBC micro:bit, to function.
 OpenHaystack is open-source under the GNU Affero General Public License v3.0, supports various devices, and includes a mobile version for Android and iOS, though it remains experimental and unaffiliated with Apple.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/seemoo-lab/openhaystack</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-27T00:00:00.000ZOpenhaystack: Build &apos;AirTags&apos; – track Bluetooth devices via Apple&apos;s network</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lessons in creating family photos that people want to keep (2018)]]></title>
            <link
      >https://estherschindler.medium.com/the-old-family-photos-project-lessons-in-creating-family-photos-that-people-want-to-keep-ea3909129943</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-27T00:00:00.000ZLessons in creating family photos that people want to keep (2018)</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DeepSeek My User Agent]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>DeepSeek R1 is a new model designed to reveal the chain-of-thought to users, available for free at chat.deepseek.com or through a more affordable API compared to OpenAI.
 Following the article&#39;s release, the DeepSeek API encountered issues, with platform.deepseek.com returning 404 errors, indicating potential disruptions caused by DeepSeek My User Agent.
 Users can explore top judgments on Hacker News and utilize the &quot;Judge Me&quot; prompt at chat.deepseek.com for a personalized experience.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.jasonthorsness.com/20</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-27T00:00:00.000ZDeepSeek My User Agent</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Purelymail: Cheap, no-nonsense email]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Purelymail provides cost-effective email hosting with compatibility for IMAP and POP3, allowing use with most mail applications or through Roundcube webmail.
 The service is notably affordable, offering a single email account with 3 GB of storage for $10 annually, which is cheaper than competitors such as Protonmail, Fastmail, and Google Workspace.
 While Purelymail is in beta and may have occasional issues like email blocking and lack of 24/7 support, it emphasizes security and does not sell user data.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://purelymail.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-27T00:00:00.000ZPurelymail: Cheap, no-nonsense email</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Astronomers delete asteroid because it turned out to be Tesla Roadster]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Astronomers initially misclassified Elon Musk&#39;s Tesla Roadster as an asteroid, emphasizing the need for improved transparency in tracking deep-space objects.
 The Minor Planet Center corrected the classification error, highlighting the difficulty in distinguishing between natural and artificial objects in space.
 The incident points to the absence of a central repository for tracking deep-space objects, complicating efforts to monitor potential asteroid threats, with amateur astronomers playing a vital role in identification.</p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.astronomy.com/science/astronomers-just-deleted-an-asteroid-because-it-turned-out-to-be-elon-musks-tesla-roadster/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-27T00:00:00.000ZAstronomers delete asteroid because it turned out to be Tesla Roadster</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DeepSeek releases Janus Pro, a text-to-image generator [pdf]]]></title>
            <link>https://github.com/deepseek-ai/Janus/blob/main/janus_pro_tech_report.pdf</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-27T00:00:00.000ZDeepSeek releases Janus Pro, a text-to-image generator [pdf]</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brazil bans Sam Altman's tech firm Tools for Humanity from paying for iris scans]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Brazil&#39;s data protection authority has prohibited Tools for Humanity from offering compensation, including cryptocurrency, for iris scans to prevent undue influence on individuals&#39; decisions to share biometric data.
 Tools for Humanity, co-founded by OpenAI CEO Sam Altman, aims to develop a global identity system through iris scans under its World project.
 The company asserts compliance with Brazilian laws and is engaging with the authority to resolve concerns following an investigation that began last November.</p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://economictimes.indiatimes.com/tech/technology/brazil-bans-sam-altmans-tech-firm-tools-for-humanity-from-paying-for-iris-scans/articleshow/117540826.cms?from=mdr</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-27T00:00:00.000ZBrazil bans Sam Altman&apos;s tech firm Tools for Humanity from paying for iris scans</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My failed attempt to shrink all NPM packages by 5%]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>In 2022, a proposal was made to use the Zopfli compressor to reduce npm package sizes by 5%, aiming to enhance performance and lower storage costs. The proposal was rejected by npm maintainers due to concerns about Zopfli&#39;s slow compression speed, decompression time, lockfile issues, and integration complexity. The experience provided insights into proposal writing and evaluating trade-offs, despite the proposal&#39;s withdrawal.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://evanhahn.com/my-failed-attempt-to-shrink-all-npm-packages-by-5-percent/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-27T00:00:00.000ZMy failed attempt to shrink all NPM packages by 5%</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Former tech CEO suing to get the record of his arrest removed from the internet]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Former tech CEO Maury Blackman is suing journalist Jack Poulson for $25 million to remove a 2021 domestic violence arrest from the internet, despite the record being sealed by a judge.
 The lawsuit has ignited First Amendment debates, with the Electronic Frontier Foundation defending Poulson, emphasizing the public interest in the publication.
 The First Amendment Coalition has filed a lawsuit challenging the California law that prevents the publication of sealed arrest records, highlighting the tension between privacy and free speech rights.</p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://sf.gazetteer.co/a-former-tech-ceo-is-on-a-crusade-to-get-the-record-of-his-arrest-removed-from-the-internet</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-27T00:00:00.000ZFormer tech CEO suing to get the record of his arrest removed from the internet</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nvidia, ASML Plunge as DeepSeek Triggers Tech Stock Selloff]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Nvidia&#39;s stock value dropped by $560 billion, marking the largest decline in market history, primarily due to concerns over the Chinese AI startup DeepSeek.
 DeepSeek&#39;s competitive low-cost AI model has raised fears about the future of US companies&#39; AI investments, affecting Nvidia&#39;s shares and major indexes like the S&amp;P 500 and Nasdaq 100.
 Despite Nvidia&#39;s challenges, Meta plans to boost AI project spending, and OpenAI, SoftBank, and Oracle have announced a significant $100 billion AI infrastructure venture.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://finance.yahoo.com/news/asml-sinks-china-ai-startup-081823609.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-27T00:00:00.000ZNvidia, ASML Plunge as DeepSeek Triggers Tech Stock Selloff</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mark Zuckerberg: This Man Is a Coward]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Mark Zuckerberg faces criticism for his silence as former President Donald Trump dismantles the National Institutes of Health, affecting $40 billion in research funding, despite Zuckerberg&#39;s previous commitments to disease research.
 Zuckerberg&#39;s actions at Meta, including reducing fact-checking, content moderation, and diversity initiatives, while promoting Republican executives, suggest a shift in principles, aligning with Trump&#39;s demands.
 Critics argue that Zuckerberg&#39;s compliance with Trump&#39;s authoritarian tendencies reflects a lack of courage, influencing other tech companies like Amazon to potentially adopt similar stances, thus impacting his legacy.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theindex.media/this-man-is-a-coward/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-27T00:00:00.000ZMark Zuckerberg: This Man Is a Coward</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Oliver Heaviside and the theory of transmission lines (2021)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>PA3FWM&#39;s amateur radio website delves into technical topics such as single-sideband FM, software-defined radio (SDR) soundcards, and antenna design.
 The site highlights Oliver Heaviside&#39;s contributions to transmission line theory, including his improvements to Maxwell&#39;s equations and telegraph cable models.
 Content is adapted from a November 2021 article in the Dutch amateur radio magazine Electron, providing historical and technical insights into signal transmission and cable design.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pa3fwm.nl/technotes/tn28-heaviside-transmission-lines.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-27T00:00:00.000ZOliver Heaviside and the theory of transmission lines (2021)</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Steam Brick: No screen, no controller, just a power button and a USB port]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The Steam Brick Mod is a custom project that modifies a Steam Deck to be smaller and lighter by removing the screen and controller, leaving only essential components. The modification uses a 1TB OLED Steam Deck and involves creating a custom case with a 3D printer, resulting in a device about a third the size and 24% lighter than the original. Despite its portability benefits, the mod has limitations, such as no BIOS access and difficulty determining if the device is on, and it is not officially supported by Valve, posing risks of damage.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://crastinator-pro.github.io/steam-brick/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-26T00:00:00.000ZSteam Brick: No screen, no controller, just a power button and a USB port</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It's not a crime if we do it with an app]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Big food companies are allegedly using apps to engage in price-fixing, a practice termed &quot;greedflation,&quot; by coordinating pricing through third-party data brokers like Potatotrac.
 This issue is not limited to the food industry but also affects housing and other sectors, drawing attention from antitrust authorities.
 Cory Doctorow&#39;s new book, &quot;Picks and Shovels,&quot; delves into these themes, with the author making several appearances to promote it.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://pluralistic.net/2025/01/25/potatotrac/#carbo-loading</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-26T00:00:00.000ZIt&apos;s not a crime if we do it with an app</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Every HTML Element]]></title>
            <link>https://iamwillwang.com/dollar/every-html-element/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-26T00:00:00.000ZEvery HTML Element</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title
      ><![CDATA[The South Vietnamese pilot who landed a Cessna on a carrier to save his family (2019)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>In April 1975, Maj. Buang-Ly, a South Vietnamese pilot, executed a daring escape with his family in a small plane during the fall of South Vietnam. Captain Lawrence Chambers of the USS Midway made the unprecedented decision to clear the deck for Buang&#39;s landing, even discarding helicopters, allowing Buang to land safely. This event was part of Operation Frequent Wind, the final phase of the evacuation of American civilians and &quot;at-risk&quot; Vietnamese from Saigon, and Buang&#39;s plane is now displayed at the National Naval Aviation Museum.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.historynet.com/maj-buang-lys-daring-feat-to-save-his-family/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-26T00:00:00.000ZThe South Vietnamese pilot who landed a Cessna on a carrier to save his family (2019)</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[YC Graveyard: 821 inactive Y Combinator startups]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The YC Graveyard lists 821 inactive startups from Y Combinator, a prominent startup accelerator, highlighting the challenges faced by new ventures. These startups, from 39 batches and 50 industries, include sectors like finance, healthcare, retail, and technology, demonstrating the broad scope of Y Combinator&#39;s influence. Notable companies such as Blume Benefits, Fileforge, and Celest are among those that have ceased operations, reflecting the high-risk nature of startup ventures.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ycgraveyard.iamwillwang.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-26T00:00:00.000ZYC Graveyard: 821 inactive Y Combinator startups</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[An invalid 68030 instruction accidentally allowed the Mac Classic II to boot]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Doug Brown identified a bug in the Macintosh Classic II&#39;s ROM that should have stopped it from booting, but an undefined instruction on the Motorola MC68030 CPU allowed it to proceed. Using the MAME emulator, Doug discovered that the Classic II failed to boot in 32-bit mode due to a bus error from an invalid address, corrected by an undocumented instruction on actual hardware. This finding underscores the role of emulators in uncovering hidden hardware bugs and the intricacies of undocumented CPU instructions, with real hardware tests confirming the undocumented instruction&#39;s importance for booting.</p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.downtowndougbrown.com/2025/01/the-invalid-68030-instruction-that-accidentally-allowed-the-mac-classic-ii-to-successfully-boot-up/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-26T00:00:00.000ZAn invalid 68030 instruction accidentally allowed the Mac Classic II to boot</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Caltrain's electric fleet more efficient than expected]]></title>
            <link>https://www.caltrain.com/news/caltrains-electric-fleet-more-efficient-expected</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-25T00:00:00.000ZCaltrain&apos;s electric fleet more efficient than expected</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lightpanda, an open-source headless browser in Zig]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Lightpanda is a new open-source headless browser developed in Zig, designed to be faster and more efficient than existing options like Chrome headless, particularly for web scraping and automation tasks. It features an HTTP loader, HTML parser, DOM tree, JavaScript runtime, and a CDP server, making it compatible with tools like Puppeteer and Playwright, while being approximately 10 times faster and using 10 times less memory than Chrome headless. Currently in beta, Lightpanda supports limited web APIs, with plans for expansion, and offers a Managed Cloud service as part of its business model.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/lightpanda-io/browser</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-25T00:00:00.000ZLightpanda, an open-source headless browser in Zig</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[PhysicsForums and the Dead Internet Theory]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>&quot;Hall of Impossible Dreams&quot; is a repository featuring diverse content, including code and literature, and recently discussed the decline of PhysicsForums due to AI-generated content. PhysicsForums, established in 2001, was a thriving science forum until the rise of centralized platforms like StackExchange and the infiltration of AI-generated posts by 2025. The post raises concerns about the &quot;Dead Internet Theory,&quot; which posits that much of the internet is now non-human content, highlighting the challenges and ethical implications of sustaining online communities in the face of evolving technology.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hallofdreams.org/posts/physicsforums/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-25T00:00:00.000ZPhysicsForums and the Dead Internet Theory</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[File Explorer is merged to Helix editor]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The Helix editor has introduced a new file explorer feature, inspired by the telescope-file-browser, allowing users to navigate files like a file picker.
 Developed by contributor drybalka, the feature has been positively received, with feedback for enhancements such as directory slashes and icons.
 Some users on MacOS reported issues with the command palette, but the file explorer functions effectively with keybindings, and future updates may address .gitignore file exclusions.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/helix-editor/helix/pull/11285</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-25T00:00:00.000ZFile Explorer is merged to Helix editor</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A QR code that sends you to a different destination – lenticular and adversarial]]></title>
            <link>https://mstdn.social/@isziaui/113874436953157913</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-24T00:00:00.000ZA QR code that sends you to a different destination – lenticular and adversarial</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The State of Vim]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Following the death of Bram Moolenaar, Vim&#39;s founder, in 2023, the community has reorganized to ensure the continuation of Vim&#39;s development, with Christian Brabandt taking a more active role. The project is addressing challenges such as managing the Vim GitHub organization, updating the website, and considering changes like XDG support, while remaining in maintenance mode. VimConf 2024 in Tokyo highlighted international collaboration, with presentations in English and Japanese, and emphasized community input and careful testing over a single leader approach.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://lwn.net/Articles/1002342/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-24T00:00:00.000ZThe State of Vim</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UI is hell: four-function calculators]]></title>
            <link>https://lcamtuf.substack.com/p/ui-is-hell-four-function-calculators</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-24T00:00:00.000ZUI is hell: four-function calculators</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Build It Yourself]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Armin Ronacher addresses the problem of dependency churn in software development, especially in JavaScript and Rust ecosystems, where frequent updates and numerous dependencies can lead to security vulnerabilities and complexity.
 He suggests a shift towards writing code with minimal dependencies, emphasizing the advantages of stable, self-written functions over extensive dependency graphs.
 Ronacher calls for a cultural change in both corporate and open-source communities to prioritize simplicity and stability in coding practices, which can lead to reduced maintenance and faster implementation.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://lucumr.pocoo.org/2025/1/24/build-it-yourself/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-24T00:00:00.000ZBuild It Yourself</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I made an open-source laptop from scratch]]></title>
            <link>https://www.byran.ee/posts/creation/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZI made an open-source laptop from scratch</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to improve your WFH lighting to reduce eye strain]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>To minimize eye strain while working from home, create a balanced lighting environment using natural light, sheer curtains, and flicker-free artificial lights. Implement the 20/20/20 rule: every 20 minutes, look at something 20 feet away for 20 seconds to relax your eyes. Complement your workspace with light-filtering curtains and desk lighting that matches monitor brightness, while also taking regular breaks to maintain overall health.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://rustle.ca/posts/articles/work-from-home-lighting</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZHow to improve your WFH lighting to reduce eye strain</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tailwind CSS v4.0]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Tailwind CSS v4.0 introduces a high-performance engine, achieving builds up to 5x faster and incremental builds over 100x faster, enhancing performance and flexibility for developers. The update includes modern CSS features such as cascade layers, color-mix(), and built-in container queries, along with a first-party Vite plugin for improved integration and simplified installation. New features like 3D transform utilities, expanded gradient APIs, and CSS-first configuration with design tokens as CSS variables make it easier and faster to build modern web projects, with an upgrade guide available for existing projects.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://tailwindcss.com/blog/tailwindcss-v4</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZTailwind CSS v4.0</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Federal Court (Finally) Rules Backdoor Searches of Data Unconstitutional]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>A federal district court has ruled that backdoor searches of databases containing Americans&#39; private communications under Section 702 require a warrant, marking a significant legal decision in United States v. Hasbajrami. Despite Congress reauthorizing Section 702, evidence shows misuse by the FBI and intelligence community, with 3.4 million warrantless searches conducted in 2021, prompting calls for reform to ensure constitutional protections. The court&#39;s decision highlights the unconstitutional nature of warrantless searches under Section 702, urging Congress to mandate warrants for searches involving U.S. persons&#39; data before its expiration in 2026.</p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.eff.org/deeplinks/2025/01/victory-federal-court-finally-rules-backdoor-searches-702-data-unconstitutional</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZFederal Court (Finally) Rules Backdoor Searches of Data Unconstitutional</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Most Influential Papers in Computer Science History]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The list highlights seven seminal papers in computer science history, each contributing foundational concepts that underpin modern technology, such as the Turing Machine, information theory, and the relational database model.
 These papers introduced groundbreaking ideas like NP-completeness, TCP/IP, the World Wide Web, and PageRank, which have significantly influenced computation, communication, and internet development.
 Bonus mentions include influential works on Lisp, distributed systems, and the &quot;Attention Is All You Need&quot; paper, showcasing the evolution and diversity of computer science research.</p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://terriblesoftware.org/2025/01/22/the-7-most-influential-papers-in-computer-science-history/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZMost Influential Papers in Computer Science History</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[F-Droid's Progress and What's Coming in 2025]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>In 2024, F-Droid made notable advancements in decentralizing app distribution, enhancing its infrastructure, and expanding its ecosystem, largely due to community support and funding. Significant achievements included infrastructure upgrades and the expansion of tools like Repomaker and Mobifree, with over 7205 app updates and 402 new apps added. Looking forward to 2025, F-Droid plans to utilize an Open Technology Fund grant to further improve infrastructure and continue focusing on decentralizing app distribution and promoting open-source alternatives.</p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://f-droid.org/2025/01/21/a-look-back-at-2024-f-droids-progress-and-whats-coming-in-2025.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZF-Droid&apos;s Progress and What&apos;s Coming in 2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Understanding gRPC, OpenAPI and REST and when to use them in API design (2020)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>API design primarily uses two models: gRPC (Remote Procedure Call) and REST (Representational State Transfer), both often mapped to HTTP, with gRPC using HTTP/2 for efficient communication.
 REST APIs are known for their simplicity and stability, while gRPC offers efficient client libraries and server implementations, making it suitable for internal APIs or when using specific tools like Cloud Endpoints.
 OpenAPI, similar to RPC, requires constructing URLs from templates, exposing HTTP details, and may involve complex custom HTTP mappings, offering broader HTTP tool compatibility compared to gRPC.</p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://cloud.google.com/blog/products/api-management/understanding-grpc-openapi-and-rest-and-when-to-use-them</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZUnderstanding gRPC, OpenAPI and REST and when to use them in API design (2020)</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[NIH hit with freezes on meetings, travel, communications, and hiring]]></title>
            <link
      >https://www.science.org/content/article/trump-hits-nih-devastating-freezes-meetings-travel-communications-and-hiring</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZNIH hit with freezes on meetings, travel, communications, and hiring</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bun 1.2 Is Released]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Bun 1.2 is a significant update for JavaScript and TypeScript development, enhancing Node.js compatibility and adding built-in support for S3 and Postgres. The update introduces Bun.sql for SQL databases, a faster package manager, and a built-in test runner, alongside improved performance and new JavaScript features. Bun 1.2 also enhances bundling with HTML imports, standalone executables, and a new CSS parser, while remaining free and open-source with ongoing community contributions.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://bun.sh/blog/bun-v1.2</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZBun 1.2 Is Released</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tech takes the Pareto principle too far]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Bobby Lockhart critiques the tech industry&#39;s reliance on the Pareto Principle and MVPs, which often result in unfinished products due to insufficient incentives to complete them.
 He contrasts this with the gaming industry&#39;s &#39;vertical slice&#39; approach, which focuses on creating a polished product from the start.
 Lockhart advocates for a craftsmanlike approach to software development, emphasizing the importance of completing and refining products for a polished final outcome.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://bobbylox.com/blog/tech-takes-the-pareto-principle-too-far/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZTech takes the Pareto principle too far</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I made a multiplayer shooter game in Lisp, here is my journey]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The game &quot;Wizard Masters,&quot; a multiplayer third-person shooter, was developed using Clojure, a Lisp dialect, and is available on CrazyGames. Clojure was chosen for its full-stack capabilities and interactive REPL system, while Babylon.js was used for graphics due to its features and community support. Challenges included complex networking with Clojure async libraries, state management with Clojure&#39;s immutability, and the lack of a strong Clojure game development community, highlighting the potential benefits of transitioning to mainstream engines like Unity or Unreal for future projects.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ertu.dev/posts/i-made-an-online-shooter-game-in-lisp/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZI made a multiplayer shooter game in Lisp, here is my journey</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trae: An AI-powered IDE by ByteDance]]></title>
            <link>https://www.trae.ai/home</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZTrae: An AI-powered IDE by ByteDance</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Foundations of Large Language Models]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The book &quot;Foundations of Large Language Models&quot; by Tong Xiao and Jingbo Zhu explores key concepts such as pre-training, generative models, prompting techniques, and alignment methods in large language models. It targets college students, professionals, and practitioners in the field of natural language processing, making it a valuable resource for those interested in Computation and Language, Artificial Intelligence, and Machine Learning. The book is available for further reading on arXiv under the identifier 2501.09223 [cs.CL].</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2501.09223</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZFoundations of Large Language Models</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hacking Subaru: Tracking and Controlling Cars via the Starlink Admin Panel]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>A security vulnerability in Subaru&#39;s STARLINK service was discovered on November 20, 2024, allowing unauthorized access to vehicles and customer accounts in the US, Canada, and Japan. The flaw enabled attackers to remotely control vehicles and access personal information using minimal data, such as a last name and ZIP code, due to issues in the STARLINK admin panel. The vulnerability was reported and patched within 24 hours without any malicious exploitation, underscoring the challenges in securing connected car systems due to broad access permissions.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://samcurry.net/hacking-subaru</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZHacking Subaru: Tracking and Controlling Cars via the Starlink Admin Panel</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Where is London's most central sheep?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Vauxhall City Farm, established in 1976, is the closest city farm to central London, located just over a mile from Trafalgar Square.
 The farm houses several sheep, including a Shetland and a Herdwick named Daffodil, showcasing the rural charm within the urban environment.
 Spitalfields City Farm, the second closest to central London, hosts a Herdwick ewe named Beatrix and several Castlemilk Moorits, emphasizing the unique appeal of city farms in London.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://diamondgeezer.blogspot.com/2025/01/londons-most-central-sheep.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-23T00:00:00.000ZWhere is London&apos;s most central sheep?</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ross Ulbricht granted a full pardon]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Ross has been granted a full pardon by former President Donald Trump, resulting in his release.
 The pardon has been met with significant gratitude, with Trump being commended for fulfilling his promise.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/Free_Ross/status/1881851923005165704</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-22T00:00:00.000ZRoss Ulbricht granted a full pardon</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stargate Project: SoftBank, OpenAI, Oracle, MGX to build data centers]]></title>
            <link
      >https://apnews.com/article/trump-ai-openai-oracle-softbank-son-altman-ellison-be261f8a8ee07a0623d4170397348c41</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-22T00:00:00.000ZStargate Project: SoftBank, OpenAI, Oracle, MGX to build data centers</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Is anyone doing anything cool with tiny language models?]]></title>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42784365</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-22T00:00:00.000ZIs anyone doing anything cool with tiny language models?</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hunyuan3D 2.0 – High-Resolution 3D Assets Generation]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Hunyuan3D Studio has launched 3D generation capabilities on their website and released inference code and pretrained models for Hunyuan3D 2.0.
 Hunyuan3D 2.0 is an advanced system for creating high-resolution 3D assets, featuring a shape generation model (Hunyuan3D-DiT) and a texture synthesis model (Hunyuan3D-Paint), offering superior geometry details and texture quality.
 Users can access Hunyuan3D 2.0 through code or the Gradio App, with more information available on their official site and open-source plan.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/Tencent/Hunyuan3D-2</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-22T00:00:00.000ZHunyuan3D 2.0 – High-Resolution 3D Assets Generation</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mastercard DNS error went unnoticed for years]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>MasterCard resolved a DNS (Domain Name System) error that could have led to traffic interception by registering an unused domain, which had been a vulnerability for nearly five years. Security researcher Philippe Caturegli identified the issue, involving a typo in a DNS server name, and registered the domain for $300 to prevent potential misuse, despite MasterCard&#39;s claim of no security risk. Caturegli&#39;s actions and public disclosure highlighted potential vulnerabilities and criticized MasterCard&#39;s response, revealing a history of similar DNS typos with the domain.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://krebsonsecurity.com/2025/01/mastercard-dns-error-went-unnoticed-for-years/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-22T00:00:00.000ZMastercard DNS error went unnoticed for years</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What are these bumps on the top of a pull-tab can?]]></title>
            <link>https://old.reddit.com/r/whatisthisthing/comments/1i5ztq4/comment/m8a7m8m/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-22T00:00:00.000ZWhat are these bumps on the top of a pull-tab can?</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DHS removes all members of cyber security advisory boards, halts investigations]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The splash screen&#39;s minimal styles are defined, with additional styles located in a separate CSS file, ensuring a consistent and optimized user interface.
 The Department of Homeland Security (DHS) has ended all advisory committee memberships, impacting cybersecurity panels such as the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (CISA).
 The Cyber Safety Review Board&#39;s investigation into the Salt Typhoon incident has been discontinued, indicating a halt in progress on this cybersecurity issue.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://bsky.app/profile/ericjgeller.com/post/3lgbpqmxeok2f</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-22T00:00:00.000ZDHS removes all members of cyber security advisory boards, halts investigations</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Isolating complexity is the essence of successful abstractions]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Complexity in software development should be managed and isolated rather than eliminated, as emphasized by Fred Hebert. In microservices, complexity is often hidden within individual services, while programming languages like Rust and TypeScript manage complexity through type systems and tools like Rust&#39;s borrow checker. Rust and TypeScript are favored by developers for their ability to reveal and manage complexity, allowing for successful abstractions by isolating complexity in well-defined areas.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://v5.chriskrycho.com/journal/essence-of-successful-abstractions/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-22T00:00:00.000ZIsolating complexity is the essence of successful abstractions</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My Struggle with Doom Scrolling]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The author addresses their doom scrolling habit by removing distracting apps like YouTube and Instagram and disabling the browser on their phone. They experienced some inconveniences, such as limited access to services, but found it beneficial for setting boundaries and reducing distractions. Reintroducing a restricted browser with a minimal user interface helped them regain control over media consumption, leading to more reading time and a calmer mindset.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://allthatjazz.me/posts/doom-scrolling-struggles</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-22T00:00:00.000ZMy Struggle with Doom Scrolling</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Tyranny of Structurelessness (1970)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Jo Freeman, also known as Joreen, critiques the concept of &quot;structurelessness&quot; in the women&#39;s liberation movement, arguing that all groups form structures, whether formal or informal. The article highlights issues with informal structures, such as elitism and lack of accountability, and suggests principles for democratic structuring. Emphasizes the necessity of formal structures to prevent power imbalances and to help the movement achieve its goals effectively and inclusively.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.jofreeman.com/joreen/tyranny.htm</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-22T00:00:00.000ZThe Tyranny of Structurelessness (1970)</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[0-click deanonymization attack targeting Signal, Discord, other platforms]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>A 15-year-old high school student discovered a 0-click deanonymization attack using Cloudflare&#39;s caching system, which can locate users within a 250-mile radius. This vulnerability affects popular apps like Signal and Discord, enabling attackers to track users without their consent. Despite reporting the issue, only a related bug was patched by Cloudflare, leaving the core vulnerability unaddressed, highlighting the need for users, particularly journalists and activists, to be vigilant about their privacy.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://gist.github.com/hackermondev/45a3cdfa52246f1d1201c1e8cdef6117</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-21T00:00:00.000Z0-click deanonymization attack targeting Signal, Discord, other platforms</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Startup Winter: Hacker News Lost Its Faith]]></title>
            <link>https://www.vincentschmalbach.com/startup-winter-hacker-news-lost-its-faith/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-21T00:00:00.000ZStartup Winter: Hacker News Lost Its Faith</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reverse engineering Call of Duty anti-cheat]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The Treyarch Anti-Cheat (TAC) in Black Ops Cold War is a user-mode anti-cheat system, lacking the kernel-mode component found in Modern Warfare&#39;s Ricochet. TAC employs Arxan for obfuscation, which complicates reverse engineering through techniques like runtime executable decryption, executable checksums, and pointer encryption. Key anti-cheat features include detection of API hooking, debug registers, network traffic monitoring, and external overlays, alongside various anti-debugging techniques and custom syscall stubs to bypass hooks.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ssno.cc/posts/reversing-tac-1-4-2025/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-21T00:00:00.000ZReverse engineering Call of Duty anti-cheat</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Did Elon Musk Appear to Sieg Heil at Trump Inauguration?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk was observed making a gesture at Trump&#39;s inauguration that some interpreted as a Nazi salute, leading to social media controversy. The Anti-Defamation League (ADL) suggested the gesture was likely an awkward moment rather than an intentional salute, with some attributing it to Musk&#39;s Asperger&#39;s syndrome. Musk responded to the controversy with a laughing emoji and expressed enthusiasm about Trump&#39;s mention of Mars, which aligns with his space exploration goals.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.jpost.com/international/article-838444</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-21T00:00:00.000ZDid Elon Musk Appear to Sieg Heil at Trump Inauguration?</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Musk appears to make back-to-back fascist salutes at inauguration rally]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Elon Musk faced backlash for making a gesture resembling a fascist-style salute during Donald Trump&#39;s inauguration celebrations, which some interpreted as a Nazi salute.
 The Anti-Defamation League acknowledged the gesture&#39;s resemblance to a Nazi salute but later suggested it was an awkward moment of enthusiasm, drawing criticism from Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez.
 Musk&#39;s actions were celebrated by some far-right figures, fueling debates about his political affiliations and intentions.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2025/jan/20/trump-elon-musk-salute</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-21T00:00:00.000ZElon Musk appears to make back-to-back fascist salutes at inauguration rally</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meta Censoring '#Democrat' on Instagram]]></title>
            <link>https://mstdn.chrisalemany.ca/@chris/113864600222476627</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-21T00:00:00.000ZMeta Censoring &apos;#Democrat&apos; on Instagram</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Organize local communities without Facebook?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The individual is seeking to transition local community interactions from Facebook to a self-hosted, federated platform, which allows for decentralized control and management.
 They are looking for off-the-shelf solutions or collaborators to facilitate this move, indicating a need for accessible and customizable options.
 The context involves rural areas with multiple small towns, each with a population of around 50,000, highlighting the importance of connectivity and community engagement.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42779776</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-21T00:00:00.000ZOrganize local communities without Facebook?</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Metacognitive laziness: Effects of generative AI on learning motivation]]></title>
            <link>https://bera-journals.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/bjet.13544</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-21T00:00:00.000ZMetacognitive laziness: Effects of generative AI on learning motivation</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Official DeepSeek R1 Now on Ollama]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>DeepSeek has introduced its first-generation reasoning models, which perform on par with OpenAI-o1 in tasks involving math, code, and reasoning. The models vary significantly in size, from 1.5 billion to 671 billion parameters, indicating diverse storage needs. These models are accessible under the MIT License, allowing for broad usage and modification.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ollama.com/library/deepseek-r1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-21T00:00:00.000ZOfficial DeepSeek R1 Now on Ollama</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[People are bad at reporting what they eat. That's a problem for dietary research]]></title>
            <link
      >https://www.science.org/content/article/people-are-bad-reporting-what-they-eat-s-problem-dietary-research</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-21T00:00:00.000ZPeople are bad at reporting what they eat. That&apos;s a problem for dietary research</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ROCm Device Support Wishlist]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>ROCm is gathering community feedback to determine which GPUs to support in future updates, with current compatibility details available on their website. Users are advocating for broader support, particularly for older and consumer-grade GPUs, and improved integration with Windows systems. There is a strong demand for consistent support across all architectures, emphasizing the significance of VRAM for AI applications, and calls for enhancements in AMD&#39;s APU support and a development process similar to NVIDIA&#39;s CUDA.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/ROCm/ROCm/discussions/4276</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-21T00:00:00.000ZROCm Device Support Wishlist</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ruff: Python linter and code formatter written in Rust]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Ruff DocsPlayground is a Python linter and code formatter written in Rust, offering speeds 10-100 times faster than traditional tools like Flake8 and Black. It supports Python 3.13, integrates with editors such as VS Code, and can replace multiple tools like Flake8, Black, and isort, while being monorepo-friendly. Ruff is widely adopted in major projects like Apache Airflow, FastAPI, and Pandas, and is available for installation via pip, pipx, and other package managers, with configuration support through pyproject.toml.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/astral-sh/ruff</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-21T00:00:00.000ZRuff: Python linter and code formatter written in Rust</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kimi K1.5: Scaling Reinforcement Learning with LLMs]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Kimi k1.5 is a cutting-edge multi-modal model that significantly outperforms GPT-4o and Claude Sonnet 3.5 in short-chain-of-thought (CoT) tasks, with improvements up to 550% on benchmarks such as AIME, MATH-500, and LiveCodeBench.
 It matches OpenAI&#39;s o1 in long-CoT performance across various modalities, utilizing reinforcement learning with long context scaling and enhanced policy optimization, while avoiding complex methods like Monte Carlo tree search.
 Kimi k1.5 is trained on both text and vision data, allowing for joint reasoning, and will soon be accessible via the Kimi OpenPlatform at <a href="https://kimi.ai">https://kimi.ai</a>.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/MoonshotAI/Kimi-k1.5</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-21T00:00:00.000ZKimi K1.5: Scaling Reinforcement Learning with LLMs</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Authors seek Meta's torrent client logs and seeding data in AI piracy probe]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Meta is facing a lawsuit for allegedly using pirated materials, specifically copyrighted books from LibGen, to train its AI models via BitTorrent.
 Authors, including Richard Kadrey and Sarah Silverman, accuse Meta of copyright infringement, while Meta claims its actions fall under fair use.
 The court has permitted new allegations about Meta&#39;s torrenting activities, with authors seeking access to Meta&#39;s torrent client logs and seeding data, underscoring the legal challenges surrounding AI training data and copyright issues.</p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://torrentfreak.com/authors-seek-metas-torrent-client-logs-and-seeding-data-in-ai-piracy-probe-250120/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-21T00:00:00.000ZAuthors seek Meta&apos;s torrent client logs and seeding data in AI piracy probe</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Elon Gives Nazi Salute During Inauguration Speech]]></title>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=e2bbb-6Clhs</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-21T00:00:00.000ZElon Gives Nazi Salute During Inauguration Speech</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[It's time to make computing personal again]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The article highlights the decline of personal computing freedom due to surveillance capitalism and Digital Rights Management (DRM), which have transferred control from users to corporations.
 It contrasts the past era of personal computing, which offered more user freedom, with today&#39;s tech environment dominated by business models that erode privacy.
 The author advocates for reclaiming digital autonomy through supporting open-source projects, pushing for privacy legislation, and reforming DRM laws to restore personal computing values.</p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.vintagecomputing.com/index.php/archives/3292/the-pc-is-dead-its-time-to-make-computing-personal-again</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-20T00:00:00.000ZIt&apos;s time to make computing personal again</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DeepSeek-R1]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>DeepSeek-R1 and DeepSeek-R1-Zero are first-generation reasoning models, with DeepSeek-R1 addressing issues like repetition and language mixing seen in DeepSeek-R1-Zero.
 The models, including six distilled versions, are open-sourced, with DeepSeek-R1-Distill-Qwen-32B achieving state-of-the-art results in reasoning, code, and math tasks.
 These models are available for download on HuggingFace, and users can interact with them via a chat website or an OpenAI-Compatible API, with instructions for local deployment provided.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/deepseek-ai/DeepSeek-R1</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-20T00:00:00.000ZDeepSeek-R1</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UK's hardware talent is being wasted]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The UK is experiencing a talent drain as top engineering graduates from prestigious universities face lower salaries compared to Silicon Valley, prompting many to switch to higher-paying fields like consulting or finance. This talent misallocation hinders innovation and economic growth, with issues such as geographical constraints, lack of venture capital for hardware, and stagnant traditional engineering firms contributing to the problem. The UK risks losing its best talent to overseas markets, missing the chance to create tech giants, and must act now to leverage its research institutions and engineering talent for a hardware revolution.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://josef.cn/blog/uk-talent</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-20T00:00:00.000ZUK&apos;s hardware talent is being wasted</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reverse Engineering Bambu Connect]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The guide discusses extracting a private key from the Bambu Connect app, an Electron application with known security vulnerabilities. Users are cautioned that the guide may be incomplete or outdated and should be followed at their own risk. The process involves using tools like Ghidra and asarfix to locate and decrypt the obfuscated private key and certificates, with a Python script provided for extraction.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://wiki.rossmanngroup.com/wiki/Reverse_Engineering_Bambu_Connect</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-20T00:00:00.000ZReverse Engineering Bambu Connect</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FrontierMath was funded by OpenAI]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The post highlights a lack of transparency in the collaboration between OpenAI and FrontierMath, with funding details only disclosed after a delay, causing confusion among contributors.
 Concerns are raised about OpenAI&#39;s potential access to and use of the dataset for training, despite verbal agreements suggesting otherwise, emphasizing the need for written agreements.
 The discussion underscores the importance of transparency and trust in collaborations, especially those involving AI capabilities, with commitments to improve transparency in future projects.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.lesswrong.com/posts/cu2E8wgmbdZbqeWqb/meemi-s-shortform</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-20T00:00:00.000ZFrontierMath was funded by OpenAI</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why is Git Autocorrect too fast for Formula One drivers?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Git&#39;s autocorrect feature executes a mistyped command after a default delay of 0.1 seconds, which is often too quick for users to cancel. Introduced in 2008, the feature uses a modified Levenshtein distance algorithm to guess the intended command, but defaults to not running any command if mistyped. A proposed patch suggests interpreting a setting of &quot;1&quot; as &quot;immediately&quot; to enhance usability, allowing users to configure the delay or prompt for confirmation.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.gitbutler.com/why-is-git-autocorrect-too-fast-for-formula-one-drivers/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-20T00:00:00.000ZWhy is Git Autocorrect too fast for Formula One drivers?</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I Met Paul Graham Once]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>The author attended Y Combinator in 2015, where they met Paul Graham and received advice on their startup, Appcanary, which was later acquired by GitHub.
 The author, now a transgender woman, expresses concern over Paul Graham&#39;s recent essay on &quot;Wokeness,&quot; feeling it reflects a rejection of inclusivity in the tech industry.
 The author is worried about increasing intolerance and potential discrimination in the tech industry but remains committed to living with respect and kindness.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>http://okayfail.com/2025/i-met-pg-once.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-20T00:00:00.000ZI Met Paul Graham Once</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Escape the walled garden and algorithm black boxes with RSS feeds]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>RSS (Really Simple Syndication) and Atom provide decentralized alternatives to centralized social media, allowing users to control their content consumption. Feed readers such as Miniflux, NetNewsWire, and Newsboat enable subscriptions to diverse content sources, including YouTube channels, podcasts, and blogs. Tools like PolitePol can create feeds for websites lacking them, promoting user autonomy in media consumption.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.johnwalker.nl/posts/escape-the-walled-garden-with-rss</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-20T00:00:00.000ZEscape the walled garden and algorithm black boxes with RSS feeds</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Please don't force dark mode]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<p>Website designers are advised not to enforce dark mode on users, as it can cause eye strain, especially with high contrast settings like white text on a black background. The Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG) currently suggest a minimum contrast ratio but do not address maximum contrast, which may lead to discomfort; this might be addressed in the upcoming WCAG 3.0. Dark mode is beneficial in specific scenarios, such as reading on OLED screens in dark environments or coding with Integrated Development Environments (IDEs) that offer comfortable contrast settings.</p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://iamvishnu.com/posts/please-dont-force-dark-mode</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-20T00:00:00.000ZPlease don&apos;t force dark mode</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
