<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0"
>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 19:16:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/story/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[One of my papers got declined today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://mathstodon.xyz/@tao/113721192051328193</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZOne of my papers got declined today</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MitmProxy2Swagger: Automagically reverse-engineer REST APIs]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>mitmproxy2swagger is a tool that converts mitmproxy captures into OpenAPI 3.0 specifications, facilitating the reverse-engineering of REST APIs by capturing application traffic. - The tool now supports HTTP Archive (HAR) files from browser Developer Tools, expanding its usability for developers. - Installation can be done using Python3 and pip or Docker, and the project employs tools like poetry, pre-commit, and pytest for development, with an MIT license.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/alufers/mitmproxy2swagger</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZMitmProxy2Swagger: Automagically reverse-engineer REST APIs</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The GPU, not the TPM, is the root of hardware DRM]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://mjg59.dreamwidth.org/70954.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZThe GPU, not the TPM, is the root of hardware DRM</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Zasper: A Modern and Efficient Alternative to JupyterLab, Built in Go]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Zasper is a high-performance Integrated Development Environment (IDE) inspired by Jupyter, optimized for massive concurrency and minimal memory usage. - It is built with the Go programming language for enhanced concurrency and performance, offering both Electron and Web App versions, and is open-source under the AGPL-3.0 license. - Zasper supports REPL-style (Read-Eval-Print Loop) data applications and aims to expand beyond Jupyter Notebooks to support custom data applications, with full support on Mac and limited support on Linux.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/zasper-io/zasper</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZZasper: A Modern and Efficient Alternative to JupyterLab, Built in Go</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rails for everything]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Rails 8 is optimized for small projects and single developers, offering a comprehensive &quot;Getting Started with Rails&quot; guide to build full-featured applications.</li>
<li>SQLite is now production-ready in Rails 8, reducing the dependency on PostgreSQL or Redis, and includes basic continuous integration (CI) configuration with 2000 free GitHub action minutes.</li>
<li>The new authentication generator and straightforward deployment with Kamal make user sign-in and live app setup with SSL easier, promoting best practices.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://literallythevoid.com/blog/rails_for_everything.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZRails for everything</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Where to Work After 40?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42573875</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZWhere to Work After 40?</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My favourite computer ergonomics hack]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Jacob Vosmaer introduces &quot;The Beeper,&quot; a DIY device designed to encourage movement by beeping if the computer screen remains unlocked for too long. - The Beeper is composed of hardware (Adafruit Feather Huzzah ESP8266, switch, piezo buzzer), firmware (Lua script), and software that manages activation. - Despite its simplicity, the device effectively promotes regular movement, and Jacob acknowledges his wife&#39;s support in the project.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.jacobvosmaer.nl/0036-beeper/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZMy favourite computer ergonomics hack</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UBlockOrigin GPL code being stolen by team behind Honey browser extension]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://old.reddit.com/r/uBlockOrigin/comments/1hr6xjc/ubo_quick_filters_list_being_stolen_by_team/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZUBlockOrigin GPL code being stolen by team behind Honey browser extension</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blogs rot. Wikis wait]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The post contrasts the enduring nature of wikis with the transient nature of blogs, suggesting that by 2025, wikis will become more personal and meaningful.</li>
<li>Wikis are described as dynamic and reflective of the writer&#39;s evolving thoughts, whereas blogs are likened to static, forgotten storefronts.</li>
<li>The author is transitioning from a traditional website to a wiki format, indicating a shift in how personal content is managed and shared.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://j3s.sh/thought/blogs-rot-wikis-wait.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZBlogs rot. Wikis wait</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Meta Wants More AI Bots on Facebook and Instagram]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Meta is set to launch AI bots on Facebook and Instagram to engage younger users and leverage its investment in generative AI technology. - These AI bots will have profiles and create content, functioning similarly to regular social media accounts, following Meta&#39;s acquisition of SocialAI. - This initiative reflects Meta&#39;s broader strategy of automating social interactions and content curation, aligning with trends seen in apps like Character.ai.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://nymag.com/intelligencer/article/meta-wants-more-ai-bots-on-facebook-and-instagram.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZMeta Wants More AI Bots on Facebook and Instagram</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My 25-year adventure in AI and ML]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Austin Z. Henley, an Associate Teaching Professor at Carnegie Mellon University, shares his 25-year journey in AI (Artificial Intelligence) and ML (Machine Learning), highlighting his transition from initial disinterest to active involvement through various projects.</li>
<li>His career path includes developing simple games, studying AI and neural networks, and applying decision trees and clustering during his PhD to analyze code editor data.</li>
<li>Henley joined Microsoft&#39;s program synthesis team in 2022, working on AI projects, including tools based on LLMs (Large Language Models), and continues to explore AI tools independently while teaching.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://austinhenley.com/blog/25yearsofai.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-02T00:00:00.000ZMy 25-year adventure in AI and ML</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Happy New Year 2025]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42562750</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZHappy New Year 2025</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DOOM CAPTCHA]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://doom-captcha.vercel.app/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZDOOM CAPTCHA</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Static search trees: faster than binary search]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article discusses the implementation and optimization of static search trees (S+ trees) for significantly faster searching of sorted data, achieving speeds 40 times faster than traditional binary search. - Optimization techniques such as batching, prefetching, and manual SIMD (Single Instruction, Multiple Data) are employed to enhance query throughput. - The article also explores various tree layouts, node sizes, and memory management strategies, with a discussion on future work like branchy search and interpolation search to further improve search efficiency.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://curiouscoding.nl/posts/static-search-tree/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZStatic search trees: faster than binary search</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[30% Drop In o1-Preview Accuracy When Putnam Problems Are Slightly Variated]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Putnam-AXIOM is a benchmark designed to assess large language models (LLMs) on advanced mathematical reasoning using problems from the Putnam Mathematical Competition. - The benchmark includes 236 original problems and a variation with 52 altered problems to avoid data contamination. - OpenAI&#39;s top-performing model achieved 41.95% accuracy on the original problems but experienced a significant performance drop of approximately 30% on the altered problems, highlighting challenges in adapting to variations.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://openreview.net/forum?id=YXnwlZe0yf&amp;noteId=yrsGpHd0Sf</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-01T00:00:00.000Z30% Drop In o1-Preview Accuracy When Putnam Problems Are Slightly Variated</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Databases in 2024: A Year in Review]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The database landscape in 2024 experienced significant changes, including major acquisitions, license shifts, and ongoing rivalries among key players like Redis, Elasticsearch, Databricks, and Snowflake. - DuckDB gained popularity for analytical queries, with integrations into Postgres, while notable releases included Amazon Aurora DSQL and Microsoft Garnet. - Acquisitions such as Tabular by Databricks and OrioleDB by Supabase were significant, and despite setbacks like OtterTune&#39;s closure, the industry remains dynamic with new projects and funding.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cs.cmu.edu/~pavlo/blog/2025/01/2024-databases-retrospective.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZDatabases in 2024: A Year in Review</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Books I Loved Reading in 2024]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The list features a diverse range of books, including historical, philosophical, scientific, and personal narratives, each offering unique insights and enriching experiences.</li>
<li>Highlights include Cicero&#39;s letters for insights into Roman life, Ben-Ari&#39;s works on computer science logic and program verification, and Steve Martin&#39;s memoir on comedic success.</li>
<li>The collection also includes philosophical explorations by Pierre Hadot and Nietzsche, Greek tragedies by Aeschylus, and literary works by Ursula Le Guin and Rabindranath Tagore.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://thoughts.wyounas.com/p/books-i-enjoyed-most-in-2024</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZBooks I Loved Reading in 2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Terence Tao: One of my papers got declined today]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://mathstodon.xyz/@tao/113721192051328193</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZTerence Tao: One of my papers got declined today</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[API Parrot – Automatically Reverse Engineer HTTP APIs]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>API Parrot is a new tool designed to simplify the automation of business processes by automatically identifying data correlations between API requests and providing a graphical flow representation. - It allows users to record requests, define inputs and outputs, and export these flows as JavaScript code, making the process more efficient than manual reverse engineering or using less optimal technologies like Robotic Process Automation (RPA). - The tool is built on Electron and is available for both Windows and Linux platforms, with a tutorial available for reverse engineering the USPS API.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://apiparrot.com/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZAPI Parrot – Automatically Reverse Engineer HTTP APIs</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FBI: Largest homemade explosives cache in agency history found in Virginia]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://thehill.com/national-security/5061535-virginia-man-arrested-explosives/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZFBI: Largest homemade explosives cache in agency history found in Virginia</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Déjà vu: Ghostly CVEs in my terminal title]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Ghostty, a new terminal emulator, had a security vulnerability similar to one from 2003, allowing ASCII escape characters to execute commands like opening applications. - The issue was notably problematic with Zsh and Bash in vi mode, but Ghostty 1.0.1 has resolved this by disabling the feature by default. - Despite the security flaw, Ghostty is commended for its features, and the developer promptly addressed the issue, providing fixes and workarounds for users.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://dgl.cx/2024/12/ghostty-terminal-title</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZDéjà vu: Ghostly CVEs in my terminal title</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Large Concept Models: Language modeling in a sentence representation space]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The repository offers implementations for Large Concept Models (LCM), which utilize &quot;concepts&quot; as a higher-level semantic representation for language modeling.</li>
<li>LCM supports 200 text languages and 57 speech languages using the SONAR embedding space, and is trained for auto-regressive sentence prediction with methods like MSE regression and diffusion-based generation.</li>
<li>The repository provides installation instructions, data preparation, training, finetuning, and evaluation guidelines, and is released under the MIT license, using fairseq2 with UV and pip installation options.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/facebookresearch/large_concept_model</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2025-01-01T00:00:00.000ZLarge Concept Models: Language modeling in a sentence representation space</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Merry Christmas Everyone]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42506577</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-25T00:00:00.000ZMerry Christmas Everyone</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[macOS menu bar app that shows how full the ISS urine tank is in real time]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>pISSStream is a macOS menu bar application that displays the real-time status of the International Space Station&#39;s (ISS) urine tank capacity.- The app is developed using Swift and macOS, marking the developer&#39;s first attempt, which may result in potential bugs and limited error handling.- The data for the app is sourced from the ISS Mimic project, although the developer does not plan to include additional statistics from the source.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/Jaennaet/pISSStream</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-25T00:00:00.000ZmacOS menu bar app that shows how full the ISS urine tank is in real time</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[T * sin (t)' ≈ Ornamented Christmas Tree (2013)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://community.wolfram.com/c/portal/getImageAttachment?filename=tree.gif&amp;userId=93201</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-25T00:00:00.000ZT * sin (t)&apos; ≈ Ornamented Christmas Tree (2013)</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This open problem taught me what topology is [video]]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IQqtsm-bBRU</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-25T00:00:00.000ZThis open problem taught me what topology is [video]</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ruby 3.4.0]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Ruby 3.4.0 introduces new features such as block parameter reference using <code>it</code>, Prism as the default parser, and Happy Eyeballs Version 2 for improved network connectivity.</li>
<li>The update includes performance enhancements, new command-line options, and various bug fixes, along with deprecation warnings for mutable string literals and support for keyword splatting nil.</li>
<li>Compatibility issues and C API updates are addressed, with updates to core classes and the standard library, making it a significant release for developers.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ruby-lang.org/en/news/2024/12/25/ruby-3-4-0-released/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-25T00:00:00.000ZRuby 3.4.0</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trying out QvQ – Qwen's new visual reasoning model]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Alibaba has released a new visual reasoning model, QvQ-72B-Preview, in December 2024, which integrates vision with text prompts to enhance visual reasoning capabilities.</li>
<li>The model is available for testing on Hugging Face Spaces and can be run locally using Prince Canuma’s mlx-vlm package, showcasing its open-source nature and accessibility.</li>
<li>Simon Willison&#39;s blog highlights the model&#39;s potential for creative applications, despite mixed results, and emphasizes its entertaining approach to problem-solving.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://simonwillison.net/2024/Dec/24/qvq/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-25T00:00:00.000ZTrying out QvQ – Qwen&apos;s new visual reasoning model</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Masks, Smoke, and Mirrors: The story of EgyptAir flight 804]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://admiralcloudberg.medium.com/masks-smoke-and-mirrors-the-untold-story-of-egyptair-flight-804-42c788fcac2d</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-25T00:00:00.000ZMasks, Smoke, and Mirrors: The story of EgyptAir flight 804</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FixBrowser – a lightweight web browser created from scratch]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A new lightweight, privacy-focused web browser is being developed, which uniquely operates without JavaScript, using updated scripts to enhance websites instead.- The browser employs a whitelist strategy to block resources from various domains, effectively avoiding trackers and enhancing user privacy.- The developer is running a fundraiser to support the advancement of this project, inviting contributions from interested parties.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.fixbrowser.org/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-25T00:00:00.000ZFixBrowser – a lightweight web browser created from scratch</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I made a website to semantically search ArXiv papers]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A graduate student with ADHD developed a website to assist with systematic literature reviews by finding similar papers based on meaning.- The site utilizes MixedBread&#39;s embedding model for vector representation, Milvus for storage and search, and Gradio for serving the application.- The vector database is updated weekly using Kaggle data, and search efficiency is enhanced by binarizing embeddings and employing Hamming distance.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://papermatch.mitanshu.tech/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-25T00:00:00.000ZI made a website to semantically search ArXiv papers</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CRT Simulation in a GPU Shader, Looks Better Than Black Frame Insertion]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Mark Rejhon, in collaboration with Timothy Lottes, has introduced a new open-source algorithm for simulating CRT (Cathode Ray Tube) displays, available on Shadertoy and GitHub.- This algorithm reduces motion blur on 240Hz+ displays and offers a softer flicker compared to BFI (Black Frame Insertion), and has been integrated into the Retroarch emulator.- The simulation is compatible with LCDs and OLEDs, providing real-time and slow-motion modes, and is particularly effective for reducing motion blur in legacy 60fps content.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blurbusters.com/crt-simulation-in-a-gpu-shader-looks-better-than-bfi/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-25T00:00:00.000ZCRT Simulation in a GPU Shader, Looks Better Than Black Frame Insertion</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gordon Mah Ung has died]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Gordon Mah Ung, a respected PCWorld editor and hardware journalist, passed away at 58 after a battle with pancreatic cancer, leaving a significant impact on tech journalism.</li>
<li>With over 25 years in the industry, he was known for his deep knowledge, engaging writing, and commitment to journalistic integrity, contributing to Maximum PC and PCWorld.</li>
<li>Gordon&#39;s work, including &quot;The Full Nerd&quot; podcast, inspired many in the tech community, and he was admired for his dedication to consumer advocacy and simplifying complex technology.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pcworld.com/article/2564783/gordon-mah-ung-remembered.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-25T00:00:00.000ZGordon Mah Ung has died</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I just updated my wife's Chrome, and uBlock is no longer supported]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42506506</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-25T00:00:00.000ZI just updated my wife&apos;s Chrome, and uBlock is no longer supported</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A pilot raced through the airport to surprise the woman who saved his life]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnn.com/2024/12/21/travel/united-pilot-reunites-bone-marrow-donor/index.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-25T00:00:00.000ZA pilot raced through the airport to surprise the woman who saved his life</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What happened to the world's largest tube TV? [video]]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JfZxOuc9Qwk</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-24T00:00:00.000ZWhat happened to the world&apos;s largest tube TV? [video]</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The number pi has an evil twin]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://mathstodon.xyz/@johncarlosbaez/113703444230936435</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-24T00:00:00.000ZThe number pi has an evil twin</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[38th Chaos Communication Congress]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The 38th Chaos Communication Congress (38C3) is scheduled to take place in Hamburg from December 27-30, 2024, organized by the Chaos Computer Club.- This annual event emphasizes the intersection of technology, society, and utopia, offering lectures, workshops, and discussions on technology&#39;s impact.- Participants are invited to engage by volunteering, hosting events, or presenting projects, with key information accessible on the event&#39;s info pages and blog.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://events.ccc.de/congress/2024/infos/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-24T00:00:00.000Z38th Chaos Communication Congress</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Build a Low-Cost Drone Using ESP32]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.digikey.com/en/maker/projects/a-step-by-step-guide-to-build-a-low-cost-drone-using-esp32/8afccd0690574bcebfa0d2ad6fd0a391</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-24T00:00:00.000ZBuild a Low-Cost Drone Using ESP32</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Making AMD GPUs competitive for LLM inference (2023)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>MLC-LLM facilitates the compilation and deployment of Large Language Models (LLMs) on AMD GPUs using ROCm, achieving performance close to NVIDIA&#39;s high-end GPUs.- The AMD Radeon RX 7900 XTX offers competitive performance, reaching 80% of NVIDIA RTX 4090&#39;s speed and 94% of RTX 3090 Ti&#39;s for specific models, while being significantly more affordable.- The project highlights the potential of AMD GPUs for LLM inference, with ongoing improvements in software support and plans for future enhancements like batching and multi-GPU support.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.mlc.ai/2023/08/09/Making-AMD-GPUs-competitive-for-LLM-inference</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-24T00:00:00.000ZMaking AMD GPUs competitive for LLM inference (2023)</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why are cancer guidelines stuck in PDFs?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://seangeiger.substack.com/p/why-are-cancer-guidelines-stuck-in</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-24T00:00:00.000ZWhy are cancer guidelines stuck in PDFs?</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Complete decompilation of Lego Island]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The project involves a complete decompilation of LEGO Island (Version 1.1, English), aiming to replicate the original machine code as closely as possible.</li>
<li>It utilizes CMake for building, with Microsoft Visual C++ 4.20 recommended for optimal results, and involves setting up the environment, configuring with CMake, and building with nmake.</li>
<li>Contributions are encouraged, focusing specifically on the English release of version 1.1, with ongoing improvements to the decompiled ISLE.EXE and LEGO1.DLL files.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/isledecomp/isle</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-24T00:00:00.000ZComplete decompilation of Lego Island</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Intel shareholders file case asking ex CEO, CFO to return 3 years of salary]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Intel shareholders are seeking the return of compensation from former CEO Pat Gelsinger and CFO David Zinsner, accusing them of misleading shareholders about the financial performance of Intel&#39;s foundry unit.</li>
<li>The lawsuit claims a breach of fiduciary duties, following Intel&#39;s failed turnaround plan and a record $16.6 billion quarterly loss, which led to a 9.2% drop in Intel&#39;s shares.</li>
<li>The foundry unit, initially expected to drive growth, was later identified as a significant cost center, prompting restructuring efforts by Zinsner, now co-interim CEO, while Gelsinger has resigned.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cfodive.com/news/intel-shareholders-yank-exceo-cfo-compensation-foundry/736193/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-24T00:00:00.000ZIntel shareholders file case asking ex CEO, CFO to return 3 years of salary</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tokyo released point cloud data of the entire city for free]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Tokyo has made available free point cloud data of the entire city, allowing for public download.</li>
<li>Point cloud data is a collection of data points in space, often used in 3D modeling and geographic information systems (GIS).</li>
<li>This release is significant as it provides valuable resources for developers, researchers, and urban planners interested in 3D modeling and spatial analysis of Tokyo.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/spatiallyjess/status/1871342549958537326</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-24T00:00:00.000ZTokyo released point cloud data of the entire city for free</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Demystifying Debuggers, Part 2: The Anatomy of a Running Program]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article &quot;Demystifying Debuggers, Part 2: The Anatomy Of A Running Program&quot; explains the components involved in program execution, such as virtual address spaces, threads, and processes.- It details how operating systems use virtual memory and scheduling to manage multiple programs running simultaneously.- The post is part of a series focused on explaining how debuggers interact with these processes to analyze program execution.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.rfleury.com/p/demystifying-debuggers-part-2-the</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-24T00:00:00.000ZDemystifying Debuggers, Part 2: The Anatomy of a Running Program</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Automating the search for artificial life with foundation models]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Automated Search for Artificial Life (ASAL) algorithm utilizes AI vision-language foundation models to discover artificial lifeforms in simulations, enhancing the field of Artificial Life (ALife) research.- ASAL has successfully identified new lifeforms in simulations such as Lenia, Boids, Particle Life, and Game of Life, showcasing dynamic patterns and novel cellular automata rules.- This approach automates the discovery process, overcoming the limitations of manually designed simulations, and encourages further exploration and collaboration to integrate ALife concepts into AI for more adaptive and creative systems.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://sakana.ai/asal/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-24T00:00:00.000ZAutomating the search for artificial life with foundation models</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parsing millions of URLs per Second (2023)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/spe.3296</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-24T00:00:00.000ZParsing millions of URLs per Second (2023)</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Paris to Berlin by train is now faster by five hours]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Deutsche Bahn and SNCF have launched a new direct daytime train service from Paris to Berlin, reducing travel time by five hours to 7 hours and 59 minutes.</li>
<li>The route includes scenic views and stops in Strasbourg, Karlsruhe, and Frankfurt, with tickets starting at €59.99 for second class.</li>
<li>While the service offers a more leisurely travel experience, some argue it needs to be faster to effectively compete with air travel.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2024/dec/24/paris-to-berlin-by-train-faster-service-via-strasbourg</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-24T00:00:00.000ZParis to Berlin by train is now faster by five hours</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
