<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0"
>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 19:06:31 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/story/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nyxt: The Hacker's Browser]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Nyxt is a browser designed for advanced users, emphasizing keyboard navigation and efficiency in online information analysis and extraction.</li>
<li>It features powerful tools like link hinting, Jump Headings for document navigation, and fuzzy search for easy tab management and command execution.</li>
<li>Additional functionalities include a built-in REPL (Read-Eval-Print Loop) for programmability, smart bookmark search, customizable autofills, clipboard history, and a tree-based history for tracking visited pages.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://nyxt.atlas.engineer/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-08T00:00:00.000ZNyxt: The Hacker&apos;s Browser</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Syrian government falls in end to 50-year rule of Assad family]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://apnews.com/article/syria-assad-sweida-daraa-homs-hts-qatar-7f65823bbf0a7bd331109e8dff419430</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-08T00:00:00.000ZSyrian government falls in end to 50-year rule of Assad family</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reverse engineering the Sega Channel game image file format]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Sega Channel was a pioneering games-on-demand service for the Sega Genesis, active from 1994 to 1998, offering around 50 games monthly.- In 2024, a user discovered a Sega Channel game image CD from 1996, leading to efforts in reverse engineering to extract and preserve its data.- The project successfully decoded exclusive games, emphasizing the role of community efforts and reverse engineering in preserving gaming history.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.infochunk.com/schannel/index.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-08T00:00:00.000ZReverse engineering the Sega Channel game image file format</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Notre Dame Cathedral reopens]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://apnews.com/article/notre-dame-paris-latest-e50813cf016f08607c20ab115bc4b153</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-08T00:00:00.000ZNotre Dame Cathedral reopens</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brian Krebs Investigates Internet's Most Vicious Hackers–From a Secret Location]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wsj.com/tech/cybersecurity/hacking-brian-krebs-snowflake-waifu-49b87fce</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-08T00:00:00.000ZBrian Krebs Investigates Internet&apos;s Most Vicious Hackers–From a Secret Location</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Airline informant received thousands from passenger cash seizures]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.atlantanewsfirst.com/2024/12/03/airline-informant-received-thousands-passenger-cash-seizures/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-08T00:00:00.000ZAirline informant received thousands from passenger cash seizures</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Browsing negative content online makes mental health struggles worse: Study]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>MIT researchers have created a web plug-in named &quot;Digital Diet&quot; to assist users in making informed choices about online content to safeguard their mental health.</li>
<li>The tool employs natural language processing (NLP) to evaluate web pages based on emotion, knowledge, and actionability, steering users towards more positive content.</li>
<li>The research underscores the two-way relationship between online behavior and mental health, with findings published in Nature Human Behavior.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://news.mit.edu/2024/study-browsing-negative-content-online-makes-mental-health-struggles-worse-1205</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-08T00:00:00.000ZBrowsing negative content online makes mental health struggles worse: Study</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My second year without a job]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://shilin.ca/my-second-year-without-job/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-07T00:00:00.000ZMy second year without a job</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[: The Dialog Element]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The HTML `` element is used to create dialog boxes, which can be modal (pausing page interaction) or non-modal (allowing interaction).</li>
<li>JavaScript methods <code>.showModal()</code> and <code>.show()</code> are used to display modal and non-modal dialogs, respectively, while <code>.close()</code> is used to close them.</li>
<li>Accessibility is crucial; ensure focus is set correctly and provide a closing mechanism, such as a button, while using CSS <code>::backdrop</code> for styling modal backdrops.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML/Element/dialog</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-07T00:00:00.000Z: The Dialog Element</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maps.me co-founder tries to close down Organic Maps open-source fork]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Organic Maps has released the source code for its &quot;metaserver,&quot; which optimizes map download speeds by directing users to the best Content Delivery Network (CDN) servers based on their location.</li>
<li>The code, initially closed to prevent unauthorized forks, is now open under the MIT license, promoting transparency and community involvement.</li>
<li>The team is reconsidering the use of Cloudflare Workers to prevent vendor lock-in and has reverted unauthorized changes made by a contributor, emphasizing their commitment to privacy and transparency.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/orgs/organicmaps/discussions/9837</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-07T00:00:00.000ZMaps.me co-founder tries to close down Organic Maps open-source fork</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to use Postgres for everything]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;Postgres for Everything&quot; is a repository that promotes the use of PostgreSQL, a popular open-source relational database, for a wide range of applications beyond traditional database tasks.- The repository invites contributions and tracks various innovative uses of PostgreSQL, including cron jobs, message queues, analytics, and more, highlighting its versatility.- The initiative includes 11 items related to Supabase, a platform that provides backend services using PostgreSQL, showcasing its integration and utility in modern application development.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/Olshansk/postgres_for_everything</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-07T00:00:00.000ZHow to use Postgres for everything</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lies I was told about collab editing, Part 1: Algorithms for offline editing]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>In early 2024, research into collaborative editing systems for Moment&#39;s text editor highlighted challenges with offline editing, where popular algorithms like CRDTs (Conflict-free Replicated Data Types) and OT (Operational Transformation) often fail.- Offline editing increases direct conflicts, with 20-30% of these conflicts resulting in unacceptable outcomes, suggesting the issue is more of a user interface/user experience (UI/UX) challenge than an algorithmic one.- Researchers are now focusing on improving the user experience in offline editing, drawing parallels to how git handles document merging, which is a promising development.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moment.dev/blog/lies-i-was-told-pt-1</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-07T00:00:00.000ZLies I was told about collab editing, Part 1: Algorithms for offline editing</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Structured Outputs with Ollama]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Ollama has introduced support for structured outputs, enabling models to generate outputs in a specific format using a JSON schema.</li>
<li>This feature is now available in the updated Ollama Python and JavaScript libraries, useful for tasks like data parsing from documents and images.</li>
<li>Users should update to the latest Ollama version and use the format parameter in cURL requests or libraries, with future updates promising performance enhancements and more format options.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ollama.com/blog/structured-outputs</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-07T00:00:00.000ZStructured Outputs with Ollama</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RollerCoaster Tycoon was the last of its kind [video]]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0JouTsMQsEA</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-07T00:00:00.000ZRollerCoaster Tycoon was the last of its kind [video]</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fructose in diet enhances tumor growth: research]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Fructose consumption has increased significantly over the last 50 years, primarily due to high-fructose corn syrup in beverages and processed foods.</li>
<li>Research from Washington University in St. Louis indicates that while fructose doesn&#39;t directly fuel tumors, the liver converts it into nutrients that support tumor growth in cancers such as melanoma, breast, and cervical cancer.</li>
<li>The study suggests potential new cancer treatments by exploring methods to prevent fructose from aiding tumor growth, possibly through dietary changes or pharmaceuticals, with partial funding from the National Institutes of Health (NIH).</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://source.washu.edu/2024/12/research-reveals-how-fructose-in-diet-enhances-tumor-growth/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-07T00:00:00.000ZFructose in diet enhances tumor growth: research</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Biggest shell programs]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The page highlights significant shell programs, focusing on substantial hand-written scripts rather than those generated by tools like autoconf.- Notable entries include akinomyoga/ble.sh, a Bash Line Editor with 61K lines of code (LoC), and kalua, an OpenWRT addon with 56K source lines of code (SLoC).- The list provides insights into the complexity and diversity of shell scripting, featuring programs that utilize data structures and algorithms, typically exceeding 5,000 lines of code.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/oils-for-unix/oils/wiki/The-Biggest-Shell-Programs-in-the-World</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-07T00:00:00.000ZBiggest shell programs</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DSPy – Programming–not prompting–LMs]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>DSPy is a framework designed for building modular AI systems using compositional Python code, focusing on improving language model (LM) outputs without relying solely on prompts.- It supports multiple large language model (LLM) providers like OpenAI, Anthropic, and Databricks, allowing users to describe AI behavior as code, facilitating easier iteration and optimization.- Originating from Stanford NLP, DSPy has a strong community presence on GitHub and Discord, contributing to open-source AI research and advancing program architectures and optimizers.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://dspy.ai/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-07T00:00:00.000ZDSPy – Programming–not prompting–LMs</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The correct amount of ads is zero]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Verge has introduced a subscription model with a paywalled version, offering benefits like full-text RSS feeds to subscribers.</li>
<li>The subscription aims to reduce ad exposure, but there is criticism that paying subscribers should not see any ads at all.</li>
<li>Concerns are raised about potential data selling to advertisers, suggesting that subscribers should not be subject to both ads and data monetization.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://manuelmoreale.com/the-correct-amount-of-ads-is-zero</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZThe correct amount of ads is zero</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The 70% problem: Hard truths about AI-assisted coding]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://addyo.substack.com/p/the-70-problem-hard-truths-about</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZThe 70% problem: Hard truths about AI-assisted coding</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Portland airport grows with expansive mass timber roof canopy]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Portland Airport (PDX) has expanded its main terminal with a sustainable mass timber roof canopy, designed by ZGF, using locally sourced glulam Douglas Fir.</li>
<li>The nine-acre canopy aims to enhance airport capacity and passenger experience while reducing the carbon footprint, incorporating biophilic elements for a welcoming atmosphere.</li>
<li>This project sets a new standard for sustainable airport design, with completion anticipated in 2026.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://design-milk.com/portland-airport-grows-with-expansive-mass-timber-roof-canopy/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZPortland airport grows with expansive mass timber roof canopy</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Intel’s board, and an example of when boards and short-termism fail]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Pat Gelsinger&#39;s exit from Intel is portrayed as a firing rather than a retirement, emphasizing the board&#39;s failures and short-term focus over long-term strategy.- The board&#39;s lack of semiconductor expertise and focus on immediate shareholder value have been criticized, potentially harming Intel&#39;s long-term prospects and the U.S. semiconductor industry.- The board&#39;s failure to support Gelsinger&#39;s IDM 2.0 strategy suggests a shift towards selling company parts, which may benefit shareholders short-term but could damage Intel&#39;s future.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.fabricatedknowledge.com/p/the-death-of-intel-when-boards-fail</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZIntel’s board, and an example of when boards and short-termism fail</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trailbase: Fast, single-file, open-source app server built using Rust and SQLite]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>TrailBase is an open-source application server designed for fast, type-safe APIs, utilizing Rust, SQLite, and V8, and is suitable for mobile, web, or desktop applications.</li>
<li>It offers sub-millisecond latencies, removing the need for dedicated caches, and supports various platforms with pre-built binaries and client packages available for Linux, MacOS, and multiple programming languages.</li>
<li>TrailBase is licensed under OSL-3.0, allowing it to be used as a framework without additional licensing requirements, and contributions from the community are encouraged.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/trailbaseio/trailbase</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZTrailbase: Fast, single-file, open-source app server built using Rust and SQLite</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gitlab names Bill Staples as new CEO]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>GitLab has appointed Bill Staples as the new CEO, with co-founder Sid Sijbrandij moving to Executive Chair of the Board due to health reasons.</li>
<li>Staples, formerly CEO at New Relic, brings extensive experience in developer platforms to GitLab, a prominent AI-powered DevSecOps platform.</li>
<li>GitLab serves over 10,000 customers, generates over $750 million in revenue, and is trusted by more than 40 million users, including over half of the Fortune 100 companies.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20241205391064/en/GitLab-Names-Bill-Staples-as-New-CEO</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZGitlab names Bill Staples as new CEO</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ukraine's three nuclear power plants have restored electricity production]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Ukraine&#39;s nuclear power plants have resumed electricity production following recent grid attacks, highlighting the importance of a stable power supply for nuclear safety.</li>
<li>The International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) is actively monitoring the situation in Ukraine, underscoring its commitment to nuclear safety and security.</li>
<li>Equipment valued at over 14 million euros has been provided to Ukraine to bolster nuclear safety and security measures.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.iaea.org/newscenter/pressreleases/update-263-iaea-director-general-statement-on-situation-in-ukraine</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZUkraine&apos;s three nuclear power plants have restored electricity production</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ExxonMobil's Alleged Hack-for-Hire Campaign Targeting Climate Activists]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>ExxonMobil is accused of orchestrating a hack-for-hire campaign, &quot;Fox Hunt,&quot; targeting over 500 climate activists and journalists using advanced cyber capabilities.</li>
<li>The operation allegedly involved phishing attacks and leaked emails to undermine environmental advocates and support Exxon’s legal strategies, despite the company&#39;s denial of involvement.</li>
<li>This case underscores the growing trend of digital warfare in corporate disputes, prompting FBI investigations and calls for stronger legal measures to combat such cyber operations.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.vulnu.com/p/inside-exxonmobils-alleged-hack-for-hire-campaign-targeting-climate-activists</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZExxonMobil&apos;s Alleged Hack-for-Hire Campaign Targeting Climate Activists</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kagi Teams]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Kagi for Teams, set to launch on December 5, 2024, provides businesses with a privacy-focused search and AI tool, emphasizing no ads, tracking, or data harvesting.</li>
<li>The service includes a premium search engine and universal AI access, with flexible pricing based on active users, offering Professional and Ultimate plans.</li>
<li>Kagi promises quick setup, available support, and significant return on investment (ROI) through faster research times, ensuring data privacy for businesses.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.kagi.com/kagi-teams</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZKagi Teams</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I spent a year building an Android course for the elderly]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author developed a video course to teach elderly individuals how to use Android smartphones, addressing common challenges such as intimidation by interfaces and lack of basic skills like scrolling or swiping.</li>
<li>The course includes a 400-page script, video recordings, and an Android app with exercises, initially hosted on Udemy and later moved to a dedicated website, &quot;Smartphone How-To.&quot;</li>
<li>Marketing the course is challenging due to the target audience&#39;s difficulties with online registration and payment, and the author seeks feedback for improvement.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://kopiascsaba.hu/blog/teaching-elderly-people-to-use-android/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZI spent a year building an Android course for the elderly</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[McKinsey unit will pay $123M to settle claims it bribed South African officials]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A McKinsey &amp; Company subsidiary has agreed to pay $123 million to settle allegations of bribing South African officials, as reported by the U.S. Department of Justice.</li>
<li>The bribery scheme, involving McKinsey Africa, resulted in $85 million in profits through contracts with state-controlled utility companies.</li>
<li>Former McKinsey partner Vikas Sagar admitted guilt to conspiracy charges under the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act, and McKinsey Africa has agreed to a three-year deferred prosecution agreement, pledging to enhance compliance measures.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbc.com/2024/12/05/mckinsey-bribery-settlement-south-africa.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZMcKinsey unit will pay $123M to settle claims it bribed South African officials</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Llama-3.3-70B-Instruct]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://huggingface.co/meta-llama/Llama-3.3-70B-Instruct</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZLlama-3.3-70B-Instruct</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Install postmarketOS on Android phone and use Docker as a home server]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The guide details installing Docker on a OnePlus 6T using postmarketOS, effectively converting it into a home server, but it erases all phone data.</li>
<li>Key requirements include a OnePlus 6 or 6T, Fastboot on a PC, and postmarketOS files, with steps involving enabling Developer Mode, flashing postmarketOS, and setting up SSH.</li>
<li>While this setup offers an alternative to a Raspberry Pi with an integrated screen and battery, it lacks Ethernet support and is limited to internal storage.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://crackoverflow.com/docs/system_administration/containerization/install-docker-natively-on-android-phone-and-use-it-as-a-home-server/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZInstall postmarketOS on Android phone and use Docker as a home server</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hacker Herald – like HN but with crowdsourced pics and subtitles]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author, along with former instructor Arnav and student Archis, has launched a project called Hacker Herald, a front end for Hacker News.- The project was developed during an online JavaScript programming course and aims to provide a visually appealing layout similar to popular newspaper sites.- The inclusion of visuals, such as images, is intended to enhance the storytelling experience by providing immediate context without needing to click through articles.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hackerherald.com/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZHacker Herald – like HN but with crowdsourced pics and subtitles</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Congo gov. says it's 'on alert' over mystery flu-like disease that killed dozens]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.ctvnews.ca/health/congo-government-says-it-s-on-alert-over-mystery-flu-like-disease-that-killed-dozens-1.7134550</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZCongo gov. says it&apos;s &apos;on alert&apos; over mystery flu-like disease that killed dozens</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diátaxis – A systematic approach to technical documentation authoring]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Diátaxis is a systematic approach to technical documentation that focuses on user needs by categorizing content into four types: tutorials, how-to guides, technical reference, and explanation.</li>
<li>This method addresses issues related to content, style, and organization, benefiting both users and creators by enhancing documentation quality and accessibility.</li>
<li>Diátaxis has been successfully implemented in projects like Gatsby and Cloudflare, demonstrating its practical effectiveness in improving clarity and user accessibility.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://diataxis.fr/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-05T00:00:00.000ZDiátaxis – A systematic approach to technical documentation authoring</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bringing K/V context quantisation to Ollama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://smcleod.net/2024/12/bringing-k/v-context-quantisation-to-ollama/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-05T00:00:00.000ZBringing K/V context quantisation to Ollama</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Next stop: Miami]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Waymo One is set to expand its autonomous, all-electric ride-hailing service to Miami in 2026, using Jaguar I-PACEs.</li>
<li>The expansion is in partnership with Moove and follows successful tests in Miami&#39;s challenging weather conditions.</li>
<li>This move aligns with Miami&#39;s emphasis on sustainable and clean energy transportation, and the service will be accessible through the Waymo One app.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://waymo.com/blog/2024/12/next-stop-miami/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-05T00:00:00.000ZNext stop: Miami</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Federal Court Says Dismantling a Phone to Install Firmware Isn't a 'Search']]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The iPhone 6 is susceptible to the checkm8 exploit, which is a known security vulnerability.</li>
<li>Devices such as the iPhone XS and newer models are currently not affected by this exploit, indicating improved security measures in later models.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.techdirt.com/2024/12/04/federal-court-says-dismantling-a-phone-to-install-firmware-isnt-a-search-even-if-was-done-to-facilitate-a-search/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-05T00:00:00.000ZFederal Court Says Dismantling a Phone to Install Firmware Isn&apos;t a &apos;Search&apos;</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[VectorChord: Store 400k Vectors for $1 in PostgreSQL]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>VectorChord is a new PostgreSQL extension designed for efficient vector search, capable of storing 400,000 vectors for just $1, making it more cost-effective than competitors.- It utilizes IVF (Inverted File) and RaBitQ (Random Bit Quantization) techniques to enhance search speed and memory efficiency, making it suitable for handling large datasets.- VectorChord outperforms alternatives like Pinecone and pgvector in terms of both price and performance, offering scalable vector search with improved speed and precision for applications needing quick and accurate responses.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.pgvecto.rs/vectorchord-store-400k-vectors-for-1-in-postgresql</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-05T00:00:00.000ZVectorChord: Store 400k Vectors for $1 in PostgreSQL</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bitcoin is over $100k]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/BTCUSD/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-05T00:00:00.000ZBitcoin is over $100k</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IMG_0001]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Between 2009 and 2012, iPhones featured a &quot;Send to YouTube&quot; button in the Photos app, resulting in numerous uploads with default IMG_XXXX filenames.- A bot was developed, inspired by Ben Wallace, to locate 5 million of these videos, showcasing raw and unedited moments.- The collection of videos is available for viewing, presented in a random order, offering a glimpse into unfiltered content from that era.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://walzr.com/IMG_0001/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZIMG_0001</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My son (9 yrs old) used plain JavaScript to make a game, and wants your feedback]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A 9-year-old has been learning coding, mastering HTML and CSS, and recently used Google Gemini to enhance his skills.- He created a game by coding HTML, CSS, and JavaScript in VSCode and used Piskel for animated graphics, with guidance from his parents and Google Gemini.- The child documented his experience in a blog post, discussing the process and receiving feedback from his programmer parents to refine his writing.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.armaansahni.com/game/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZMy son (9 yrs old) used plain JavaScript to make a game, and wants your feedback</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Egoless Engineering]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The talk emphasizes the importance of fostering better work environments by breaking down unnecessary role divisions and encouraging collaboration across roles.- It highlights inefficiencies caused by excessive role splitting and the misconception of &quot;devops&quot; practices that create barriers rather than promoting collaboration.- The speaker advocates for valuing cooperation, curiosity, and shared responsibility, suggesting that misery should not be equated with productivity.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://egoless.engineering</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZEgoless Engineering</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Phoenix LiveView 1.0.0 is here]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Phoenix LiveView 1.0.0 has been released, offering a major update that simplifies dynamic server-rendered applications by reducing the need for JavaScript and enhancing real-time capabilities.- Key features of this release include a diffing engine for efficient updates, HEEx components for improved HTML composability, and interactive uploads, all leveraging Elixir and the Erlang VM for superior latency and scalability.- The update also introduces new features like streams and async operations, with future plans to integrate JavaScript hooks and Web Components, encouraging developers to explore its easy setup.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.phoenixframework.org/blog/phoenix-liveview-1.0-released?release=1.0</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZPhoenix LiveView 1.0.0 is here</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Genie 2: A large-scale foundation world model]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Research Genie 2, released on December 4, 2024, is a large-scale foundation world model designed to generate diverse 3D environments for AI agent training.- Developed by Jack Parker-Holder&#39;s team, Genie 2 can create action-controllable, playable worlds from a single image prompt, supporting rapid prototyping and interactive experiences.- Genie 2 advances AI research by modeling object interactions, character animations, and environmental physics, addressing the challenge of creating rich training environments for embodied agents.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/genie-2-a-large-scale-foundation-world-model/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZGenie 2: A large-scale foundation world model</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenTTD is an open source simulation game based upon Transport Tycoon Deluxe]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>OpenTTD 14.1 was released on May 3, 2024, focusing on bug fixes since the initial release.- Key updates include resolving a multiplayer desynchronization bug and enhancements to the ship pathfinder and unbunching feature.- Players have shown significant engagement, logging 34,700 hours in 17,219 games in the past week.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.openttd.org/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZOpenTTD is an open source simulation game based upon Transport Tycoon Deluxe</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My C compiler compiled itself]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/keyvank/30cc</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZMy C compiler compiled itself</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to grow professional relationships]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The TJS (The Journey to Synergy) Collaboration Model outlines seven states of professional relationships, ranging from competitive to shared identity, to enhance collaboration.</li>
<li>The model emphasizes moving from a zero-sum mindset to high-quality synergy, encouraging an abundance mindset and alignment with personal goals and values.</li>
<li>Key stages include Competition, Coexist, Communicate, Cooperate, Coordinate, Collaborate, and &quot;We are the same,&quot; with the ultimate goal of achieving more collectively than individually.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://tej.as/blog/how-to-grow-professional-relationships-tjs-model</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZHow to grow professional relationships</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A particle physics course for high-school students]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>CERN&#39;s Physics Education Research team has developed a pilot particle physics course for high-school students, consisting of 16 chapters with videos and quizzes.- The course, lasting approximately 4 hours, covers fundamental topics such as &quot;What is a particle?&quot; and &quot;What is a particle accelerator?&quot; and includes DIY experiments.- Participants can complete chapters in any order and earn a digital certificate upon completing all quizzes, with feedback encouraged to enhance future iterations.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ppc.web.cern.ch/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZA particle physics course for high-school students</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No NAT November: My month without IPv4]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The &quot;No NAT November&quot; challenge involved disabling IPv4 and using only IPv6, highlighting the potential and challenges of transitioning to IPv6-only networks.- The author suggests an &quot;IPv6-mostly&quot; approach, which prioritizes IPv6 while maintaining dual-stack networks, reducing maintenance and preparing for an IPv4-free future.- Transitional technologies like NAT64 and DNS64 helped address compatibility issues, with Apple devices adapting well, while Windows and Linux showed mixed results.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.infected.systems/posts/2024-12-01-no-nat-november/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZNo NAT November: My month without IPv4</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Formaldehyde Causes More Cancer Than Any Other Toxic Air Pollutant]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Formaldehyde, a prevalent air pollutant from sources like car exhaust and factories, poses significant cancer risks, particularly linked to myeloid leukemia.- Efforts to regulate formaldehyde have been obstructed by industry influence and political changes, with notable setbacks during the Trump administration.- ProPublica&#39;s investigation underscores the underestimated risks of formaldehyde exposure and the ongoing challenges in implementing effective regulations, despite some progress under the Biden administration.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.propublica.org/article/formaldehyde-epa-trump-public-health-danger</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZFormaldehyde Causes More Cancer Than Any Other Toxic Air Pollutant</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EmacsConf 2024]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>EmacsConf 2024 is scheduled to be held online on December 7-8, featuring talks, volunteer opportunities, and discussions centered around GNU Emacs and Emacs Lisp.</li>
<li>The event will utilize free software for streaming and includes a satellite event in Lucerne, Switzerland, offering a hybrid experience.</li>
<li>Participants can engage in discussions via the emacsconf-discuss mailing list, organize through emacsconf-org, and connect on IRC at #emacsconf on irc.libera.chat, with content licensed under CC BY-SA 4.0 and GPLv3+.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://emacsconf.org/2024/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZEmacsConf 2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UnitedHealthcare CEO fatally shot in midtown Manhattan]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnn.com/2024/12/04/us/brian-thompson-united-healthcare-death/index.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZUnitedHealthcare CEO fatally shot in midtown Manhattan</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stephen King to shut down his 3 radio stations in Maine]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Stephen King is closing his three radio stations in Bangor, Maine, after over 40 years of ownership, due to financial losses and his age.</li>
<li>The stations, which reflect King&#39;s passion for rock music and local media, will cease operations on New Year&#39;s Eve.</li>
<li>This decision marks a significant change in King&#39;s business affairs, as he reorganizes his ventures.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/12/03/arts/stephen-king-maine-radio-stations.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZStephen King to shut down his 3 radio stations in Maine</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Porsche Macan EV is being recalled because its headlights are too bright]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Porsche is recalling 2,941 Macan Electric models in the U.S. due to headlights that are too bright, requiring a service center visit for a software update.</li>
<li>The issue cannot be resolved through an over-the-air update, necessitating a physical visit to a service center for the free fix.</li>
<li>The recall affects vehicles manufactured between March 15 and November 4, 2024, with dealers and owners being notified in December 2024 and January 2025, respectively.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://insideevs.com/news/742893/porsche-macan-electric-ev-recall-headlights/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZThe Porsche Macan EV is being recalled because its headlights are too bright</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Facebook's Little Red Book]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>In 2012, Facebook created a &quot;Little Red Book&quot; to maintain its identity and focus as it expanded to a billion users, emphasizing principles like breaking things, thinking big, and moving fast.</li>
<li>The book, designed by Ben Barry, served as a manifesto to preserve Facebook&#39;s ethos during rapid growth, showcasing the importance of storytelling in scaling company culture.</li>
<li>A high-quality digital version of this rare book has been created to illustrate how successful companies maintain their identity and culture.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.map.cv/blog/redbook</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-03T00:00:00.000ZFacebook&apos;s Little Red Book</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korean president declares emergency martial law]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://apnews.com/article/south-korea-yoon-martial-law-997c22ac93f6a9bece68454597e577c1</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-03T00:00:00.000ZSouth Korean president declares emergency martial law</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lessons I learned working at an art gallery]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.henrikkarlsson.xyz/p/art-gallery</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-03T00:00:00.000ZLessons I learned working at an art gallery</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Y Combinator and Power in Silicon Valley]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>In 2010, AdGrok, a small startup, faced a lawsuit from their former employer, Adchemy, which threatened their financial stability.- Y Combinator, a startup accelerator backing AdGrok, played a pivotal role in resolving the lawsuit by leveraging its influence with Adchemy&#39;s investors and potential business partners.- Despite winning the lawsuit, the ordeal led to AdGrok&#39;s sale to Twitter in 2011, while Adchemy was later sold to Walmart Labs in a fire-sale acquisition.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://commoncog.com/c/cases/y-combinator-power/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-03T00:00:00.000ZY Combinator and Power in Silicon Valley</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8 months of OCaml after 8 years of Haskell in production (2023)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author compares Haskell and OCaml based on their experience, highlighting that Haskell has more features and packages, but OCaml&#39;s simplicity enhances productivity.- Haskell&#39;s tooling is powerful yet inconsistent, while OCaml&#39;s tooling is straightforward and reliable, with succinct compiler messages.- Both languages are suitable for industrial use, but the author prefers OCaml for its focus on development rather than overthinking, despite Haskell&#39;s more comprehensive documentation.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://chshersh.com/blog/2023-12-16-8-months-of-ocaml-after-8-years-of-haskell.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-03T00:00:00.000Z8 months of OCaml after 8 years of Haskell in production (2023)</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Twice-Yearly HIV Shot Shows 100% Effectiveness in Women]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://apnews.com/article/hiv-infections-aids-prevention-shot-02606f7d7892f0baf55bd0a0ff2ba3de</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-03T00:00:00.000ZTwice-Yearly HIV Shot Shows 100% Effectiveness in Women</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blizzard's pulling of Warcraft I and II tests GOG's new Preservation Program]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Blizzard has requested GOG to remove the DRM-free bundle of Warcraft I &amp; II from its store due to the release of remastered versions.</li>
<li>GOG is offering the bundle at a discount before removal, ensuring that buyers will still have access and receive updates for compatibility with modern systems.</li>
<li>This situation underscores the ongoing tension between remastered and original game versions, with GOG striving to preserve classic games despite publisher decisions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/12/blizzards-pulling-of-warcraft-i-ii-tests-gogs-new-preservation-program/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-03T00:00:00.000ZBlizzard&apos;s pulling of Warcraft I and II tests GOG&apos;s new Preservation Program</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi boosts Pi 5 performance with SDRAM tuning]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Raspberry Pi engineers have optimized SDRAM (Synchronous Dynamic Random-Access Memory) timings, resulting in a 10-20% performance boost for Pi 5 and Pi 4 at 2.4 GHz.</li>
<li>Overclocking, which involves increasing the clock speed beyond the manufacturer&#39;s specifications, can achieve up to a 32% speedup, with most Pi 5s reaching 2.6-3.0 GHz.</li>
<li>These performance enhancements, including NUMA (Non-Uniform Memory Access) emulation for better multi-core workload handling, may soon be available through firmware updates, potentially becoming standard features.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2024/raspberry-pi-boosts-pi-5-performance-sdram-tuning</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-03T00:00:00.000ZRaspberry Pi boosts Pi 5 performance with SDRAM tuning</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No need to email me about Cisco AnyConnect]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author&#39;s name and email are included in Cisco&#39;s AnyConnect VPN client due to the use of the curl library, leading to confusion among users seeking support.- The author clarifies they are the lead developer of curl, a component used in the app, but not affiliated with Cisco or AnyConnect.- Users needing support for AnyConnect should contact Cisco directly at <a href="mailto:ac-mobile-feedback@cisco.com">ac-mobile-feedback@cisco.com</a>.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2024/12/03/no-need-to-email-me-about-cisco-anyconnect/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-03T00:00:00.000ZNo need to email me about Cisco AnyConnect</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DuckDuckGo Donates $25k to the Perl and Raku Foundation]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>DuckDuckGo has donated $25,000 to The Perl and Raku Foundation (TPRF) on &quot;Giving Tuesday,&quot; contributing to their mission of advancing Perl and Raku programming languages.</li>
<li>Since 2011, DuckDuckGo has donated over $6 million to organizations that support online trust, highlighting its commitment to fostering secure and trustworthy online environments.</li>
<li>The donation will aid in funding core Perl development and community projects, with TPRF expressing gratitude for DuckDuckGo&#39;s support and confidence in their mission.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.perl.com/article/duckduckgo-donates-25-000-to-the-perl-and-raku-foundation/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-03T00:00:00.000ZDuckDuckGo Donates $25k to the Perl and Raku Foundation</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Company claims 1k% price hike drove it from VMware to open source rival]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Beeks Group, a UK cloud operator, transitioned 20,000 virtual machines (VMs) from VMware to OpenNebula following a 1,000% price increase after Broadcom acquired VMware.</li>
<li>This migration enhanced VM efficiency by 200% and allowed Beeks to allocate more resources to client workloads.</li>
<li>Broadcom&#39;s acquisition of VMware has led to increased costs and reduced support, prompting many companies, including AT&amp;T, to seek alternatives due to customer dissatisfaction.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2024/12/company-claims-1000-percent-price-hike-drove-it-from-vmware-to-open-source-rival/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-03T00:00:00.000ZCompany claims 1k% price hike drove it from VMware to open source rival</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Intel announces retirement of Pat Gelsinger]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Intel&#39;s CEO Pat Gelsinger announced his retirement after over 40 years, effective December 1, 2024, with David Zinsner and Michelle Johnston Holthaus serving as interim co-CEOs.</li>
<li>The board is committed to maintaining product leadership and efficiency, with Frank Yeary as interim executive chair during the search for a new CEO.</li>
<li>Intel remains a leader in semiconductor technology, inspired by Moore’s Law, with a focus on innovation and leadership continuity.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.intel.com/content/www/us/en/newsroom/news/intel-ceo-news-dec-2024.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-02T00:00:00.000ZIntel announces retirement of Pat Gelsinger</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What Will Enter the Public Domain in 2025?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>On January 1, 2025, new works will enter the public domain, including those by creators who died in 1954 and 1974, and U.S. films/books from 1929.</li>
<li>The Public Domain Review, a UK Community Interest Company, uses profits for community benefit and relies on reader donations.</li>
<li>Readers are encouraged to explore resources like John Mark Ockerbloom’s “Public Domain Day Countdown” and Communia’s Manifesto for more information on the public domain.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://publicdomainreview.org/features/entering-the-public-domain/2025/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-02T00:00:00.000ZWhat Will Enter the Public Domain in 2025?</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to Study Mathematics (2017)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The essay by Lawrence Neff Stout provides strategies for studying college-level mathematics, emphasizing the need for a deeper understanding of theory, definitions, and proofs compared to high school math.- Key strategies include understanding precise definitions, memorizing and comprehending theorems and proofs, and using techniques like working backwards to see how concepts interconnect.- The essay highlights the importance of practicing problems to develop techniques and judgment, and stresses that understanding is more crucial than memorization in college mathematics.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.math.uh.edu/~dblecher/pf2.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-02T00:00:00.000ZHow to Study Mathematics (2017)</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gene behind orange fur in cats]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.science.org/content/article/gene-behind-orange-fur-cats-found-last</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-02T00:00:00.000ZGene behind orange fur in cats</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[’Brain rot‘ named Oxford Word of the Year 2024]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Oxford Word of the Year for 2024 is &quot;brain rot,&quot; selected through a public vote with over 37,000 participants, highlighting its growing relevance.- &quot;Brain rot&quot; describes the mental decline from consuming trivial online content, with a 230% increase in usage from 2023 to 2024, reflecting concerns about digital consumption&#39;s impact on mental health.- Originally coined by Henry David Thoreau in 1854, the term has gained popularity on platforms like TikTok, sparking discussions about the effects of excessive online content, particularly among Gen Z and Gen Alpha.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://corp.oup.com/news/brain-rot-named-oxford-word-of-the-year-2024/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-02T00:00:00.000Z’Brain rot‘ named Oxford Word of the Year 2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Programming the C64 with Visual Studio Code]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The VS64 extension allows programming the Commodore 64 using Visual Studio Code on Mac, Windows, and Linux, providing a modern, cross-platform alternative to the Windows-only CBM PRG Studio.</li>
<li>VS64 supports BASIC, Assembly, and C programming with syntax highlighting, tools, and features like auto-numbering and label usage, enhancing the development experience.</li>
<li>It integrates with ACME and Kick assemblers, CC65 and LLVM-MOS C/C++ compilers, and the VICE C64 emulator for debugging, making it a comprehensive tool for C64 development.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://retrogamecoders.com/c64-visual-studio-code/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-02T00:00:00.000ZProgramming the C64 with Visual Studio Code</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Advent of Code 2024]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Advent of Code, created by Eric Wastl, is an Advent calendar featuring programming puzzles suitable for all skill levels, which can be solved in any programming language.</li>
<li>The puzzles are designed to run efficiently on older hardware and are intended for practice, interviews, or entertainment, without requiring a computer science background.</li>
<li>Participants are encouraged to share their experiences, test solutions with examples, and seek help if needed, while adhering to guidelines such as not using AI for solving puzzles and respecting trademark rules.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://adventofcode.com/2024/about</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-01T00:00:00.000ZAdvent of Code 2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Brazilian CA trusted only by Microsoft has issued a certificate for google.com]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://follow.agwa.name/notice/AoZSMI38xcA3TrN1sm</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-01T00:00:00.000ZA Brazilian CA trusted only by Microsoft has issued a certificate for google.com</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Open-source private home security camera system (end-to-end encryption)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author developed a home security camera system called Privastead, focusing on privacy by using end-to-end encryption with OpenMLS and implementing it mostly in Rust.- Privastead is open-sourced for those with privacy concerns, requiring a compatible IP camera, a local machine, a server, and an Android smartphone for setup.- Currently, the system supports only one IP camera and Android, but the author seeks community feedback and contributions to enhance its capabilities.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/privastead/privastead</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-01T00:00:00.000ZOpen-source private home security camera system (end-to-end encryption)</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ntfs2btrfs does in-place conversion of NTFS filesystem to the open-source Btrfs]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Ntfs2btrfs is a tool designed to convert NTFS file systems to Btrfs in-place, preserving the original image as a reflink copy for potential space recovery.</li>
<li>The tool is available for both Windows and Linux, with specific installation instructions and dependencies for each platform, and it includes features like compression support and rollback to NTFS.</li>
<li>Limitations include the lack of support for older extended attributes, large alternate data streams (ADS), and encrypted files, with specific conditions required for booting Windows from a Btrfs file system.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/maharmstone/ntfs2btrfs</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-01T00:00:00.000ZNtfs2btrfs does in-place conversion of NTFS filesystem to the open-source Btrfs</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[AMD Disables Zen 4's Loop Buffer]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>AMD has disabled the loop buffer in its Zen 4 CPUs, a feature intended for power optimization rather than performance enhancement.- Performance tests indicate negligible differences with the loop buffer disabled, as the op cache compensates with sufficient bandwidth.- The decision to disable the loop buffer, possibly due to a hardware bug, is unlikely to significantly impact performance or power consumption, and the feature was not widely documented by AMD.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://chipsandcheese.com/p/amd-disables-zen-4s-loop-buffer</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-01T00:00:00.000ZAMD Disables Zen 4&apos;s Loop Buffer</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenWRT One Released: First Router Designed Specifically for OpenWrt]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Software Freedom Conservancy (SFC) and OpenWrt have released the OpenWrt One, a wireless router designed to promote software freedom and the right to repair, priced at $89 with a case or $68.42 for the board.</li>
<li>The router is unbrickable, fully copyleft-compliant, and features a MediaTek MT7981B SoC, MT7976C wifi, 1 GiB DDR4 RAM, supporting Power over Ethernet (PoE) and USB-C power, with a USB serial interface for advanced users.</li>
<li>The device is FCC compliant, demonstrating that software right to repair can align with regulatory requirements, and each purchase includes a $10 donation to OpenWrt at the Software Freedom Conservancy.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://sfconservancy.org/news/2024/nov/29/openwrt-one-wireless-router-now-ships-black-friday/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-01T00:00:00.000ZOpenWRT One Released: First Router Designed Specifically for OpenWrt</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Jeff Dean Responds to EDA Industry about AlphaChip]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/JeffDean/status/1858540085794451906</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-01T00:00:00.000ZJeff Dean Responds to EDA Industry about AlphaChip</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What does this button do? – My new car has a mysterious and undocumented switch]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A 2020 Opel Corsa owner discovered a mysterious switch linked to a fleet tracking system, likely installed by the previous owner, a large company.</li>
<li>The system functions as a GPS tracker and possibly an immobilizer, tracking the driver&#39;s movements and sending data to a fleet manager.</li>
<li>The owner plans to remove the system due to privacy concerns, highlighting the issue of unknowingly driving with tracking devices.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.koenvh.nl/what-does-this-button-do-cm42u2oi7000a09l42f54g2pr</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-11-30T00:00:00.000ZWhat does this button do? – My new car has a mysterious and undocumented switch</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Breaking the 4Chan CAPTCHA]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The project aimed to develop a machine learning model using TensorFlow to solve 4Chan CAPTCHAs with over 80% accuracy, ultimately achieving over 90% accuracy.</li>
<li>The model utilized an LSTM CNN architecture with CTC encoding, trained on 500 hand-solved and 50,000 synthetic images, and was converted for browser use with TensorFlow.js.</li>
<li>The project provided valuable insights into machine learning and computer vision, overcoming challenges like data collection, synthetic data generation, and compatibility issues.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nullpt.rs/breaking-the-4chan-captcha</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-11-30T00:00:00.000ZBreaking the 4Chan CAPTCHA</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Geometric line-art of Wacław Szpakowski (2017)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theparisreview.org/blog/2017/02/15/rhythmical-lines/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-11-30T00:00:00.000ZGeometric line-art of Wacław Szpakowski (2017)</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Engineering Sleep]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Familial Natural Short Sleep (FNSS) is a condition where individuals can sleep less without adverse effects due to a genetic mutation, notably in the DEC2 gene affecting orexin levels.- Orexin plays a key role in sleep regulation, with imbalances leading to sleepiness or insomnia, and research is exploring FNSS replication through orexin agonists or gene therapy.- Despite its potential, FNSS remains under-researched, indicating a need for further studies to develop improved sleep engineering methods.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://minjunes.ai/posts/sleep/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-11-30T00:00:00.000ZEngineering Sleep</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Deterioration of Google]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The closure of Giant Freakin Robot underscores the challenges faced by independent publishers, as many sites are shutting down due to decreased traffic from major platforms like Google and Facebook.- Google&#39;s machine learning system, designed to enhance search results, has unintentionally delisted numerous small sites, leading to financial difficulties for content creators.- The algorithm&#39;s complexity and Google&#39;s dominant market position contribute to the ongoing issue, leaving creators with limited alternatives and solutions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.baldurbjarnason.com/2024/the-deterioration-of-google/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-11-30T00:00:00.000ZThe Deterioration of Google</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Sol-Ark manufacturer reportedly disables all Deye inverters in the US]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Sol-Ark disabled all Deye inverters in the US, disrupting homeowners by intentionally bricking them with a message about regional restrictions.</li>
<li>Sol-Ark, holding exclusive US sales rights, offered a discounted replacement program to affected customers, raising concerns about control and security of internet-connected solar inverters.</li>
<li>The incident emphasizes the importance of selecting inverters with reliable support and secure networking to avoid similar disruptions, particularly with Chinese-manufactured products.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://solarboi.com/2024/11/17/sol-ark-oem-disables-all-deye-inverters-in-the-us/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-11-30T00:00:00.000ZSol-Ark manufacturer reportedly disables all Deye inverters in the US</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Send someone you appreciate an official 'Continue and Persist' Letter]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ContinueAndPersist.org</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-11-29T00:00:00.000ZSend someone you appreciate an official &apos;Continue and Persist&apos; Letter</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Engineers do not get to make startup mistakes when they build ledgers]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Payments Engineer Playbook underscores the critical role of accurate ledgers in fintech startups, highlighting the pitfalls of neglecting double-entry accounting systems.</li>
<li>Alvaro Duran shares a cautionary tale from his startup experience, where the absence of a double-entry system led to financial discrepancies and customer dissatisfaction.</li>
<li>Duran is contemplating authoring a book on creating scalable and future-proof ledgers, seeking feedback on its potential interest.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.alvaroduran.com/p/engineers-do-not-get-to-make-startup</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-11-29T00:00:00.000ZEngineers do not get to make startup mistakes when they build ledgers</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Don't Fuck with Scroll]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Momentum scrolling plugins are criticized for disrupting the natural web browsing experience by degrading usability, accessibility, and performance.- Key issues include violating user expectations, causing motion sickness, reducing accessibility, and inconsistent performance, particularly on older devices.- These plugins also increase page load times, break native browser features, and add maintenance overhead, leading to user frustration and complexity.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://dontfuckwithscroll.com</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-11-29T00:00:00.000ZDon&apos;t Fuck with Scroll</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hetzner raises prices while significantly lowering bandwidth (US)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Hetzner is increasing prices in the US by up to 27.52% for CPX21 servers while reducing bandwidth by an average of 88.19%.- The changes, announced on Thanksgiving, are intended to align costs with resource usage, as lighter users were subsidizing heavier users.- New pricing and bandwidth limits will take effect from December 2024 for new servers and February 2025 for existing ones, with Hetzner maintaining it offers the best price-performance ratio.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://adriano.fyi/posts/hetzner-raises-prices-while-significantly-lowering-bandwidth-in-us/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-11-29T00:00:00.000ZHetzner raises prices while significantly lowering bandwidth (US)</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Car tires shed a quarter of all microplastics in the environment]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://phys.org/news/2024-11-car-quarter-microplastics-environment-urgent.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-11-29T00:00:00.000ZCar tires shed a quarter of all microplastics in the environment</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The success and failure of Ninja (2020)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Ninja, a build system created as a side project, has gained significant popularity and is now used by major projects like Chrome, Android, and Meson.</li>
<li>The system is designed for speed and efficiency, utilizing a bipartite graph for better build structure and focusing on fast incremental builds.</li>
<li>The creator reflects on the challenges of being an open-source maintainer, noting the high demands and limited gratitude despite Ninja&#39;s success.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://neugierig.org/software/blog/2020/05/ninja.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-11-29T00:00:00.000ZThe success and failure of Ninja (2020)</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How much memory do you need in 2024 to run 1M concurrent tasks?]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A 2024 benchmark tested memory consumption for running 1 million concurrent tasks using coroutines across various programming languages, including Rust, C#, Go, and Java.- C# with NativeAOT demonstrated the best memory efficiency, outperforming other languages, while Go consumed more memory than anticipated, even more than Java with GraalVM.- The study underscores that some languages, like .NET with NativeAOT and Java&#39;s GraalVM, have improved scalability, whereas Go&#39;s goroutines were less efficient, and Rust&#39;s memory usage was optimized by adjusting task handling.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hez2010.github.io/async-runtimes-benchmarks-2024/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-11-29T00:00:00.000ZHow much memory do you need in 2024 to run 1M concurrent tasks?</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Goodbye, Rust. I wish you success but I'm back to C++ (sorry, it is a rant)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://old.reddit.com/r/rust/comments/1h15md8/goodbye_rust_i_wish_you_success_but_im_back_to_c/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-11-29T00:00:00.000ZGoodbye, Rust. I wish you success but I&apos;m back to C++ (sorry, it is a rant)</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GIMP 3.0 is on the way]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>GIMP 3.0 is anticipated to release soon, marking the first major update since 2018, featuring a modernized GTK 3 interface and improved performance.- Key updates include non-destructive editing, enhanced color management, improved layer workflows, and a new extension system for easier plugin management.- Although the exact release date is unknown, development builds are available, indicating a significant advancement for the open-source image editor with more frequent future updates expected.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://lwn.net/SubscriberLink/998793/6c8d00bd1b2a7948/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-11-29T00:00:00.000ZGIMP 3.0 is on the way</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Vince – A self hosted alternative to Google Analytics]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Vince is a Golang-based port of the Plausible Analytics dashboard, designed as a single binary, single-user system for multiple websites without runtime dependencies.- It includes features like automatic TLS (Transport Layer Security), outbound link tracking, file download tracking, 404 page tracking, and custom event tracking, making it nearly equivalent to the Plausible dashboard.- Vince aims to make the Plausible dashboard accessible for self-hosting, serving as a drop-in replacement for personal websites, with a demo available on a $6 Vultr instance.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/vinceanalytics/vince</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-11-29T00:00:00.000ZVince – A self hosted alternative to Google Analytics</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Australian Parliament bans social media for under-16s]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://apnews.com/article/australia-social-media-children-ban-safeguarding-harm-accounts-d0cde2603bdbc7167801da1d00ecd056</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-11-29T00:00:00.000ZAustralian Parliament bans social media for under-16s</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Screen Sharing in the Browser]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Bolt.new is a tool that allows users to rapidly create web applications, demonstrated by building a screen-sharing app in just 30 minutes.- The app functions by generating a unique code for a room, which others can use to join and view the screen being shared.- The project was further developed using Cursor and is available for viewing on GitHub, with a live demo hosted on Vercel.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/tonghohin/screen-sharing</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-11-29T00:00:00.000ZScreen Sharing in the Browser</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Prometheus 3.0]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Prometheus 3.0, the first major release in 7 years, introduces a modernized UI, Remote Write 2.0, UTF-8 support, OTLP support, and native histograms.- Key features include improved protocol efficiency with Remote Write 2.0, enhanced interoperability with OpenTelemetry through OTLP ingestion, and more efficient metrics with native histograms.- Users should be aware of some breaking changes and consult the migration guide, but the release maintains backward compatibility and encourages user feedback.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://prometheus.io/blog/2024/11/14/prometheus-3-0/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-11-29T00:00:00.000ZPrometheus 3.0</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
