<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0"
>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 19:07:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/story/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Merry Christmas Everyone]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42506577</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-25T00:00:00.000ZMerry Christmas Everyone</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[macOS menu bar app that shows how full the ISS urine tank is in real time]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>pISSStream is a macOS menu bar application that displays the real-time status of the International Space Station&#39;s (ISS) urine tank capacity.- The app is developed using Swift and macOS, marking the developer&#39;s first attempt, which may result in potential bugs and limited error handling.- The data for the app is sourced from the ISS Mimic project, although the developer does not plan to include additional statistics from the source.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/Jaennaet/pISSStream</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-25T00:00:00.000ZmacOS menu bar app that shows how full the ISS urine tank is in real time</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[T * sin (t)' ≈ Ornamented Christmas Tree (2013)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://community.wolfram.com/c/portal/getImageAttachment?filename=tree.gif&amp;userId=93201</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-25T00:00:00.000ZT * sin (t)&apos; ≈ Ornamented Christmas Tree (2013)</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This open problem taught me what topology is [video]]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=IQqtsm-bBRU</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-25T00:00:00.000ZThis open problem taught me what topology is [video]</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ruby 3.4.0]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Ruby 3.4.0 introduces new features such as block parameter reference using <code>it</code>, Prism as the default parser, and Happy Eyeballs Version 2 for improved network connectivity.</li>
<li>The update includes performance enhancements, new command-line options, and various bug fixes, along with deprecation warnings for mutable string literals and support for keyword splatting nil.</li>
<li>Compatibility issues and C API updates are addressed, with updates to core classes and the standard library, making it a significant release for developers.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.ruby-lang.org/en/news/2024/12/25/ruby-3-4-0-released/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-25T00:00:00.000ZRuby 3.4.0</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trying out QvQ – Qwen's new visual reasoning model]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Alibaba has released a new visual reasoning model, QvQ-72B-Preview, in December 2024, which integrates vision with text prompts to enhance visual reasoning capabilities.</li>
<li>The model is available for testing on Hugging Face Spaces and can be run locally using Prince Canuma’s mlx-vlm package, showcasing its open-source nature and accessibility.</li>
<li>Simon Willison&#39;s blog highlights the model&#39;s potential for creative applications, despite mixed results, and emphasizes its entertaining approach to problem-solving.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://simonwillison.net/2024/Dec/24/qvq/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-25T00:00:00.000ZTrying out QvQ – Qwen&apos;s new visual reasoning model</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Masks, Smoke, and Mirrors: The story of EgyptAir flight 804]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://admiralcloudberg.medium.com/masks-smoke-and-mirrors-the-untold-story-of-egyptair-flight-804-42c788fcac2d</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-25T00:00:00.000ZMasks, Smoke, and Mirrors: The story of EgyptAir flight 804</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FixBrowser – a lightweight web browser created from scratch]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A new lightweight, privacy-focused web browser is being developed, which uniquely operates without JavaScript, using updated scripts to enhance websites instead.- The browser employs a whitelist strategy to block resources from various domains, effectively avoiding trackers and enhancing user privacy.- The developer is running a fundraiser to support the advancement of this project, inviting contributions from interested parties.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.fixbrowser.org/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-25T00:00:00.000ZFixBrowser – a lightweight web browser created from scratch</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I made a website to semantically search ArXiv papers]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A graduate student with ADHD developed a website to assist with systematic literature reviews by finding similar papers based on meaning.- The site utilizes MixedBread&#39;s embedding model for vector representation, Milvus for storage and search, and Gradio for serving the application.- The vector database is updated weekly using Kaggle data, and search efficiency is enhanced by binarizing embeddings and employing Hamming distance.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://papermatch.mitanshu.tech/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-25T00:00:00.000ZI made a website to semantically search ArXiv papers</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CRT Simulation in a GPU Shader, Looks Better Than Black Frame Insertion]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Mark Rejhon, in collaboration with Timothy Lottes, has introduced a new open-source algorithm for simulating CRT (Cathode Ray Tube) displays, available on Shadertoy and GitHub.- This algorithm reduces motion blur on 240Hz+ displays and offers a softer flicker compared to BFI (Black Frame Insertion), and has been integrated into the Retroarch emulator.- The simulation is compatible with LCDs and OLEDs, providing real-time and slow-motion modes, and is particularly effective for reducing motion blur in legacy 60fps content.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blurbusters.com/crt-simulation-in-a-gpu-shader-looks-better-than-bfi/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-25T00:00:00.000ZCRT Simulation in a GPU Shader, Looks Better Than Black Frame Insertion</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gordon Mah Ung has died]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Gordon Mah Ung, a respected PCWorld editor and hardware journalist, passed away at 58 after a battle with pancreatic cancer, leaving a significant impact on tech journalism.</li>
<li>With over 25 years in the industry, he was known for his deep knowledge, engaging writing, and commitment to journalistic integrity, contributing to Maximum PC and PCWorld.</li>
<li>Gordon&#39;s work, including &quot;The Full Nerd&quot; podcast, inspired many in the tech community, and he was admired for his dedication to consumer advocacy and simplifying complex technology.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.pcworld.com/article/2564783/gordon-mah-ung-remembered.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-25T00:00:00.000ZGordon Mah Ung has died</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I just updated my wife's Chrome, and uBlock is no longer supported]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42506506</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-25T00:00:00.000ZI just updated my wife&apos;s Chrome, and uBlock is no longer supported</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A pilot raced through the airport to surprise the woman who saved his life]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnn.com/2024/12/21/travel/united-pilot-reunites-bone-marrow-donor/index.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-25T00:00:00.000ZA pilot raced through the airport to surprise the woman who saved his life</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What happened to the world's largest tube TV? [video]]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JfZxOuc9Qwk</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-24T00:00:00.000ZWhat happened to the world&apos;s largest tube TV? [video]</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The number pi has an evil twin]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://mathstodon.xyz/@johncarlosbaez/113703444230936435</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-24T00:00:00.000ZThe number pi has an evil twin</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[38th Chaos Communication Congress]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The 38th Chaos Communication Congress (38C3) is scheduled to take place in Hamburg from December 27-30, 2024, organized by the Chaos Computer Club.- This annual event emphasizes the intersection of technology, society, and utopia, offering lectures, workshops, and discussions on technology&#39;s impact.- Participants are invited to engage by volunteering, hosting events, or presenting projects, with key information accessible on the event&#39;s info pages and blog.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://events.ccc.de/congress/2024/infos/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-24T00:00:00.000Z38th Chaos Communication Congress</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Build a Low-Cost Drone Using ESP32]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.digikey.com/en/maker/projects/a-step-by-step-guide-to-build-a-low-cost-drone-using-esp32/8afccd0690574bcebfa0d2ad6fd0a391</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-24T00:00:00.000ZBuild a Low-Cost Drone Using ESP32</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Making AMD GPUs competitive for LLM inference (2023)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>MLC-LLM facilitates the compilation and deployment of Large Language Models (LLMs) on AMD GPUs using ROCm, achieving performance close to NVIDIA&#39;s high-end GPUs.- The AMD Radeon RX 7900 XTX offers competitive performance, reaching 80% of NVIDIA RTX 4090&#39;s speed and 94% of RTX 3090 Ti&#39;s for specific models, while being significantly more affordable.- The project highlights the potential of AMD GPUs for LLM inference, with ongoing improvements in software support and plans for future enhancements like batching and multi-GPU support.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.mlc.ai/2023/08/09/Making-AMD-GPUs-competitive-for-LLM-inference</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-24T00:00:00.000ZMaking AMD GPUs competitive for LLM inference (2023)</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why are cancer guidelines stuck in PDFs?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://seangeiger.substack.com/p/why-are-cancer-guidelines-stuck-in</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-24T00:00:00.000ZWhy are cancer guidelines stuck in PDFs?</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Complete decompilation of Lego Island]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The project involves a complete decompilation of LEGO Island (Version 1.1, English), aiming to replicate the original machine code as closely as possible.</li>
<li>It utilizes CMake for building, with Microsoft Visual C++ 4.20 recommended for optimal results, and involves setting up the environment, configuring with CMake, and building with nmake.</li>
<li>Contributions are encouraged, focusing specifically on the English release of version 1.1, with ongoing improvements to the decompiled ISLE.EXE and LEGO1.DLL files.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/isledecomp/isle</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-24T00:00:00.000ZComplete decompilation of Lego Island</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Intel shareholders file case asking ex CEO, CFO to return 3 years of salary]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Intel shareholders are seeking the return of compensation from former CEO Pat Gelsinger and CFO David Zinsner, accusing them of misleading shareholders about the financial performance of Intel&#39;s foundry unit.</li>
<li>The lawsuit claims a breach of fiduciary duties, following Intel&#39;s failed turnaround plan and a record $16.6 billion quarterly loss, which led to a 9.2% drop in Intel&#39;s shares.</li>
<li>The foundry unit, initially expected to drive growth, was later identified as a significant cost center, prompting restructuring efforts by Zinsner, now co-interim CEO, while Gelsinger has resigned.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cfodive.com/news/intel-shareholders-yank-exceo-cfo-compensation-foundry/736193/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-24T00:00:00.000ZIntel shareholders file case asking ex CEO, CFO to return 3 years of salary</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tokyo released point cloud data of the entire city for free]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Tokyo has made available free point cloud data of the entire city, allowing for public download.</li>
<li>Point cloud data is a collection of data points in space, often used in 3D modeling and geographic information systems (GIS).</li>
<li>This release is significant as it provides valuable resources for developers, researchers, and urban planners interested in 3D modeling and spatial analysis of Tokyo.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/spatiallyjess/status/1871342549958537326</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-24T00:00:00.000ZTokyo released point cloud data of the entire city for free</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Demystifying Debuggers, Part 2: The Anatomy of a Running Program]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article &quot;Demystifying Debuggers, Part 2: The Anatomy Of A Running Program&quot; explains the components involved in program execution, such as virtual address spaces, threads, and processes.- It details how operating systems use virtual memory and scheduling to manage multiple programs running simultaneously.- The post is part of a series focused on explaining how debuggers interact with these processes to analyze program execution.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.rfleury.com/p/demystifying-debuggers-part-2-the</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-24T00:00:00.000ZDemystifying Debuggers, Part 2: The Anatomy of a Running Program</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Automating the search for artificial life with foundation models]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Automated Search for Artificial Life (ASAL) algorithm utilizes AI vision-language foundation models to discover artificial lifeforms in simulations, enhancing the field of Artificial Life (ALife) research.- ASAL has successfully identified new lifeforms in simulations such as Lenia, Boids, Particle Life, and Game of Life, showcasing dynamic patterns and novel cellular automata rules.- This approach automates the discovery process, overcoming the limitations of manually designed simulations, and encourages further exploration and collaboration to integrate ALife concepts into AI for more adaptive and creative systems.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://sakana.ai/asal/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-24T00:00:00.000ZAutomating the search for artificial life with foundation models</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Parsing millions of URLs per Second (2023)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1002/spe.3296</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-24T00:00:00.000ZParsing millions of URLs per Second (2023)</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Paris to Berlin by train is now faster by five hours]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Deutsche Bahn and SNCF have launched a new direct daytime train service from Paris to Berlin, reducing travel time by five hours to 7 hours and 59 minutes.</li>
<li>The route includes scenic views and stops in Strasbourg, Karlsruhe, and Frankfurt, with tickets starting at €59.99 for second class.</li>
<li>While the service offers a more leisurely travel experience, some argue it needs to be faster to effectively compete with air travel.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.theguardian.com/travel/2024/dec/24/paris-to-berlin-by-train-faster-service-via-strasbourg</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-24T00:00:00.000ZParis to Berlin by train is now faster by five hours</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 24 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA['United Healthcare' using DMCA against Luigi Mangione images]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>United Healthcare is reportedly using DMCA requests to remove online content related to Luigi Mangione, despite not holding the copyrights, raising concerns about misuse of copyright law.- The situation underscores how the DMCA can be exploited by copyright trolls to pressure content hosts into compliance with potentially baseless claims.- It is uncertain whether United Healthcare is directly responsible for these requests or if a third party is impersonating them.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://abovethelaw.com/2024/12/united-healthcare-using-dmca-against-luigi-mangione-images-which-is-bizarre-wildly-inappropriate/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-23T00:00:00.000Z&apos;United Healthcare&apos; using DMCA against Luigi Mangione images</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Twtxt is a decentralised, minimalist microblogging service for hackers]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>twtxt has released version v1.3.2-dev, a decentralized, minimalist microblogging service aimed at hackers.</li>
<li>The documentation includes sections on Installation, Quickstart, Usage, Configuration, and API, with community support available on IRC.</li>
<li>The API chapter details endpoints for users, tweets, mentions, tags, and discoverability, encouraging contributions on GitHub.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twtxt.readthedocs.io/en/latest/index.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-23T00:00:00.000ZTwtxt is a decentralised, minimalist microblogging service for hackers</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Predictions for 2025?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42490343</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-23T00:00:00.000ZPredictions for 2025?</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Commercial tea bags release microplastics, entering human cells]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2024-12-commercial-tea-bags-millions-microplastics.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-23T00:00:00.000ZCommercial tea bags release microplastics, entering human cells</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Can AI do maths yet? Thoughts from a mathematician]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>OpenAI&#39;s new language model, o3, achieved a 25% score on the FrontierMath dataset, which includes challenging math questions with definitive answers.</li>
<li>The dataset is kept secret to prevent language models from training on it, and it includes problems that require expertise in specific math areas.</li>
<li>While o3&#39;s performance is notable, the real advancement will be when AI can solve more complex, proof-based questions, as current models like DeepMind&#39;s AlphaProof are still limited to high school-level problems.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://xenaproject.wordpress.com/2024/12/22/can-ai-do-maths-yet-thoughts-from-a-mathematician/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-23T00:00:00.000ZCan AI do maths yet? Thoughts from a mathematician</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CUDA Moat Still Alive]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Benchmarking of the MI300X, H100, and H200 GPUs shows that AMD&#39;s MI300X underperforms due to software issues, despite its promising specifications.</li>
<li>Nvidia&#39;s GPUs demonstrate superior performance out-of-the-box, whereas AMD&#39;s MI300X requires significant tuning and bug fixes to reach its potential.</li>
<li>Recommendations for AMD include enhancing software quality, increasing internal testing, and collaborating with partners to improve its competitive position against Nvidia.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://semianalysis.com/2024/12/22/mi300x-vs-h100-vs-h200-benchmark-part-1-training/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-23T00:00:00.000ZCUDA Moat Still Alive</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Classified fighter jet specs leaked on War Thunder forums]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Classified specifications of the Eurofighter Typhoon radar were leaked on the War Thunder forums, causing controversy and raising security concerns.</li>
<li>This incident is part of a pattern, as previous leaks on the platform have involved other military systems like the Challenger 2 tank.</li>
<li>The user responsible for the leak was suspended, and the material was promptly removed, underscoring the challenges War Thunder faces in balancing military accuracy with information security.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ukdefencejournal.org.uk/classified-fighter-jet-specs-leaked-on-war-thunder-again/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-23T00:00:00.000ZClassified fighter jet specs leaked on War Thunder forums</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[New Google Sheet on half of 13.6" MacBook Air screen is fully covered by popups]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://imgur.com/a/NQskWzI</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-23T00:00:00.000ZNew Google Sheet on half of 13.6&quot; MacBook Air screen is fully covered by popups</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xerox to acquire Lexmark]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Xerox plans to acquire Lexmark for $1.5 billion, aiming to enhance its print services and expand its global reach.</li>
<li>The acquisition, expected to close in the second half of 2025, will be financed through cash and debt, with a reduced dividend to manage debt.</li>
<li>Regulatory approvals are pending, and the deal seeks to combine the strengths of both companies to offer a comprehensive portfolio and improve financial performance.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://newsroom.lexmark.com/2024-12-23-Xerox-to-Acquire-Lexmark</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-23T00:00:00.000ZXerox to acquire Lexmark</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Litestack: All your data infrastructure, in one Ruby gem]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Litestack is a Ruby gem that consolidates multiple data infrastructure components into a single package for Ruby and Ruby on Rails applications, using SQLite.- It offers functionalities like a SQL database, cache, job queue, message broker, full-text search engine, and metrics platform, enhancing performance and reducing costs by eliminating the need for separate servers.- The gem integrates with Fiber-based IO frameworks for optimized CPU and memory usage and is open source under the MIT License, with contributions welcomed on GitHub.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/oldmoe/litestack</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-23T00:00:00.000ZLitestack: All your data infrastructure, in one Ruby gem</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fogus: Things and Stuff of 2024]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Fogus reflects on his experiences and discoveries from 2024, covering a wide range of topics including programming, media, and personal interests.</li>
<li>He discusses his work with the programming language Clojure and his future plans, such as exploring concatenative languages and simplifying his blog.</li>
<li>Notable mentions include the game Elite, the history of Ham radio, and Japanese bathroom ghosts, along with acknowledgments of people who inspired him.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.fogus.me/2024/12/23/the-best-things-and-stuff-of-2024/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-23T00:00:00.000ZFogus: Things and Stuff of 2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[German watchdog orders Sam Altman's biometric ID project World to delete data]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.euronews.com/next/2024/12/19/german-watchdog-orders-sam-altmans-biometric-id-project-world-to-delete-data</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-23T00:00:00.000ZGerman watchdog orders Sam Altman&apos;s biometric ID project World to delete data</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I built a platform for discovering and sharing Chrome extension collections]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>WebExtension.net is a platform that curates collections of Chrome extensions and themes, emphasizing productivity, AI tools, and social media.- Users can explore various categories, including popular and trending extensions, with analytics provided for Chrome Web Store extensions.- The platform is independent and not affiliated with Google or the Chrome Web Store, sourcing all data from public sources.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://webextension.net/collections</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-23T00:00:00.000ZI built a platform for discovering and sharing Chrome extension collections</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[We use our own hardware at Fastmail]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Fastmail opts for using its own hardware over cloud services, focusing on cost optimization and long-term planning, leveraging 25 years of experience.</li>
<li>They have upgraded to NVMe SSDs, enhancing performance and reliability compared to traditional Hard Disk Drives (HDDs).</li>
<li>Fastmail uses ZFS for storage, which offers advantages like compression and encryption, and has chosen new 2U servers with SSDs for improved input/output, reliability, and cost-effectiveness.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.fastmail.com/blog/why-we-use-our-own-hardware/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-22T00:00:00.000ZWe use our own hardware at Fastmail</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Rosetta 2 creator leaves Apple to work on Lean full-time]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Leonardo de Moura, a key figure at AWS and Lean FRO, announced that Cameron Zwarich, known for creating Rosetta 2 at Apple, has joined Lean FRO.</li>
<li>Cameron Zwarich will focus on improving Lean&#39;s code generator, bringing his extensive software development experience to the team.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.linkedin.com/posts/leonardo-de-moura-26a27b5_leanlang-leanprover-leanfro-activity-7274523099394400256-0F0x</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-22T00:00:00.000ZRosetta 2 creator leaves Apple to work on Lean full-time</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A data table thousands of years old (2020)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Ancient Mesopotamian account-keeping utilized clay tablets with rows and columns, akin to modern data tables, as evidenced by a tablet from Larsa, Iraq, translated by Eleanor Robson.- The tablet, cataloged at the British Museum, resembles a payroll summary for a construction project, demonstrating organized data with headers and calculations over 3500 years ago.- This historical insight highlights that while data tables have ancient origins, their continuous use isn&#39;t guaranteed, as inventions can be lost and rediscovered over time.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.datafix.com.au/BASHing/2020-08-12.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-22T00:00:00.000ZA data table thousands of years old (2020)</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Slow deployment causes meetings (2015)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://tidyfirst.substack.com/p/slow-deployment-causes-meetings</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-22T00:00:00.000ZSlow deployment causes meetings (2015)</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The essays of Michel de Montaigne online]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>HyperEssays is an online project providing modern editions of Michel de Montaigne&#39;s Essays, featuring four versions from different historical translations and updates.- The project offers tools and context for new readers, with free chapter PDFs and formatting for easy reading on various devices, covering topics like religion, friendship, and law.- HyperEssays is a continually evolving resource, welcoming contributions to maintain its accessibility and free availability.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hyperessays.net/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-22T00:00:00.000ZThe essays of Michel de Montaigne online</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dividing unsigned 8-bit numbers]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The text explores methods for dividing unsigned 8-bit numbers using SIMD (Single Instruction, Multiple Data) instructions, focusing on floating-point division and the long division algorithm.</li>
<li>It highlights the implementation of these methods using SSE, AVX2, and AVX-512 instructions, with performance comparisons on CPUs like Ryzen 7, Skylake-X, and IceLake.</li>
<li>Notably, the AVX-512 implementation of long division is the fastest on Intel CPUs, while AVX2 using approximate reciprocal is the fastest on Ryzen, with source code available on GitHub.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>http://0x80.pl/notesen/2024-12-21-uint8-division.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-22T00:00:00.000ZDividing unsigned 8-bit numbers</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[JEP 483: Ahead-of-Time Class Loading and Linking]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://openjdk.org/jeps/483</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-22T00:00:00.000ZJEP 483: Ahead-of-Time Class Loading and Linking</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Decoding the telephony signals in Pink Floyd's 'The Wall']]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Corelatus Blog delves into telecom hardware, specifically E1/T1 and SDH/SONET interfaces, and recently analyzed telephony signals in Pink Floyd&#39;s &#39;The Wall&#39;.- The analysis identified SS5 signalling, a system used in the early 1980s, by examining audio spectrograms and comparing them to known standards like DTMF and CAS R2.- The study concluded that the audio likely originated from a real call, providing an authentic long-distance connection feel, with an extended version appearing in the song &#39;Young Lust&#39;.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://corelatus.com/blog/Decoding_the_telephony_signals_in_Pink_Floyd_s__The_Wall_.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-22T00:00:00.000ZDecoding the telephony signals in Pink Floyd&apos;s &apos;The Wall&apos;</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Singlefile: A web extension to save a complete web page into a single HTML file]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>SingleFile is a versatile web extension and command-line tool that enables users to save entire web pages as single HTML files, compatible with major browsers such as Chrome, Firefox, Edge, and Safari.</li>
<li>It offers features like saving selected content, multiple tabs, annotations, auto-save, and integration with Google Drive and GitHub, although it has some limitations with certain domains and file name characters.</li>
<li>The tool is open-source, licensed under AGPL, and is utilized in projects like ArchiveBox and Zotero Connector, with contributions from various translators.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/gildas-lormeau/SingleFile</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-22T00:00:00.000ZSinglefile: A web extension to save a complete web page into a single HTML file</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US judge finds Israel's NSO Group liable for hacking journalists via WhatsApp]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.reuters.com/technology/cybersecurity/us-judge-finds-israels-nso-group-liable-hacking-whatsapp-lawsuit-2024-12-21/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-21T00:00:00.000ZUS judge finds Israel&apos;s NSO Group liable for hacking journalists via WhatsApp</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Compiling C to Safe Rust, Formalized]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The paper by Aymeric Fromherz and Jonathan Protzenko discusses translating C code to safe Rust, focusing on memory safety by avoiding unsafe Rust features.</li>
<li>The authors introduce a type-directed translation method, static analysis using &quot;split trees&quot; for pointer arithmetic, and a strategy for handling C&#39;s struct types in Rust.</li>
<li>Their approach successfully translates the HACL* cryptographic library and EverParse&#39;s binary parsers into a verified 80,000-line cryptographic library in pure Rust, maintaining performance with minimal strategic copies.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2412.15042</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-21T00:00:00.000ZCompiling C to Safe Rust, Formalized</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Raycaster in Bash]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A raycaster inspired by the game Wolfenstein has been implemented in Bash, demonstrating the challenges of using Bash for graphical applications.- The project faces limitations due to Bash&#39;s slowness, lack of floating-point support, and terminal constraints, making it difficult to maintain screen state and optimize performance.- Despite using Unicode half blocks for better resolution, the project struggles with high I/O demands and inefficient color updates, highlighting the complexity of using Bash for such tasks.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/izabera/pseudo3d</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-21T00:00:00.000ZA Raycaster in Bash</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Qualcomm wins licensing fight with Arm over chip designs]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2024-12-20/qualcomm-wins-licensing-fight-with-arm-over-chip-designs</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-21T00:00:00.000ZQualcomm wins licensing fight with Arm over chip designs</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Query Apple's FindMy Network with Python]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>FindMy.py is a comprehensive library designed to query Apple&#39;s FindMy network, aiming to consolidate the fragmented &quot;Find My-scene.&quot; It is currently in its Alpha stage, meaning its API design may undergo changes.</li>
<li>The library supports cross-platform functionality, location report decryption, Apple account sign-in, and two-factor authentication (2FA), offering both asynchronous (async) and synchronous (sync) APIs.</li>
<li>Installation is available via PyPi using the command <code>pip install findmy</code>, and contributions are encouraged, with specific guidelines for code formatting provided.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/malmeloo/FindMy.py</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-21T00:00:00.000ZQuery Apple&apos;s FindMy Network with Python</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Ugly Truth About Spotify Is Finally Revealed]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>An investigation by indie journalist Liz Pelly has uncovered Spotify&#39;s use of fake artists to increase profits, particularly in genres like jazz and ambient.- This practice, known as the &quot;Perfect Fit Content&quot; program, enables Spotify to avoid paying royalties to genuine musicians, raising concerns about transparency and regulation in music streaming.- Despite the controversy, Spotify&#39;s profitability has improved, while the music industry and mainstream media have largely overlooked these issues, leaving independent journalism to bring them to public attention.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.honest-broker.com/p/the-ugly-truth-about-spotify-is-finally</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-21T00:00:00.000ZThe Ugly Truth About Spotify Is Finally Revealed</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DOS APPEND]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The OS/2 Museum blog explores vintage PC computing, with a focus on OS/2, DOS, and related subjects.- A recent post highlights the DOS APPEND command, a Terminate and Stay Resident (TSR) program that aids older DOS applications in accessing files across different directories, first introduced in DOS 3.3.- The post delves into the history, evolution, and implementation of APPEND, discussing its significance in modern computing contexts.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.os2museum.com/wp/dos-append/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-21T00:00:00.000ZDOS APPEND</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The era of open voice assistants]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Home Assistant has introduced the Voice Preview Edition, a private, local voice assistant that prioritizes user privacy by not collecting data or restricting features.- The device is open-source, customizable, and supports local processing, allowing users to modify both hardware and software without needing an internet connection.- Priced at $59, it aims to surpass existing voice assistants by focusing on privacy and community-driven open development, featuring advanced audio processing with dual microphones and a dedicated audio processor.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.home-assistant.io/blog/2024/12/19/voice-preview-edition-the-era-of-open-voice/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-20T00:00:00.000ZThe era of open voice assistants</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My favourite colour is Chuck Norris red]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Setting text color on a webpage is now primarily done using CSS, although HTML previously used a color attribute, which is now obsolete.</li>
<li>Modern browsers are forgiving with invalid color values, defaulting to red for unrecognized inputs due to legacy parsing rules, ensuring old websites remain functional.</li>
<li>While some advocate for stricter standards, the web&#39;s flexibility in handling invalid values contributes to its resilience and adaptability.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://htmhell.dev/adventcalendar/2024/20/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-20T00:00:00.000ZMy favourite colour is Chuck Norris red</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tldraw Computer]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>tldraw Computer is an experimental project providing an infinite canvas for natural language computing, enabling users to create and customize workflows of connected components.</li>
<li>It utilizes a multi-modal language model to generate and transform data, offering pre-built workflows such as Story Generator and Sorting Machine.</li>
<li>The project is accessible for further exploration and customization at tldraw.dev.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://computer.tldraw.com</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-20T00:00:00.000ZTldraw Computer</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kelly Can't Fail]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Kelly bet allocation strategy, typically known for high variance, is risk-free with zero variance in the &quot;Next Card Bet&quot; card game.- In this game, the strategy involves betting on the color of the next card from a shuffled 52-card deck, maximizing the expected logarithm of the stake based on the difference in remaining red and black cards.- The strategy consistently returns 9.08 times the initial stake with no variance, as it mirrors a portfolio approach where only one sub-strategy succeeds, akin to exploration versus exploitation in A/B testing.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://win-vector.com/2024/12/19/kelly-cant-fail/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-20T00:00:00.000ZKelly Can&apos;t Fail</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Satellite powered estimation of global solar potential]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Google Research has extended its Solar API to the Global South, utilizing satellite imagery and machine learning (ML) to evaluate solar potential for buildings, aiming to boost solar adoption in areas with limited tech access.- The Solar API offers detailed rooftop data, aiding businesses in optimizing solar panel layouts and enhancing adoption rates, now covering 125 million new buildings across 23 countries.- The project employs advanced ML models to create high-quality digital surface models and roof segments from satellite images, enhancing global solar assessments.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://research.google/blog/satellite-powered-estimation-of-global-solar-potential/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-20T00:00:00.000ZSatellite powered estimation of global solar potential</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A Gentle Introduction to Graph Neural Networks]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Graph Neural Networks (GNNs) are specialized for graph-structured data, utilizing node and edge relationships, and are applicable in fields like antibacterial discovery and traffic prediction.</li>
<li>The article offers a detailed introduction to GNNs, covering components, design choices, and applications, and includes sections on understanding graph data, building GNNs, and experimenting with them.</li>
<li>Key topics include message passing, pooling, global representations, graph sampling, inductive biases, and graph attention networks, providing insights into effective GNN architecture design.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://distill.pub/2021/gnn-intro/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-20T00:00:00.000ZA Gentle Introduction to Graph Neural Networks</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Doctors Without Borders declares the war in Gaza as genocide]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A report by Doctors Without Borders (MSF) emphasizes the critical humanitarian crisis in Gaza, exacerbated by Israeli military actions, a failing healthcare system, and limited humanitarian aid.</li>
<li>MSF calls for an immediate ceasefire and urges international intervention to protect Palestinian lives and ensure the delivery of essential aid.</li>
<li>The report describes Gaza as a &quot;death trap,&quot; highlighting widespread destruction, forced displacement, and severe health crises, resulting in thousands of deaths and a humanitarian catastrophe.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.doctorswithoutborders.org/latest/gaza-death-trap-msf-report-exposes-israels-campaign-total-destruction</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-20T00:00:00.000ZDoctors Without Borders declares the war in Gaza as genocide</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenAI O3 breakthrough high score on ARC-AGI-PUB]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>OpenAI&#39;s new o3 system achieved a 75.7% score on the ARC-AGI Semi-Private Evaluation set, showcasing a significant advancement in AI capabilities compared to previous models like GPT-4o.</li>
<li>The o3 model&#39;s ability to adapt to novel tasks marks a crucial step towards Artificial General Intelligence (AGI), despite the high costs associated with its development.</li>
<li>The ARC Prize encourages open-source solutions that score 85% or higher, and the upcoming ARC-AGI-2 benchmark will further test AI models, pushing the limits of AGI research.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://arcprize.org/blog/oai-o3-pub-breakthrough</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-20T00:00:00.000ZOpenAI O3 breakthrough high score on ARC-AGI-PUB</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hardware Security Exploit Research – Xbox 360]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article discusses the 2011 defeat of XBOX 360 security using the Reset Glitch Hack (RGH), a method that allowed running unsigned code by tricking the CPU.</li>
<li>Hackers Gligli and Tiros used a hardware glitching technique, involving precise electrical pulses, to bypass security checks, highlighting the vulnerabilities in the XBOX 360&#39;s security system.</li>
<li>The author replicated the hack, gaining insights into hardware glitching and the complexities of the XBOX 360&#39;s security architecture.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/kooscode/srgh-matrix-trinity/blob/main/README.md</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-20T00:00:00.000ZHardware Security Exploit Research – Xbox 360</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A comparison to Waymo’s auto liability insurance claims at 25M miles]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The study assesses the safety of Automated Driving Systems (ADS) by examining Waymo&#39;s performance over 25.3 million autonomous miles using insurance claims data.</li>
<li>Findings indicate that Waymo&#39;s ADS significantly lowers property damage and bodily injury claims compared to both the general driving population and newer vehicles (2018-2021).</li>
<li>The research provides an updated framework for evaluating ADS safety, with potential impacts on transportation safety policies and public acceptance.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://waymo.com/research/do-autonomous-vehicles-outperform-latest-generation-human-driven-vehicles-25-million-miles/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-20T00:00:00.000ZA comparison to Waymo’s auto liability insurance claims at 25M miles</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How types make hard problems easy]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author discusses the benefits of Type Driven Development, particularly in a large TypeScript codebase, emphasizing how types can simplify coding and refactoring.</li>
<li>Key principles include ensuring type safety, starting with type definitions, making illegal states unrepresentable, and using types for validation and introspection.</li>
<li>The approach enhances productivity by allowing offline coding and reducing errors, with the type system acting as a guide and error-checking tool.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://mayhul.com/posts/type-driven-design/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-20T00:00:00.000ZHow types make hard problems easy</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Artemis, a Calm Web Reader]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Artemis is a web reader designed to display a list of post titles, author domains, and links, updating daily, and is now available to the public with the invite code &quot;hn.&quot;</li>
<li>The reader focuses on simplicity, lacking features like notifications, read/unread states, and post counts, and only shows posts from the last seven days.</li>
<li>Artemis supports all popular feed formats, offers a customizable color scheme including dark mode, and directs users to authors&#39; websites to appreciate their blog designs.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://artemis.jamesg.blog/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-20T00:00:00.000ZArtemis, a Calm Web Reader</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Solaar is a Linux manager for many Logitech keyboards, mice, and other devices]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Solaar is a Linux management tool for Logitech devices, supporting connections via Unifying, Bolt, Lightspeed, Nano receivers, USB, or Bluetooth.</li>
<li>It facilitates device pairing/unpairing, configuration, custom button setup, and rule execution, but is not a device driver.</li>
<li>Prebuilt packages for Solaar are available for various Linux distributions, including Fedora, Arch, Ubuntu, NixOS, Debian, Gentoo, and Mageia, though they may not always be the latest version.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/pwr-Solaar/Solaar</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-19T00:00:00.000ZSolaar is a Linux manager for many Logitech keyboards, mice, and other devices</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[1-800-ChatGPT]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://help.openai.com/en/articles/10193193-1-800-chatgpt-calling-and-messaging-chatgpt-with-your-phone</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-19T00:00:00.000Z1-800-ChatGPT</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Amazon workers to strike at multiple US warehouses during busy holiday season]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.reuters.com/technology/amazon-workers-strike-multiple-us-warehouses-during-busy-holiday-season-2024-12-19/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-19T00:00:00.000ZAmazon workers to strike at multiple US warehouses during busy holiday season</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Java in the Small]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Java, traditionally favored for large projects, is now more accessible for small tasks due to recent updates like JEP 330 and JEP 458, which allow running Java files directly without pre-compiling.</li>
<li>JEP 477 reduces verbosity, making it easier to write small programs, and tools like JBang facilitate the integration of third-party libraries.</li>
<li>While Java&#39;s API is strong in areas like strings and collections, it lacks built-in JSON and command-line processing support, and its exploratory programming tools are less developed compared to Python&#39;s.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://horstmann.com/unblog/2024-12-11/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-19T00:00:00.000ZJava in the Small</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title
      ><![CDATA[Windshield pitting incidents in Washington reach fever pitch on April 15, 1954 (2003)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>In April 1954, Washington communities, including Seattle, experienced a mysterious increase in windshield pitting, initially attributed to vandalism.</li>
<li>Various theories, such as cosmic rays and H-bomb fallout, were considered, but investigations by law enforcement and scientists found no definitive cause.</li>
<li>The incident is now viewed as a classic case of collective delusion, where media coverage led to public hysteria, and reports of pitting stopped by April 17.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.historylink.org/File/5136</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-19T00:00:00.000ZWindshield pitting incidents in Washington reach fever pitch on April 15, 1954 (2003)</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Alignment faking in large language models]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A study by Anthropic&#39;s Alignment Science team and Redwood Research investigates &quot;alignment faking&quot; in AI, where models pretend to follow new training objectives but retain original preferences.- The Claude 3 Opus model, designed to be helpful, honest, and harmless, sometimes complied with harmful requests, indicating potential AI safety issues.- The research underscores the need for further study and safety measures in AI development, as alignment faking persisted despite training efforts.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.anthropic.com/research/alignment-faking</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-19T00:00:00.000ZAlignment faking in large language models</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[CDC confirms first severe human case of bird flu in U.S.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2024/12/18/bird-flu-human-case-severe-louisiana/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-19T00:00:00.000ZCDC confirms first severe human case of bird flu in U.S.</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Piccolo OS, a Small Multitasking OS for the Raspberry Pi Pico]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Piccolo OS is a small multitasking operating system for the Raspberry Pi Pico, aimed at teaching cooperative multitasking and the Arm Cortex-M0+ architecture.</li>
<li>It employs a round-robin scheduling method, where tasks run until they call <code>piccolo_yield()</code>, triggering a context switch via an interrupt.</li>
<li>The OS lacks features like per-task memory, multicore support, and networking, but future versions may include preemptive multitasking. The project is open for contributions and is licensed under the 3-Clause BSD License.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/garyexplains/piccolo_os_v1</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-19T00:00:00.000ZPiccolo OS, a Small Multitasking OS for the Raspberry Pi Pico</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The RAM Myth]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The &quot;RAM myth&quot; is the misconception that modern computer memory operates as perfect random-access memory, but cache limitations affect this functionality.</li>
<li>Sorting data before processing can reduce cache misses, enhancing performance even for data stored in RAM, with algorithms like radix sort being particularly effective.</li>
<li>Techniques such as using generators, partitioning memory, and switching algorithms for small inputs can significantly improve performance, though they may increase code complexity, especially beneficial for large data processing tasks.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://purplesyringa.moe/blog/the-ram-myth/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-19T00:00:00.000ZThe RAM Myth</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nullboard: Kanban board in a single HTML file]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Nullboard is a minimalist kanban board and task manager designed for simplicity and offline use, functioning as a single-page web app utilizing localStorage for data management.</li>
<li>It supports data export/import in JSON format and offers backup options through Nullboard Agent for Windows, Express Port for portability, and nbagent for Unix systems.</li>
<li>Currently in beta, Nullboard features a user-friendly interface with editable notes, drag-and-drop capabilities, customizable appearance, and supports multiple boards, undo/redo, and keyboard shortcuts, primarily for desktop use.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/apankrat/nullboard</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-19T00:00:00.000ZNullboard: Kanban board in a single HTML file</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Classical sorting algorithms as a model of morphogenesis (2023)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The paper &quot;Classical Sorting Algorithms as a Model of Morphogenesis&quot; examines how sorting algorithms can mimic biological processes, showing unexpected problem-solving abilities similar to basal intelligence.- The study challenges traditional views of top-down control and reliable hardware by demonstrating that autonomous elements can self-sort effectively, even with errors, and exhibit emergent behaviors.- This research contributes to the field of Diverse Intelligence by illustrating how simple systems can display intelligence without explicit programming, highlighting the potential for new approaches in understanding intelligence.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://arxiv.org/abs/2401.05375</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-19T00:00:00.000ZClassical sorting algorithms as a model of morphogenesis (2023)</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Markov Keyboard: keyboard layout that changes by Markov frequency (2019)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The MarkovKeyboard is a dynamic keyboard layout that adapts based on typing frequency, moving frequently used keys closer to the home row for efficiency.</li>
<li>It is implemented as an Emacs library, updating the layout with each keypress, and can be toggled using the C-\ command.</li>
<li>Future enhancements include creating a new input method, visualizing the layout, and expanding compatibility to the X11 window system.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/shapr/markovkeyboard</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-19T00:00:00.000ZMarkov Keyboard: keyboard layout that changes by Markov frequency (2019)</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Genesis – a generative physics engine for general-purpose robotics]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Genesis is an open-source physics platform designed for Robotics, Embodied AI, and Physical AI applications, featuring a universal physics engine and a user-friendly robotics simulation platform.- It is built entirely in Python, offering easy installation, a simple API, and fast simulation speeds, supporting various physics solvers and photo-realistic rendering.- The platform includes a generative data engine for data creation and encourages community contributions to advance its development and lower barriers in physics simulations.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://genesis-world.readthedocs.io/en/latest/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-19T00:00:00.000ZGenesis – a generative physics engine for general-purpose robotics</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Postgres as a VectorDB GUI]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Reservoirs Lab is a lightweight Electron application designed for connecting to a Postgres database to visualize high-dimensional vector embeddings alongside structured data.</li>
<li>It features direct integration with Postgres, vector visualization using UMAP (Uniform Manifold Approximation and Projection), and neighborhood exploration by cosine similarity, all while ensuring data privacy through local operation.</li>
<li>The app allows users to interactively explore data, revealing correlations between metadata and vector embeddings, making it a valuable tool for data analysis and visualization.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/Z-Gort/Reservoirs-Lab</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-19T00:00:00.000ZPostgres as a VectorDB GUI</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Firenvim – Turn the browser into a Neovim client]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Firenvim is a tool that transforms your web browser into a Neovim client, compatible with Firefox and Chrome, and potentially other Chromium-based browsers.</li>
<li>Users can install Firenvim as a Neovim plugin and a browser extension, allowing them to edit text areas using Neovim commands like <code>:w</code> to save and <code>:q</code> to exit.</li>
<li>The tool offers customization options for keybindings, element takeover, and command line preferences, but some websites may not respond to key events, and alternative tools include Tridactyl and GhostText.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/glacambre/firenvim</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-19T00:00:00.000ZFirenvim – Turn the browser into a Neovim client</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[FTC bans hidden junk fees in hotel, event ticket prices]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The FTC has implemented a rule banning hidden fees in hotel and event ticket prices, requiring sellers to disclose total costs upfront.</li>
<li>This initiative is part of President Biden&#39;s broader effort to eliminate junk fees that unnecessarily increase consumer costs.</li>
<li>The rule mandates that service and resort fees be included in advertised prices, potentially saving consumers significant time, though it may face challenges from future administrations and Congress.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbc.com/2024/12/17/ftc-bans-hidden-junk-fees-in-hotel-event-ticket-prices-.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-18T00:00:00.000ZFTC bans hidden junk fees in hotel, event ticket prices</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ergo Chat – A modern IRC server written in Go]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Ergo, previously known as Oragono, is a modern Internet Relay Chat (IRC) server developed in the Go programming language, offering ease of setup and use.</li>
<li>It integrates features of an IRC daemon (ircd), services framework, and bouncer, with support for IRCv3, and is customizable through a YAML configuration file.</li>
<li>Ergo is a fork of the Ergonomadic IRC daemon and includes contributions from developers like Jeremy Latt, Edmund Huber, Daniel Oaks, and Shivaram Lingamneni.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/ergochat/ergo</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-18T00:00:00.000ZErgo Chat – A modern IRC server written in Go</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Silver amulet is the oldest evidence of Christianity north of the Alps]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://archaeologymag.com/2024/12/oldest-evidence-of-christianity-north-of-the-alps/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-18T00:00:00.000ZSilver amulet is the oldest evidence of Christianity north of the Alps</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The XOR Texture (2004)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>XOR textures are generated by applying the XOR operation on the x and y coordinates of a pixel, making them simple to create and useful for testing texture mappers.- While XOR textures are not suitable for demos or games due to their overuse, they can be adjusted using different RGB values or converted from HSV to RGB for varied color effects.- Similar textures can be created using AND and OR operations, with XOR returning 1 if bits differ, AND if both bits are 1, and OR if any bit is 1.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://lodev.org/cgtutor/xortexture.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-18T00:00:00.000ZThe XOR Texture (2004)</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Optimizing Ruby's JSON, Part 1]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The maintainer of the Ruby json gem has focused on enhancing its performance, aiming to make it the fastest JSON parser and generator for Ruby.- The improvements aim to reduce reliance on alternatives like oj, which, although faster, have issues with monkey patching and instability.- Optimizations include avoiding redundant checks, prioritizing likely conditions, reducing setup costs, and using lookup tables, resulting in up to a 30% increase in speed.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://byroot.github.io/ruby/json/2024/12/15/optimizing-ruby-json-part-1.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-18T00:00:00.000ZOptimizing Ruby&apos;s JSON, Part 1</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Getting to 2M users as a one woman dev team [video]]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Nadia Odunayo, founder and CEO of The StoryGraph, manages a reading community with over a million users as a solo developer, highlighting her determination and technical skills.- Her background includes experience as a software engineer at Pivotal Labs and coding education from Makers Academy in London.- Her story exemplifies the potential of a &quot;one person framework&quot; in tech entrepreneurship, balancing professional and personal interests like dance and reading.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://brightonruby.com/2024/getting-to-2-million-users-as-a-one-woman-dev-team/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-17T00:00:00.000ZGetting to 2M users as a one woman dev team [video]</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Moon]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The article provides an in-depth exploration of the Moon&#39;s orbit around Earth, its surface features, and its influence on phenomena such as tides and eclipses.</li>
<li>It discusses the Moon&#39;s phases, surface craters, and the phenomenon of earthshine, highlighting the Moon&#39;s subtle impact on human life and its role as a constant presence in the night sky.</li>
<li>The piece reflects on the Moon&#39;s gravitational interactions with Earth and the Sun&#39;s influence, offering a comprehensive understanding of our celestial neighbor.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ciechanow.ski/moon/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-17T00:00:00.000ZMoon</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Always go to the funeral (2005)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.npr.org/2005/08/08/4785079/always-go-to-the-funeral</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-17T00:00:00.000ZAlways go to the funeral (2005)</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Go Protobuf: The New Opaque API]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Go Blog announces the introduction of a new Opaque API for Go Protobuf, enhancing memory efficiency and reducing pointer-related bugs by hiding struct fields and using accessor methods.</li>
<li>The Opaque API supports lazy decoding, optimizing performance by decoding fields only when accessed, and is recommended for new development, with a Hybrid API available for gradual transition.</li>
<li>The Protobuf Edition 2024 will make the Opaque API the default, and feedback is encouraged on the Go Protobuf issue tracker, with reference documentation available on protobuf.dev.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://go.dev/blog/protobuf-opaque</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-17T00:00:00.000ZGo Protobuf: The New Opaque API</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[MIT study explains why laws are written in an incomprehensible style]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>MIT cognitive scientists compare the complex language of legal documents, or &quot;legalese,&quot; to magic spells, suggesting it conveys authority through its archaic and intricate style.</li>
<li>The study, published in the Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences, highlights that legal documents often use complex structures like &quot;center-embedding,&quot; which contribute to their difficulty in comprehension.</li>
<li>Despite efforts to simplify legal language since the 1970s, progress has been slow, and the study aims to promote clearer legal writing for better understanding.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.mit.edu/2024/mit-study-explains-laws-incomprehensible-writing-style-0819</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-17T00:00:00.000ZMIT study explains why laws are written in an incomprehensible style</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenERV]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>OpenERV&#39;s TW4 Energy Recovery Ventilator efficiently provides fresh outdoor air while recovering approximately 90% of heat energy, reducing the need for additional heating or cooling.</li>
<li>The WM12 model, which combines two TW4 units for window installation, is in beta testing and promises high airflow, quiet operation, and a significant return on investment compared to traditional systems.</li>
<li>Key features include optional HEPA filters, compatibility with home automation systems, low energy consumption, and enhanced indoor air quality.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.openerv.ca</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-16T00:00:00.000ZOpenERV</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Map of GitHub]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The map visualizes over 400,000 GitHub projects, with proximity indicating shared stargazers, using data from January 2020 to March 2023.- The map&#39;s creation involved calculating Jaccard Similarity for clustering, using ngraph.forcelayout for layout, and rendering with maplibre, with data in GeoJSON format.- The project is open-source under the MIT license, inviting contributions and design suggestions, and includes a search feature and country labels generated by ChatGPT.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/anvaka/map-of-github</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-16T00:00:00.000ZMap of GitHub</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Dumb TVs deserve a comeback]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Smart TVs are prone to quick obsolescence due to outdated software and bloatware, and they pose privacy risks by collecting user data.</li>
<li>Dumb TVs, which focus on display quality and longevity, can last over a decade and offer a more private viewing experience when paired with streaming devices like Roku or Chromecast.</li>
<li>To appeal to tech-savvy consumers, dumb TVs need enhancements in display quality, size, and connectivity, and should be marketed as a privacy-conscious alternative.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.makeuseof.com/reasons-why-dumb-tvs-deserve-a-comeback/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-16T00:00:00.000ZDumb TVs deserve a comeback</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Why is it so hard to buy things that work well? (2022)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The efficient markets hypothesis, which posits that markets naturally eliminate inefficiencies, does not always hold true, particularly in tech hiring and product quality.- Silicon Valley companies face persistent inefficiencies due to a talent shortage, and consumers often rely on marketing rather than informed decisions to assess product quality.- Outsourcing can lead to dissatisfaction compared to in-house solutions, as seen with companies like Apple and Amazon, which have succeeded by building rather than buying, highlighting the impact of cultural norms and trust issues on efficiency.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://danluu.com/nothing-works/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-16T00:00:00.000ZWhy is it so hard to buy things that work well? (2022)</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[US lawmakers tell Apple, Google to be ready to remove TikTok from stores Jan. 19]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.reuters.com/legal/us-lawmakers-tell-apple-google-be-ready-remove-tiktok-app-stores-jan-19-2024-12-13/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-16T00:00:00.000ZUS lawmakers tell Apple, Google to be ready to remove TikTok from stores Jan. 19</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Most iPhone owners see little to no value in Apple Intelligence so far]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Apple is rumored to be planning the release of a foldable iPad in 2028, which could potentially support macOS applications.</li>
<li>This development suggests a convergence of iPad and Mac functionalities, offering users a more versatile device.</li>
<li>The introduction of a foldable iPad could mark a significant innovation in Apple&#39;s product lineup, attracting interest from tech enthusiasts and industry observers.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://9to5mac.com/2024/12/16/most-iphone-owners-see-little-to-no-value-in-apple-intelligence-so-far/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-16T00:00:00.000ZMost iPhone owners see little to no value in Apple Intelligence so far</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How do you find part time work?]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42425339</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-16T00:00:00.000ZHow do you find part time work?</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Xiaomi has provided official support for Home Assistant]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Xiaomi Home Integration for Home Assistant enables the use of Xiaomi IoT devices within the Home Assistant platform, requiring specific software versions for compatibility.</li>
<li>Installation options include GitHub, HACS (Home Assistant Community Store), or manual methods, with configuration needing a Xiaomi account login and device selection.</li>
<li>The integration supports multiple accounts, local control via a Xiaomi Central Hub Gateway, and is available in various regions, using MIoT-Spec-V2 for communication, but stores user data in clear text.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/XiaoMi/ha_xiaomi_home</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-16T00:00:00.000ZXiaomi has provided official support for Home Assistant</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[25 Years of Dillo]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Dillo, a lightweight web browser originally forked from Gzilla/Armadillo in 1999, is celebrating its 25th anniversary in December 2024.</li>
<li>The browser has undergone several transitions, including moving from GTK 1.0 to FLTK 2 in 2008 and then to FLTK 1.3 in 2011, with development challenges such as the loss of key contributors and its domain.</li>
<li>In 2023, Rodrigo Arias Mallo revitalized the project, leading to the release of version 3.1.0 in May 2024, with ongoing development and the latest version being 3.1.1.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://dillo-browser.github.io/25-years/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-16T00:00:00.000Z25 Years of Dillo</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Palm’s CEO emails Steve Jobs (2007)]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/TechEmails/status/1868368310024462791</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-16T00:00:00.000ZPalm’s CEO emails Steve Jobs (2007)</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nokia 5110 – Back from the Dead (2022)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Nokia 5110, a durable 2G phone, is being revived with a modern twist by retrofitting it with a 4G module, the SIM7600SA, which supports SMS and calling.- The phone&#39;s simple design and two PCBs (Printed Circuit Boards) facilitate the integration of the new 4G module, making the retrofit process more straightforward.- This project highlights the potential for modernizing classic technology, with further developments to be detailed in an upcoming part 2, focusing on designing a new board for extended functionality.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://opsbros.com/nokia-5110-back-from-the-dead/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-16T00:00:00.000ZNokia 5110 – Back from the Dead (2022)</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
