<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss
  xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
  xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
  version="2.0"
>
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Heimdall]]></description>
        <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        <image>
            <url>https://hn.cho.sh/img/android-chrome-512x512.png</url>
            <title>Heimdall</title>
            <link>https://hn.cho.sh</link>
        </image>
        <generator>RSS for Node</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 19:07:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="https://hn.cho.sh/rss/story/en.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
        <ttl>60</ttl>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gukesh becomes the youngest chess world champion in history]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>GM Gukesh D became the youngest world champion in the 2024 World Chess Championship by defeating GM Ding Liren in Round 14.</li>
<li>The match was notable for Gukesh&#39;s strategic play and deep preparation, capitalizing on Ding&#39;s blunder in a king and pawn endgame.</li>
<li>Lichess provided live coverage with commentary from GM Felix Blohberger, IM Laura Unuk, and guest GM Ivan Cheparinov, highlighting the event&#39;s significance and emotional moments.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://lichess.org/@/Lichess/blog/wcc-2024-round-14-gukesh-becomes-the-youngest-world-champion-in-history/cDggdNZw</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-12T00:00:00.000ZGukesh becomes the youngest chess world champion in history</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Timemap.org – Interactive Map of History]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.oldmapsonline.org/en/history/regions</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-12T00:00:00.000ZTimemap.org – Interactive Map of History</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Mysterious New Jersey drone sightings prompt call for 'state of emergency']]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Over 3,000 drone sightings in New Jersey and the US northeast have led to calls for a &quot;limited state of emergency&quot; and a temporary drone ban by State Senator Jon Bramnick.</li>
<li>Concerns are heightened due to drones being spotted near sensitive locations, such as President-elect Trump&#39;s golf course and critical infrastructure.</li>
<li>Despite the large number of sightings, the FBI has not provided an explanation, and the Pentagon has dismissed claims of foreign involvement, including from an &quot;Iranian mothership.&quot;</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2024/dec/11/new-jersey-drone-sightings-state-of-emergency</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-12T00:00:00.000ZMysterious New Jersey drone sightings prompt call for &apos;state of emergency&apos;</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A ChatGPT clone, in 3000 bytes of C, backed by GPT-2 (2023)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Nicholas Carlini has developed a ChatGPT clone using a minimal C implementation of GPT-2, which is only about 3000 bytes in size.- The project is dependency-free and optimized to run GPT-2 Small on modern machines, though it produces low-quality output.- This initiative highlights the simplicity of neural networks and the ability to condense complex machine learning models into compact code, with the source code available on GitHub.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://nicholas.carlini.com/writing/2023/chat-gpt-2-in-c.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-12T00:00:00.000ZA ChatGPT clone, in 3000 bytes of C, backed by GPT-2 (2023)</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bankruptcy judge rejects sale of Infowars to The Onion]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A judge has halted the sale of Infowars to The Onion, which intended to transform it into a satirical platform.</li>
<li>The decision was made despite backing from Sandy Hook victims&#39; families, leaving Infowars&#39; future in limbo.</li>
<li>A court-appointed trustee is now responsible for determining a new course of action, while The Onion remains interested in the acquisition.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/12/10/business/media/the-onion-infowars-alex-jones.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-11T00:00:00.000ZBankruptcy judge rejects sale of Infowars to The Onion</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gemini 2.0: our new AI model for the agentic era]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Google DeepMind has launched Gemini 2.0, an advanced AI model designed for the &quot;agentic era,&quot; featuring capabilities such as native image and audio output and tool use.- Gemini 2.0 Flash is currently accessible to developers and trusted testers, with a wider release expected early next year, indicating a phased rollout strategy.- Google is focusing on responsible AI development, emphasizing safety and security, with potential applications in search, games, and robotics, highlighting the model&#39;s versatility and commitment to ethical AI practices.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.google/technology/google-deepmind/google-gemini-ai-update-december-2024/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-11T00:00:00.000ZGemini 2.0: our new AI model for the agentic era</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[GM exits robotaxi market, will bring Cruise operations in house]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>General Motors (GM) is discontinuing its funding for the Cruise robotaxi division, opting to integrate it into its tech team to focus on autonomous systems for personal vehicles.</li>
<li>GM aims to acquire the remaining Cruise shares by 2025, significantly reducing its annual expenditure on the division by more than half.</li>
<li>Cruise has faced challenges, such as a $1.5 million fine for not reporting a crash, while competitors like Waymo and Tesla continue to progress in the robotaxi market.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbc.com/2024/12/10/gm-halts-funding-of-robotaxi-development-by-cruise.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-11T00:00:00.000ZGM exits robotaxi market, will bring Cruise operations in house</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Electric (Postgres sync engine) beta release]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Electric&#39;s sync engine, now in BETA with version 1.0.0-beta.1, facilitates real-time partial replication of Postgres data into local apps, enabling instant local data access without altering existing technology stacks.- The engine includes PGlite, a lightweight WebAssembly (WASM) version of Postgres for browsers, and is production-ready after a six-month rewrite, already utilized by companies like Google and Supabase.- Electric supports high-throughput workloads with low latency, is easy to adopt with simple APIs, and can be integrated incrementally, with Electric Cloud, a managed hosting service, in development.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://electric-sql.com/blog/2024/12/10/electric-beta-release</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-11T00:00:00.000ZElectric (Postgres sync engine) beta release</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[WPEngine, Inc. vs. Automattic– Order on Motion for Preliminary Injunction]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.courtlistener.com/docket/69221176/64/wpengine-inc-v-automattic-inc/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-11T00:00:00.000ZWPEngine, Inc. vs. Automattic– Order on Motion for Preliminary Injunction</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What we know about CEO shooting suspect]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Luigi Mangione, a 26-year-old from a notable Baltimore family, has been charged with the murder of UnitedHealthcare CEO Brian Thompson in New York City.</li>
<li>Mangione was arrested in Pennsylvania with a ghost gun and a document hinting at a motive related to anger towards corporate America.</li>
<li>Despite his academic achievements and career as a data engineer, Mangione&#39;s social media suggests recent isolation from family and friends.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cp9nxee2r0do</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-10T00:00:00.000ZWhat we know about CEO shooting suspect</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[This is not a joke, Funko just called my mom]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://twitter.com/itchio/status/1866239798924763227</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-10T00:00:00.000ZThis is not a joke, Funko just called my mom</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Tree Calculus]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Tree Calculus is a Turing-complete computational model with a single operator, allowing for program analysis, type checking, compilation, and optimization directly within the code.- It supports arbitrary type systems and gradual typing, enabling powerful Read-Eval-Print Loops (REPLs) and program deployment without external tools.- Its minimal syntax and semantics make it portable and easy to implement interpreters on any platform, suitable for modeling, formal specifications, and educational purposes.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://treecalcul.us/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-10T00:00:00.000ZTree Calculus</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trellis – 3D mesh generative model]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The post introduces a new 3D generation method using a unified Structured LATent (SLAT) representation, enhancing the creation of versatile and high-quality 3D assets.</li>
<li>The model, named TRELLIS, utilizes rectified flow transformers and is trained on a large dataset, outperforming existing methods in 3D generation.</li>
<li>The approach supports flexible output formats and local 3D editing, with plans to release the code, model, and data to the public.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://trellis3d.github.io/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-10T00:00:00.000ZTrellis – 3D mesh generative model</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Save Music, Save the Archive]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Over 500 musicians are advocating for major labels to withdraw a $621 million lawsuit against the Internet Archive, a nonprofit cultural institution.</li>
<li>The musicians emphasize the need for fair compensation, protection of music legacies, and investment in living artists rather than supporting monopolistic practices.</li>
<li>They argue that the music industry&#39;s survival depends on prioritizing artists&#39; futures and preserving their works, urging public support through an open letter.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.savethearchive.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-10T00:00:00.000ZSave Music, Save the Archive</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[From where I left]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://antirez.com/news/144</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-10T00:00:00.000ZFrom where I left</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Developer wrote 25k lines of Neovim plugin code using phone and touchscreen]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://old.reddit.com/r/neovim/comments/1h7vhmg/bro_been_developing_his_2k_star_plugin_on_a/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-10T00:00:00.000ZDeveloper wrote 25k lines of Neovim plugin code using phone and touchscreen</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Debanking (and Debunking?)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Debanking, the involuntary closure of bank accounts, is a contentious issue, particularly affecting crypto businesses, with concerns it may be used as a political tool.</li>
<li>The debate involves complex interactions between private and state actors, with some viewing debanking as necessary for risk management, while others see it as unfair and lacking due process.</li>
<li>Historical regulatory actions like Operation Choke Point, which pressured banks to sever ties with certain industries, are cited by critics as similar to current actions against crypto businesses, termed &quot;Choke Point 2.0.&quot;</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.bitsaboutmoney.com/archive/debanking-and-debunking/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-10T00:00:00.000ZDebanking (and Debunking?)</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Double (YC W24) – Index Investing with 0% Expense Ratios]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Double is a financial platform that allows investment in over 50 stock market indexes with no expense ratios, charging a flat fee of $1/month for management, rebalancing, and tax-loss harvesting.</li>
<li>The platform offers direct indexing by purchasing individual stocks from popular indexes, providing customization and daily portfolio optimization, distinguishing itself from other robo-advisors.</li>
<li>Double has achieved $10 million in assets under management (AUM) and aims to disrupt the $100 billion/year ETF and mutual fund market by offering low-fee investment strategies.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=42377018</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-10T00:00:00.000ZDouble (YC W24) – Index Investing with 0% Expense Ratios</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Itch.io Taken Down by Funko]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://bsky.app/profile/itch.io/post/3lcu6h465bs2n</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-09T00:00:00.000ZItch.io Taken Down by Funko</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Compromising OpenWrt Supply Chain]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A security engineer identified vulnerabilities in OpenWrt&#39;s firmware upgrade process, including command injection and SHA-256 hash collision issues.- The vulnerabilities allowed potential attackers to inject commands and create hash collisions, leading to the installation of malicious firmware.- The OpenWrt team promptly addressed and fixed these vulnerabilities, emphasizing the need for strong security in software supply chains.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://flatt.tech/research/posts/compromising-openwrt-supply-chain-sha256-collision/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-09T00:00:00.000ZCompromising OpenWrt Supply Chain</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Pat Gelsinger was wrong for Intel]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Pat Gelsinger, despite his technical expertise and managerial skills, was deemed unsuitable as Intel&#39;s CEO due to his inability to address the company&#39;s cultural and strategic challenges.</li>
<li>His leadership decisions, such as maintaining dividends and aggressive advertising, were criticized for reflecting a peacetime approach rather than the necessary wartime leadership.</li>
<li>Gelsinger&#39;s management of Intel&#39;s Foundry Services and the termination of the Tofino project, a promising programmable switch silicon, were seen as significant missteps, leaving Intel&#39;s cultural issues unresolved.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://bcantrill.dtrace.org/2024/12/08/why-gelsinger-was-wrong-for-intel/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-09T00:00:00.000ZPat Gelsinger was wrong for Intel</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[JSON5 – JSON for Humans]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>JSON5, an extension of JSON, is designed for easier manual editing, making it ideal for configuration files but not suitable for machine communication.</li>
<li>Since its launch in 2012, JSON5 has gained significant popularity, with over 65 million downloads weekly, and is utilized by major projects like Chromium and Next.js.</li>
<li>JSON5 is a superset of JSON, incorporating ECMAScript 5.1 features, allowing for flexible syntax, and is compatible with ES5, with a JavaScript library available for parsing and serialization.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://json5.org/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-09T00:00:00.000ZJSON5 – JSON for Humans</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UK bans daytime TV ads for cereals, muffins and burgers]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The UK government is implementing a ban on daytime TV advertisements for sugary and &quot;less healthy&quot; foods, such as cereals, muffins, and burgers, to address child obesity.</li>
<li>Starting next October, these ads will only be allowed to air after 9:00 pm, with the goal of preventing 20,000 cases of childhood obesity each year.</li>
<li>Health Secretary Wes Streeting highlighted the importance of stopping the targeting of children with junk food advertisements.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.france24.com/en/live-news/20241204-uk-bans-daytime-tv-ads-for-cereals-muffins-and-burgers</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-09T00:00:00.000ZUK bans daytime TV ads for cereals, muffins and burgers</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hetzner has decided to cancel our account and terminate all servers.]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://mastodon.social/@kiwix/113622081750449356</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-09T00:00:00.000ZHetzner has decided to cancel our account and terminate all servers.</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Willow, Our Quantum Chip]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Google has introduced Willow, a quantum chip that marks a significant advancement in quantum error correction and computation speed.- Willow demonstrated its capability by performing a computation in under five minutes, a task that would take a supercomputer 10 septillion years, indicating its potential to tackle complex problems beyond classical computers.- This development is pivotal for the future of commercially viable quantum computers, with implications for revolutionizing industries such as medicine, energy, and artificial intelligence (AI).</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.google/technology/research/google-willow-quantum-chip/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-09T00:00:00.000ZWillow, Our Quantum Chip</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenAI: Sora]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://sora.com/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-09T00:00:00.000ZOpenAI: Sora</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Nyxt: The Hacker's Browser]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Nyxt is a browser designed for advanced users, emphasizing keyboard navigation and efficiency in online information analysis and extraction.</li>
<li>It features powerful tools like link hinting, Jump Headings for document navigation, and fuzzy search for easy tab management and command execution.</li>
<li>Additional functionalities include a built-in REPL (Read-Eval-Print Loop) for programmability, smart bookmark search, customizable autofills, clipboard history, and a tree-based history for tracking visited pages.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://nyxt.atlas.engineer/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-08T00:00:00.000ZNyxt: The Hacker&apos;s Browser</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Syrian government falls in end to 50-year rule of Assad family]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://apnews.com/article/syria-assad-sweida-daraa-homs-hts-qatar-7f65823bbf0a7bd331109e8dff419430</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-08T00:00:00.000ZSyrian government falls in end to 50-year rule of Assad family</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Reverse engineering the Sega Channel game image file format]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Sega Channel was a pioneering games-on-demand service for the Sega Genesis, active from 1994 to 1998, offering around 50 games monthly.- In 2024, a user discovered a Sega Channel game image CD from 1996, leading to efforts in reverse engineering to extract and preserve its data.- The project successfully decoded exclusive games, emphasizing the role of community efforts and reverse engineering in preserving gaming history.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.infochunk.com/schannel/index.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-08T00:00:00.000ZReverse engineering the Sega Channel game image file format</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Notre Dame Cathedral reopens]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://apnews.com/article/notre-dame-paris-latest-e50813cf016f08607c20ab115bc4b153</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-08T00:00:00.000ZNotre Dame Cathedral reopens</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Brian Krebs Investigates Internet's Most Vicious Hackers–From a Secret Location]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.wsj.com/tech/cybersecurity/hacking-brian-krebs-snowflake-waifu-49b87fce</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-08T00:00:00.000ZBrian Krebs Investigates Internet&apos;s Most Vicious Hackers–From a Secret Location</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Airline informant received thousands from passenger cash seizures]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.atlantanewsfirst.com/2024/12/03/airline-informant-received-thousands-passenger-cash-seizures/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-08T00:00:00.000ZAirline informant received thousands from passenger cash seizures</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Browsing negative content online makes mental health struggles worse: Study]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>MIT researchers have created a web plug-in named &quot;Digital Diet&quot; to assist users in making informed choices about online content to safeguard their mental health.</li>
<li>The tool employs natural language processing (NLP) to evaluate web pages based on emotion, knowledge, and actionability, steering users towards more positive content.</li>
<li>The research underscores the two-way relationship between online behavior and mental health, with findings published in Nature Human Behavior.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://news.mit.edu/2024/study-browsing-negative-content-online-makes-mental-health-struggles-worse-1205</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-08T00:00:00.000ZBrowsing negative content online makes mental health struggles worse: Study</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 08 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My second year without a job]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://shilin.ca/my-second-year-without-job/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-07T00:00:00.000ZMy second year without a job</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[: The Dialog Element]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The HTML `` element is used to create dialog boxes, which can be modal (pausing page interaction) or non-modal (allowing interaction).</li>
<li>JavaScript methods <code>.showModal()</code> and <code>.show()</code> are used to display modal and non-modal dialogs, respectively, while <code>.close()</code> is used to close them.</li>
<li>Accessibility is crucial; ensure focus is set correctly and provide a closing mechanism, such as a button, while using CSS <code>::backdrop</code> for styling modal backdrops.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML/Element/dialog</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-07T00:00:00.000Z: The Dialog Element</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Maps.me co-founder tries to close down Organic Maps open-source fork]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Organic Maps has released the source code for its &quot;metaserver,&quot; which optimizes map download speeds by directing users to the best Content Delivery Network (CDN) servers based on their location.</li>
<li>The code, initially closed to prevent unauthorized forks, is now open under the MIT license, promoting transparency and community involvement.</li>
<li>The team is reconsidering the use of Cloudflare Workers to prevent vendor lock-in and has reverted unauthorized changes made by a contributor, emphasizing their commitment to privacy and transparency.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/orgs/organicmaps/discussions/9837</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-07T00:00:00.000ZMaps.me co-founder tries to close down Organic Maps open-source fork</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to use Postgres for everything]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>&quot;Postgres for Everything&quot; is a repository that promotes the use of PostgreSQL, a popular open-source relational database, for a wide range of applications beyond traditional database tasks.- The repository invites contributions and tracks various innovative uses of PostgreSQL, including cron jobs, message queues, analytics, and more, highlighting its versatility.- The initiative includes 11 items related to Supabase, a platform that provides backend services using PostgreSQL, showcasing its integration and utility in modern application development.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/Olshansk/postgres_for_everything</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-07T00:00:00.000ZHow to use Postgres for everything</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lies I was told about collab editing, Part 1: Algorithms for offline editing]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>In early 2024, research into collaborative editing systems for Moment&#39;s text editor highlighted challenges with offline editing, where popular algorithms like CRDTs (Conflict-free Replicated Data Types) and OT (Operational Transformation) often fail.- Offline editing increases direct conflicts, with 20-30% of these conflicts resulting in unacceptable outcomes, suggesting the issue is more of a user interface/user experience (UI/UX) challenge than an algorithmic one.- Researchers are now focusing on improving the user experience in offline editing, drawing parallels to how git handles document merging, which is a promising development.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.moment.dev/blog/lies-i-was-told-pt-1</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-07T00:00:00.000ZLies I was told about collab editing, Part 1: Algorithms for offline editing</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Structured Outputs with Ollama]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Ollama has introduced support for structured outputs, enabling models to generate outputs in a specific format using a JSON schema.</li>
<li>This feature is now available in the updated Ollama Python and JavaScript libraries, useful for tasks like data parsing from documents and images.</li>
<li>Users should update to the latest Ollama version and use the format parameter in cURL requests or libraries, with future updates promising performance enhancements and more format options.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ollama.com/blog/structured-outputs</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-07T00:00:00.000ZStructured Outputs with Ollama</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[RollerCoaster Tycoon was the last of its kind [video]]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=0JouTsMQsEA</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-07T00:00:00.000ZRollerCoaster Tycoon was the last of its kind [video]</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Fructose in diet enhances tumor growth: research]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Fructose consumption has increased significantly over the last 50 years, primarily due to high-fructose corn syrup in beverages and processed foods.</li>
<li>Research from Washington University in St. Louis indicates that while fructose doesn&#39;t directly fuel tumors, the liver converts it into nutrients that support tumor growth in cancers such as melanoma, breast, and cervical cancer.</li>
<li>The study suggests potential new cancer treatments by exploring methods to prevent fructose from aiding tumor growth, possibly through dietary changes or pharmaceuticals, with partial funding from the National Institutes of Health (NIH).</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://source.washu.edu/2024/12/research-reveals-how-fructose-in-diet-enhances-tumor-growth/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-07T00:00:00.000ZFructose in diet enhances tumor growth: research</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Biggest shell programs]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The page highlights significant shell programs, focusing on substantial hand-written scripts rather than those generated by tools like autoconf.- Notable entries include akinomyoga/ble.sh, a Bash Line Editor with 61K lines of code (LoC), and kalua, an OpenWRT addon with 56K source lines of code (SLoC).- The list provides insights into the complexity and diversity of shell scripting, featuring programs that utilize data structures and algorithms, typically exceeding 5,000 lines of code.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/oils-for-unix/oils/wiki/The-Biggest-Shell-Programs-in-the-World</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-07T00:00:00.000ZBiggest shell programs</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DSPy – Programming–not prompting–LMs]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>DSPy is a framework designed for building modular AI systems using compositional Python code, focusing on improving language model (LM) outputs without relying solely on prompts.- It supports multiple large language model (LLM) providers like OpenAI, Anthropic, and Databricks, allowing users to describe AI behavior as code, facilitating easier iteration and optimization.- Originating from Stanford NLP, DSPy has a strong community presence on GitHub and Discord, contributing to open-source AI research and advancing program architectures and optimizers.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://dspy.ai/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-07T00:00:00.000ZDSPy – Programming–not prompting–LMs</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The correct amount of ads is zero]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The Verge has introduced a subscription model with a paywalled version, offering benefits like full-text RSS feeds to subscribers.</li>
<li>The subscription aims to reduce ad exposure, but there is criticism that paying subscribers should not see any ads at all.</li>
<li>Concerns are raised about potential data selling to advertisers, suggesting that subscribers should not be subject to both ads and data monetization.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://manuelmoreale.com/the-correct-amount-of-ads-is-zero</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZThe correct amount of ads is zero</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The 70% problem: Hard truths about AI-assisted coding]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://addyo.substack.com/p/the-70-problem-hard-truths-about</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZThe 70% problem: Hard truths about AI-assisted coding</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Portland airport grows with expansive mass timber roof canopy]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Portland Airport (PDX) has expanded its main terminal with a sustainable mass timber roof canopy, designed by ZGF, using locally sourced glulam Douglas Fir.</li>
<li>The nine-acre canopy aims to enhance airport capacity and passenger experience while reducing the carbon footprint, incorporating biophilic elements for a welcoming atmosphere.</li>
<li>This project sets a new standard for sustainable airport design, with completion anticipated in 2026.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://design-milk.com/portland-airport-grows-with-expansive-mass-timber-roof-canopy/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZPortland airport grows with expansive mass timber roof canopy</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Intel’s board, and an example of when boards and short-termism fail]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Pat Gelsinger&#39;s exit from Intel is portrayed as a firing rather than a retirement, emphasizing the board&#39;s failures and short-term focus over long-term strategy.- The board&#39;s lack of semiconductor expertise and focus on immediate shareholder value have been criticized, potentially harming Intel&#39;s long-term prospects and the U.S. semiconductor industry.- The board&#39;s failure to support Gelsinger&#39;s IDM 2.0 strategy suggests a shift towards selling company parts, which may benefit shareholders short-term but could damage Intel&#39;s future.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.fabricatedknowledge.com/p/the-death-of-intel-when-boards-fail</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZIntel’s board, and an example of when boards and short-termism fail</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Trailbase: Fast, single-file, open-source app server built using Rust and SQLite]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>TrailBase is an open-source application server designed for fast, type-safe APIs, utilizing Rust, SQLite, and V8, and is suitable for mobile, web, or desktop applications.</li>
<li>It offers sub-millisecond latencies, removing the need for dedicated caches, and supports various platforms with pre-built binaries and client packages available for Linux, MacOS, and multiple programming languages.</li>
<li>TrailBase is licensed under OSL-3.0, allowing it to be used as a framework without additional licensing requirements, and contributions from the community are encouraged.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/trailbaseio/trailbase</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZTrailbase: Fast, single-file, open-source app server built using Rust and SQLite</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Gitlab names Bill Staples as new CEO]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>GitLab has appointed Bill Staples as the new CEO, with co-founder Sid Sijbrandij moving to Executive Chair of the Board due to health reasons.</li>
<li>Staples, formerly CEO at New Relic, brings extensive experience in developer platforms to GitLab, a prominent AI-powered DevSecOps platform.</li>
<li>GitLab serves over 10,000 customers, generates over $750 million in revenue, and is trusted by more than 40 million users, including over half of the Fortune 100 companies.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20241205391064/en/GitLab-Names-Bill-Staples-as-New-CEO</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZGitlab names Bill Staples as new CEO</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Ukraine's three nuclear power plants have restored electricity production]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Ukraine&#39;s nuclear power plants have resumed electricity production following recent grid attacks, highlighting the importance of a stable power supply for nuclear safety.</li>
<li>The International Atomic Energy Agency (IAEA) is actively monitoring the situation in Ukraine, underscoring its commitment to nuclear safety and security.</li>
<li>Equipment valued at over 14 million euros has been provided to Ukraine to bolster nuclear safety and security measures.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.iaea.org/newscenter/pressreleases/update-263-iaea-director-general-statement-on-situation-in-ukraine</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZUkraine&apos;s three nuclear power plants have restored electricity production</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[ExxonMobil's Alleged Hack-for-Hire Campaign Targeting Climate Activists]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>ExxonMobil is accused of orchestrating a hack-for-hire campaign, &quot;Fox Hunt,&quot; targeting over 500 climate activists and journalists using advanced cyber capabilities.</li>
<li>The operation allegedly involved phishing attacks and leaked emails to undermine environmental advocates and support Exxon’s legal strategies, despite the company&#39;s denial of involvement.</li>
<li>This case underscores the growing trend of digital warfare in corporate disputes, prompting FBI investigations and calls for stronger legal measures to combat such cyber operations.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.vulnu.com/p/inside-exxonmobils-alleged-hack-for-hire-campaign-targeting-climate-activists</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZExxonMobil&apos;s Alleged Hack-for-Hire Campaign Targeting Climate Activists</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Kagi Teams]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Kagi for Teams, set to launch on December 5, 2024, provides businesses with a privacy-focused search and AI tool, emphasizing no ads, tracking, or data harvesting.</li>
<li>The service includes a premium search engine and universal AI access, with flexible pricing based on active users, offering Professional and Ultimate plans.</li>
<li>Kagi promises quick setup, available support, and significant return on investment (ROI) through faster research times, ensuring data privacy for businesses.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.kagi.com/kagi-teams</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZKagi Teams</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[I spent a year building an Android course for the elderly]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author developed a video course to teach elderly individuals how to use Android smartphones, addressing common challenges such as intimidation by interfaces and lack of basic skills like scrolling or swiping.</li>
<li>The course includes a 400-page script, video recordings, and an Android app with exercises, initially hosted on Udemy and later moved to a dedicated website, &quot;Smartphone How-To.&quot;</li>
<li>Marketing the course is challenging due to the target audience&#39;s difficulties with online registration and payment, and the author seeks feedback for improvement.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://kopiascsaba.hu/blog/teaching-elderly-people-to-use-android/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZI spent a year building an Android course for the elderly</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[McKinsey unit will pay $123M to settle claims it bribed South African officials]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A McKinsey &amp; Company subsidiary has agreed to pay $123 million to settle allegations of bribing South African officials, as reported by the U.S. Department of Justice.</li>
<li>The bribery scheme, involving McKinsey Africa, resulted in $85 million in profits through contracts with state-controlled utility companies.</li>
<li>Former McKinsey partner Vikas Sagar admitted guilt to conspiracy charges under the Foreign Corrupt Practices Act, and McKinsey Africa has agreed to a three-year deferred prosecution agreement, pledging to enhance compliance measures.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnbc.com/2024/12/05/mckinsey-bribery-settlement-south-africa.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZMcKinsey unit will pay $123M to settle claims it bribed South African officials</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Llama-3.3-70B-Instruct]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://huggingface.co/meta-llama/Llama-3.3-70B-Instruct</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZLlama-3.3-70B-Instruct</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Install postmarketOS on Android phone and use Docker as a home server]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The guide details installing Docker on a OnePlus 6T using postmarketOS, effectively converting it into a home server, but it erases all phone data.</li>
<li>Key requirements include a OnePlus 6 or 6T, Fastboot on a PC, and postmarketOS files, with steps involving enabling Developer Mode, flashing postmarketOS, and setting up SSH.</li>
<li>While this setup offers an alternative to a Raspberry Pi with an integrated screen and battery, it lacks Ethernet support and is limited to internal storage.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://crackoverflow.com/docs/system_administration/containerization/install-docker-natively-on-android-phone-and-use-it-as-a-home-server/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZInstall postmarketOS on Android phone and use Docker as a home server</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hacker Herald – like HN but with crowdsourced pics and subtitles]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author, along with former instructor Arnav and student Archis, has launched a project called Hacker Herald, a front end for Hacker News.- The project was developed during an online JavaScript programming course and aims to provide a visually appealing layout similar to popular newspaper sites.- The inclusion of visuals, such as images, is intended to enhance the storytelling experience by providing immediate context without needing to click through articles.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://hackerherald.com/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZHacker Herald – like HN but with crowdsourced pics and subtitles</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Congo gov. says it's 'on alert' over mystery flu-like disease that killed dozens]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.ctvnews.ca/health/congo-government-says-it-s-on-alert-over-mystery-flu-like-disease-that-killed-dozens-1.7134550</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-06T00:00:00.000ZCongo gov. says it&apos;s &apos;on alert&apos; over mystery flu-like disease that killed dozens</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Diátaxis – A systematic approach to technical documentation authoring]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Diátaxis is a systematic approach to technical documentation that focuses on user needs by categorizing content into four types: tutorials, how-to guides, technical reference, and explanation.</li>
<li>This method addresses issues related to content, style, and organization, benefiting both users and creators by enhancing documentation quality and accessibility.</li>
<li>Diátaxis has been successfully implemented in projects like Gatsby and Cloudflare, demonstrating its practical effectiveness in improving clarity and user accessibility.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://diataxis.fr/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-05T00:00:00.000ZDiátaxis – A systematic approach to technical documentation authoring</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bringing K/V context quantisation to Ollama]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://smcleod.net/2024/12/bringing-k/v-context-quantisation-to-ollama/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-05T00:00:00.000ZBringing K/V context quantisation to Ollama</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Next stop: Miami]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Waymo One is set to expand its autonomous, all-electric ride-hailing service to Miami in 2026, using Jaguar I-PACEs.</li>
<li>The expansion is in partnership with Moove and follows successful tests in Miami&#39;s challenging weather conditions.</li>
<li>This move aligns with Miami&#39;s emphasis on sustainable and clean energy transportation, and the service will be accessible through the Waymo One app.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://waymo.com/blog/2024/12/next-stop-miami/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-05T00:00:00.000ZNext stop: Miami</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Federal Court Says Dismantling a Phone to Install Firmware Isn't a 'Search']]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The iPhone 6 is susceptible to the checkm8 exploit, which is a known security vulnerability.</li>
<li>Devices such as the iPhone XS and newer models are currently not affected by this exploit, indicating improved security measures in later models.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://www.techdirt.com/2024/12/04/federal-court-says-dismantling-a-phone-to-install-firmware-isnt-a-search-even-if-was-done-to-facilitate-a-search/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-05T00:00:00.000ZFederal Court Says Dismantling a Phone to Install Firmware Isn&apos;t a &apos;Search&apos;</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[VectorChord: Store 400k Vectors for $1 in PostgreSQL]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>VectorChord is a new PostgreSQL extension designed for efficient vector search, capable of storing 400,000 vectors for just $1, making it more cost-effective than competitors.- It utilizes IVF (Inverted File) and RaBitQ (Random Bit Quantization) techniques to enhance search speed and memory efficiency, making it suitable for handling large datasets.- VectorChord outperforms alternatives like Pinecone and pgvector in terms of both price and performance, offering scalable vector search with improved speed and precision for applications needing quick and accurate responses.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.pgvecto.rs/vectorchord-store-400k-vectors-for-1-in-postgresql</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-05T00:00:00.000ZVectorChord: Store 400k Vectors for $1 in PostgreSQL</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Bitcoin is over $100k]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.tradingview.com/symbols/BTCUSD/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-05T00:00:00.000ZBitcoin is over $100k</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[IMG_0001]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Between 2009 and 2012, iPhones featured a &quot;Send to YouTube&quot; button in the Photos app, resulting in numerous uploads with default IMG_XXXX filenames.- A bot was developed, inspired by Ben Wallace, to locate 5 million of these videos, showcasing raw and unedited moments.- The collection of videos is available for viewing, presented in a random order, offering a glimpse into unfiltered content from that era.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://walzr.com/IMG_0001/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZIMG_0001</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My son (9 yrs old) used plain JavaScript to make a game, and wants your feedback]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>A 9-year-old has been learning coding, mastering HTML and CSS, and recently used Google Gemini to enhance his skills.- He created a game by coding HTML, CSS, and JavaScript in VSCode and used Piskel for animated graphics, with guidance from his parents and Google Gemini.- The child documented his experience in a blog post, discussing the process and receiving feedback from his programmer parents to refine his writing.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.armaansahni.com/game/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZMy son (9 yrs old) used plain JavaScript to make a game, and wants your feedback</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Egoless Engineering]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The talk emphasizes the importance of fostering better work environments by breaking down unnecessary role divisions and encouraging collaboration across roles.- It highlights inefficiencies caused by excessive role splitting and the misconception of &quot;devops&quot; practices that create barriers rather than promoting collaboration.- The speaker advocates for valuing cooperation, curiosity, and shared responsibility, suggesting that misery should not be equated with productivity.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://egoless.engineering</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZEgoless Engineering</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Phoenix LiveView 1.0.0 is here]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Phoenix LiveView 1.0.0 has been released, offering a major update that simplifies dynamic server-rendered applications by reducing the need for JavaScript and enhancing real-time capabilities.- Key features of this release include a diffing engine for efficient updates, HEEx components for improved HTML composability, and interactive uploads, all leveraging Elixir and the Erlang VM for superior latency and scalability.- The update also introduces new features like streams and async operations, with future plans to integrate JavaScript hooks and Web Components, encouraging developers to explore its easy setup.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.phoenixframework.org/blog/phoenix-liveview-1.0-released?release=1.0</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZPhoenix LiveView 1.0.0 is here</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Genie 2: A large-scale foundation world model]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Research Genie 2, released on December 4, 2024, is a large-scale foundation world model designed to generate diverse 3D environments for AI agent training.- Developed by Jack Parker-Holder&#39;s team, Genie 2 can create action-controllable, playable worlds from a single image prompt, supporting rapid prototyping and interactive experiences.- Genie 2 advances AI research by modeling object interactions, character animations, and environmental physics, addressing the challenge of creating rich training environments for embodied agents.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://deepmind.google/discover/blog/genie-2-a-large-scale-foundation-world-model/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZGenie 2: A large-scale foundation world model</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[OpenTTD is an open source simulation game based upon Transport Tycoon Deluxe]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>OpenTTD 14.1 was released on May 3, 2024, focusing on bug fixes since the initial release.- Key updates include resolving a multiplayer desynchronization bug and enhancements to the ship pathfinder and unbunching feature.- Players have shown significant engagement, logging 34,700 hours in 17,219 games in the past week.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.openttd.org/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZOpenTTD is an open source simulation game based upon Transport Tycoon Deluxe</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[My C compiler compiled itself]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://github.com/keyvank/30cc</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZMy C compiler compiled itself</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[How to grow professional relationships]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The TJS (The Journey to Synergy) Collaboration Model outlines seven states of professional relationships, ranging from competitive to shared identity, to enhance collaboration.</li>
<li>The model emphasizes moving from a zero-sum mindset to high-quality synergy, encouraging an abundance mindset and alignment with personal goals and values.</li>
<li>Key stages include Competition, Coexist, Communicate, Cooperate, Coordinate, Collaborate, and &quot;We are the same,&quot; with the ultimate goal of achieving more collectively than individually.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://tej.as/blog/how-to-grow-professional-relationships-tjs-model</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZHow to grow professional relationships</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A particle physics course for high-school students]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>CERN&#39;s Physics Education Research team has developed a pilot particle physics course for high-school students, consisting of 16 chapters with videos and quizzes.- The course, lasting approximately 4 hours, covers fundamental topics such as &quot;What is a particle?&quot; and &quot;What is a particle accelerator?&quot; and includes DIY experiments.- Participants can complete chapters in any order and earn a digital certificate upon completing all quizzes, with feedback encouraged to enhance future iterations.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://ppc.web.cern.ch/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZA particle physics course for high-school students</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No NAT November: My month without IPv4]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The &quot;No NAT November&quot; challenge involved disabling IPv4 and using only IPv6, highlighting the potential and challenges of transitioning to IPv6-only networks.- The author suggests an &quot;IPv6-mostly&quot; approach, which prioritizes IPv6 while maintaining dual-stack networks, reducing maintenance and preparing for an IPv4-free future.- Transitional technologies like NAT64 and DNS64 helped address compatibility issues, with Apple devices adapting well, while Windows and Linux showed mixed results.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://blog.infected.systems/posts/2024-12-01-no-nat-november/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZNo NAT November: My month without IPv4</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Formaldehyde Causes More Cancer Than Any Other Toxic Air Pollutant]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Formaldehyde, a prevalent air pollutant from sources like car exhaust and factories, poses significant cancer risks, particularly linked to myeloid leukemia.- Efforts to regulate formaldehyde have been obstructed by industry influence and political changes, with notable setbacks during the Trump administration.- ProPublica&#39;s investigation underscores the underestimated risks of formaldehyde exposure and the ongoing challenges in implementing effective regulations, despite some progress under the Biden administration.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.propublica.org/article/formaldehyde-epa-trump-public-health-danger</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZFormaldehyde Causes More Cancer Than Any Other Toxic Air Pollutant</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[EmacsConf 2024]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>EmacsConf 2024 is scheduled to be held online on December 7-8, featuring talks, volunteer opportunities, and discussions centered around GNU Emacs and Emacs Lisp.</li>
<li>The event will utilize free software for streaming and includes a satellite event in Lucerne, Switzerland, offering a hybrid experience.</li>
<li>Participants can engage in discussions via the emacsconf-discuss mailing list, organize through emacsconf-org, and connect on IRC at #emacsconf on irc.libera.chat, with content licensed under CC BY-SA 4.0 and GPLv3+.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://emacsconf.org/2024/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZEmacsConf 2024</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[UnitedHealthcare CEO fatally shot in midtown Manhattan]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.cnn.com/2024/12/04/us/brian-thompson-united-healthcare-death/index.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZUnitedHealthcare CEO fatally shot in midtown Manhattan</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Stephen King to shut down his 3 radio stations in Maine]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Stephen King is closing his three radio stations in Bangor, Maine, after over 40 years of ownership, due to financial losses and his age.</li>
<li>The stations, which reflect King&#39;s passion for rock music and local media, will cease operations on New Year&#39;s Eve.</li>
<li>This decision marks a significant change in King&#39;s business affairs, as he reorganizes his ventures.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.nytimes.com/2024/12/03/arts/stephen-king-maine-radio-stations.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZStephen King to shut down his 3 radio stations in Maine</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[The Porsche Macan EV is being recalled because its headlights are too bright]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Porsche is recalling 2,941 Macan Electric models in the U.S. due to headlights that are too bright, requiring a service center visit for a software update.</li>
<li>The issue cannot be resolved through an over-the-air update, necessitating a physical visit to a service center for the free fix.</li>
<li>The recall affects vehicles manufactured between March 15 and November 4, 2024, with dealers and owners being notified in December 2024 and January 2025, respectively.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://insideevs.com/news/742893/porsche-macan-electric-ev-recall-headlights/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-04T00:00:00.000ZThe Porsche Macan EV is being recalled because its headlights are too bright</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Facebook's Little Red Book]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>In 2012, Facebook created a &quot;Little Red Book&quot; to maintain its identity and focus as it expanded to a billion users, emphasizing principles like breaking things, thinking big, and moving fast.</li>
<li>The book, designed by Ben Barry, served as a manifesto to preserve Facebook&#39;s ethos during rapid growth, showcasing the importance of storytelling in scaling company culture.</li>
<li>A high-quality digital version of this rare book has been created to illustrate how successful companies maintain their identity and culture.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.map.cv/blog/redbook</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-03T00:00:00.000ZFacebook&apos;s Little Red Book</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[South Korean president declares emergency martial law]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://apnews.com/article/south-korea-yoon-martial-law-997c22ac93f6a9bece68454597e577c1</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-03T00:00:00.000ZSouth Korean president declares emergency martial law</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Lessons I learned working at an art gallery]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.henrikkarlsson.xyz/p/art-gallery</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-03T00:00:00.000ZLessons I learned working at an art gallery</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Y Combinator and Power in Silicon Valley]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>In 2010, AdGrok, a small startup, faced a lawsuit from their former employer, Adchemy, which threatened their financial stability.- Y Combinator, a startup accelerator backing AdGrok, played a pivotal role in resolving the lawsuit by leveraging its influence with Adchemy&#39;s investors and potential business partners.- Despite winning the lawsuit, the ordeal led to AdGrok&#39;s sale to Twitter in 2011, while Adchemy was later sold to Walmart Labs in a fire-sale acquisition.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://commoncog.com/c/cases/y-combinator-power/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-03T00:00:00.000ZY Combinator and Power in Silicon Valley</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8 months of OCaml after 8 years of Haskell in production (2023)]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author compares Haskell and OCaml based on their experience, highlighting that Haskell has more features and packages, but OCaml&#39;s simplicity enhances productivity.- Haskell&#39;s tooling is powerful yet inconsistent, while OCaml&#39;s tooling is straightforward and reliable, with succinct compiler messages.- Both languages are suitable for industrial use, but the author prefers OCaml for its focus on development rather than overthinking, despite Haskell&#39;s more comprehensive documentation.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://chshersh.com/blog/2023-12-16-8-months-of-ocaml-after-8-years-of-haskell.html</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-03T00:00:00.000Z8 months of OCaml after 8 years of Haskell in production (2023)</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Twice-Yearly HIV Shot Shows 100% Effectiveness in Women]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<p>- </p>
]]></description>
            <link>https://apnews.com/article/hiv-infections-aids-prevention-shot-02606f7d7892f0baf55bd0a0ff2ba3de</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-03T00:00:00.000ZTwice-Yearly HIV Shot Shows 100% Effectiveness in Women</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Blizzard's pulling of Warcraft I and II tests GOG's new Preservation Program]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Blizzard has requested GOG to remove the DRM-free bundle of Warcraft I &amp; II from its store due to the release of remastered versions.</li>
<li>GOG is offering the bundle at a discount before removal, ensuring that buyers will still have access and receive updates for compatibility with modern systems.</li>
<li>This situation underscores the ongoing tension between remastered and original game versions, with GOG striving to preserve classic games despite publisher decisions.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://arstechnica.com/gaming/2024/12/blizzards-pulling-of-warcraft-i-ii-tests-gogs-new-preservation-program/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-03T00:00:00.000ZBlizzard&apos;s pulling of Warcraft I and II tests GOG&apos;s new Preservation Program</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Raspberry Pi boosts Pi 5 performance with SDRAM tuning]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Raspberry Pi engineers have optimized SDRAM (Synchronous Dynamic Random-Access Memory) timings, resulting in a 10-20% performance boost for Pi 5 and Pi 4 at 2.4 GHz.</li>
<li>Overclocking, which involves increasing the clock speed beyond the manufacturer&#39;s specifications, can achieve up to a 32% speedup, with most Pi 5s reaching 2.6-3.0 GHz.</li>
<li>These performance enhancements, including NUMA (Non-Uniform Memory Access) emulation for better multi-core workload handling, may soon be available through firmware updates, potentially becoming standard features.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.jeffgeerling.com/blog/2024/raspberry-pi-boosts-pi-5-performance-sdram-tuning</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-03T00:00:00.000ZRaspberry Pi boosts Pi 5 performance with SDRAM tuning</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[No need to email me about Cisco AnyConnect]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>The author&#39;s name and email are included in Cisco&#39;s AnyConnect VPN client due to the use of the curl library, leading to confusion among users seeking support.- The author clarifies they are the lead developer of curl, a component used in the app, but not affiliated with Cisco or AnyConnect.- Users needing support for AnyConnect should contact Cisco directly at <a href="mailto:ac-mobile-feedback@cisco.com">ac-mobile-feedback@cisco.com</a>.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://daniel.haxx.se/blog/2024/12/03/no-need-to-email-me-about-cisco-anyconnect/</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2024-12-03T00:00:00.000ZNo need to email me about Cisco AnyConnect</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[DuckDuckGo Donates $25k to the Perl and Raku Foundation]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>DuckDuckGo has donated $25,000 to The Perl and Raku Foundation (TPRF) on &quot;Giving Tuesday,&quot; contributing to their mission of advancing Perl and Raku programming languages.</li>
<li>Since 2011, DuckDuckGo has donated over $6 million to organizations that support online trust, highlighting its commitment to fostering secure and trustworthy online environments.</li>
<li>The donation will aid in funding core Perl development and community projects, with TPRF expressing gratitude for DuckDuckGo&#39;s support and confidence in their mission.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link>https://www.perl.com/article/duckduckgo-donates-25-000-to-the-perl-and-raku-foundation/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-03T00:00:00.000ZDuckDuckGo Donates $25k to the Perl and Raku Foundation</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Company claims 1k% price hike drove it from VMware to open source rival]]></title>
            <description
      ><![CDATA[<ul>
<li>Beeks Group, a UK cloud operator, transitioned 20,000 virtual machines (VMs) from VMware to OpenNebula following a 1,000% price increase after Broadcom acquired VMware.</li>
<li>This migration enhanced VM efficiency by 200% and allowed Beeks to allocate more resources to client workloads.</li>
<li>Broadcom&#39;s acquisition of VMware has led to increased costs and reduced support, prompting many companies, including AT&amp;T, to seek alternatives due to customer dissatisfaction.</li>
</ul>
]]></description>
            <link
      >https://arstechnica.com/information-technology/2024/12/company-claims-1000-percent-price-hike-drove-it-from-vmware-to-open-source-rival/</link>
            <guid
        isPermaLink="false"
      >2024-12-03T00:00:00.000ZCompany claims 1k% price hike drove it from VMware to open source rival</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
